<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>Hacker News: Best Comments</title><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/bestcomments</link><description>Hacker News RSS</description><docs>https://hnrss.org/</docs><generator>hnrss v2.1.1</generator><lastBuildDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2025 23:53:13 +0000</lastBuildDate><ns0:link href="https://hnrss.org/bestcomments" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item><title>New comment by haolez in "ChatControl: EU wants to scan all private messages, even in encrypted apps"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I think the challenge for society here is not to simply reject attempts like this, but how to prevent them from being pushed over and over until a specific context allows it to be approved.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2025 16:20:49 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45374802</link><dc:creator>haolez</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45374802</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45374802</guid></item><item><title>New comment by mosura in "Cloudflare Email Service: private beta"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Eventually all Internet protocols will be MITMed by cloudflare. Your single point of interception!&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2025 15:07:19 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45373568</link><dc:creator>mosura</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45373568</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45373568</guid></item><item><title>New comment by godelski in "Helium Browser"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;  &gt; Helium is based on Chromium
  &gt; Best privacy by default
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
Sorry, pass...&lt;p&gt;Even with un-googled Chromium I do not think these statements are self-consistent. We need browsers that do not allow Google to control the ecosystem. We need legitimate competition. So what, our choices are Firefox (Gecko), Safari (WebKit), and Ladybird?&lt;p&gt;Personally I go with Firefox on most devices and Orion (WebKit) on my iPhone and iPad.&lt;p&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;  &gt; Helium anonymizes all internal requests to the Chrome Web Store via Helium services.
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
This seems like something pretty easy to mess up. Maybe it is good now, but it sure is going to be a cat and mouse game.&lt;p&gt;I really would be curious to have some breakdown comparison with something like the Mullvad browser (Gecko). I have a lot of trust for both the Mullvad and Tor teams. They have a much longer history working with this kind of stuff and have been consistently updating it since release. Launched in early 2023[0] and last update was last week[1].&lt;p&gt;[0] The Mullvad Browser (mullvad.net) &lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=35421034"&gt;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=35421034&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;[0.5] Mullvad Browser (torproject.org) &lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=37159744"&gt;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=37159744&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;[1] &lt;a href="https://github.com/mullvad/mullvad-browser" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://github.com/mullvad/mullvad-browser&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2025 05:16:37 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45369511</link><dc:creator>godelski</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45369511</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45369511</guid></item><item><title>New comment by CSMastermind in "Everything that's wrong with Google Search in one image"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I'm old enough to remember when a big selling point of Google was that it didn't do this.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 24 Sep 2025 23:03:44 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45366964</link><dc:creator>CSMastermind</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45366964</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45366964</guid></item><item><title>New comment by jsheard in "Everything that's wrong with Google Search in one image"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;They do the same thing on the Play Store, for example I just searched for Firefox and the first result is a sponsored spot for Opera. Does Apple do that on the App Store?&lt;p&gt;A funnier example: searching for Amazon gives Temu as the first result. Searching for Temu gives Shein as the first result. Searching for Shein gives Shein as the first result! ...but only because they outbid everyone else for the ad spot on their own name, resulting in Double Shein: &lt;a href="https://i.imgur.com/0buR8Hq.png" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://i.imgur.com/0buR8Hq.png&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 24 Sep 2025 22:58:04 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45366914</link><dc:creator>jsheard</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45366914</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45366914</guid></item><item><title>New comment by zelphirkalt in "Just let me select text"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I have a habit of selecting and highlighting text on computer screens, while reading. I have no issues tracking lines usually, but somehow I still select and highlight. Maybe it is just easier to track lines this way. When I see some web page, that prevents this, then that website gets a -50 reputation score out of 100 in my book. So if the site is perfect in every other way (almost no site is) then -50 still makes it pretty terrible. If additionally it would actually be useful in other ways to highlight and copy text on a site, then I get really annoyed by web non-sense like that. Similarly I get annoyed, if every pixel is some clickable action trigger.&lt;p&gt;This is not what hypertext has been created for. Stop making the web into a cesspit of bad accessibility.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 24 Sep 2025 18:38:16 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45364329</link><dc:creator>zelphirkalt</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45364329</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45364329</guid></item><item><title>New comment by cs702 in "Terence Tao: The role of small organizations in society has shrunk significantly"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Great post, thought-provoking. Highly recommended.&lt;p&gt;Interestingly, in the past, the US federal government actively made efforts to keep private organizations from becoming too dominant. Here are just a few examples, from memory:&lt;p&gt;* The Bell system was broken up, resulting in a geographically distributed telecom network: &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Breakup_of_the_Bell_System" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Breakup_of_the_Bell_System&lt;/a&gt; : Your phone company was local.&lt;p&gt;* Banks could not cross state lines, resulting in a geographically distributed financial system: &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/McFadden_Act" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/McFadden_Act&lt;/a&gt; : Your bank was always local.&lt;p&gt;* Banks were prohibited from entering riskier businesses, resulting in a compartmentalized system: &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Glass%E2%80%93Steagall_legislation" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Glass%E2%80%93Steagall_legisla...&lt;/a&gt; : Your bank did not try to sell you investments.&lt;p&gt;* Monopolies and oligopolies were routinely busted, resulting in less concentration in many industries: &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Competition_law#United_States_antitrust" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Competition_law#United_States_...&lt;/a&gt; .&lt;p&gt;The companies you dealt with every day were typically smaller, more local, more subject to competition, and less able to yield economic and political power, particularly at the national level.&lt;p&gt;Nowadays, power and resources seem to be far more concentrated.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 24 Sep 2025 16:59:57 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45363077</link><dc:creator>cs702</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45363077</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45363077</guid></item><item><title>New comment by gaoshan in "That Secret Service SIM farm story is bogus"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;There is so much to address in this post but I want to look at just this part: "One of the reasons we know this story is bogus is because of the New York Times story which cites anonymous officials, “speaking on the condition of anonymity to discuss an ongoing investigation”. That’s not a thing, that’s not a valid reason to grant anonymity under normal journalistic principles. It’s the “Washington Game” of “official leaks”, disseminating propaganda without being held accountable."&lt;p&gt;It is not accurate to claim "that's not a thing". Citing anonymous sources is a long established practice (in particular when it comes to law enforcement activities or potentially sensitive political reporting). The NYT has formal editorial standards around the identity of anonymous sources that require editors to assess the justification for applying it. It doesn't mean the information is reliable, that's where an editorial eye comes into play, but it does fall under the category of normal journalistic practice.&lt;p&gt;Next the "Washington Game": there’s a grain of truth here, but it is overstated. Yes, leaks can be part of a strategic move by politicians and it can be a source of exploitation by political operators but to equate all anonymous sourcing with propaganda is misleading. Plenty of such reporting has resulted in significant truths being revealed and powerful people being held accountable (Watergate, the Pentagon Papers, Abu Ghraib). Responsible reporting involves weighing a source's motivations as well as corroborating and contextualizing that information as accurately and truthfully as possible.&lt;p&gt;The author's dismissiveness oversimplifies (or mischaracterizes, if I am being less generous) the reason and function of anonymity here. They overstate the issue with propaganda and anonymous sources. Accurate in the sense that anonymity can enable propaganda (it has happened), it is inaccurate in its absolutism.&lt;p&gt;I feel like this sort of tone, with the absolutism, the attempt to reduce the complexity and nuance of reporting to the point where it can be dismissed is pretty typical of what passes for commentary in today's blog/tweet/commentary culture but it really plays more into the hands of those that would sow confusion and mistrust than it does into that of the truth and accuracy.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 24 Sep 2025 14:31:40 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45360977</link><dc:creator>gaoshan</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45360977</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45360977</guid></item><item><title>New comment by NoraCodes in "Just let me select text"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Given that this page has the following styles which aren't applied anywhere else on the blog:&lt;p&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;   body {
       -webkit-user-select: none;
       -webkit-touch-callout: none;
       -moz-user-select: none;
       -ms-user-select: none;
       user-select: none;
    }
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
I think it's safe to assume that being unable to select text on this page is not unintentional, as several comments here assume, nor "ironic", but an intentional effort to demonstrate how annoying this behavior is.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 24 Sep 2025 14:27:00 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45360922</link><dc:creator>NoraCodes</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45360922</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45360922</guid></item><item><title>New comment by piyuv in "Yt-dlp: Upcoming new requirements for YouTube downloads"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I’m a paying YouTube premium subscriber. Last weekend, I wanted to download something so I can watch it on my way in the train. The app got stuck at “waiting for download..” on my iPad. Same on iPhone. Restart did not work. I gave up after an hour (30 mins hands on trying stuff, 30 mins waiting for it to fix itself). Downloaded the video using yt-dlp, transferred it to my USB c flash drive, and watched it from that.&lt;p&gt;Awaiting their “premium cannot be shared with people outside household” policy so I can finally cancel. Family members make good use of ad-free.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 24 Sep 2025 12:58:07 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45359665</link><dc:creator>piyuv</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45359665</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45359665</guid></item><item><title>New comment by hackitup7 in "Libghostty is coming"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I love how this guy founds + takes public + sells a multibillion company and then just goes right back to hacking. Legend.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 23 Sep 2025 17:32:08 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45350260</link><dc:creator>hackitup7</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45350260</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45350260</guid></item><item><title>New comment by recursivedoubts in "Mesh: I tried Htmx, then ditched it"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Sounds like this app wasn't a good fit for htmx.  I have added it to the "On The Other Hand" section on the htmx website:&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://htmx.org/essays/#on-the-other-hand" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://htmx.org/essays/#on-the-other-hand&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;Regarding the default swap behavior of "innerHTML":&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://htmx.org/quirks/#the-default-swap-strategy-is-innerhtml" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://htmx.org/quirks/#the-default-swap-strategy-is-innerh...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;Our proposal to merge htmx functionality into the HTML spec uses outerHTML:&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://alexanderpetros.com/triptych/" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://alexanderpetros.com/triptych/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;Also consider datastar, it was written from an SSE-first perspective by a go engineer:&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://data-star.dev/" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://data-star.dev/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 23 Sep 2025 13:21:59 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45346654</link><dc:creator>recursivedoubts</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45346654</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45346654</guid></item><item><title>New comment by adastra22 in "Delete FROM users WHERE location = 'Iran';"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;OP, some context from the other side might be helpful.&lt;p&gt;Yes, there are fines for American companies if they do business with Iranians. That's how sanctions work as I'm sure you're aware. But the story doesn't stop there.&lt;p&gt;If an American finds out they are transacting with a sanctioned individual, or citizens of a sanctioned country like Iran or North Korea, the stakes go up: $1M USD fine &lt;i&gt;and up to 20 years in federal prison&lt;/i&gt;. Oh and that's a personal risk -- &lt;i&gt;you&lt;/i&gt;, the manager or executive in charge, and anyone else who is in the know on the transaction is now facing 20 years in federal pounding-in-the-ass prison if they don't immediately cease all communication and break off contact. Hence why they ghost you and remove your data from prod. It sucks, but I would do the same thing in that situation. Nobody should be expected to take that risk.&lt;p&gt;That's why you have these experiences :(&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 23 Sep 2025 05:58:38 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45343246</link><dc:creator>adastra22</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45343246</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45343246</guid></item><item><title>New comment by rpigab in "You did this with an AI and you do not understand what you're doing here"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;"I heard you were extremely quick at math"&lt;p&gt;Me: "yes, as a matter of fact I am"&lt;p&gt;Interviewer: "Whats 14x27"&lt;p&gt;Me: "49"&lt;p&gt;Interviewer: "that's not even close"&lt;p&gt;me: "yeah, but it was fast"&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 22 Sep 2025 09:53:48 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45331148</link><dc:creator>rpigab</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45331148</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45331148</guid></item><item><title>New comment by dansmith1919 in "You did this with an AI and you do not understand what you're doing here"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Crazy how he doubled down by just pasting badger's answer into Chat and submitting the (hilariously obvious AI) reply:&lt;p&gt;&gt; Thanks for the quick review. You’re right — my attached PoC does not exercise libcurl and therefore does not demonstrate a cURL bug. I retract the cookie overflow claim and apologize for the noise. Please close this report as invalid. If helpful, I can follow up separately with a minimal C reproducer that actually drives libcurl’s cookie parser (e.g., via an HTTP response with oversized Set-Cookie or using CURLOPT_COOKIELIST) and reference the exact function/line in lib/cookie.c should I find an issue.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 22 Sep 2025 09:51:46 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45331135</link><dc:creator>dansmith1919</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45331135</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45331135</guid></item><item><title>New comment by misnome in "You did this with an AI and you do not understand what you're doing here"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I wonder where the balance of “Actual time saved for me” vs “Everyone else's time wasted” lies in this technological “revolution”.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 22 Sep 2025 09:40:11 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45331057</link><dc:creator>misnome</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45331057</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45331057</guid></item><item><title>New comment by nomilk in "How I, a non-developer, read the tutorial you, a developer, wrote for me"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Can't recommend this approach highly enough: have someone with minimal expertise go through your docs with the goal of achieving the goal of the docs. Sit next to them or screenshare. Do not speak to them, certainly do not help, just watch. Watch them fumble. Watch them not know what to do. Watch them experience things you (the author) didn't, because you already had xyz configured on your machine and you forgot users won't have it. (even watch them pretend to know what they're supposed to do when they don't really).&lt;p&gt;If the user achieves what they need with minimal stress/guesswork/ambiguity, the docs pass. If not, note every single place they fail, address each one, and repeat &lt;i&gt;with a new user&lt;/i&gt;.&lt;p&gt;I've used FAANG docs that don't come close to passing the above criteria.&lt;p&gt;I've been incredibly grateful my org set this high bar. Especially when using docs for critical tech I only use from time to time (where I forget lots of it). Saves meetings, support inquiries, and video calls, because the user can self-serve.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 22 Sep 2025 04:15:40 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45329050</link><dc:creator>nomilk</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45329050</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45329050</guid></item><item><title>New comment by kaydub in "AI was supposed to help juniors shine. Why does it mostly make seniors stronger?"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Because juniors don't know when they're being taken down a rabbit hole. So they'll let the LLM go too deep in its hallucinations.&lt;p&gt;I have a Jr that was supposed to deploy a terraform module I built. This task has been hanging out for a while so I went to check in on them. They told me the problem they're having and asked me to take a look.&lt;p&gt;Their repo is a disaster, it's very obvious claude took them down a rabbit hole just from looking. When I asked, "Hey, why is all this python in here? The module has it self contained" and they respond with "I don't know, claude did that" affirming my assumptions.&lt;p&gt;They lack the experience and they're overly reliant on the LLM tools. Not just in the design and implementation phases but also for troubleshooting. And if you're troubleshooting with something that's hallucinating and you don't know enough to know it's hallucinating you're in for a long ride.&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile the LLM tools have taken away a lot of the type of work I hated doing. I can quickly tell when the LLM is going down a rabbit hole (in most cases at least) and prevent it from continuing. It's kinda re-lit my passion for coding and building software. So that's ended up in me producing more and giving better results.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 21 Sep 2025 16:16:33 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45324013</link><dc:creator>kaydub</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45324013</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45324013</guid></item><item><title>New comment by em500 in "Why, as a responsible adult, SimCity 2000 hits differently"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&gt; Now with kids, I understand why "Americans love their cars" - it switched form a derogatory statement to one of understanding. There's a reason that "ban the cars" posters never mention a partner or children in their bios.&lt;p&gt;This seems very different from the large anti-car movement in the Netherlands in the 1970s (which eventually led to massive investments in bike infrastructure  and car restrictions in the cities).&lt;p&gt;There was significant parent involvement, touting the memorable slogan "Stop de Kindermoord" ("Stop the Child Murder").&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Road_transport_in_the_Netherlands#Road_safety" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Road_transport_in_the_Netherla...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 21 Sep 2025 09:49:51 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45321371</link><dc:creator>em500</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45321371</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45321371</guid></item><item><title>New comment by Taek in "Ultrasonic Chef's Knife"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I'm a bit surprised to see how much snark there is in the comment sections of this video. The requests for "let's see an independent chef use this knife to do real kitchen work" make total sense, but the moralizing around e-waste and losing fingers etc feels off balance.&lt;p&gt;People spend hundreds of dollars and many hours sharpening kitchen knives, of course there's a viable market for sharper kitchen knives. And for e-waste, you are never going to make meaningful progress by telling consumers to feel bad for buying fun things. The problem is so much bigger than that, the energy is better spent in a different place.&lt;p&gt;This is a cool and novel tool, at least as far as its genuine utility can be verified. It doesn't seem harmful to let people get excited about it.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 20 Sep 2025 23:24:58 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45318527</link><dc:creator>Taek</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45318527</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45318527</guid></item><item><title>New comment by hellcow in "FLX1s phone is launched"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;The comments here are awful. What happened to “Hacker” news?&lt;p&gt;This is a Linux phone that actually works, running Debian. It has a battery that competes with the runtime of any modern phone. It has a snappy UI and can reliably make calls. Already it’s the best Linux phone in the world, just on that basis.&lt;p&gt;They’re selling it for the same price as the outgoing model despite tons of bullshit tariffs being levied against them. What an achievement!&lt;p&gt;I want a Linux phone that works, and I want to support a world where Linux phones exist and are financially viable to make, therefore I will buy this as my next phone.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 20 Sep 2025 13:38:41 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45313299</link><dc:creator>hellcow</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45313299</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45313299</guid></item><item><title>New comment by gejose in "Less is safer: Reducing the risk of supply chain attacks"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;This is one way to look at it, but ignores the fact that most users use third party community plugins.&lt;p&gt;Obsidian has a truly terrible security model for plugins. As I realized while building my own, Obsidian plugins have full, unrestricted access to all files in the vault.&lt;p&gt;Obsidian could've instead opted to be more 'batteries-included', at the cost of more development effort, but instead leaves this to the community, which in turn increases the attack surface significantly.&lt;p&gt;Or it could have a browser extension like manifest that declares all permissions used by the plugin, where attempting to access a permission that's not granted gets blocked.&lt;p&gt;Both of these approaches would've led to more real security to end users than "we have few third party dependencies".&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 23:42:12 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45308131</link><dc:creator>gejose</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45308131</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45308131</guid></item><item><title>New comment by roughly in "Trump to impose $100k fee for H-1B worker visas, White House says"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;The hollowing out of the middle class in the US isn't because of immigrants, it's because of a sustained campaign by capital to reduce the power of labor over the last 50-odd years and to concentrate wealth as best they can. Immigrant labor contributes to that because we've got inadequate labor protections and because we bought into the idea that lower consumer prices was a fine reason to ignore both labor and antitrust.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 21:31:12 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45306892</link><dc:creator>roughly</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45306892</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45306892</guid></item><item><title>New comment by molticrystal in "The best YouTube downloaders, and how Google silenced the press"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;The claim that Google secretly wants YouTube downloaders to work doesn't hold up. Their focus is on delivering videos across a vast range of devices without breaking playback(and even that is blurring[0]), not enabling downloads.&lt;p&gt;If you dive into the yt-dlp source code, you see the insane complexity of calculations needed to download a video. There is code to handle nsig checks, internal YouTube API quirks, and constant obfuscation that makes it a nightmare(and the maintainers heroes) to keep up.  Google frequently rejects download attempts, blocks certain devices or access methods, and breaks techniques that yt-dlp relies on.&lt;p&gt;Half the battle is working around attempts by Google to make ads unblockable, and the other half is working around their attempts to shut down downloaders. The idea of a "gray market ecosystem" they tacitly approve ignores how aggressively they tweak their systems to make downloading as unreliable as possible. If Google wanted downloaders to thrive, they wouldn't make developers jump through these hoops. Just look at the yt-dlp issue tracker overflowing with reports of broken functionality. There are no secret nods, handshakes, or other winks, as Google begins to care less and less about compatibility, the doors will close. For example, there is already a secret header used for authenticating that you are using the Google version of Chrome browser [1] [2] that will probably be expanded.&lt;p&gt;[0] Ask HN: Does anyone else notice YouTube causing 100% CPU usage and stattering?
&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45301499"&gt;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45301499&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;[1] Chrome's hidden X-Browser-Validation header reverse engineered &lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44527739"&gt;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44527739&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;[2] &lt;a href="https://github.com/dsekz/chrome-x-browser-validation-header" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://github.com/dsekz/chrome-x-browser-validation-header&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 20:49:53 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45306399</link><dc:creator>molticrystal</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45306399</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45306399</guid></item><item><title>New comment by jpadkins in "Trump to impose $100k fee for H-1B worker visas, White House says"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;The top end of H1B has been great for America.  In the last few decades, there has been growth of abuse of the program to get mid level talent at below market rates which really hurts the middle class in America.  People need to understand that most reformists don't want to get rid of the truly exceptional immigration to the US.  We need to limit the volume, especially the immigrants that are directly competing with a hollowed out middle class in the US.  Let me know if you want further reading on this topic.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 20:49:29 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45306392</link><dc:creator>jpadkins</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45306392</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45306392</guid></item><item><title>New comment by roughly in "Trump to impose $100k fee for H-1B worker visas, White House says"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I think there’s plenty of interesting debates to be had about immigration policy and its effects on the labor market, but one thing worth noting here is that the primary problem that damn near every other country on earth has isn’t immigration, it’s brain drain.&lt;p&gt;A core strategic strength of the US over the last century has been that everyone with any talent wants to come here to work, and by and large we’ve let them do so. You can argue how well that’s worked out for us - having worked with a great many extremely talented H1bs in an industry largely built by immigrants, I’d consider it pretty positive - but it damn sure hasn’t worked out well for the countries those talented folks came from.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 20:40:08 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45306289</link><dc:creator>roughly</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45306289</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45306289</guid></item><item><title>New comment by ToDougie in "Trevor Milton's Nikola case dropped by SEC following Trump pardon"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Lest we forget:&lt;p&gt;"The entire infotainment system is a HTML 5 super computer," Milton said. "That's the standard language for computer programmers around the world, so using it let's us build our own chips. And HTML 5 is very secure. Every component is linked on the data network, all speaking the same language. It's not a bunch of separate systems that somehow still manage to communicate."&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.truckinginfo.com/330475/whats-behind-the-grille-of-the-new-nikola-hydrogen-electric-truck" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://www.truckinginfo.com/330475/whats-behind-the-grille-...&lt;/a&gt; - April 24, 2019&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 15:24:45 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45302670</link><dc:creator>ToDougie</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45302670</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45302670</guid></item><item><title>New comment by Illniyar in "Help us raise $200k to free JavaScript from Oracle"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I don't get the hate here. This is practically a public service and Deno doesn't have any direct or obvious material gains from this. Definitely not more then dozens of other projects (from Chrome to Node.js to Tutorial sites and any company offering something with JS)&lt;p&gt;So what if they are a VC backed company? If you perform a public service, it's fair to ask the public for money.
No one is suggesting this money would go to fund their product.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 12:03:31 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45300639</link><dc:creator>Illniyar</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45300639</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45300639</guid></item><item><title>New comment by arghwhat in "Want to piss off your IT department? Are the links not malicious looking enough?"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Ah no need, corporate IT already make all URLs malicious looking through some microsoft "secure link" service, and constantly shows everyone shady looking prompts that constantly change and have cmd.exe windows flash in at random.&lt;p&gt;A phone call from Microsoft about my Norton anti-virus subscription putting me into debt that can only be settled with Nintendo gift cards bought in cash across 16 specific gas stations seem much more legitimate in comparison.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 09:16:50 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45299604</link><dc:creator>arghwhat</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45299604</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45299604</guid></item><item><title>New comment by schmichael in "Shipping 100 hardware units in under eight weeks"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Please stop multitasking while driving.&lt;p&gt;The tech seems neat and all but please stop multitasking while driving, encouraging others to multitask while driving, and building products specifically designed to encourage multitasking while driving.&lt;p&gt;If you want to work while you're in transit: take public transit.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2025 21:31:29 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45295251</link><dc:creator>schmichael</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45295251</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45295251</guid></item></channel></rss>