<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>Hacker News: Best Comments</title><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/bestcomments</link><description>Hacker News RSS</description><docs>https://hnrss.org/</docs><generator>hnrss v2.1.1</generator><lastBuildDate>Sun, 09 Nov 2025 23:49:11 +0000</lastBuildDate><ns0:link href="https://hnrss.org/bestcomments" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item><title>New comment by dehrmann in "AI isn't replacing jobs. AI spending is"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Hacker News doesn't like to hear it, but remote work is a big part of this. All that effort convincing management you're just as effective working remotely was also a collective sales pitch to outsource your role.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 09 Nov 2025 17:55:30 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45867504</link><dc:creator>dehrmann</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45867504</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45867504</guid></item><item><title>New comment by Glyptodon in "AI isn't replacing jobs. AI spending is"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;As a recently laid of senior engineer, to the extent that my job was replaced, it was replaced with offshore junior devs who'd already been working with the company for over  year with a pretty rough level of productivity by man-hour, though maybe taking 3x the time to get things done is worth it if they're cheap enough. Which is to say I see my layoff as as cost cutting backed by a premise that there is no value in retaining senior level talent, to try and keep operating in the black, not because AI was materially producing a lot of benefits. (Because to the extent it was, I was the one reaping them compared to the offshore folks and less experienced onshore ones.)&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 09 Nov 2025 16:51:24 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45866918</link><dc:creator>Glyptodon</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45866918</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45866918</guid></item><item><title>New comment by ksajadi in "Samsung Family Hub for 2025 Update Elevates the Smart Home Ecosystem"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;My Samsung TV keeps blocking around 20% of the display at random times to tell me their terms and conditions have changed. Of course I have the option of checking it by reading the whole thing on my TV and then running a diff to see what’s changed but I don’t have an option to opt out of the terms.&lt;p&gt;It’s way too frequent and runs at random times in the middle of a movie so I always choose Accept.&lt;p&gt;Give me a dumb TV any time of the day now&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 09 Nov 2025 16:20:27 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45866654</link><dc:creator>ksajadi</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45866654</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45866654</guid></item><item><title>New comment by robin_reala in "Samsung Family Hub for 2025 Update Elevates the Smart Home Ecosystem"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;It’s really quite impressive how much this press release turns me off from every buying any white goods from Samsung at any point in the future. It’s a vortex of “no”.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 09 Nov 2025 15:47:45 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45866377</link><dc:creator>robin_reala</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45866377</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45866377</guid></item><item><title>New comment by talkingtab in "Alive internet theory"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Somehow, reading the comments made something CLICK for me about how passive and reactive we have all become in this culture.&lt;p&gt;1. The issue is real. Not sure it is articulated but I related to live vs dead internet.&lt;p&gt;2. The comments (only 10 as of now) are mostly critiques. (no javascript, call to action, style, theory is wrong)&lt;p&gt;The CLICK: "Critiques kill". You want a live internet? Don't critique. If you want a no javascript version make one. If you have a better solution do it. If you have insight into the problem share it.&lt;p&gt;The "follower" internet has somehow instilled the notion that making a comment is the same as "doing something". It is not.&lt;p&gt;Someone has done something here. If you want to comment, try to develop the thought, not critique. Help build something.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 09 Nov 2025 13:36:24 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45865520</link><dc:creator>talkingtab</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45865520</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45865520</guid></item><item><title>New comment by microtonal in "Ask HN: How would you set up a child’s first Linux computer?"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;My kids loved the power, freedom and later unexpected community this bought them.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;p&gt;I think it is also important to realize/point out that we do a lot of projecting and our child may have very different interests. Not saying that applies to you &lt;i&gt;evolve2k&lt;/i&gt;, just wanted to make the general point.&lt;p&gt;I set up a Linux machine with our daughter and while it was initially ok, she did not have much interest in the power/freedom and it only became a nuisance for her. Her school/friends use PowerPoint - there is a lot of friction trying work with them in LibreOffice. She wanted to do DTP-like things several times and the Linux options are not exactly... user-friendly. Etc.&lt;p&gt;In the end we got her a Mac Mini. She can still open a terminal, use Homebrew, etc. if she ever develops an interest. Heck, she can use most free software. However, she can also do the stuff she is currently interested in much more easily. E.g., she uses Swift Publisher, which is a very simple/user-friendly DTP program, can collaborate on PowerPoint presentations when needed, etc.&lt;p&gt;First and foremost listen to what &lt;i&gt;your child&lt;/i&gt; is interested in.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 09 Nov 2025 12:30:55 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45865082</link><dc:creator>microtonal</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45865082</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45865082</guid></item><item><title>New comment by bertil in "I Am Mark Zuckerberg"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;A friend of mine has a relatively common first name and last name, and she regularly gets mail that is clearly not meant for her. She started a Facebook group for homonyms to help her route mail, and it now have a hundred members and have helped people get important documents.&lt;p&gt;At some point, they even organized an impersonation because someone needed to retrieve an official document and couldn’t be there in person. Another member nearby offered to go and get it. “Won’t you need my ID for that? — Oh, I have one with just the right name…”&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 09 Nov 2025 10:43:28 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45864600</link><dc:creator>bertil</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45864600</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45864600</guid></item><item><title>New comment by mjd in "I Am Mark Zuckerberg"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Dennis Ritchie (co-inventor of the C programming language) had a page on his personal web site called “My other lives” with a list of other Dennis Ritchies.&lt;p&gt;“Outside of my main professional career, I have accumulated other WWW-recorded accomplishments and have other interests. Generally I pursue these interests using separate mail addresses, SS#, and DNA.”&lt;p&gt;It's preserved here:&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.nokia.com/bell-labs/about/dennis-m-ritchie/otherlives.html" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://www.nokia.com/bell-labs/about/dennis-m-ritchie/other...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 09 Nov 2025 09:05:27 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45864116</link><dc:creator>mjd</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45864116</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45864116</guid></item><item><title>New comment by jowea in "I Am Mark Zuckerberg"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;This is why we should replace names with uuids.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 09 Nov 2025 08:36:07 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45863939</link><dc:creator>jowea</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45863939</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45863939</guid></item><item><title>New comment by thesumofall in "How Airbus took off"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I worked for Airbus a long time ago, and obviously I have some rose-tinted glasses, but what stands out in my memories:&lt;p&gt;- While the French and Germans love to hate each other, they culturally complement each other very well. I don’t think Airbus could have happened as a purely French or German project (and yes, the UK and Spain are also part of Airbus but are much less visible)&lt;p&gt;- Despite being a highly political entity, you wouldn’t feel any of that day to day. Even up to the highest management levels, it felt like an engineering company focused on incredibly hard engineering challenges. Every once in a while, there was fighting over which country would get which work share for a new project, but it felt more like internal teams pushing their pet peeves rather than external political influence&lt;p&gt;- It was a truly international company. My first team had eight colleagues based in four countries. To make it all work, they had some very early video conferencing systems where the equipment would take up entire side rooms.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 09 Nov 2025 07:22:24 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45863606</link><dc:creator>thesumofall</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45863606</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45863606</guid></item><item><title>New comment by bawolff in "Boring Company fined nearly $500K after it dumped drilling fluids into manholes"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;How is that only a $500,000 fine???&lt;p&gt;Stopping when inspectors are there only to restart once they leave is willful enough that you wonder why this doesn't go into criminal liability?&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 09 Nov 2025 04:35:29 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45862928</link><dc:creator>bawolff</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45862928</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45862928</guid></item><item><title>New comment by nullhole in "Largest cargo sailboat completes first Atlantic crossing"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;They have a passenger service too!&lt;p&gt;€3200 for France &lt;-&gt; Baltimore, 13 day trip. But with that you get three meals a day, a decent looking cabin, private bathroom, private balcony, and internet service (though how solid the connection is / what surcharges there may be is a question).&lt;p&gt;~€250/d doesn't sound too bad, and you could get work done along the way. Kind of sounds nice...&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.voilasailcoop.fr/transatlantic/" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://www.voilasailcoop.fr/transatlantic/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.voilasailcoop.fr/transatlantic/transatlantic-a-bord/" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://www.voilasailcoop.fr/transatlantic/transatlantic-a-b...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 09 Nov 2025 03:08:30 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45862554</link><dc:creator>nullhole</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45862554</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45862554</guid></item><item><title>New comment by Arrath in "Judge denies request to exempt Flock footage from Public Records Act"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Good, such records shouldn't be exempt. So what if they were gathered by a third party, it was a service carried out under request of the local government/law enforcement, and paid for by public money.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 09 Nov 2025 01:47:32 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45862150</link><dc:creator>Arrath</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45862150</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45862150</guid></item><item><title>New comment by Hizonner in "IP blocking the UK is not enough to comply with the Online Safety Act"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;You shouldn't even be expected to geoblock. If I'm operating a Web site in country A, I should not have to care about country B's laws unless I am taking &lt;i&gt;specific action intended to attract users in country B in particular&lt;/i&gt;. That's doesn't mean just to target the whole world, either. If you don't want your citizens to access something in another country, take it up with your citizens.&lt;p&gt;It was obvious from the minute that idiots started creating IP location databases in the first place that people would demand that they be used like that... and those demands seem to be winning out.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 08 Nov 2025 23:30:06 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45861128</link><dc:creator>Hizonner</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45861128</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45861128</guid></item><item><title>New comment by hypeatei in "I Want You to Understand Chicago"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;A news station producer was arrested by ICE and the agents peeled away ripping off someone's bumper[0][1] just for her to be released later without charges.&lt;p&gt;0: &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2025/oct/14/chicago-ice-tv-producer-arrest" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2025/oct/14/chicago-ice-...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;1: &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=JLGI2hMaz5Q" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=JLGI2hMaz5Q&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 08 Nov 2025 21:56:25 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45860423</link><dc:creator>hypeatei</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45860423</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45860423</guid></item><item><title>New comment by tedivm in "I Want You to Understand Chicago"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I live in Chicago, and this article doesn't even scratch the surface of how bad it is. My wife went to the beach yesterday for 10 minutes to try and rest from the chaos and a fucking black hawk helicopter buzzed by her. They literally fly over my house daily.&lt;p&gt;People, US citizens included, are literally being abducted. People have been shot and killed by masked agents. People have had their children abandoned on the side of the road after being kidnapped. Just today they raided Little Village with hundreds of masked troops. I'm in a dozen signal groups to get alerted about where things are.&lt;p&gt;What scares me the most is how few people seem to actually know what is happening here. I talk to people outside of Chicago, and watch the news, and I don't see or hear about anything that's going on here. I tell them what's happening and they are shocked.&lt;p&gt;It is impossible to convey what is happening here, how scared we all are for this country, and how much things seem to escalate every single day that this goes on.&lt;p&gt;Edit: This post has been flagged and hidden, just demonstrating how much this country wants to pretend this isn't happening. It's unflagged now, but the fact that anyone would want to hide what's happening here shows how bad things are for all of us.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 08 Nov 2025 20:47:43 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45859830</link><dc:creator>tedivm</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45859830</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45859830</guid></item><item><title>New comment by Buttons840 in "Ticker: Don't die of heart disease"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I am not a statin skeptic--or rather, I don't want to be a statin skeptic. I've done the research and it makes sense to me, but I still feel some social and psychological pressures to reject statins.&lt;p&gt;When I see that it is widely accepted that ApoB is better to measure than LDL-C, but the industry continues to measure LDL-C, but not ApoB, I wonder why. It makes me skeptical.&lt;p&gt;When I see that the purpose of statins is to reduce plaque buildup in the arteries, and that we have the ability to measure these plaque buildups with scans, but the scans are rarely done, I wonder why. Like, we will see a high LDL-C number (which, again, we should be looking at ApoB instead), and so we get worried about arterial plaque, and we have the ability to directly measure arterial plaque, but we don't, and instead just prescribe a statin. We're worried about X, and have the ability to measure X, but we don't measure X, and instead just prescribe a pill based on proxy indicator Y. It makes me skeptical.&lt;p&gt;In the end statins reduce the chance of heart attack by like 30% I think. Not bad, but if you have a heart attack without statins, you probably (70%) would have had a heart attack with statins too. That's what a 30% risk reduction means, right?&lt;p&gt;As you can see, I'm worried about cholesterol and statins.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 08 Nov 2025 17:25:27 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45858334</link><dc:creator>Buttons840</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45858334</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45858334</guid></item><item><title>New comment by web3-is-a-scam in "Btop: A better modern alternative of htop with a gamified interface"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I’m a btop user how is it gamified?  If by “gamified” thy mean “looks like something you would see in a video game (or movie)” then yeah tha tracks but that’s not what “gamified” typically means…&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 08 Nov 2025 16:56:53 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45858114</link><dc:creator>web3-is-a-scam</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45858114</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45858114</guid></item><item><title>New comment by risho in "Btop: A better modern alternative of htop with a gamified interface"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;i dont think they could have possibly chosen a word to make me want to use it less than gamified.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 08 Nov 2025 16:27:43 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45857864</link><dc:creator>risho</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45857864</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45857864</guid></item><item><title>New comment by nba456_ in "$1T in tech stocks sold off as market grows skeptical of AI"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;NASDAQ hasn't been this low since 2 weeks ago!&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 08 Nov 2025 15:22:11 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45857244</link><dc:creator>nba456_</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45857244</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45857244</guid></item><item><title>New comment by bubblelicious in "Study identifies weaknesses in how AI systems are evaluated"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I work on LLM benchmarks and human evals for a living in a research lab (as opposed to product). I can say: it’s pretty much the Wild West and a total disaster. No one really has a good solution, and researchers are also in a huge rush and don’t want to end up making their whole job benchmarking. Even if you could, and even if you have the right background you can do benchmarks full time and they still would be a mess.&lt;p&gt;Product testing (with traditional A/B tests) are kind of the best bet since you can measure what you care about _directly_ and at scale.&lt;p&gt;I would say there is of course “benchmarketing” but generally people do sincerely want to make good benchmarks it’s just hard or impossible. For many of these problems we’re hitting capabilities where we don’t even have a decent paradigm to use,&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 08 Nov 2025 14:56:28 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45857030</link><dc:creator>bubblelicious</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45857030</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45857030</guid></item><item><title>New comment by SonnyTark in "Why is Zig so cool?"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;This is a very confusing blog post. I found myself looking for ChatGPT markers because it doesn't make sense to say: omg zig is so much cooler than C here's why, then start listing the absolute basics of the language that are identical in most modern languages without any actual reflection why writing the same thing in a different syntax somehow makes zig superior?&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 08 Nov 2025 13:41:18 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45856597</link><dc:creator>SonnyTark</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45856597</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45856597</guid></item><item><title>New comment by jeremyjh in "My friends and I accidentally faked the Ryzen 7 9700X3D leaks"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&gt; A weeks ago, my friends and I were talking about the inner workings of Zen 5. We were talking about how the CPUID instruction works, and how AMD MSRs are technically editable if you ask the processor nicely.&lt;p&gt;As do we all.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 08 Nov 2025 12:25:02 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45856176</link><dc:creator>jeremyjh</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45856176</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45856176</guid></item><item><title>New comment by serial_dev in "Valdi – A cross-platform UI framework that delivers native performance"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;It’s because if a webview app experience is good, you don’t notice it, you only notice if it’s bad.&lt;p&gt;A while ago saw a blog link on HN that explained how Apple uses it everywhere and we never notice it because they are done well. Of course I can’t find that link now, I summon the HN gods…&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 08 Nov 2025 06:33:04 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45854620</link><dc:creator>serial_dev</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45854620</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45854620</guid></item><item><title>New comment by adastra22 in "Valdi – A cross-platform UI framework that delivers native performance"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I have never once experienced a WebView app that I would say had “a really good experience.”&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 08 Nov 2025 05:02:40 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45854285</link><dc:creator>adastra22</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45854285</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45854285</guid></item><item><title>New comment by unscaled in "Why is Zig so cool?"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I'm afraid this article kinda fails at at its job. It starts out with a very bold claim ("Zig is not only a new programming language, but it’s a totally new way to write programs"), but ends up listing a bunch of features that are not unique to Zig or even introduced by Zig: type inference (Invented in the late 60s, first practically implemented in the 80s), anonymous structs (C#, Go, Typescript, many ML-style languages), labeled breaks, functions that are not globally public by default...&lt;p&gt;It seems like this is written from the perspective of C/C++ and Java and perhaps a couple of traditional (dynamically typed) languages.&lt;p&gt;On the other hand, the concept that makes Zig really unique (comptime) is not touched upon at all. I would argue compile-time evaluation is not entirely new (you can look at Lisp macros back in the 60s), but the way Zig implements this  feature and how it is used instead of generics is interesting enough to make Zig unique. I still feel like the claim is a bit hyperbolic, but there is a story that you can sell about Zig being unique. I wanted to read this story, but I feel like this is not it.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 08 Nov 2025 04:23:00 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45854097</link><dc:creator>unscaled</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45854097</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45854097</guid></item><item><title>New comment by bearjaws in "Valdi – A cross-platform UI framework that delivers native performance"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Working at a company that uses react-native I wish nothing more than for the end of app stores and differing platform languages.&lt;p&gt;We're heavily considering just having a website next year with a mobile app using webview, and then native code for the native notifications, GPS and healthkit / health connect.&lt;p&gt;I feel like AI is changing the equation, its nearly better to write your business UI 3 times one for each platform.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 08 Nov 2025 03:02:09 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45853740</link><dc:creator>bearjaws</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45853740</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45853740</guid></item><item><title>New comment by WarOnPrivacy in "YouTube Removes Windows 11 Bypass Tutorials, Claims 'Risk of Physical Harm'"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Mount a Windows 11 ISO.  Open an administrative command window. Navigate to the new drive letter. Enter this command:&lt;p&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;    .\setup.exe /product server /auto upgrade /EULA accept /migratedrivers all /ShowOOBE none /Compat IgnoreWarning /Telemetry Disable
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
I've used this to upgrade 10 to 11 on non approved hardware, going back to at least 2nd gen Intel CPUs. I've used it to upgrade existing Pro, EDU and IOT that didn't want to upgrade.&lt;p&gt;The install window will say server but it isn't.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 08 Nov 2025 00:43:45 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45853012</link><dc:creator>WarOnPrivacy</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45853012</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45853012</guid></item><item><title>New comment by simonw in "Why is Zig so cool?"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;A neat little thing I like about Zig is one of the options for installing it is via PyPI like this: &lt;a href="https://pypi.org/project/ziglang/" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://pypi.org/project/ziglang/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;  pip install ziglang
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
Which means you don't even have to install it separately to try it out via uvx. If you have uv installed already try this:&lt;p&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;  cd /tmp
  echo '#include &lt;stdio.h&gt;                     
  
  int main() {
      printf("Hello, World!");
      return 0;
  }' &gt; hello.c

  uvx --from ziglang python-zig cc /tmp/hello.c
  ./a.out&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 08 Nov 2025 00:06:00 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45852792</link><dc:creator>simonw</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45852792</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45852792</guid></item><item><title>New comment by pron in "Why is Zig so cool?"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&gt; I can’t think of any other language in my 45 years long career that surprised more than Zig.&lt;p&gt;I can say the same (although my career spans only 30 years), or, more accurately, that it's one of the few languages that surprised me most.&lt;p&gt;Coming to it from a language design perspective, what surprised me is just how far partial evaluation can be taken. While strictly weaker than AST macros in expressive power (macros are "referentially opaque" and therefore more powerful than a referentially transparent partial evaluation - e.g. partial evaluation has no access to an argument's name), it turns out that it's powerful enough to replace not only most "reasonable" uses of macros, but also generics and interfaces. What gives Zig's partial evaluation (comptime) this power is its access to reflection.&lt;p&gt;Even when combined with reflection, partial evaluation is more pleasurable to work with than macros. In fact, to understand the program's semantics, partial evaluation can be ignored altogether (as it doesn't affect the meaning of computations). I.e. the semantics of a Zig program are the same as if it were interpreted by some language Zig' that is able to run all of Zig's partial-evaluation code (comptime) at runtime rather than at compile time.&lt;p&gt;Since it also removes the need for other specialised features (generics, interfaces) - even at the cost of an aesthetic that may not appeal to fans of those specialised features - it ends up creating a very expressive, yet surprisingly simple and easy-to-understand language (Lisps are also simple and expressive, but the use of macros makes understanding a Lisp program less easy).&lt;p&gt;Being simple and easy to understand makes code reviews easier, which may have a positive impact on correctness. The simplicity can also reduce compilation time, which may also have a positive impact on correctness.&lt;p&gt;Zig's insistence on explicitness - no overloading, no hidden control flow - which also assists reviews, may not be appropriate for a high-level language, but it's a great fit for an unabashedly low-level language, where being able to see every operation as explicit code "on the page" is important. While its designer may or may not admit this, I think Zig abandons C++'s belief that programs of all sizes and kinds will be written in the same language (hence its "zero-cost abstractions", made to give the illusion of a high-level language without its actual high-level abstraction). Developers writing low-level code lose the explicitness they need for review, while those writing high-level programs don't actually gain the level of abstraction required for a smooth program evolution that they need. That belief may have been reasonable in the eighties, but I think it has since been convincingly disproved.&lt;p&gt;Some Zig decisions surprised me in a way that made me go more "huh" than "wow", such as it having little encapsulation to speak of. In a high-level language I wouldn't have that (after years of experience with Java's wide ecosystem of libraries, we learned that we need even &lt;i&gt;more&lt;/i&gt; and stronger encapsulation than we originally had to keep compatibility while evolving code). But perhaps this is the right choice for a low-level language where programs are expected to be smaller and with fewer dependencies (certainly shallower dependency graphs). I'm curious to see how this pans out.&lt;p&gt;Zig's terrific support for arenas also makes one of the most powerful low-level memory management techniques (that, like a tracing garbage collector, gives the developer a knob to trade off RAM usage for CPU) very accessible.&lt;p&gt;I have no idea or prediction on whether Zig will become popular, but it's certainly fascinating. And, being so remarkably easy to learn (especially if you're familiar with low-level programming), it costs little effort to give it a try.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 08 Nov 2025 00:03:08 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45852774</link><dc:creator>pron</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45852774</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45852774</guid></item></channel></rss>