<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>Hacker News: Best Comments</title><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/bestcomments</link><description>Hacker News RSS</description><docs>https://hnrss.org/</docs><generator>hnrss v2.1.1</generator><lastBuildDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2026 00:25:22 +0000</lastBuildDate><ns0:link href="https://hnrss.org/bestcomments" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item><title>New comment by crote in "I canceled my book deal"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&gt; Why buy this book when ChatGPT can generate the same style of tutorial for ANY project that is customized to you?&lt;p&gt;Isn't it obvious? Because the ChatGPT output &lt;i&gt;wouldn't be reviewed!&lt;/i&gt;&lt;p&gt;You buy books like these &lt;i&gt;exactly&lt;/i&gt; because they are written by a professional, who has taken the time to divide it up into easily digestible chunks which form a coherent narrative, with runnable intermediate stages in-between.&lt;p&gt;For example, I expect a raytracing project to start with simple ray casting of single-color objects. After that it can add things like lights and Blinn-Phong shading, progress with Whitted-style recursive raytracing for the shiny reflections and transparent objects, then progress to modern path tracing with things like BRDFs, and end up with BVHs to make it not &lt;i&gt;horribly&lt;/i&gt; slow.&lt;p&gt;You can stop at any point and &lt;i&gt;still&lt;/i&gt; end up with a functional raytracer, and the added value of each step is immediately obvious to the reader. There's just no way in hell ChatGPT at its current level is going to guide you flawlessly through all of that if you start with a simple "I want to build a raytracer" prompt!&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2025 20:21:50 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46447897</link><dc:creator>crote</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46447897</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46447897</guid></item><item><title>New comment by bevr1337 in "Stardew Valley developer made a $125k donation to the FOSS C# framework MonoGame"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&gt; Gifts do not confer obligation.&lt;p&gt;Remind me, which Ferengi Rule of Acquisition is this?&lt;p&gt;There's not much argument to be had. You've created a logical justification for a myopic, misanthropic world view.&lt;p&gt;&gt; My friend bought me lunch. I used that energy at my job. Do I owe them part of my paycheck?&lt;p&gt;Many find reciprocation important in a relationship.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2025 17:40:17 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46446343</link><dc:creator>bevr1337</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46446343</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46446343</guid></item><item><title>New comment by mindcrash in "Stardew Valley developer made a $125k donation to the FOSS C# framework MonoGame"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Not without reason:&lt;p&gt;Stardew Valley, which has been sold to millions of gamers, has been created using the free MonoGame engine. So ConcernedApe is giving back to the open source software which made his commercial success possible, like commercial parties should.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2025 17:19:43 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46446103</link><dc:creator>mindcrash</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46446103</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46446103</guid></item><item><title>New comment by QuantumNomad_ in "Stardew Valley developer made a $125k donation to the FOSS C# framework MonoGame"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Epic Games has a program called MegaGrants where they give a bunch of money to various projects.&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.unrealengine.com/en-US/megagrants" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://www.unrealengine.com/en-US/megagrants&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;For example they gave $250k to the Godot game engine project in 2020.&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://godotengine.org/article/godot-engine-was-awarded-epic-megagrant/" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://godotengine.org/article/godot-engine-was-awarded-epi...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2025 16:12:54 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46445420</link><dc:creator>QuantumNomad_</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46445420</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46445420</guid></item><item><title>New comment by kamranjon in "Google Opal"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Does it seem, I'm not sure, ironic maybe? That the main example here is "An app that writes blog posts" - "Researches a topic and writes a blog post about it" - that the company who helped champion the network effects of the internet and surface truly useful search results is now helping to  destroy that very same thing they built their entire business on?&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2025 05:43:49 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46441740</link><dc:creator>kamranjon</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46441740</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46441740</guid></item><item><title>New comment by Waterluvian in "Honey's Dieselgate: Detecting and tricking testers"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&gt; what the engineers thought when doing design reviews for a "selective stand down" feature.&lt;p&gt;Possibly a version of, “I lack the freedom to operate with a moral code at work because I’m probably replaceable, the job market makes me anxious, my family’s well-being and healthcare are tied to having a job, and I don’t believe the government has my back.”&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2025 01:50:18 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46440431</link><dc:creator>Waterluvian</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46440431</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46440431</guid></item><item><title>New comment by fooblaster in "OpenAI's cash burn will be one of the big bubble questions of 2026"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;There is a pretty big moat for Google: extreme amounts of video data on their existing services and  absolutely no dependence on Nvidia and it's 90% margin.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2025 01:01:50 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46440140</link><dc:creator>fooblaster</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46440140</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46440140</guid></item><item><title>New comment by avalys in "OpenAI's cash burn will be one of the big bubble questions of 2026"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;AI is going to be a highly-competitive, extremely capital-intensive commodity market that ends up in a race to the bottom competing on cost and efficiency of delivering models that have all reached the same asymptotic performance in the sense of intelligence, reasoning, etc.&lt;p&gt;The simple evidence for this is that everyone who has invested the same resources in AI has produced roughly the same result. OpenAI, Anthropic, Google, Meta, Deepseek, etc. There's no evidence of a technological moat or a competitive advantage in any of these companies.&lt;p&gt;The conclusion? AI is a world-changing technology, just like the railroads were, and it is going to soon explode in a huge bubble - just like the railroads did. That doesn't mean AI is going to go away, or that it won't change the world - railroads are still here and they did change the world - but from a venture investment perspective, get ready for a massive downturn.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2025 00:31:40 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46439964</link><dc:creator>avalys</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46439964</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46439964</guid></item><item><title>New comment by crazygringo in "NYC Mayoral Inauguration bans Raspberry Pi and Flipper Zero alongside explosives"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;It's not like they're banning them across all of NYC... it's just security at the inauguration event. "Large bags" are banned too.&lt;p&gt;&gt; &lt;i&gt;When a policy bans specific devices rather than behaviors or capabilities, it creates ambiguity for people on the ground.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;p&gt;To the contrary, how the heck is someone working security at the entrance supposed to check for a device's "behaviors or capabilities"? This is a quick visual inspection, this &lt;i&gt;reduces&lt;/i&gt; ambiguity.&lt;p&gt;Presumably, the cops are aware of previous disruption with these &lt;i&gt;specific&lt;/i&gt; devices, or threats thereof. And it's not like they're going to say exactly what, nor should they, lest it give people ideas...&lt;p&gt;&gt; &lt;i&gt;Today it’s Raspberry Pi and Flipper Zero. Tomorrow it’s BeagleBone Blacks, Arduino Qs, ESP32 dev boards, Teensy boards, Pine64s, Orange Pis...&lt;/i&gt;&lt;p&gt;Which is totally fine. There's no legitimate purpose in bringing any of those &lt;i&gt;to a high-profile political event&lt;/i&gt;. Drones, laser pens, and beach balls are prohibited too.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2025 00:09:02 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46439805</link><dc:creator>crazygringo</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46439805</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46439805</guid></item><item><title>New comment by Aurornis in "A faster heart for F-Droid"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&gt; this server is physically held by a long time contributor with a proven track record of securely hosting services. We can control it remotely, we know exactly where it is, and we know who has access.&lt;p&gt;I can’t be the only one who read this and had flashbacks to projects that fell apart because one person had the physical server in their basement or a rack at their workplace and it became a sticking point when an argument arose.&lt;p&gt;I know self-hosting is held as a point of pride by many, but in my experience you’re still better off putting lower cost hardware in a cheap colo with the contract going to the business entity which has defined ownership and procedures. Sending it over to a single member to put somewhere puts a lot of control into that one person’s domain.&lt;p&gt;I hope for the best for this team and I’m leaning toward believing that this person really is trusted and capable, but I would strongly recommend against these arrangements in any form in general.&lt;p&gt;EDIT: F-Droid received a $400,000 grant from a single source this year ( &lt;a href="https://f-droid.org/2025/02/05/f-droid-awarded-otf-grant.html" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://f-droid.org/2025/02/05/f-droid-awarded-otf-grant.htm...&lt;/a&gt; ) so now I’m even more confused about how they decided to hand this server to a single team member to host in unspoken conditions instead of paying basic colocation expenses.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Dec 2025 21:50:50 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46438440</link><dc:creator>Aurornis</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46438440</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46438440</guid></item><item><title>New comment by wrs in "Everything as code: How we manage our company in one monorepo"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;This is sort of a whole &lt;i&gt;product&lt;/i&gt;, but it’s hardly managing the whole &lt;i&gt;company&lt;/i&gt;. Financials? HR? Contracts? Pictures of the last  team meeting?&lt;p&gt;It just looks like a normal frontend+backend product monorepo, with the only somewhat unusual inclusion of the marketing folder.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Dec 2025 21:17:42 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46438106</link><dc:creator>wrs</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46438106</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46438106</guid></item><item><title>New comment by lrvick in "A faster heart for F-Droid"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;As someone that has run many volunteer open source communities and projects for more than 2 decades, I totally get how big "small" wins like this are.&lt;p&gt;The internet is run on binaries compiled in servers in random basements and you should be thankful for those basements because the corpos are never going to actually help fund any of it.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Dec 2025 21:12:56 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46438057</link><dc:creator>lrvick</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46438057</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46438057</guid></item><item><title>New comment by simonw in "Show HN: 22 GB of Hacker News in SQLite"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Don't miss how this works. It's not a server-side application - this code runs entirely in your browser using SQLite compiled to WASM, but rather than fetching a full 22GB database it instead uses a clever hack that retrieves just "shards" of the SQLite database needed for the page you are viewing.&lt;p&gt;I watched it in the browser network panel and saw it fetch:&lt;p&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;  https://hackerbook.dosaygo.com/static-shards/shard_1636.sqlite.gz
  https://hackerbook.dosaygo.com/static-shards/shard_1635.sqlite.gz
  https://hackerbook.dosaygo.com/static-shards/shard_1634.sqlite.gz
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
As I paginated to previous days.&lt;p&gt;It's reminiscent of that brilliant SQLite.js VFS trick from a few years ago: &lt;a href="https://github.com/phiresky/sql.js-httpvfs" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://github.com/phiresky/sql.js-httpvfs&lt;/a&gt; - only that one used HTTP range headers, this one uses sharded files instead.&lt;p&gt;The interactive SQL query interface at &lt;a href="https://hackerbook.dosaygo.com/?view=query" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://hackerbook.dosaygo.com/?view=query&lt;/a&gt; asks you to select which shards to run the query against, there are 1636 total.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Dec 2025 19:27:22 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46436937</link><dc:creator>simonw</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46436937</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46436937</guid></item><item><title>New comment by CiPHPerCoder in "A Vulnerability in Libsodium"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;This also affected the PHP library, sodium_compat. &lt;a href="https://github.com/FriendsOfPHP/security-advisories/pull/756" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://github.com/FriendsOfPHP/security-advisories/pull/756&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;I'm planning to spend my evening checking every other Ed25519 implementation I can find to see if this check is missing any where else in the open source ecosystem.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Dec 2025 19:15:44 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46436836</link><dc:creator>CiPHPerCoder</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46436836</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46436836</guid></item><item><title>New comment by kasabali in "A faster heart for F-Droid"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Context: "F-Droid build servers can't build modern Android apps due to outdated CPUs" (&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44884709"&gt;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44884709&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Dec 2025 18:36:37 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46436410</link><dc:creator>kasabali</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46436410</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46436410</guid></item><item><title>New comment by solaire_oa in "The future of software development is software developers"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Most people in this thread are quibbling about the exact degree of utility LLMs provide, which a tedious argument.&lt;p&gt;What's more interesting to me is, per the article, the concern regarding everyone who is leaning into LLMs without realizing (or downplaying) the exorbitant, externalized cost. Our current LLM usage is being subsidized to the point of being free by outside investment. One day when the well runs dry, you must be able to either pay the actual cost (barring grand technology breakthroughs), or switch back to non-LLM workflows. I run local LLMs infrequently, and every single prompt makes my beefy PC sounds like a jet engine taking off. It's a great reminder to not become codependent.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Dec 2025 16:19:18 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46434832</link><dc:creator>solaire_oa</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46434832</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46434832</guid></item><item><title>New comment by LucasFonts in "Times New American: A Tale of Two Fonts"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Our studio, LucasFonts, designed Calibri. Here are our CEO Luc(as) de Groot’s thoughts on the matter:&lt;p&gt;Back to bad...&lt;p&gt;Deciding to ditch Calibri as a ‘wasteful diversity’ font is both hilarious and sad. I designed Calibri to make reading on modern computer screens easier, and in 2006 Microsoft chose it to replace Times New Roman as the default font in the Office suite. Microsoft moved away from Times for good reasons. Calibri performs exceptionally well at small sizes and on standard office monitors, whereas serif fonts like Times New Roman create more visual disturbance. Although serif fonts work well on high-resolution displays, such as those found on modern smartphones, the serifs can introduce unnecessary visual noise on typical office screens and be particularly problematic for users with impaired vision, such as older adults.&lt;p&gt;Professional typography can be achieved with serif or sans serif fonts. However, that is not very easy with Times New Roman, a typeface older than the current president. Originally crafted in Great Britain for newspaper printing, Times was optimised for paper, with each letterform meticulously cut and tested for specific sizes. In the digital era, larger-size drawings were repurposed as models, resulting in a typeface that appears too thin and sharp when printed at a high quality.&lt;p&gt;Depending on the situation, fonts with serifs are often considered more classic, but they take more work to get right. While a skilled typographer can produce excellent results with Times New Roman, using the digital default version is not considered professional practice. This font only offers two weights, Regular and Bold, and the Bold version has a very different design that does not fit well. There are many better serif typefaces available. The digital version of Times New Roman, developed in the early days of computing, includes only minimal adjustments to letter pairs. This is particularly noticeable in all-capital words such as ‘CHICAGO’, where the spacing is inconsistent: the letters ‘HIC’ are tightly packed, while ‘CAG’ are spaced too far apart. By contrast, Calibri incorporates extensive spacing adjustments and language-specific refinements.&lt;p&gt;This decision takes the administration back to the past and back to bad.&lt;p&gt;(Microsoft could not rectify spacing issues in Times New Roman without altering the appearance of existing documents.)&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Dec 2025 14:58:22 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46433916</link><dc:creator>LucasFonts</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46433916</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46433916</guid></item><item><title>New comment by Fiveplus in "Netflix Open Content"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;This could be a huge deal for anyone working on video codecs or display tech. Finding legally clear, high-quality, uncompressed (or mezzanine) 4K HDR footage to test encoders against is surprisingly difficult. Most test footage you find online has already been stomped on by YouTube or Meta compression.&lt;p&gt;Having the raw EXR sequences and the IMF packages for Sol Levante and Meridian means researchers can finally benchmark AV1 vs HEVC vs VVC using source material that actually has the dynamic range to show the differences. The fact that they included the Dolby vision metadata is the cherry on top.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Dec 2025 13:46:08 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46433281</link><dc:creator>Fiveplus</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46433281</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46433281</guid></item><item><title>New comment by reddalo in "Netflix Open Content"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;It's because their blog is hosted on blogger.com (yeah, weird decision), which is owned by Google and does that by default.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Dec 2025 12:57:32 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46432873</link><dc:creator>reddalo</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46432873</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46432873</guid></item><item><title>New comment by beloch in "Nicolas Guillou, French ICC judge sanctioned by the US and “debanked”"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;"Without commenting on ongoing cases, he called on European authorities to activate a mechanism that could limit the impact of US restrictions."&lt;p&gt;-------------------&lt;p&gt;ICC member states should take steps to ensure the sanctioned judges and prosecutors do not suffer as a result of U.S. sanctions.  The goal should be to ensure that they feel no repercussions that might bias them one way or the other in future cases and thus maintain impartiality.  If this is not done, it could create an apparent feedback loop, if only in the public's imagination.  i.e. After some future ICC ruling goes against them (or Israel/Russia), the U.S. may claim that ICC judges and prosecutors are prejudiced against them and are seeking revenge.  Protecting ICC personnel now could blunt such claims.  Sadly, I fear that the U.S. may have need of defence from ICC rulings relatively soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Dec 2025 11:48:09 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46432354</link><dc:creator>beloch</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46432354</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46432354</guid></item><item><title>New comment by meander_water in "Go away Python"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Actually you can go one better:&lt;p&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;  #!/usr/bin/env -S uv run --python 3.14 --script
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
Then you don't even need python installed. uv will install the version of python you specified and run the command.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Dec 2025 11:37:03 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46432267</link><dc:creator>meander_water</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46432267</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46432267</guid></item><item><title>New comment by hamishwhc in "Go away Python"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;The author’s point about “not caring about pip vs poetry vs uv” is missing that uv directly supports this use case, including PyPI dependencies, and all you need is uv and your preferred Python version installed: &lt;a href="https://docs.astral.sh/uv/guides/scripts/#using-a-shebang-to-create-an-executable-file" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://docs.astral.sh/uv/guides/scripts/#using-a-shebang-to...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Dec 2025 11:09:22 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46432032</link><dc:creator>hamishwhc</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46432032</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46432032</guid></item><item><title>New comment by sschueller in "HSBC blocks its app due to F-Droid-installed Bitwarden"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;That's Google's SafeNet. HSBC picked a level that causes this. Google manages the blacklist of apps.&lt;p&gt;We are rapidly losing our freedoms to the will of these companies. If they decide they don't want to they can even if the law doesn't forbid it.&lt;p&gt;People in Switzerland and the EU are being de-banked by local banks because of US pressure allowing them to force any bank that wants to use USD. The US has started to sanction people for free speech resulting in de-banking.&lt;p&gt;Swiss law requires one bank (Postfinance) to offer banking irregardless but if you are sanctioned you can't use the wire system, no other currencies, no credit cards and you cant use Twint either so it's in effect useless. You can't pay for your health insurance or rent.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Dec 2025 10:13:09 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46431572</link><dc:creator>sschueller</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46431572</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46431572</guid></item><item><title>New comment by omnicognate in "Stranger Things creator says turn off “garbage” settings"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;It would help if TV manufacturers would clearly document what these features do, and use consistent names that reflect that.&lt;p&gt;It seems they want to make these settings usable without specialist knowledge, but the end result of their opaque naming and vague descriptions is that anybody who actually cares about what they see and thinks they might benefit from some of the features has to either systematically try every possible combination of options or teach themselves video engineering and try to figure out for themselves what each one actually does.&lt;p&gt;This isn't unique to TVs. It's amazing really how much effort a company will put into adding a feature to a product only to completely negate any value it might have by assuming any attempt at clearly documenting it, even if buried deep in a manual, will cause their customers' brains to explode.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Dec 2025 08:58:41 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46431084</link><dc:creator>omnicognate</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46431084</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46431084</guid></item><item><title>New comment by omarforgotpwd in "Tesla’s 4680 battery supply chain collapses as partner writes down deal by 99%"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Tesla is actually starting to make cathodes in house via a dry process, which is why they are no longer buying cathode material from this supplier. Typical sloppy reporting from Electrek.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Dec 2025 04:46:17 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46429645</link><dc:creator>omarforgotpwd</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46429645</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46429645</guid></item><item><title>New comment by pupppet in "Stranger Things creator says turn off “garbage” settings"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;The fact that I have to turn on closed captioning to understand anything tells me these producers have no idea what we want and shouldn’t be telling us what settings to use.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Dec 2025 04:38:27 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46429597</link><dc:creator>pupppet</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46429597</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46429597</guid></item><item><title>New comment by xbmcuser in "Google is dead. Where do we go now?"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Most of her friends are probably women. Try making an account with an obvious female name and you will see a marked difference on most social platforms I am saying this as a guy we really don't understand the world women live in online or offline.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Dec 2025 03:02:43 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46429070</link><dc:creator>xbmcuser</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46429070</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46429070</guid></item><item><title>New comment by hamstergene in "Karpathy on Programming: “I've never felt this much behind”"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I feel like many people in the comments aren't aware that Karpathy is an ML scientist for whom programming is a complementary skill, not a profession. The only reason he came up with "vibe coding" is because maximum complexity of his hobby projects made it seem believable. Maybe take his opinions about fate of programming with a grain of salt.&lt;p&gt;He is brilliant no doubt, but not in that field.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Dec 2025 02:58:00 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46429036</link><dc:creator>hamstergene</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46429036</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46429036</guid></item><item><title>New comment by gbnwl in "Show HN: Stop Claude Code from forgetting everything"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I'm not sure how many HN users frequent other places related to agentic coding like the subreddits of particular providers, but this has got to be the 1000th "ultimate memory system"/break-free-of-the-context-limit-tyranny! project I've seen, and like all other similar projects there's never any evidence or even attempt at measuring any metric of performance improved by it. Of course it's hard to measure such a thing, but that's part of exactly why it's hard to build something like this. Here's user #1001 that's been told by Claude "What a fascinating idea! You've identified a real gap in the market for a simple database based memory system to extend agent memory."&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Dec 2025 01:22:17 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46428368</link><dc:creator>gbnwl</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46428368</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46428368</guid></item><item><title>New comment by kevinlearynet in "Stranger Things creator says turn off “garbage” settings"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;All the settings in the world won't change the story.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Dec 2025 00:59:45 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46428205</link><dc:creator>kevinlearynet</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46428205</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46428205</guid></item></channel></rss>