<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>Hacker News: Best Comments</title><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/bestcomments</link><description>Hacker News RSS</description><docs>https://hnrss.org/</docs><generator>hnrss v2.1.1</generator><lastBuildDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2025 00:23:14 +0000</lastBuildDate><ns0:link href="https://hnrss.org/bestcomments" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item><title>New comment by CobrastanJorji in "Steam Machine"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&gt; Install your own apps, or even another operating system. Who are we to tell you how to use your computer?&lt;p&gt;From your mouth to Tim Cook's ear, friend.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 21:24:55 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45906945</link><dc:creator>CobrastanJorji</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45906945</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45906945</guid></item><item><title>New comment by modeless in "Steam Frame"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Foveated streaming! That's a great idea. Foveated rendering is complicated to implement with current rendering APIs in a way that actually improves performance, but foveated streaming seems like a much easier win that applies to all content automatically. And the dedicated 6 GHz dongle should do a much better job at streaming than typical wifi routers.&lt;p&gt;&gt; Just like any SteamOS device, install your own apps, open a browser, do what you want: It's your PC.&lt;p&gt;It's an ARM Linux PC that presumably gives you root access, in addition to being a VR headset. And it has an SD card slot for storage expansion. Very cool, should be very hackable. Very unlike every other standalone VR headset.&lt;p&gt;&gt; 2160 x 2160 LCD (per eye) 72-144Hz refresh rate&lt;p&gt;Roughly equivalent resolution to Quest 3 and less than Vision Pro. This won't be suitable as a monitor replacement for general desktop use. But the price is hopefully low. I'd love to see a high-end option with higher resolution displays in the future, good enough for monitor replacement.&lt;p&gt;&gt; Monochrome passthrough&lt;p&gt;So AR is not a focus here, which makes sense. However:&lt;p&gt;&gt; User accessible front expansion port w/ Dual high speed camera interface (8 lanes @ 2.5Gbps MIPI) / PCIe Gen 4 interface (1-lane)&lt;p&gt;Full color AR could be done as an optional expansion pack. And I can imagine people might come up with other fun things to put in there. Mouth tracking?&lt;p&gt;One thing I don't see here is optional tracking pucks for tracking objects or full body tracking. That's something the SteamVR Lighthouse tracking ecosystem had, and the Pico standalone headset also has it.&lt;p&gt;More detail from the LTT video: Apparently it can run Android APKs too? Quest compatibility layer maybe? There's an optional accessory kit that adds a top strap (I'm surprised it isn't standard) and palm straps that enable using the controllers in the style of the Valve Index's "knuckles" controllers.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 19:02:33 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45904494</link><dc:creator>modeless</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45904494</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45904494</guid></item><item><title>New comment by Night_Thastus in "The last-ever penny will be minted today in Philadelphia"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I'd say screw it, get rid of nickles and dimes as well. Quarters can stay, for now.&lt;p&gt;It's a complete waste of money and time continuing to mint such low-value currency. It can't be used for just about anything.&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, I do see the problem with part of this. For a handful of items where it does matter, it will force people to use cards more if they want to avoid rounding. And the card providers already have a choke-hold on retailers, and the whole thing is basically a scheme that funnels money from the poor to the wealthy via interest and fees on the consumer, interchange fees, and rewards programs.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 18:13:53 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45903609</link><dc:creator>Night_Thastus</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45903609</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45903609</guid></item><item><title>New comment by 1vuio0pswjnm7 in "Fighting the New York Times' invasion of user privacy"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;"The New York Times is demanding that we turn over 20 million of your private ChatGPT conversations."&lt;p&gt;As might any plaintiff.  NYT might be the first of many others and the lawsuits may not be limited to copyright claims&lt;p&gt;Why has OpenAI collected and stored 20 million conversations (including "deleted chats")&lt;p&gt;What is the purpose of OpenAI storing millions of private conversations&lt;p&gt;By contrast the purpose of NYT's request is both clear and limited&lt;p&gt;The documents requested are not being made public by the plaintiffs.  The documents will presumably be redacted to protect any confidential information before being produced to the plaintiffs, the documents can only be used by the plaintiffs for the purpose of the litigation against OpenAI and, unlike OpenAI who has collected and stored these conversations for as long as OpenAI desires, the plaintiffs are prohibited from retaining copies of the documents after the litigation is concluded&lt;p&gt;The privacy issue here has been created by OpenAI for their own commercial benefit&lt;p&gt;It is not even clear what this benefit, if any, will be as OpenAI continues to search for a "business model"&lt;p&gt;Wanton data collection&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 16:11:27 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45901917</link><dc:creator>1vuio0pswjnm7</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45901917</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45901917</guid></item><item><title>New comment by Tabular-Iceberg in "Yt-dlp: External JavaScript runtime now required for full YouTube support"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I remember when QuickTime came out in 1991 and it was obvious to everyone that video should be copied, pasted and saved like any arbitrary data.&lt;p&gt;It's absolutely insane to me how bad the user experience is with video nowadays, even video that's not encumbered by DRM or complex JavaScript clients.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 13:36:17 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45899963</link><dc:creator>Tabular-Iceberg</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45899963</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45899963</guid></item><item><title>New comment by mehulashah in "Yann LeCun to depart Meta and launch AI startup focused on 'world models'"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Most of the folks on this topic are focused on Meta and Yann’s departure. But, I’m seeing something different.&lt;p&gt;This is the weirdest technology market that I’ve seen. Researchers are getting rewarded with VC money to try what remains a science experiment. That used to be a bad word and now that gets rewarded with billions of dollars in valuation.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 13:21:19 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45899804</link><dc:creator>mehulashah</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45899804</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45899804</guid></item><item><title>New comment by ineedasername in "Pakistani newspaper mistakenly prints AI prompt with the article"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;When reached for comment on how this occurred, the journalist in question replied:&lt;p&gt;“This is the perfect question that gets to the heart of this issue. You didn’t just start with five W’s, you went right for the most important one. Let’s examine why that question works so well in this instance…”&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 12:35:45 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45899395</link><dc:creator>ineedasername</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45899395</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45899395</guid></item><item><title>New comment by chrismorgan in "Pakistani newspaper mistakenly prints AI prompt with the article"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;The current title (“Pakistani newspaper mistakenly prints AI prompt with the article”) isn’t correct, it wasn’t the &lt;i&gt;prompt&lt;/i&gt; that was printed, but trailing chatbot fluff:&lt;p&gt;&gt; &lt;i&gt;If you want, I can also create an even snappier “front-page style” version with punchy one-line stats and a bold, infographic-ready layout—perfect for maximum reader impact. Do you want me to do that next?&lt;/i&gt;&lt;p&gt;The article in question is titled “Auto sales rev up in October” and is an exceedingly dry slab of statistic-laden prose, of the sort that LLMs &lt;i&gt;love&lt;/i&gt; to err in (though there’s no indication of whether they have or not), and for which alternative (non-prose) presentations can be drastically better. Honestly, if the entire thing came from “here’s tabular data, select insights and churn out prose”… I can understand not wanting to do such drudgework.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 12:05:15 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45899143</link><dc:creator>chrismorgan</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45899143</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45899143</guid></item><item><title>New comment by gdiamos in "What happened to Transmeta, the last big dotcom IPO"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Transmeta made a technology bet that dynamic compilation could beat OOO super scalar CPUs in SPEC.&lt;p&gt;It was wrong, but it was controversial among experts at the time.&lt;p&gt;I’m glad that they tried it even though it turned out to be wrong. Many of the lessons learned are documented in systems conferences and incorporated into modern designs, ie GPUs.&lt;p&gt;To me transmeta is a great example of a venture investment. If it would have beaten Intel at SPEC by a margin, it would have dominated the market. Sometimes the only way to get to the bottom of a complex system is to build it.&lt;p&gt;The same could be said of scaling laws and LLMs. It was theory before Dario, Ilya, OpenAI, et al trained it.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 11:25:27 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45898849</link><dc:creator>gdiamos</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45898849</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45898849</guid></item><item><title>New comment by xuancanh in "Yann LeCun to depart Meta and launch AI startup focused on 'world models'"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;In industry research, someone in a chief position like LeCun should know how to balance long-term research with short-term projects. However, for whatever reason, he consistently shows hostility toward LLMs and engineering projects, even though Llama and PyTorch are two of the most influential projects from Meta AI. His attitude doesn’t really match what is expected from a Chief position at a product company like Facebook. When Llama 4 got criticized, he distanced himself from the project, stating that he only leads FAIR and that the project falls under a different organization. That kind of attitude doesn’t seem suitable for the face of AI at the company. It's not a surprise that Zuck tried to demote him.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 08:55:07 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45897885</link><dc:creator>xuancanh</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45897885</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45897885</guid></item><item><title>New comment by sebmellen in "Yann LeCun to depart Meta and launch AI startup focused on 'world models'"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Making LeCun report to Wang was the most boneheaded move imaginable. But… I suppose Zuckerberg knows what he wants, which is AI slopware and not truly groundbreaking foundation models.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 07:57:49 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45897467</link><dc:creator>sebmellen</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45897467</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45897467</guid></item><item><title>New comment by ivraatiems in "I can build enterprise software but I can't charge for it"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I am not a lawyer or diplomat or expert on trade, but I can make some general observations from an American/Western perspective:&lt;p&gt;First, the sanctions on Iran are such that any partnership with an Iranian person for business reasons is effectively impossible in the West, without the resources of a multi-million or billion-dollar company to circumvent them. The author says "I am not looking for anyone to bypass sanctions" but that is very obviously exactly what they are asking for.&lt;p&gt;Second, circumventing sanctions is illegal, and people regularly go to prison or are given massive monetary fines for this. OP, I don't question your motives, but you need to understand that people have literally gone to prison and lost their whole livelihoods for doing exactly what you are asking.&lt;p&gt;Therefore, posting this on a Western platform (Github) and advertising it on a Western message board (HN) is unlikely to help. I don't think the author's intentions are poor; I think they may simply not understand the intensity of the legal regime that makes working with them impossible.&lt;p&gt;There is also the matter of Westerners' general opinions on Iran, which - general attitudes of multiculturalism and tolerance nonwithstanding - is typically quite negative. The sanctions didn't come from nowhere.&lt;p&gt;I would recommend the author look into partnerships with persons from countries that are more sympathetic to their situation. The ones with strong tech industries would be Russia, China, and India. Vietnam is another example of a country with some tech industry which also has mostly positive relationships with Western countries, these days. I realize this is not as attractive as the West, but there are good people even in places whose governments I may as a Westerner may not particularly like, and English is a lingua franca the world over. I'd strongly recommend those places as a starting point.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 00:27:33 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45894833</link><dc:creator>ivraatiems</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45894833</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45894833</guid></item><item><title>New comment by judah in ".NET MAUI is coming to Linux and the browser"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;This is interesting for sure. Kudos for bringing this capability to the web!&lt;p&gt;One issue the demos reveal is, it doesn't _feel_ like the web. That is, I can't hit Ctrl+F to find text on a page. I can't select text with my cursor. I can't copy the address of a hyperlink. On my phone, I can't hard press on an image and share it to others. Screen readers can't handle it. I can't press a shortcut key to make everything larger.&lt;p&gt;These all may seem pedantic, but they contribute to the feeling "this is not the real web."&lt;p&gt;This is the same problem with Java applets in the late '90s, Flash and Silverlight in the early 2000s. They are islands of richness within a web page, but those islands are, well, opaque to browsers, search engines, and virtually all web tooling.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 11 Nov 2025 23:49:36 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45894501</link><dc:creator>judah</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45894501</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45894501</guid></item><item><title>New comment by fao_ in "FFmpeg to Google: Fund us or stop sending bugs"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;As yet, Valve is the only company I know of doing this, and it's paying off in dividends both for Linux and for Valve. In just 5ish years of Valve investing people and money into Linux- specifically mesa and WINE, Linux has gone from a product that is kind of shaky with Windows, to "I can throw a windows program or game at it and it usually works". Imagine how further the OSS ecosystem would be if Open Source hadn't existed, only FOSS; and companies were legally obligated to either publish source code or otherwise invest in the ecosystem.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 11 Nov 2025 23:47:41 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45894483</link><dc:creator>fao_</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45894483</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45894483</guid></item><item><title>New comment by 98codes in "iPhone Pocket"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;It's November, but I still had to make sure the date on the page wasn't April 1st.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 11 Nov 2025 21:43:33 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45893288</link><dc:creator>98codes</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45893288</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45893288</guid></item><item><title>New comment by stackskipton in "The Department of War just shot the accountants and opted for speed"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;As someone who has some familiarity with this process, just like safety regulations are written in blood, Federal Acquisition rules are written in misuse of money, sometimes criminally.&lt;p&gt;Yes, we have swung too much towards the bureaucrats but I'm not sure throwing out everything is solution to the issue.&lt;p&gt;Move fast works great when it's B2B software and failures means stock price does not go up. It's not so great when brand new jet acts up and results in crashes.&lt;p&gt;Oh yea, F-35 was built with move fast, they rolled models off the production line quickly, so Lockheed could get more money, but it looks like whole "We will fix busted models later" might have been more expensive. Time will tell.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 11 Nov 2025 21:26:23 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45893105</link><dc:creator>stackskipton</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45893105</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45893105</guid></item><item><title>New comment by bborud in "iPhone Pocket"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Objects have to earn the right to exist.  We make so much stuff. Most of it unnecessary.  Stuff that will soon be cluttering your home and then end up in a landfill.&lt;p&gt;This is not a product that deserves to exist. It is not made from quality materials ( Nylon (14%), Polyester (85%), Polyurethane (1%)).  It is not innovative.  It is questionable whether it solves its primary use case particularly well.&lt;p&gt;What makes this particularly objectionable is that it is from a design house that usually makes quality garments.  And then they stoop to making this crap, slapping their designer label on it and then exploit ghastly people who don't know any better to waste tons of money on it.&lt;p&gt;This is pissing on Issey Miyake's grave.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 11 Nov 2025 21:10:59 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45892905</link><dc:creator>bborud</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45892905</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45892905</guid></item><item><title>New comment by throwaway713 in "Collaboration sucks"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&gt; Every time you see collaboration happening, speak up and destroy it. Say “there are too many people involved. X, you are the driver, you decide.” (This is a great way to make friends btw).&lt;p&gt;Corollary for managers: Do &lt;i&gt;not&lt;/i&gt; say "it's your call", then once the decision has been made (and you skipped all the meetings pertaining to that decision), comment about how you would have done it differently and then retroactively request your report to go back and make changes. This is a great way to lose employees.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 11 Nov 2025 20:53:31 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45892683</link><dc:creator>throwaway713</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45892683</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45892683</guid></item><item><title>New comment by AbrahamParangi in "FFmpeg to Google: Fund us or stop sending bugs"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;If google bears no role in fixing the issues it finds and nobody else is being paid to do it either, it functionally is just providing free security vulnerability research for malicious actors because almost nobody can take over or switch off of ffmpeg.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 11 Nov 2025 19:50:01 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45891930</link><dc:creator>AbrahamParangi</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45891930</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45891930</guid></item><item><title>New comment by simianparrot in "iPhone Pocket"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I got excited for a moment, thought it was a new line of iPhone Mini -- you know, the actual handheld iPhones. I still use my 13 Mini.&lt;p&gt;This was the biggest letdown of clicking a link since my last Rickroll in the early 2000's&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 11 Nov 2025 19:41:45 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45891834</link><dc:creator>simianparrot</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45891834</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45891834</guid></item><item><title>New comment by phkahler in "FFmpeg to Google: Fund us or stop sending bugs"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;From TFA this was telling:&lt;p&gt;Thus, as Mark Atwood, an open source policy expert, pointed out on Twitter, he had to keep telling Amazon to not do things that would mess up FFmpeg because, he had to keep explaining to his bosses that “They are not a vendor, there is no NDA, we have no leverage, your VP has refused to help fund them, and they could kill three major product lines tomorrow with an email. So, stop, and listen to me … ”&lt;p&gt;I agree with the headline here. If Google can pay someone to find bugs, they can pay someone to fix them. How many time have managers said "Don't come to me with problems, come with solutions"&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 11 Nov 2025 19:41:20 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45891830</link><dc:creator>phkahler</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45891830</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45891830</guid></item><item><title>New comment by woodruffw in "FFmpeg to Google: Fund us or stop sending bugs"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I’m an open source maintainer, so I empathize with the sentiment that large companies &lt;i&gt;appear&lt;/i&gt; to produce labor for unpaid maintainers by disclosing security issues. But &lt;i&gt;appearance&lt;/i&gt; is operative: a security issue is something that I (as the maintainer) would need to fix regardless of who reports it, or would otherwise need to accept the reputational hit that comes with not triaging security reports. That’s sometimes perfectly fine (it’s okay for projects to decide that security isn’t a priority!), but you can’t have it both ways.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 11 Nov 2025 19:16:02 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45891521</link><dc:creator>woodruffw</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45891521</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45891521</guid></item><item><title>New comment by tempestn in "iPhone Pocket"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Had to double check the date here. This really is indistinguishable from an April 1 post.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 11 Nov 2025 18:47:58 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45891190</link><dc:creator>tempestn</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45891190</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45891190</guid></item><item><title>New comment by jitbit in ".NET 10"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;For us, every .NET upgrade since .NET 5 has gone surprisingly smoothly and reduced CPU/RAM usage by 10–15%.&lt;p&gt;We were even able to downgrade our cloud servers to smaller instances, literally.&lt;p&gt;I wish .NET was more popular among startups, if only C# could get rid of the "enterpisey" stigma.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 11 Nov 2025 15:48:41 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45888669</link><dc:creator>jitbit</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45888669</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45888669</guid></item><item><title>New comment by perihelions in "iPhone Pocket"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&gt; &lt;i&gt;"Greater China"&lt;/i&gt;&lt;p&gt;Irredentist pro-war language, Tim Cook? I am so done with Apple. They knew what they did when they chose the words; they certainly spent thousands of hours deliberating them.&lt;p&gt;This is Lebensraum with Chinese Characteristics.&lt;p&gt;&gt; &lt;i&gt;"The term is often used to avoid invoking sensitivities over the political status of Taiwan.[16] Contrastingly, it has been used in reference to Chinese irredentism in nationalist contexts, such as the notion that China should reclaim its "lost territories" to create a Greater China.[17][18]"&lt;/i&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Greater_China" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Greater_China&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 11 Nov 2025 15:27:44 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45888370</link><dc:creator>perihelions</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45888370</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45888370</guid></item><item><title>New comment by davidmurdoch in "iPhone Pocket"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Had to make sure it wasn't April 1st.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 11 Nov 2025 14:45:01 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45887806</link><dc:creator>davidmurdoch</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45887806</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45887806</guid></item><item><title>New comment by fxtentacle in "iPhone Pocket"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Awww... I was so much hoping for an iPhone that will fit into my pocket. The 1st iPhone SE was the perfect form factor. But no, Apple's phones just had to grow and grow and grow like cancer ...&lt;p&gt;In my opinion, the fact that Apple is now selling a bag to carry your oversized phone around in, is an admission that they failed to make phones that are convenient to carry.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 11 Nov 2025 14:41:57 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45887773</link><dc:creator>fxtentacle</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45887773</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45887773</guid></item><item><title>New comment by janeway in "The 'Toy Story' You Remember"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;This topic is fascinating to me. The Toy Story film workflow is a perfect illustration of intentional compensation: artists pushed greens in the digital master because 35 mm film would darken and desaturate them. The aim was never neon greens on screen, it was colour calibration for a later step. Only later, when digital masters were reused without the film stage, did those compensating choices start to look like creative ones.&lt;p&gt;I run into this same failure mode often. We introduce purposeful scaffolding in the workflow that isn’t meant to stand alone, but exists solely to ensure the final output behaves as intended. Months later, someone is pitching how we should “lean into the bold saturated greens,” not realising the topic only exists because we specifically wanted neutral greens in the final output. The scaffold becomes the building.&lt;p&gt;In our work this kind of nuance isn’t optional, it is the project. If we lose track of which decisions are compensations and which are targets, outcomes drift badly and quietly, and everything built after is optimised for the wrong goal.&lt;p&gt;I’d genuinely value advice on preventing this. Is there a good name or framework for this pattern? Something concise that distinguishes a process artefact from product intent, and helps teams course-correct early without sounding like a semantics debate?&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 11 Nov 2025 11:55:17 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45886316</link><dc:creator>janeway</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45886316</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45886316</guid></item><item><title>New comment by blopker in "AI documentation you can talk to, for every repo"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I took a look at a project I maintain[0], and wow. It's so wrong in every section I saw. The generated diagrams make no sense. The text sections take implementation details that don't matter and present them to the user like they need to know them. It's also outdated.&lt;p&gt;I hope actual users never see this. I dread thinking about having to go around to various LLM generated sites to correct documentation I never approved of to stop confusing users that are tricked into reading it.&lt;p&gt;[0]: &lt;a href="https://deepwiki.com/blopker/codebook" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://deepwiki.com/blopker/codebook&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 11 Nov 2025 07:16:05 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45884860</link><dc:creator>blopker</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45884860</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45884860</guid></item><item><title>New comment by zmmmmm in "Time to start de-Appling"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I know this is a tangent but honestly, this is why the Google decision to de-openify Android is &lt;i&gt;insane&lt;/i&gt; even from Google's point of view. Who would want to be an iron clad gate keeper when the world is descending into authoritarianism? You just paint a giant target on your back for the authoritarians to come after.&lt;p&gt;If Apple had supported open iCloud alternatives for backup and other services from day one, it woudn't even be a discussion now. The UK probably wouldn't have thought of the idea of mandating against E2E encryption because it would be self evident it would actually just churn people to alternatives where they have less leverage and visibility. But Apple couldn't resist bricking up the walled garden and now it's hostile to both them and their users, and to be honest, everyone on the planet since it is obvious that once this happens in the UK it will be silly for every government everywhere not to follow suit.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 11 Nov 2025 00:14:32 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45882625</link><dc:creator>zmmmmm</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45882625</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45882625</guid></item></channel></rss>