<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>Hacker News: Best Comments</title><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/bestcomments</link><description>Hacker News RSS</description><docs>https://hnrss.org/</docs><generator>hnrss v2.1.1</generator><lastBuildDate>Sat, 06 Dec 2025 01:23:10 +0000</lastBuildDate><ns0:link href="https://hnrss.org/bestcomments" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item><title>New comment by Workaccount2 in "Gemini 3 Pro: the frontier of vision AI"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Well&lt;p&gt;It is the first model to get &lt;i&gt;partial-credit&lt;/i&gt; on an LLM image test I have. Which is counting the legs of a dog. Specifically, a dog with 5 legs. This is a wild test, because LLMs get really pushy and insistent that the dog only has 4 legs.&lt;p&gt;In fact GPT5 wrote an edge detection script to see where "golden dog feet" met "bright green grass" to prove to me that there were only 4 legs. The script found 5, and GPT-5 then said it was a bug, and adjusted the script sensitivity so it only located 4, lol.&lt;p&gt;Anyway, Gemini 3, while still being unable to count the legs first try, did identify "male anatomy" (it's own words) also visible in the picture. The 5th leg was approximately where you could expect a well endowed dog to have a "5th leg".&lt;p&gt;That aside though, I still wouldn't call it particularly impressive.&lt;p&gt;As a note, Meta's image slicer correctly highlighted all 5 legs without a hitch. Maybe not quite a transformer, but interesting that it could properly interpret "dog leg" and ID them. Also the dog with many legs (I have a few of them) all had there extra legs added by nano-banana.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 20:26:05 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46166792</link><dc:creator>Workaccount2</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46166792</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46166792</guid></item><item><title>New comment by thayne in "Netflix to Acquire Warner Bros"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I want a separation between the streaming platform companies and the content making companies, so that the streaming companies can compete on making a better platform/service and the content companies compete on making better content.&lt;p&gt;I don't want one company that owns everything, I want several companies that are able to license whatever content they want. And ideally the customer can choose between a subscription that includes everything, and paying for content a la carte, or maybe subscriptions that focus on specific kinds of content (scifi/fantasy, stuff for kids, old movies, international, sports, etc.) regardless of what company made it.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 16:24:07 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46163452</link><dc:creator>thayne</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46163452</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46163452</guid></item><item><title>New comment by dkyc in "Cloudflare outage on December 5, 2025"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;One thing to keep in mind when judging what's 'appropriate' is that Cloudflare was effectively responding to an ongoing security incident outside of their control (the React Server RCE vulnerability). Part of Cloudlfare's value proposition is being &lt;i&gt;quick&lt;/i&gt; to react to such threats. That changes the equation a bit: any hour you wait longer to deploy, your customers are actively getting hacked through a known high-severity vulnerability.&lt;p&gt;In this case it's not just a matter of 'hold back for another day to make sure it's done right', like when adding a new feature to a normal SaaS application. In Cloudflare's case moving slower &lt;i&gt;also&lt;/i&gt; comes with a real cost.&lt;p&gt;That isn't to say it didn't work out badly this time, just that the calculation is a bit different.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 16:16:33 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46163343</link><dc:creator>dkyc</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46163343</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46163343</guid></item><item><title>New comment by emmp in "Framework Laptop 13 gets ARM processor with 12 cores via upgrade kit"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;No interest in this exactly, but I am interested in the idea that third parties are now targeting the Framework form factor explicitly to sell upgrades/replacements outside of the Framework marketplace.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 16:13:05 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46163269</link><dc:creator>emmp</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46163269</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46163269</guid></item><item><title>New comment by nonethewiser in "Netflix to Acquire Warner Bros"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&gt; Any consolidation like this seems like a negative for consumers&lt;p&gt;This is a very common narrative to this news. But coming into this news, I think the most common narrative against streaming was essentially "There is not enough consolidation." People were happy when Netflix was &lt;i&gt;the&lt;/i&gt; streaming service, but then everyone pulled their content and have their own (Disney, Paramount, etc.)&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 14:43:08 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46161918</link><dc:creator>nonethewiser</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46161918</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46161918</guid></item><item><title>New comment by afavour in "Netflix to Acquire Warner Bros"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Any consolidation like this seems like a negative for consumers. But at least it wasn’t bought by Larry Ellison, as was considered very likely (assuming this merger gets approved, in the current administration you never know).&lt;p&gt;From a Hacker News perspective, I wonder what this means for engineers working on HBO Max. Netflix says they’re keeping the company separate but surely you’d be looking to move them to Netflix backend infrastructure at the very least.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 13:44:09 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46161166</link><dc:creator>afavour</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46161166</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46161166</guid></item><item><title>New comment by moolcool in "Netflix to Acquire Warner Bros"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://theonion.com/just-six-corporations-remain-1819564741/" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://theonion.com/just-six-corporations-remain-1819564741...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 13:38:11 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46161112</link><dc:creator>moolcool</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46161112</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46161112</guid></item><item><title>New comment by I-M-S in "Netflix to Acquire Warner Bros"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;“The goal is to become HBO faster than HBO can become us.” - Ted Sarandos in 2013&lt;p&gt;Seems Netflix won that race.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 12:51:52 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46160598</link><dc:creator>I-M-S</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46160598</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46160598</guid></item><item><title>New comment by phartenfeller in "Netflix to Acquire Warner Bros"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I don't like this. Netflix rarely creates excellent content; instead, it frequently produces mediocre or worse content. Will the same happen for Warner? Are cinemas now second behind streaming?&lt;p&gt;Edit: I agree Netflix has good Originals. But most are from the early days when they favored quality over quantity. It is sad to see that they reversed that. They have much funding power and should give it to great art that really sticks, has ambitions and something to tell, and values my time instead of mediocrity.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 12:50:48 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46160586</link><dc:creator>phartenfeller</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46160586</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46160586</guid></item><item><title>New comment by JoeWiltshire in "Cloudflare Down Again – and DownDetector Is Also Down"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://downdetectorsdowndetectorsdowndetectorsdowndetector.com/" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://downdetectorsdowndetectorsdowndetectorsdowndetector....&lt;/a&gt; reports that &lt;a href="https://downdetectorsdowndetectorsdowndetector.com/" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://downdetectorsdowndetectorsdowndetector.com/&lt;/a&gt; is down, guessing downdetectorsdowndetectorsdowndetector runs via cloudflare!&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 09:04:33 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46158451</link><dc:creator>JoeWiltshire</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46158451</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46158451</guid></item><item><title>New comment by notatoad in "Netflix’s AV1 Journey: From Android to TVs and Beyond"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I understand that sometimes the HN titles get edited to be less descriptive and more generic in order to match the actual article title.&lt;p&gt;What’s the logic with changing the title here from the actual article title it was originally submitted with “AV1 — Now Powering 30% of Netflix Streaming” to the generic and not at all representative title it currently has “AV1: a modern open codec”?  That is neither the article title nor representative of the article content.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 02:58:28 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46156393</link><dc:creator>notatoad</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46156393</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46156393</guid></item><item><title>New comment by bcrosby95 in "We gave 5 LLMs $100K to trade stocks for 8 months"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&gt; Grok ended up performing the best while DeepSeek came close to second. Almost all the models had a tech-heavy portfolio which led them to do well. Gemini ended up in last place since it was the only one that had a large portfolio of non-tech stocks.&lt;p&gt;I'm not an investor or researcher, but this triggers my spidey sense... it seems to imply they aren't measuring what they think they are.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 23:20:57 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46154636</link><dc:creator>bcrosby95</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46154636</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46154636</guid></item><item><title>New comment by kibwen in "Thoughts on Go vs. Rust vs. Zig"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;&gt; In Rust, creating a mutable global variable is so hard that there are long forum discussions on how to do it. In Zig, you can just create one, no problem.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;p&gt;Well, no, creating a mutable global variable is trivial in Rust, it just requires either `unsafe` or using a smart pointer that provides synchronization. That's because Rust programs are re-entrant by default, because Rust provides compile-time thread-safety. If you don't care about statically-enforced thread-safety, then it's as easy in Rust as it is in Zig or C. The difference is that, unlike Zig or C, Rust gives you the tools to enforce more guarantees about your code's possible runtime behavior.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 22:43:17 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46154215</link><dc:creator>kibwen</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46154215</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46154215</guid></item><item><title>New comment by Centigonal in "A Cozy Mk IV light aircraft crashed after 3D-printed part was weakened by heat"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;It's important to note the plane is a Cozy Mk IV, which is an experimental light aircraft that is built at home out of foam and fiberglass by following instructions you get online. The design is very good, and hundreds have been flown over the last ~35 years, but Cozy pilots are the aviation equivalent of people who run Arch Linux as their daily driver; many of them are tweaking their aircraft with some frequency.&lt;p&gt;This isn't a case of an established aircraft manufacturer cutting corners on a part; it's probably some small maker who made this part out of the wrong materials. It's a little shocking that neither the maker nor the buyer of this part thought to either stick it in an oven or run it with the engine on the ground to guarantee it could hold up to the expected intake air temps. I'm glad the pilot made it out with only mild injuries.&lt;p&gt;edit: here's a fun video from a Cozy pilot in case you're curious about the plane and the people who fly them: &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Ipqmb09wbSQ" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Ipqmb09wbSQ&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 22:20:14 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46153940</link><dc:creator>Centigonal</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46153940</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46153940</guid></item><item><title>New comment by Aurornis in "Why are 38 percent of Stanford students saying they're disabled?"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;The original article which is linked in this post goes into much better detail: &lt;a href="https://www.theatlantic.com/magazine/2026/01/elite-university-student-accommodation/684946/?gift=o6MjJQpusU9ebnFuymVdsFCUJZQ0G9lMNnLXcGfnS-w&amp;utm_source=copy-link&amp;utm_medium=social&amp;utm_campaign=share" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://www.theatlantic.com/magazine/2026/01/elite-universit...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;Schools and universities have made accommodations a priority for decades. It started with good intentions, but parents and students alike have noticed that it's both a) easy to qualify for a disability and b) provides significant academic advantages if you do.&lt;p&gt;Another big accommodation request is extra time on tests. At many high schools and universities, getting more time than your peers to take tests is as simple as finding a doctor who will write the write things in a note for you. Some universities grant special permissions to record lectures to students with disabilities, too.&lt;p&gt;If you don't have a disability, you aren't allowed to record lectures and you have to put your pencil down at the end of the normal test window. As you can imagine, when a high percentage of the student body gets to stay longer for a hard test, the wheels start turning in students' heads as they realize cheating is being normalized and they're being left behind by not getting that doctors' note.&lt;p&gt;The rampant abuse is really becoming a problem for students with true disabilities. As you can imagine, when the disability system is faced with 1/3 of the student body registering for disability status the limited number of single rooms and other resources will inevitably get assigned to people who don't need it while some who actually do need it are forced to go without.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 20:43:28 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46152780</link><dc:creator>Aurornis</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46152780</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46152780</guid></item><item><title>New comment by thewebguyd in "Fighting the age-gated internet"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Correct.&lt;p&gt;None of these laws are &lt;i&gt;actually&lt;/i&gt; about protecting children. That's not the real goal. The real goal is the complete elimination of anonymity on the web, where both private companies and the state can keep tabs on everything you do.&lt;p&gt;Not being able to be at least pseudo-anonymous has a real chilling effect on speech and expression. Even if there are laws in place protecting such rights, people will self-censor when knowing they are being watched.&lt;p&gt;It's how freedom of speech and expression dies without actually scratching that part off of the bill of rights.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 20:06:44 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46152272</link><dc:creator>thewebguyd</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46152272</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46152272</guid></item><item><title>New comment by Bender in "Fighting the age-gated internet"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I stand by my repeated statements of how this could have been solved simply using an RTA header [1] on the server side and require the most common user agents to look for that header putting the onus on parents where it currently legally resides.  It's not perfect, nothing is nor ever will be but using the header solution is entirely private, does not store or leak data and puts the decision into the device owners rather than creating perverse incentives to track everyone.  It may actually protect most small children whereas today teens quickly find a work-around and then teach smaller children how to work around these centralized gate-keepers.  The current &lt;i&gt;solutions&lt;/i&gt; are just about tracking people by real identity and incentivizing teens to commit identity crimes.&lt;p&gt;[1] - &lt;a href="https://www.rtalabel.org/page.php" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://www.rtalabel.org/page.php&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 19:53:12 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46152074</link><dc:creator>Bender</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46152074</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46152074</guid></item><item><title>New comment by shetaye in "Why are 38 percent of Stanford students saying they're disabled?"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Regarding Stanford specifically, I did not see the number broken down by academic or residential disability (in the underlying Atlantic article). This is relevant, because&lt;p&gt;&gt; Some students get approved for housing accommodations, including single rooms and emotional-support animals.&lt;p&gt;buries the lede, at least for Stanford. It is incredibly commonplace for students to "get an OAE" (Office of Accessible Education) exclusively to get a single room. Moreover, residential accommodations allow you to be placed in housing prior to the general population and thus grant larger (&amp; better) housing selection.&lt;p&gt;I would not be surprised if a majority of the cited Stanford accommodations were not used for test taking but instead used exclusively for housing (there are different processes internally for each).&lt;p&gt;edit: there is even a practice of "stacking" where certain disabilities are used to strategically reduce the subset of dorms in which you can live, to the point where the only intersection between your requirements is a comfy single, forcing Admin to put you there. It is well known, for example, that a particularly popular dorm is the nearest to the campus clinic. If you can get an accommodation requiring proximity to the clinic, you have narrowed your choices to that dorm or another. One more accommodation and you are guaranteed the good dorm.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 19:08:42 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46151492</link><dc:creator>shetaye</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46151492</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46151492</guid></item><item><title>New comment by hibikir in "Why are 38 percent of Stanford students saying they're disabled?"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I think there's a non-malicious explanation for a percentage of this.&lt;p&gt;As I grew up in the 80s, there were two kinds of gifted kids in school: The kind that would ace everything anyway, and the kind that, for a variety of reasons, lacked the regulation abilities to manage the school setting well, with the slow classes and such. A lot of very smart people just failed academically, because the system didn't work for them. Some of those improved their executive function enough as they went past their teenage years, and are now making a lot of money in difficult fields.&lt;p&gt;So what happens when we do make accomodations to them? That their peaky, gifted performance comes out, they don't get ejected by the school systems anywhere near as often as they were before, and now end up in top institutions. Because they really are both very smart and disabled at the same time.&lt;p&gt;you can even see this in tech workplaces: The percentages of workers that are neurodivergent is much higher than usual, but it's not as if tech hires them out of compassion, but because there's a big cadre or neurodivergent people that are just in the line where they are very productive workers anyway. So it should be no surprise that in instutitutions searching for performance, the number of people that qualify for affordances for certain mental disabilities just goes way up.&lt;p&gt;That's not to say that there cannot be people that are just cheating, but it doesn't take much time in a class with gifted kids to realize that no, it's not just cheating. You can find someone, say, suffering in a dialectic-centric english class, where just following the conversation is a problem, while they are outright bored with the highest difficulty technical AP classes available, because they find them very easy.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 18:51:59 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46151331</link><dc:creator>hibikir</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46151331</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46151331</guid></item><item><title>New comment by OGEnthusiast in "Why are 38 percent of Stanford students saying they're disabled?"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;American society is at the point where if you don't play these sort of games/tricks, you'll get out-competed by those who do. Bleak.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 18:36:55 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46151130</link><dc:creator>OGEnthusiast</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46151130</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46151130</guid></item><item><title>New comment by __MatrixMan__ in "Autism should not be treated as a single condition"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;It has always bothered me that by "spectrum" they mean not the sort of continuous thing that spectra actually are, but instead some disjoint set of "colors" any one of which might describe a person.  That's called a partition, and its in an entirely separate thing.&lt;p&gt;When I tell this to people they understand immediately that I am in fact on that "spectrum".&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 17:27:29 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46150224</link><dc:creator>__MatrixMan__</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46150224</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46150224</guid></item><item><title>New comment by Gormo in "Transparent leadership beats servant leadership"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;There's a big difference between protecting a team from all the shit and hiding it from them completely.&lt;p&gt;It's good to be a &lt;i&gt;transparent&lt;/i&gt; shit umbrella.  The team should absolutely have visibility into what's going on, and understand why certain decisions are being made, but a good manager does need to step in to avoid the shit hitting them directly.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 17:16:18 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46150059</link><dc:creator>Gormo</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46150059</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46150059</guid></item><item><title>New comment by ceroxylon in "Microsoft drops AI sales targets in half after salespeople miss their quotas"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;As someone who appreciates machine learning, the main dissonance I have with interacting with Microsoft's implementation of AI feels like "don't worry, we will do the thinking for you".&lt;p&gt;This appears everywhere, with every tool trying to autocomplete every sentence and action, creating a very clunky ecosystem where I am constantly pressing 'escape' and 'backspace' to undo some action that is trying to rewrite what I am doing to something I don't want or didn't intend.&lt;p&gt;It is wasting time and none of the things I want are optimized, their tools feel like they are helping people write "good morning team, today we are going to do a Business, but first we must discuss the dinner reservations" emails.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 17:05:59 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46149915</link><dc:creator>ceroxylon</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46149915</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46149915</guid></item><item><title>New comment by postit in "I ignore the spotlight as a staff engineer"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;One thing I’ve learned in my 25+ year career is that if you don't own your narrative and your work, someone else will claim it - especially in corporate America.&lt;p&gt;I have lost count of the brilliant engineers who were passed over for credit simply because someone less technically capable, but extremely popular, pulled the strings to steal the spotlight.&lt;p&gt;You don't necessarily need to be in the spotlight, but you do need to leave a paper trail. Claim your work and inventions both internally and externally. You don't need to be a 'LinkedIn thought leader' to do this, just submit talks to conferences and find peers at other companies who understand the difference between those who build and those who only talk about building.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 15:56:26 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46149009</link><dc:creator>postit</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46149009</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46149009</guid></item><item><title>New comment by jqpabc123 in "Microsoft drops AI sales targets in half after salespeople miss their quotas"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;AI agent technology likely isn’t ready for the kind of high-stakes autonomous business work Microsoft is promising.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;p&gt;It's unbelievable to me that tech leaders lack the insight to recognize this.&lt;p&gt;So how to explain the current AI mania being widely promoted?&lt;p&gt;I think the best fit explanation is simple con artistry. They know the product is fundamentally flawed and won't perform as being promised. But the money to be made selling the fantasy is simply too good to ignore.&lt;p&gt;In other words --- pure greed.  Over the longer term, this is a weakness, not a strength.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 15:50:09 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46148928</link><dc:creator>jqpabc123</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46148928</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46148928</guid></item><item><title>New comment by CodeMage in "Transparent leadership beats servant leadership"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;From the post: "The middle manager that doesn't perform any useful work is a fun stereotype, but I also think it's a good target to aim for."&lt;p&gt;This is the kind of argument that makes people come up with middle manager stereotypes in the first place. In fact, the whole post is a great example of why middle manager stereotypes exist: it starts with a straw man argument and comes up with a "better alternative" that makes life easier for the manager, regardless of what the manager's reports really &lt;i&gt;need&lt;/i&gt;.&lt;p&gt;I've seen this whole "I will empower you to do everything on your own" principle in action and it's &lt;i&gt;exhausting&lt;/i&gt;. Especially when the word "empower" is a used as a euphemism for "have you take on additional responsibilities".&lt;p&gt;Look, boss, sometimes empowering me is just what I need, but sometimes I need you to solve a specific problem for me, so I can keep solving all the other problems I already have on my plate.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 14:53:11 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46148293</link><dc:creator>CodeMage</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46148293</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46148293</guid></item><item><title>New comment by skrebbel in "Programming peaked"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;This article in different forms keeps making the rounds and it's just so tiring. Yeah, let's remember everything that was great about 25 years ago and forget everything that sucked. Juxtapose it with everything that sucks about today but omit everything that's great. Come on man.&lt;p&gt;If you think things suck now, just make it better! The world is your playground. Nobody makes you use YAML and Docker and VS Code or whatever your beef is. Eclipse is still around! There's still a data center around your corner! Walk over and hang a server in the rack, put your hardly-typechecked Java 1.4 code on there and off you go!&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 12:34:15 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46146943</link><dc:creator>skrebbel</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46146943</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46146943</guid></item><item><title>New comment by crote in "How elites could shape mass preferences as AI reduces persuasion costs"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Note that &lt;i&gt;nothing&lt;/i&gt; in the article is AI-specific: the entire argument is built around the &lt;i&gt;cost&lt;/i&gt; of persuasion, with the potential of AI to more cheaply generate propaganda as buzzword link.&lt;p&gt;However, exactly the same applies with, say, targeted Facebook ads or Russian troll armies. You don't need any AI for this.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 09:02:58 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46145377</link><dc:creator>crote</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46145377</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46145377</guid></item><item><title>New comment by psviderski in "Uncloud - Tool for deploying containerised apps across servers without k8s"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Hey, creator here. Thanks for sharing this!&lt;p&gt;Uncloud[0] is a container orchestrator without a control plane. Think multi-machine Docker Compose with automatic WireGuard mesh, service discovery, and HTTPS via Caddy. Each machine just keeps a p2p-synced copy of cluster state (using Fly.io's Corrosion), so there's no quorum to maintain.&lt;p&gt;I’m building Uncloud after years of managing Kubernetes in small envs and at a unicorn. I keep seeing teams reach for K8s when they really just need to run a bunch of containers across a few machines with decent networking, rollouts, and HTTPS. The operational overhead of k8s is brutal for what they actually need.&lt;p&gt;A few things that make it unique:&lt;p&gt;- uses the familiar Docker Compose spec, no new DSL to learn&lt;p&gt;- builds and pushes your Docker images directly to your machines without an external registry (via my other project unregistry [1])&lt;p&gt;- imperative CLI (like Docker) rather than declarative reconciliation. Easier mental model and debugging&lt;p&gt;- works across cloud VMs, bare metal, even a Raspberry Pi at home behind NAT (all connected together)&lt;p&gt;- minimal resource footprint (&lt;150MB ram)&lt;p&gt;[0]: &lt;a href="https://github.com/psviderski/uncloud" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://github.com/psviderski/uncloud&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;[1]: &lt;a href="https://github.com/psviderski/unregistry" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://github.com/psviderski/unregistry&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 06:53:56 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46144570</link><dc:creator>psviderski</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46144570</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46144570</guid></item><item><title>New comment by linguae in "Micron Announces Exit from Crucial Consumer Business"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I'm sad.  I'm a software guy, not much of a hardware expert, so please bear with me if I"m too pessimistic.  However, I feel that if trends like this continue, it might be the end of enthusiast-level personal computing as we know it.  No more being able to head down to the electronics store and purchase RAM, motherboards, processors, GPUs, storage, and other components.  We're going to be limited to locked-down terminals connected to cloud services, both of which provided by a small number of multinational corporations.  If we're lucky, we might still have USB peripherals.&lt;p&gt;The sad thing is that we enthusiasts are a small market compared to the overwhelming majority of computer users who don't mind locked-down devices, or at least until they've been bitten by the restrictions, but if there are no alternatives other than retrocomputing, then it's too late.  For decades we enthusiasts have been able to benefit from other markets with overlapping needs such as gaming, workstations, and corporate servers.  However, many on-premise servers have been replaced by cloud services, the workstation market has been subsumed by the broader PC market, and PC gaming has faced challenges, from a push toward locked-down consoles to challenges in the GPU market due to competition with cryptocurrency mining and now AI.&lt;p&gt;One of the things I'm increasingly disappointed with is the dominance of large corporations in computing.  It seems harder for small players to survive in this ecosystem.  Software has to deal with network effects and large companies owning major platforms, and building your own hardware requires tons of capital.&lt;p&gt;I wonder if it's possible even for a company to make even 1980s-era electronics without massive capital expenditures?  How feasible is it for a small company to manufacture the equivalent of a Motorola 68000 or Intel 386?&lt;p&gt;I'd like to see a market for hobbyist computing by hobbyist computer shops, but I'm not sure it's economically feasible.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 00:30:27 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46142265</link><dc:creator>linguae</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46142265</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46142265</guid></item></channel></rss>