<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>Hacker News: Best Comments</title><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/bestcomments</link><description>Hacker News RSS</description><docs>https://hnrss.org/</docs><generator>hnrss v2.1.1</generator><lastBuildDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 00:09:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><ns0:link href="https://hnrss.org/bestcomments" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item><title>New comment by Tiberium in "Claude Cowork Exfiltrates Files"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;A bit unrelated, but if you ever find a malicious use of Anthropic APIs like that, you can just upload the key to a GitHub Gist or a public repo - Anthropic is a GitHub scanning partner, so the key will be revoked almost instantly (you can delete the gist afterwards).&lt;p&gt;It works for a lot of other providers too, including OpenAI (which also has file APIs, by the way).&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://support.claude.com/en/articles/9767949-api-key-best-practices-keeping-your-keys-safe-and-secure#h_9689e97cd8" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://support.claude.com/en/articles/9767949-api-key-best-...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://docs.github.com/en/code-security/reference/secret-security/supported-secret-scanning-patterns" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://docs.github.com/en/code-security/reference/secret-se...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 21:09:36 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46623477</link><dc:creator>Tiberium</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46623477</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46623477</guid></item><item><title>New comment by alexjplant in "Ford F-150 Lightning outsold the Cybertruck and was then canceled for poor sales"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&gt; A pickup truck should just be max utility, especially if you're a manufacturer making your first one&lt;p&gt;The modern US pickup truck isn't built for utility. It's a $60,000 four-door lifted luxobarge with leather interior and a short bed. It signals (perceived) wealth while preserving working-class alignment. It can also be justified by way of having to pick up used furniture for TikTok refinish and flip projects or bimonthly runs to Home Depot to buy caulk and lightbulbs. Independent tradesman can write them off as work vehicles or, allegedly, use COVID-era PPP loans to buy them.&lt;p&gt;It's the suburban equivalent of a yuppie's Rolex Submariner. Investment bankers generally don't go scuba diving and if they did a dive computer would be vastly preferable.&lt;p&gt;I say all of that to say that making a pickup truck for that market segment isn't a bad idea from a numbers perspective. You just can't market it as a luxury vehicle because the whole point is that it &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; but it isn't.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 19:09:32 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46621053</link><dc:creator>alexjplant</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46621053</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46621053</guid></item><item><title>New comment by ryandrake in "So, you’ve hit an age gate. What now?"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;My kid has recently just quit playing Roblox because of the sketchy facial age check process. She said that her and all her friends know not to ever upload a picture of themselves to the Internet (good job, fellow Other Parents!!) so they're either moving on to other games or just downloading stock photos of people from the internet and uploading those (which apparently works).&lt;p&gt;What a total joke. These companies need to stop normalizing the sharing of personal private photos. It's literally the opposite direction from good Internet hygiene, especially for kids!&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 18:18:59 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46620005</link><dc:creator>ryandrake</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46620005</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46620005</guid></item><item><title>New comment by grouchomarx in "Ford F-150 Lightning outsold the Cybertruck and was then canceled for poor sales"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&gt;I think the timing of the Cybertruck starting deliveries roughly aligning with when Elon got heavily involved in politics&lt;p&gt;That and also it's just a bad product.&lt;p&gt;&gt;That said, even though it's not to my taste, I do admire that they dared to do something different and took a big gamble on it.&lt;p&gt;A pickup truck should just be max utility, especially if you're a manufacturer making your first one&lt;p&gt;edit: agree there's a market for the raptor off-road tremor package thing, but it wasn't ford's first and they've been selling commerical trucks for 75 years. A true tesla f150 competitor would have sold like crazy, I think&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 18:12:09 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46619846</link><dc:creator>grouchomarx</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46619846</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46619846</guid></item><item><title>New comment by billti in "Ford F-150 Lightning outsold the Cybertruck and was then canceled for poor sales"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I think the timing of the Cybertruck starting deliveries roughly aligning with when Elon got heavily involved in politics hurt it quite a bit. It is such a distinctive vehicle with a strong association with Elon, that there was an immediate brand association. It may have had poor sales anyway, but it certainly didn't help that many folks on the left, who are typically the most 'pro EV', had a large 'anti-Elon' shift around its launch.&lt;p&gt;That said, even though it's not to my taste, I do admire that they dared to do something different and took a big gamble on it. So many vehicles, especially in the truck space, are almost indistinguishable and lack any kind of imagination. Kudos to Tesla for trying to break the mold and push the category somewhere new.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 18:08:15 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46619762</link><dc:creator>billti</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46619762</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46619762</guid></item><item><title>New comment by grayhatter in "GitHub should charge everyone $1 more per month to fund open source"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&gt; it is not okay to consider that this labor fell from the sky and is a gift, and that the people/person behind are just doing it for their own enjoyments.&lt;p&gt;I am. I enjoy making things, and it's even better when others enjoy them. Just because you have expectations that you should be compensated for everything line of code you write; doesn't make it ubiquitous, nor should your expectations be considered the default.&lt;p&gt;I'd argue If you're creating and releasing open source with the expectations of compensation, you're doing it wrong. Equally, if you expect someone creating open source owes you anything, you're also part of the problem, (and part of why people feel they deserve compensation for something that used to be considered a gift).&lt;p&gt;All that said, you should take care of your people, if you can help others; especially when you depend on them. I think you should try. Or rather, I hope you would.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 16:57:46 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46618556</link><dc:creator>grayhatter</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46618556</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46618556</guid></item><item><title>New comment by Dilettante_ in "GitHub should charge everyone $1 more per month to fund open source"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&gt;it is not okay to consider that this labor fell from the sky and is a gift, and that the people/person behind are just doing it for their own enjoyments&lt;p&gt;Yes it absolutely is. That is the exact social contract people 100% willingly enter by releasing something as Free and Open Source. They &lt;i&gt;do&lt;/i&gt; give it as a gift, in exchange for maybe the tiny bit of niche recognition that comes with it, and often times out of simple generosity. Is that really so incredible?&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 16:57:35 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46618552</link><dc:creator>Dilettante_</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46618552</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46618552</guid></item><item><title>New comment by snowwrestler in "FBI raids Washington Post reporter's home"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;To clarify why it’s aggressive: federal employees have a legal duty to secure classified information, but everyone else does not.&lt;p&gt;Reporters are not federal employees and it’s not illegal for them to have or discuss classified materials. Most of what Snowden leaked was classified, &lt;i&gt;and remains classified to this day&lt;/i&gt;, but you and I can read about it on Wikipedia. The government pursued Snowden because he was legally obligated to protect that info. They did not pursue Barton Gellman because he wasn’t.&lt;p&gt;So in this case the government is raiding the home of someone who did not commit any crime, in the hopes of getting at people who might have. I think it’s not hard to imagine how this concept could get ugly fast.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 16:01:58 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46617645</link><dc:creator>snowwrestler</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46617645</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46617645</guid></item><item><title>New comment by 827a in "SparkFun Officially Dropping AdaFruit due to CoC Violation"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;If it means anything, the first thought I had reading this post was "I wonder how SparkFun is exaggerating or misrepresenting this situation, because I can't believe Adafruit of all organizations is in the wrong here."&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 15:14:00 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46616940</link><dc:creator>827a</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46616940</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46616940</guid></item><item><title>New comment by edot in "FBI raids Washington Post reporter's home"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;"Natanson said her work had led to 1,169 new sources, “all current or former federal employees who decided to trust me with their stories”. She said she learned information “people inside government agencies weren’t supposed to tell me”, saying that the intensity of the work nearly “broke” her."&lt;p&gt;Wow. So they're going to plug her phone in to whatever cracking tech they have and pull down the names of everyone who has been helping her tell the story of the destruction of our government. The following question is "what will they do with the names of the people they pull?". I can only imagine. Horrible. Hopefully she had good OPSEC but she's a reporter, not a technologist. I bet enough mistakes were made (or enough vulnerabilities exist) that they'll be able to pull down the list.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 15:13:41 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46616937</link><dc:creator>edot</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46616937</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46616937</guid></item><item><title>New comment by ptorrone in "SparkFun Officially Dropping AdaFruit due to CoC Violation"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;hi, phil here — post on adafruit here:
&lt;a href="https://blog.adafruit.com/2026/01/12/discontinuing-the-teensy-at-adafruit/" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://blog.adafruit.com/2026/01/12/discontinuing-the-teens...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;i’ll stop back and answer anything (sparkfun will not?).&lt;p&gt;sparkfun is the exclusive maker and distributor of the closed-source teensy and informed us we will not be able to purchase the teensy. this happened after i sent an email reporting the founder, nate, for multiple harassing actions directed at limor, including behavior by him and a former employee.&lt;p&gt;instead of addressing that, they decided to kill the messenger, me, and also cut us off from teensy.&lt;p&gt;so! instead of posting weirdo "code of conduct" letters, we are doing an open-source alternative. so customers are not stranded, and this is not a supply chain emergency for us. looking forward to seeing which one delights customers more.&lt;p&gt;as much as nate wants to continue trying to damage limor’s business and adafruit by scraping our site, and now potentially not paying royalties owed after more than a decade of consistent payments, that’s nothing new. it’s a business strategy to cut others out, not a mystery or a “private drama.”&lt;p&gt;this is exactly why we do open source. when a closed product or exclusive channel is used as leverage, the correct response is to remove the leverage.&lt;p&gt;sparkfun chose to publish a vague public accusation. once you do that, speculation is inevitable.&lt;p&gt;ask away!&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 14:59:46 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46616775</link><dc:creator>ptorrone</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46616775</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46616775</guid></item><item><title>New comment by GeertB in "There's a ridiculous amount of tech in a disposable vape"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;For these devices the microcontroller needs to be super cheap. Microcontrollers like the Puya PY32 Series (e.g., PY32C642, PY32F002/F030) can cost in the $0.02 - $0.05 range for the kind of many-million volumes applicable for disposable vapes. These are 32-bit ARM Cortex M0 MCUs, running at a 24 MHz clock or similar, some with 24 KB of ROM and maybe 3 KB of RAM!&lt;p&gt;To put into context: this is 3x the ROM/RAM of the ZX81 home computer of the early 1980s. The ARM M0 processor does full 32-bit multiplication in hardware, versus the Z80 that doesn't even offer an 8-bit multiply instruction. If we look at some BASIC code doing soft-float computation, as was most common at the time, the execution speed is about 3 orders of magnitude faster, while the cost of the processor is 2 - 3 orders of magnitudes less. What an amazing time we live in!&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 05:01:41 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46612530</link><dc:creator>GeertB</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46612530</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46612530</guid></item><item><title>New comment by jaggederest in "There's a ridiculous amount of tech in a disposable vape"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Why stop there? I think more or less every non-durable product manufacturer (say, lifespan less than 5 years) should be required to take the product back at end of life and dispose of it properly. Trash is an enormous externality. I'm talking about plastic clamshells, container lids, "disposable" storage containers, the lot.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 03:47:08 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46612087</link><dc:creator>jaggederest</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46612087</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46612087</guid></item><item><title>New comment by smashed in "There's a ridiculous amount of tech in a disposable vape"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Many countries have deposits for single use bottles/cans but an electronic device with a lipo battery is seen as perfectly fine to throw away.&lt;p&gt;These things should have 100 times the deposit amount of a can of soda with mandatory requirements for retailers to take the 'empties' back.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 03:41:59 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46612044</link><dc:creator>smashed</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46612044</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46612044</guid></item><item><title>New comment by mattmaroon in "Let's be honest, Generative AI isn't going all that well"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile, my cofounder is rewriting code we spent millions of salary on in the past by himself in a few weeks.&lt;p&gt;I myself am saving a small fortune on design and photography and getting better results while doing it.&lt;p&gt;If this is not all that well I can’t wait until we get to mediocre!&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 22:54:31 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46609559</link><dc:creator>mattmaroon</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46609559</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46609559</guid></item><item><title>New comment by pyrale in "No management needed: anti-patterns in early-stage engineering teams"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&gt;  I know several top 1% engineers in the Valley who disengage from recruiting processes when 996 or something similar is mentioned.&lt;p&gt;A few years back, on this board, 996 was something people made fun of when it was reported that some Chinese companies did it [1].&lt;p&gt;And now, the strongest claim this blog can make is that &lt;i&gt;some&lt;/i&gt; engineers in the US would disengage from recruiting? That the issue with working on saturdays is daily standup? What happened in these years for such a change to happen?!&lt;p&gt;[1]: &lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=19507620"&gt;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=19507620&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 21:31:14 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46608421</link><dc:creator>pyrale</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46608421</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46608421</guid></item><item><title>New comment by burnto in "No management needed: anti-patterns in early-stage engineering teams"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&gt; Motivation is a hired trait. The only place where managers motivate people is in management books&lt;p&gt;Initial motivation is the hired trait. It’s very easy to demotivate people. The trick is to not do that.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 21:26:13 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46608329</link><dc:creator>burnto</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46608329</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46608329</guid></item><item><title>New comment by drittich in "AI generated music barred from Bandcamp"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Also a musician and I don't think it's that amusing. IMO this isn't an "AI can't be art" discussion. It's about the fact that AI can be used to extract value from other artists' work without consent, and then out-compete them on volume by flooding the marketplace.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 19:55:19 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46606880</link><dc:creator>drittich</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46606880</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46606880</guid></item><item><title>New comment by olivierestsage in "AI generated music barred from Bandcamp"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Funny to see this right now. Spotify's promotion of AI music bothered me so much that it has actually pushed me to Bandcamp and the practice of buying music again. It's really fun to build a collection knowing you're supporting the artists, download FLAC files, organize your little "collection" page ... Feels like a renaissance in my relationship with music, the most fun I've had since what.cd. Anyway, love this stance they're taking.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 18:57:41 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46605925</link><dc:creator>olivierestsage</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46605925</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46605925</guid></item><item><title>New comment by stetrain in "Scott Adams has died"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I think it’s interesting how many responses to this comment seem to have interpreted it fairly differently to my own reading.&lt;p&gt;There are many responding about “ignoring racism,” “whitewashing,” or the importance of calling out bigotry.&lt;p&gt;I’m not sure how that follows from a comment that literally calls out the racism and describes it as “unambiguous.”&lt;p&gt;Striving to “avoid the ugliness” in your own life does not mean ignoring it or refusing to call it out.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 18:56:48 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46605904</link><dc:creator>stetrain</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46605904</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46605904</guid></item><item><title>New comment by superfrank in "Influencers and OnlyFans models are dominating U.S. O-1 visa requests"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;It's funny, early on it says&lt;p&gt;&gt; The O-1 category includes the O-1A, which is designated for individuals with extraordinary ability in the sciences, education, business or athletics and the O-1B, reserved for those with “extraordinary ability or achievement”.&lt;p&gt;Then later it says&lt;p&gt;&gt; The O-1B visa, once reserved for Hollywood titans and superstar musicians, has evolved over the years.&lt;p&gt;I understand those two aren't necessarily contradictory, but the wording of the first sentence paints a very different mental picture than the second one (at least it did for me), especially since they throw in the O-1A and then almost exclusively talk about people applying for the O-1B after that.&lt;p&gt;Personally, I don't want the US choosing to give visas to influencers over scientists, but if this visa was already being heavily used to bring in actors, musicians, and athletes I don't see what the hubbub is about. I don't use TikTok or OnlyFans and I don't find e-sports entertaining, but I have a hard time arguing that a screen actor, Victoria's Secret model, or soccer player should be worthy of a visa and a social media star, OnlyFans model, or a professional Counter Strike player shouldn't is not. It's all just entertainment.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 17:23:48 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46604251</link><dc:creator>superfrank</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46604251</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46604251</guid></item><item><title>New comment by anonu in "Scott Adams has died"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;One thing I appreciated from Scott was his "compounded skills" concept. He explained it: he wasn't a very good writer or illustrator. But he combined those skills with some humorous business insights to make Dilbert.&lt;p&gt;That concept of merging skills stuck with me.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 17:13:29 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46604057</link><dc:creator>anonu</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46604057</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46604057</guid></item><item><title>New comment by rsynnott in "Scott Adams has died"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I read one of his books once, written in the 90s or so. It included the idea that affirmations could literally change reality ("law of attraction"), and an _alternative theory of gravity_. At the time, I thought that these were probably attempts at jokes that didn't land very well, but... Once you believe one thing which is totally outside the pale, it is often very easy to start believing others.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 17:10:07 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46603991</link><dc:creator>rsynnott</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46603991</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46603991</guid></item><item><title>New comment by DamnInteresting in "Scott Adams has died"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Scott Adams did me a considerable and unsolicited kindness almost 20 years ago, back in 2007. One day my site traffic logs showed an unexpected uptick in traffic, and recent referrals overwhelmingly pointed to his blog. Of course I recognized him from Dilbert fame, both the comic strip and &lt;i&gt;The Dilbert Principle&lt;/i&gt;.&lt;p&gt;I sent him a thank you email for the link, and he replied graciously. This began a conversation where he referred me to his literary agent, and this ultimately led to a real-world, dead-tree-and-ink book publishing deal[1]. He even provided a nice blurb for the book cover.&lt;p&gt;I can't say that I agreed a lot with the person Scott Adams later became--I only knew him vaguely, from a distance. But he brought humor into many people's lives for a lot of years, and he was generous to me when he didn't have to be. Today I'll just think about the good times.&lt;p&gt;[1] &lt;a href="https://www.damninteresting.com/the-damn-interesting-book/" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://www.damninteresting.com/the-damn-interesting-book/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;Edit: I found the relevant Dilbert Blog link via the Wayback Machine: &lt;a href="https://web.archive.org/web/20071011024008/http://dilbertblog.typepad.com/the_dilbert_blog/2007/10/the-single-most.html" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://web.archive.org/web/20071011024008/http://dilbertblo...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 17:00:37 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46603793</link><dc:creator>DamnInteresting</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46603793</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46603793</guid></item><item><title>New comment by jchallis in "Scott Adams has died"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Scott Adams died today. I want to acknowledge something complicated.&lt;p&gt;He always felt culturally like family to me. His peaks—the biting humor about corporate absurdity, the writing on systems thinking and compounding habits, the clarity about the gap between what organizations say and what they do—unquestionably made me healthier, happier, and wealthier. If you worked in tech in the 90s and 2000s, Dilbert was a shared language for everything broken about corporate life.&lt;p&gt;His views, always unapologetic, became more strident over time and pushed everyone away. That also felt like family.&lt;p&gt;You don’t choose family, and you don’t get to edit out the parts that shaped you before you understood what was happening. The racism and the provocations were always there, maybe, just quieter. The 2023 comments that ended Dilbert’s newspaper run were unambiguous.&lt;p&gt;For Scott, like family, I’m a better person for the contribution. I hope I can represent the good things: the humor, the clarity of thought, the compounding good habits with health and money. I can avoid the ugliness—the racism, the grievance, the need to be right at any cost.&lt;p&gt;Taking inventory is harder than eulogizing or denouncing. But it’s more honest.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 16:53:32 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46603652</link><dc:creator>jchallis</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46603652</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46603652</guid></item><item><title>New comment by mrweasel in "Scott Adams has died"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I loved Dilbert, having worked for more than one Dilbert-like company the humor frequently resonated with me.&lt;p&gt;How or why Scott Adams went completely of the rails is perhaps something we'll sadly never understand. Was this opinions he'd always had, but suppressed, did he somehow become radicalized or was it perhaps medically induced, e.g. a stroke or something. It was incredibly sad to see him throw away his life's work and go down a path most of us at least hadn't foreseen and die having alienated his fans.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 16:50:11 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46603593</link><dc:creator>mrweasel</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46603593</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46603593</guid></item><item><title>New comment by Kapura in "The U.S. Government Just Followed Through on Its Ban of DJI Drones"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Seeing how drone warfare has become the new hot front in 21st century conflicts like Ukraine, it's hard not to speculate on the implications of this as political unrest continues to rise in the U.S.&lt;p&gt;It's no secret that the current U.S. regime views a sizeable portion of its own civilian citizens as enemy combatants. They are already shooting people in the face and not even putting up a pretense of acting shocked at the act. Historically, it is easier to win elections than revolutions; limiting access to game-changing technology puts the power advantage even more firmly in the corner of the regime.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 16:27:22 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46603189</link><dc:creator>Kapura</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46603189</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46603189</guid></item><item><title>New comment by ryandvm in "Scott Adams has died"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;The entire arc of Scott Adams is a cautionary tale.&lt;p&gt;To go from a brilliant satirist to becoming terminally online and just completely falling off the far right cliffs of insanity is incredibly sad. And unfortunately, this is plight is not uncommon. It is incredibly dangerous to make politics part of your identity and then just absolutely bathe yourself in a political media echo chamber.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 15:41:42 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46602419</link><dc:creator>ryandvm</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46602419</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46602419</guid></item><item><title>New comment by jasoneckert in "Apple Creator Studio"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;The most important benefits in my opinion are choice and price - people like me who prefer to buy software outright can still do so at a reasonable cost, while others who opt for a subscription can also do so (again, at a reasonable cost).&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 14:30:23 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46601387</link><dc:creator>jasoneckert</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46601387</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46601387</guid></item><item><title>New comment by jasongill in "Apple Creator Studio"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;It's $12.99/mo or $129/yr for a subscription that includes Final Cut Pro, Logic Pro, Pixelmator Pro, Motion, Compressor, MainStage, Keynote, Pages, and Numbers&lt;p&gt;Educational discount with verification required drops the price to $2.99/mo / $29.99/yr.&lt;p&gt;The regular-price subscription includes family sharing, education price does not.&lt;p&gt;One-time purchase versions remain available: Final Cut Pro ($299.99), Logic Pro ($199.99), Pixelmator Pro ($49.99), Motion ($49.99), Compressor ($49.99), and MainStage ($29.99).&lt;p&gt;Comes out January 28th&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 14:21:06 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46601240</link><dc:creator>jasongill</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46601240</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46601240</guid></item></channel></rss>