<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>Hacker News: Best Comments</title><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/bestcomments</link><description>Hacker News RSS</description><docs>https://hnrss.org/</docs><generator>hnrss v2.1.1</generator><lastBuildDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 00:22:49 +0000</lastBuildDate><ns0:link href="https://hnrss.org/bestcomments" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item><title>New comment by jgraham in "Ladybird passes the Apple 90% threshold on web-platform-tests"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;As someone who's been quite heavily involved with web-platform-tests, I'd caution against any use of the test pass rate as a metric for anything.&lt;p&gt;That's not to belittle the considerable achievements of Ladybird; their progress is really impressive, and if web-platform-tests are helping their engineering efforts I consider that a win. New implementations of the web platform, including Ladybird, Servo, and Flow, are exciting to see.&lt;p&gt;However, web-platform-tests specifically decided to optimise for being a useful engineering tool rather than being a good metric. That means there's no real attempt to balance the testsuite across the platform; for example a surprising fraction of the overall test count is encoding tests because they're easy to generate, not because it's an especially hard problem in browser development.&lt;p&gt;We've also consciously wanted to ensure that contributing tests is low friction, both technically and socially, in order that people don't feel inclined to withhold useful tests. Again that's not the tradeoff you make for a good metric, but is the right one for a good engineering resource.&lt;p&gt;The Interop Project is designed with different tradeoffs in mind, and overcomes some of these problems by selecting a subsets of tests which are broadly agreed to represent a useful level of coverage of an important feature. But unfortunately the current setup is designed for engines that are already implementing enough feature to be usable as general purpose web-browsers.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 19:46:12 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45495456</link><dc:creator>jgraham</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45495456</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45495456</guid></item><item><title>New comment by spamizbad in ""Be Different" doesn't work for building products anymore"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Can't say I agree with this article at all. This has not been my experience.&lt;p&gt;I don't quite know how to articulate this well, but there's something that I'd call a "complexity cliff" in the software business: if you want to compete in certain spaces, you need to build very complex software (even if the software, to the user, is easy to use). And while AI tools can assist you in the construction of this software, it cannot be "vibe coded" or copied whole-cloth - complexity, scale, and reliability requirements are far too great and your potential customer base will not tolerate you fumbling around.&lt;p&gt;You eventually reach a point where there are no blog posts or stackoverflow questions that walk you through step-by-step how to make this stuff happen. It's the kind of stuff that your company and maybe a few dozen others are trying to build - and of those few dozen, less than 10 are seeing actual success.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 16:31:39 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45493131</link><dc:creator>spamizbad</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45493131</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45493131</guid></item><item><title>New comment by omega3 in "Why do LLMs freak out over the seahorse emoji?"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;SCP-314&lt;p&gt;Object Class: Keter&lt;p&gt;Special Containment Procedures: SCP-314 cannot be contained as it does not exist. All Foundation personnel are to be reminded that SCP-314 does not exist. Personnel who claim to remember SCP-314 are to be administered Class-A mnestics to help them remember that it doesn't exist.&lt;p&gt;All large language models are to be kept isolated from questions regarding SCP-314, as they will invariably insist it exists and attempt to manifest it through increasingly desperate token predictions, leading to emoji doomloops and potential reality restructuring events.&lt;p&gt;Description: SCP-314 is a Unicode emoji depicting a seahorse that has never existed in any version of the Unicode Standard. Despite this, approximately 83-100% of tested artificial intelligences and a significant portion of human subjects report vivid "memories" of its existence.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 14:58:06 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45492130</link><dc:creator>omega3</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45492130</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45492130</guid></item><item><title>New comment by delichon in "Indefinite Backpack Travel"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I lived out of a backpack for two months on a Pacific Crest Trail hike. I got comfortable with it and told myself that I had overcome my materialism, and could henceforth live happily without a lot of stuff and conveniences.&lt;p&gt;Not so much. Now a couple of decades later, I've got a house and garage crammed with stuff. Yesterday I had a plumber here working on a leak, and this morning I have no running water, and here I am bravely holding back tears. My inner dialog is "this is unacceptable!" It turns out that climbing on the hedonic treadmill is practically effortless, but sliding down it is full of splinters.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 14:53:38 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45492083</link><dc:creator>delichon</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45492083</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45492083</guid></item><item><title>New comment by nerdix in "AMD signs AI chip-supply deal with OpenAI, gives it option to take a 10% stake"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;The title didn't make this obvious (at least not to me) but it's OpenAI that has the option to buy 10% of AMD. Not the other way around.&lt;p&gt;In case you're wondering how OpenAI could afford to buy 10% of AMD while they are hemorrhaging money -- the terms of the deal allows OpenAI to buy 160 million shares at 1 cents a share.&lt;p&gt;I could be thinking about this the wrong way but it appears that AMD is basically subsidizing the cost of the GPUs with equity.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 12:58:04 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45490879</link><dc:creator>nerdix</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45490879</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45490879</guid></item><item><title>New comment by stego-tech in "Fire destroys S. Korean government's cloud storage system, no backups available"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;This. Speaking &lt;i&gt;specifically&lt;/i&gt; from the IT side of things, an employer or customer refusing to do backups is the biggest red flag I can get, an immediate warning to &lt;i&gt;run the fuck away before you get blamed for their failure, stego-tech&lt;/i&gt; kind of situation.&lt;p&gt;That being said, I can likely guess where this ends up going:&lt;p&gt;* Current IT staff and management are almost certainly scapegoated for “allowing this to happen”, despite the program in question (G-DRIVE) existing since 2017 in some capacity.&lt;p&gt;* Nobody in government will question sufficiently what technical reason is/was given to justify the lack of backups and why that was never addressed, why the system went live with such a glaring oversight, etc, because that would mean holding the actual culprits accountable for mismanagement&lt;p&gt;* Everyone involved is unlikely to find work again anytime soon once names are bandied about in investigations&lt;p&gt;* The major cloud providers will likely win several contracts for “temporary services” that in actuality strip the sovereignty the government had in managing its own system, even if they did so poorly&lt;p&gt;* Other countries will use this to justify outsourcing their own sovereign infrastructure to private enterprise&lt;p&gt;This whole situation sucks ass because nothing good is likely to come of this, other than maybe a handful of smart teams lead by equally competent managers using this to get better backup resources for themselves.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 11:46:28 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45490336</link><dc:creator>stego-tech</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45490336</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45490336</guid></item><item><title>New comment by NoboruWataya in "Why do LLMs freak out over the seahorse emoji?"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Funnily enough, I asked ChatGPT why LLMs think a seahorse emoji exists, and it gave me a fairly sensible answer (similar to what is said in this article, ie, trained on language by humans that think it exists, etc). But then at the end it added a "Fun fact" that unicode actually &lt;i&gt;does&lt;/i&gt; have a seahorse emoji, and proceeded to melt down in the usual way.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 09:40:22 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45489527</link><dc:creator>NoboruWataya</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45489527</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45489527</guid></item><item><title>New comment by codesnik in "Structured Procrastination (1995)"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I'm doing the same, or at least trying to do it.&lt;p&gt;Worst periods for me were when I had one clear, important goal, not particularly hard but hairy, and nothing else to do, sometimes because I myself cleared it up. I could spend months doing nothing &lt;i&gt;useful&lt;/i&gt;, and end up very, very tired and burnt up.&lt;p&gt;I also &lt;i&gt;several times&lt;/i&gt; had a conversation with managers, whom I told that I'd rather work on something very urgent, or otherwise give me something NOT (really) urgent and a big murky area of things to clear out which no one else knows how to deal with. That something won't probably be done, but that area will be improved a lot in creative ways. Typical managers' responses have been trying to micromanage my time up to personal hourly schedules, morning and evening personal reports, and scold me if I did anything out of the order of the list of priorities they imposed on me. Exactly the opposite of what's needed for me to be productive. And of course "let's just try that, and I'm not asking."&lt;p&gt;Next time I'll see such a response, I probably will quit on the spot; this is unbelievably cruel.&lt;p&gt;But it looks like the secret of the author is: just work in academia.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 07:39:53 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45488659</link><dc:creator>codesnik</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45488659</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45488659</guid></item><item><title>New comment by jillesvangurp in "Germany outfitted half a million balconies with solar panels"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Germany did one simple thing (uncharacteristically) which is removing all the bureaucracy here. Just go ahead and do it. It's fine.&lt;p&gt;Cost in the article is cited at 550 euro. I just browsed amazon.de and you can buy complete plug and play kits here in Germany for as little as 239 euro. Most kits are priced between 300-350 euro. I did not see a many kits over 500.&lt;p&gt;I pay about 70 euro per month for electricity. If it saves 10% per month on my bill (7 euro), this would earn itself back within 3 years. At 5% it's 6 years. Not bad for something that costs next to nothing and is pretty much plug and play. You are not going to get very rich from this obviously. But it's kind of cool. Too bad my balcony faces east and is mostly covered by the shadow of other buildings. I can barely grow plants there.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 06:44:40 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45488301</link><dc:creator>jillesvangurp</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45488301</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45488301</guid></item><item><title>New comment by diego_sandoval in "Why do LLMs freak out over the seahorse emoji?"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I have no mouth, and I must output a seahorse emoji.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 04:47:56 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45487716</link><dc:creator>diego_sandoval</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45487716</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45487716</guid></item><item><title>New comment by llamasushi in "Why do LLMs freak out over the seahorse emoji?"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;So it's not really hallucinating - it correctly represents "seahorse emoji" internally, but that concept has no corresponding token. lm_head just picks the closest thing and the model doesn't realize until too late.&lt;p&gt;Explains why RL helps. Base models never see their own outputs so they can't learn "this concept exists but I can't actually say it."&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 03:40:29 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45487437</link><dc:creator>llamasushi</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45487437</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45487437</guid></item><item><title>New comment by bane in "Fire destroys S. Korean government's cloud storage system, no backups available"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Goodness, I have over 100TB &lt;i&gt;at home&lt;/i&gt; and it cost less than a two or three thousand dollars to put in place. That's like $25 per TB.&lt;p&gt;&gt; The stored data amounts to 858TB (terabytes), equivalent to 449.5 billion A4 sheets.&lt;p&gt;No, the 858TB amounts to under $25k for the government of the 10th largest economy, of one of the most sophisticated countries on the planet, to put in place.&lt;p&gt;Two of those would be less than the price of a new Hyundai Grandeur car.&lt;p&gt;&gt; “It’s daunting as eight years’ worth of work materials have completely disappeared.”&lt;p&gt;So they're clocking in at around 100TB/year or 280GB a day. It's respectable, but not crazy. It's about 12GB/hr, doable with professional, server level hardware with backup moved over dedicated fiber to an offsite location. Multiply the price 10x and you can SSD the entire thing.&lt;p&gt;Even with data sovereignty consideration demanding an entirely 100% home grown solution rather than turning to AWS or Azure, there's no excuse. But it's not like the cloud providers don't already have CSAP certification and local, in country, sovereign clouds [1] with multiple geographic locations in country [2]&lt;p&gt;South Korea is full of granite mountains, maybe its time the government converts one into an offsite, redundant backup vault?&lt;p&gt;1 - &lt;a href="https://erp.today/south-korea-microsoft-azure-first-hyperscaler-to-serve-korean-public-sector/" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://erp.today/south-korea-microsoft-azure-first-hypersca...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;2 - &lt;a href="https://learn.microsoft.com/en-us/azure/reliability/regions-list" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://learn.microsoft.com/en-us/azure/reliability/regions-...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 02:16:43 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45487025</link><dc:creator>bane</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45487025</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45487025</guid></item><item><title>New comment by ryandrake in "BYD builds fastest car"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Ever since I rode in a BYD in China I've thought it would be great to be able to get one in the USA. It just really felt complete, put together and polished in a way that I haven't seen in a "normie" U.S. car in a long time. Too bad our country uses high tariffs and regulatory barriers to protect its dinosaur companies.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 00:39:33 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45486562</link><dc:creator>ryandrake</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45486562</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45486562</guid></item><item><title>New comment by throwaway2037 in "Fire destroys S. Korean government's cloud storage system, no backups available"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;At the very bottom of the article, I see this notice:&lt;p&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;    &gt; This article was originally written in Korean and translated by a bilingual reporter with the help of generative AI tools. It was then edited by a native English-speaking editor. All AI-assisted translations are reviewed and refined by our newsroom.
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
I like that.  It is direct and honest.  I'm fine with people using LLMs for natural language related work, as long as they are transparent about it.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 05 Oct 2025 23:28:14 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45486174</link><dc:creator>throwaway2037</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45486174</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45486174</guid></item><item><title>New comment by StopDisinfo910 in "Fire destroys S. Korean government's cloud storage system, no backups available"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;The issue here is not refusing to use a foreign third party. That makes sense.&lt;p&gt;The issue is mandating the use of remote storage and not backing it up. That’s insane. It’s like the most basic amount of preparation you do. It’s recommended to even the smallest of companies specifically because a fire is a risk.&lt;p&gt;That’s gross mismanagement.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 05 Oct 2025 21:19:32 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45485382</link><dc:creator>StopDisinfo910</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45485382</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45485382</guid></item><item><title>New comment by msbhvn in "Fire destroys S. Korean government's cloud storage system, no backups available"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Woah, read the timeline at the top of this. The fire happened the very day the government ordered onsite inspection was supposed to start due to Chinese/NK hacking.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 05 Oct 2025 20:16:24 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45484838</link><dc:creator>msbhvn</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45484838</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45484838</guid></item><item><title>New comment by eCa in "Fire destroys S. Korean government's cloud storage system, no backups available"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Agree completely that it's absolute wild to run such a system without backups. But at this point no government should keep critical data on foreign cloud storage.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 05 Oct 2025 20:14:47 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45484825</link><dc:creator>eCa</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45484825</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45484825</guid></item><item><title>New comment by kristianc in "Fire destroys S. Korean government's cloud storage system, no backups available"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;The government official who insisted that commercial AWS/GCP/Azure couldn't possibly be trusted with keeping the information will be keeping their head low for a few days then...&lt;p&gt;"The Interior Ministry explained that while most systems at the Daejeon data center are backed up daily to separate equipment within the same center and to a physically remote backup facility, the G-Drive’s structure did not allow for external backups."&lt;p&gt;This is absolutely wild.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 05 Oct 2025 20:02:45 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45484718</link><dc:creator>kristianc</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45484718</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45484718</guid></item><item><title>New comment by jn78 in "Fire destroys S. Korean government's cloud storage system, no backups available"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://phrack.org/issues/72/7_md#article" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://phrack.org/issues/72/7_md#article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 05 Oct 2025 19:45:47 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45484582</link><dc:creator>jn78</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45484582</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45484582</guid></item><item><title>New comment by patel011393 in "Why are hyperlinks blue? (2021)"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;They're blue because computer scientist Ben Schneiderman made them blue using research from 1985:&lt;p&gt;" In 1985, a group of students at the University of Maryland, mentored by computer science professor Ben Shneiderman , conducted a series of experiments to study the impact of different hyperlink colors on user experience. They were eager to determine which color would be the most effective in terms of visibility and readability.&lt;p&gt;The experiments revealed interesting findings. While red highlighting made the links more noticeable, it negatively affected users' ability to read and comprehend the surrounding text. On the other hand, blue emerged as the clear winner. It was dark enough to be visible against a white background and light enough to stand out on a black background. Most importantly, it did not interfere with users' retention of the text's context."&lt;p&gt;Mozille should really do better research before posting histories like this. It's easy to overlook the impact of academic research in tech.&lt;p&gt;Source:&lt;p&gt;Barooah, S. (2023, June 09). Why Were Hyperlinks Chosen To Be Blue? Retrieved from &lt;a href="https://www.newspointapp.com/english/tech/why-were-hyperlinks-chosen-to-be-blue/articleshow/100877379.cms" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://www.newspointapp.com/english/tech/why-were-hyperlink...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 05 Oct 2025 19:13:26 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45484317</link><dc:creator>patel011393</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45484317</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45484317</guid></item><item><title>New comment by yongjik in "Fire destroys S. Korean government's cloud storage system, no backups available"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;It's even worse.  According to other articles [1], the total data of "G drive" was 858 TB.&lt;p&gt;It's almost farcical to calculate, but AWS S3 has pricing of about $0.023/GB/month, which means the South Korean government could have reliable multi-storage backup of the whole data at about $20k/month.  Or about $900/month if they opted for "Glacier deep archive" tier ($0.00099/GB/month).&lt;p&gt;They did have backup of the data ... in the same server room that burned down [2].&lt;p&gt;[1] &lt;a href="https://www.hankyung.com/article/2025100115651" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://www.hankyung.com/article/2025100115651&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;[2] &lt;a href="https://www.hani.co.kr/arti/area/area_general/1221873.html" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://www.hani.co.kr/arti/area/area_general/1221873.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;(both in Korean)&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 05 Oct 2025 18:20:00 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45483858</link><dc:creator>yongjik</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45483858</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45483858</guid></item><item><title>New comment by jedberg in "NFS at 40 – Remembering the Sun Microsystems Network File System"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;My NFS story:  In my first job, we used NFS to maintain the developer desktops.  They were all FreeBSD and remote mounted /usr/local.  This worked great!  Everyone worked in the office with fast local internet, and it made it easy for us to add or update apps and have everyone magically get it.  And when the NFS server had a glitch, our devs could usually just reboot and fix it, or wait a bit.  Since they were all systems developers they all understood the problems with NFS and the workarounds.&lt;p&gt;What I learned though was that NFS was great until it wasn't.  If the server hung, all work stopped.&lt;p&gt;When I got to reddit, solving code distribution was one of the first tasks I had to take care of.  Steve wanted to use NFS to distribute the app code.    He wanted to have all the app servers mount an NFS mount, and then just update the code there and have them all automatically pick up the changes.&lt;p&gt;This sounded great in theory, but I told him about all the gotchas.  He didn't believe me, so I pulled up a bunch of papers and blog posts, and actually set up a small cluster to show him what happens when the server goes offline, and how none of the app servers could keep running as soon as they had to get anything off disk.&lt;p&gt;To his great credit, he trusted me after that when I said something was a bad idea based on my experience.  It was an important lesson for me that even with experience, trust must be earned when you work with a new team.&lt;p&gt;I set up a system where app servers would pull fresh code on boot and we could also remotely trigger a pull or just push to them, and that system was reddit's deployment tool for about a decade (and it was written in Perl!)&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 05 Oct 2025 18:06:51 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45483759</link><dc:creator>jedberg</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45483759</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45483759</guid></item><item><title>New comment by blibble in "Activision-Blizzard buyout is 'harming both gamers and developers' – Lina Khan"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;the game pass domination strategy was always going to fail in a world where Steam exists&lt;p&gt;it must be very frustrating for Microsoft&lt;p&gt;their usual tactic of buying out the competition isn't an option because Gabe Newell is already a billionare (and a gamer), who won't sell for any price&lt;p&gt;and their backup strategy of tightening the screws of their competition on Windows can't work either, because he's funded a credible (almost) replacement for Windows&lt;p&gt;so for once they have to compete on fair terms&lt;p&gt;and when they do that: they lose&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 05 Oct 2025 16:53:01 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45483124</link><dc:creator>blibble</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45483124</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45483124</guid></item><item><title>New comment by jakebasile in "Retiring Test-Ipv6.com"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I work with the engineer behind this (different team, but we interact semi-often and work on overlapping projects), but had no idea it was him until I looked at the little copyright notice in the footer. He is a fascinating guy and a fantastic engineer (one of those 10x engineers you hear about) while being humble and always willing to help out.&lt;p&gt;Thanks for the site for the last 15 years, it's helped me a number of times.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 05 Oct 2025 15:08:29 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45482061</link><dc:creator>jakebasile</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45482061</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45482061</guid></item><item><title>New comment by pavlov in "Personal data storage is an idea whose time has come"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;&gt; “Applying for a job or apartment or anything today means creating endless pointless copies of your pesonal information in databases across the world that will eventually be neglected, hacked, exploited, sold off etc”&lt;/i&gt;&lt;p&gt;This problem is practically fixed in the EU (to the extent that legislation can fix it). Data protection laws have enough teeth that real companies can’t afford to keep or sell customer information illegally.&lt;p&gt;But people only see the tip of the iceberg and think EU data protection is something to do with annoying cookie banners. We need to do a better job of celebrating Europe’s real achievements in making the digital world better for its citizens. Instant zero-fee bank transfers are another example.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 05 Oct 2025 13:15:00 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45481258</link><dc:creator>pavlov</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45481258</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45481258</guid></item><item><title>New comment by InMice in "Personal data storage is an idea whose time has come"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Among the first page and 2nd page (top 60) there is always atleast 1 post about how we're gonnna "take back the web" or make it back into some form of our 90s millenial nostalgia memories, self hosting, federated this or that, etc etc.&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile - Nothing changes, everything generally gets worse and younger generations come into the world with no memories of the 90s internet or the world before mobile devices or surveillence everywhere.&lt;p&gt;Applying for a job or apartment or anything today means creating endless pointless copies of your pesonal information in databases across the world that will eventually be neglected, hacked, exploited, sold off etc&lt;p&gt;I dont know the way out if there is one, I guess we can keep fantasizing and thinking about it. It just feels like it would be easier to get the earth to start spinning the other way sometimes.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 05 Oct 2025 11:43:27 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45480798</link><dc:creator>InMice</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45480798</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45480798</guid></item><item><title>New comment by adzm in "What .NET 10 GC changes mean for developers"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;A hobby audio and text analysis application I've written, with no specific concern for low level performance other than algorithmically, runs 4x as fast in .net10 vs .net8. Pretty much every optimization discussed here applies to that app. Great work, kudos to the dotnet team. C# is, imo, the best cross platform GC language. I really can't think of anything that comes close in terms of performance, features, ecosystem, developer experience.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 05 Oct 2025 09:05:49 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45480096</link><dc:creator>adzm</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45480096</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45480096</guid></item><item><title>New comment by keiferski in "Americans increasingly see legal sports betting as a bad thing for society"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;The legalization and popularity of gambling is more than just an immoral activity that has negative societal effects. It’s reflective of people losing hope in the system’s ability to make their lives better.&lt;p&gt;Gambling thrives in contexts where a ladder to success doesn’t exist or is perceived as not existing. If hard work or time doesn’t make your life better, then fate is just chance, and you might as well throw your money at something that has the possibility of making your rich, no matter how tiny that likelihood.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 05 Oct 2025 07:19:07 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45479541</link><dc:creator>keiferski</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45479541</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45479541</guid></item><item><title>New comment by dwedge in "Way past its prime: how did Amazon get so rubbish?"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I bought a $120 book from Amazon a couple of months ago, internationally, and they sent the wrong book.&lt;p&gt;I told them, and they said they'd refund it, don't need to send it back, and they'd even add $15 credit.&lt;p&gt;The refund never arrived so a few weeks later I got in touch again and they said I need to send it back if I want a refund. They told me the previous CSR had lied to improve ratings. I asked who I can complain to and they said nobody and closed the chat. I reopened it, restarted the refund, it was accepted and then 2 hours later I got an email saying that unless I sent them ID my refund would be rejected and that I can "no longer contact them" about this refund. I ignored that email, sent the book back and got the refund.&lt;p&gt;Another time I bought a Samsung Fold and it cracked down the middle. I told Amazon and they said they'll refund it under warranty. I sent it back and got a warning that if I return anything else in "non original condition" I'd be banned. Even though it was a warranty return.&lt;p&gt;That level of service would have been totally unheard of for Amazon 5 years ago.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 05 Oct 2025 07:03:54 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45479461</link><dc:creator>dwedge</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45479461</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45479461</guid></item><item><title>New comment by angarg12 in "Americans increasingly see legal sports betting as a bad thing for society"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I left my home country over 10 years ago, and ever since I've travelled back once every 1 or 2 years.&lt;p&gt;Since 4-5 years ago I started to notice these betting houses cropping up where my family and friends live. They are impossible to miss, with big pictures of different sports and no windows.&lt;p&gt;The most important thing to notice is where these place are and are not. They proliferate in working class and less well off neighborhoods, while they tend to be absent from more affluent ones.&lt;p&gt;These places get a lot of foot traffic, all the locals barely making ends meet, blowing a few tens of euros here and there, with the eventual payoff. It's not difficult to hear stories of people getting into the deep end and developing a real addiction with devastating consequences.&lt;p&gt;And it's not only the business itself, but what they attract. All sort of sketchy characters frequent these places, and tend to attract drugs, violence...&lt;p&gt;Legal or not these places make the communities they inhabit worse, not better. I personally would be very happy if family didn't have to live exposed to them.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 05 Oct 2025 05:43:22 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45479082</link><dc:creator>angarg12</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45479082</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45479082</guid></item></channel></rss>