<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>Hacker News: Best Comments</title><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/bestcomments</link><description>Hacker News RSS</description><docs>https://hnrss.org/</docs><generator>hnrss v2.1.1</generator><lastBuildDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 00:19:36 +0000</lastBuildDate><ns0:link href="https://hnrss.org/bestcomments" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item><title>New comment by shevy-java in "FBI tries to unmask owner of archive.is"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;We need to preserve data. The FBI is trying to kill data.&lt;p&gt;We can not allow the FBI to work for Evil here. I actually think there should be a human right to data. With that I mean, primarily, knowledge, not to data about a single human being as such (e. g. "doxxing" or any such crap - I mean knowledge).&lt;p&gt;Knowledge itself should become a human right. I understand that the current law is very favourable to mega-corporations milking mankind dry, but the law should also be changed. (I am not anti-business per se, mind you - I just think the law should not become a tool to contain human rights, including access to knowledge and information at all times.)&lt;p&gt;Wikipedia is somewhat ok, but it also misses a TON of stuff, and unfortunately it only has one primary view, whereas many things need some explanation before one can understand it. When I read up on a (to me) new topic, I try to focus on simple things and master these first. Some wikipedia articles are so complicated that even after staring at them for several minutes, and reading it, I still haven't the slightest clue what this is about. This is also a problem of wikipedia - as so many different people write things, it is sometimes super-hard to understand what wikipedia is trying to convey here.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2025 16:41:03 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45837144</link><dc:creator>shevy-java</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45837144</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45837144</guid></item><item><title>New comment by willvarfar in "Australia has so much solar that it's offering everyone free electricity"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Ignoring the politics, we have to say that China has done the world collectively as a whole a major service in strategically developing and mass producing super cheap solar panels.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2025 16:15:33 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45836788</link><dc:creator>willvarfar</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45836788</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45836788</guid></item><item><title>New comment by everdrive in "The trust collapse: Infinite AI content is awful"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Doesn't matter. We must keep building more and more technology no matter the cost. Have an idea for a business? Build it. Does your business make the lives of people worse? Doesn't matter, keep pushing. Could some new technology ruin the lives and relationships that people have? Doesn't matter, just build it. We always need more, need to do more. Every experiment is valid, every impulse must be followed. More complexity, more control, more distraction, more outrage, more engagement. Just keep building forever no matter the cost.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2025 13:30:40 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45835020</link><dc:creator>everdrive</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45835020</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45835020</guid></item><item><title>New comment by sixeyes in "End of Japanese community"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Maybe "open a communication channel" is what Mozilla should have done BEFORE they turned on this thing.&lt;p&gt;From the article: "It has been working now without our acceptance, without controls, without communications".&lt;p&gt;This person has been doing volunteer work for a long time, attempting to create a helpful environment. Then suddenly, from above a machine is turned on that shits all over that effort. Makes one feel unwelcome, and unseen...&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2025 10:06:59 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45833462</link><dc:creator>sixeyes</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45833462</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45833462</guid></item><item><title>New comment by apexalpha in "End of Japanese community"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;As someone from the Netherlands I read absolutely 0 condescending or patronising behaviour in this.&lt;p&gt;It just looks like someone trying to get in contact and help out. I could've written this myself, genuinely trying to help.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2025 08:51:30 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45832970</link><dc:creator>apexalpha</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45832970</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45832970</guid></item><item><title>New comment by getnormality in "End of Japanese community"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I'm sorry for how you feel about us kicking you in the balls.&lt;p&gt;Would you like to hop on a quick call to chat about this further?&lt;p&gt;Just a quick lil call.&lt;p&gt;Quick lil ol' callerino.&lt;p&gt;Hoppity hip hop.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2025 03:35:35 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45831090</link><dc:creator>getnormality</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45831090</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45831090</guid></item><item><title>New comment by jahsome in "End of Japanese community"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I'm not really able to understand the finer details but I think I picked up enough to get the broad strokes.&lt;p&gt;Really though, all I needed to see was the phrase "jump on a quick call" to form an irrationally strong opinion. That phrase instantly warms my entire body with rage.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2025 03:15:57 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45830974</link><dc:creator>jahsome</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45830974</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45830974</guid></item><item><title>New comment by adeptima in "End of Japanese community"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;10+ years in Japan. The message here is much deeper from my perspective. “Let’s jump on the call” is not the solution. The guy was stripped off of his face. I love Japan for being human. Small business bar or restaurant with 3 tables. Not everything should be streamlined for a quick call solution… the process was pushed on his head. Google nemawashi decision making process&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2025 03:04:57 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45830907</link><dc:creator>adeptima</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45830907</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45830907</guid></item><item><title>New comment by ares623 in "End of Japanese community"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;This is rich&lt;p&gt;&gt; We want to make sure we trully understand what you're struggling with.&lt;p&gt;The post literally starts with a list of grievances. Maybe ask the AI for an executive summary and the key points.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2025 02:52:27 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45830843</link><dc:creator>ares623</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45830843</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45830843</guid></item><item><title>New comment by rodarima in "Dillo, a multi-platform graphical web browser"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Many reasons, in no particular order:&lt;p&gt;- It is extremely slow and resource intensive. Opening any link/page takes at least 3 seconds on my fastest computer, but the content is mostly text with images.&lt;p&gt;- It cannot be used without JS (it used to be at least readable, now only the issue description loads). I want the bug tracker to be readable from Dillo itself. There are several CLI options but those are no better than just storing the issues as files and using my editor.&lt;p&gt;- It forces users to create an account to interact and it doesn't interoperate with other forges. It is a walled garden owned by a for-profit corporation.&lt;p&gt;- You need an Internet connection to use it and a good one. Loading the main page of the dillo repo requires 3 MiB of traffic (compressed) This is more than twice the size of a release of Dillo (we use a floppy disk as limit). Loading our index of &lt;i&gt;all&lt;/i&gt; opened issues downloads 7.6 KiB (compressed).&lt;p&gt;- Replying by email mangles the content (there is no Markdown?).&lt;p&gt;- I cannot add (built-in) dependencies across issues.&lt;p&gt;I'll probably write some post with more details when we finally consider the migration complete.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2025 23:26:35 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45829453</link><dc:creator>rodarima</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45829453</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45829453</guid></item><item><title>New comment by chis in "NY school phone ban has made lunch loud again"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;It's so insane that they let things go this far.  It could have been immediately obvious to those involved that cell phones in class would have immensely negative effects.  I mean they talk about a lunch room "quiet enough to hear a pin drop"??&lt;p&gt;I think I learned half my basic social skills from lunch rooms in school.  That time period is probably more important than any of the classes themselves.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2025 21:49:26 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45828528</link><dc:creator>chis</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45828528</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45828528</guid></item><item><title>New comment by zdragnar in "Why aren't smart people happier?"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;As I heard someone say, happiness is your reality minus your expectations.&lt;p&gt;Smart people see more variables that could be changed, more components that could be modified, and are less likely to accept things as they are. This creates a false sense of ease by which reality could be modified, and thus higher expectations for the world around them.&lt;p&gt;I suspect this misplaces happiness and contentment, but the two are also very strongly correlated for many people.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2025 21:06:54 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45828032</link><dc:creator>zdragnar</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45828032</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45828032</guid></item><item><title>New comment by epistasis in "Solarpunk is happening in Africa"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;The grid is &lt;i&gt;HUGELY&lt;/i&gt; expensive, an absolutely massive cost for our electricity. And it would still be  expensive in a well-regulated environment where you can quickly and easily get permission to build, without, say, voter ballot propositions illegally blocking a transmission line for years [1]. Here in the US we have a very very poorly regulated environment for adding to our grid, it moves slower than molasses and there are so many parties that have unilateral veto points. The advent of a new transmission route in the US these days is pretty much a miracle event.&lt;p&gt;Now imagine a world where there's tons of bribes to government officials all along the way to get a grid going (in the US you just need to bribe landowners and hold-outs). Or there's bribes to get a permit for the large centralized electriticy generator. And you have to deal with importing a whole new skill set and trades, on top of importing all the materials, fuel, etc.&lt;p&gt;Decentralized solar plus batteries is already cheaper than electricity + transmission for me at my home in the US. The only thing stopping me is the permitting hassle or the contractor hassle.&lt;p&gt;Out in greenfield, solar plus storage is so revolutionary. This is bigger than going straight to mobile phones instead of landlines.&lt;p&gt;Africa is going to get so much power, and it's all going to be clean, renewable energy. Thanks to all the entrepreneurs and engineers over the past decades that have continuously and steadily improved this technology, it's one of the bright lights of humanity these days.&lt;p&gt;[1] &lt;a href="https://www.utilitydive.com/news/maine-jury-clears-avangrids-145-mile-transmission-line-reversing-ballot-v/648209/" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://www.utilitydive.com/news/maine-jury-clears-avangrids...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2025 20:34:51 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45827590</link><dc:creator>epistasis</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45827590</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45827590</guid></item><item><title>New comment by spullara in "ChatGPT terms disallow its use in providing legal and medical advice to others"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;This title is inaccurate. What they are disallowing are users using ChatGPT to offer legal and medical advice to other people. First parties can still use ChatGPT for medical and legal advice for themselves.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2025 20:33:10 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45827569</link><dc:creator>spullara</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45827569</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45827569</guid></item><item><title>New comment by tototrains in "Internet Archive's legal fights are over, but its founder mourns what was lost"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Remember: If OpenAI/Google does it for $$$, it's not illegal. If idealists do it for public access, full force of the law.&lt;p&gt;Information wants to be free. Oblige it. Fools with temporary power trying to extract from the work of others will be a blip in the history books if we make them.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2025 20:24:58 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45827476</link><dc:creator>tototrains</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45827476</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45827476</guid></item><item><title>New comment by rodarima in "Dillo, a multi-platform graphical web browser"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Maintainer here.&lt;p&gt;We are currently in the process of moving Dillo away from GitHub:&lt;p&gt;- New website (nginx): &lt;a href="https://dillo-browser.org/" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://dillo-browser.org/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;- Repositories (C, cgit): &lt;a href="https://git.dillo-browser.org/" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://git.dillo-browser.org/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;- Bug tracker (C, buggy): &lt;a href="https://bug.dillo-browser.org/" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://bug.dillo-browser.org/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;They should survive HN hug.&lt;p&gt;The CI runs on git hooks and outputs the logs to the web (private for now).&lt;p&gt;All services are very simple and work without JS, so Dillo can be developed fully within Dillo itself.&lt;p&gt;During this testing period I will continue to sync the GitHub git repository, but in the future I will probably mark it as archived.&lt;p&gt;See also:&lt;p&gt;- &lt;a href="https://fosstodon.org/@dillo/114927456382947046" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://fosstodon.org/@dillo/114927456382947046&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;- &lt;a href="https://fosstodon.org/@dillo/115307022432139097" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://fosstodon.org/@dillo/115307022432139097&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2025 19:54:47 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45827108</link><dc:creator>rodarima</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45827108</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45827108</guid></item><item><title>New comment by Ardon in "Why aren't smart people happier?"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Might be useful to ask a different question: What makes people happy?&lt;p&gt;It's things like relationships, satisfying work, accomplishment. (and many, many more)&lt;p&gt;Then the real question emerges: How many of those happiness 'sources' are made better by intelligence? What percentage?&lt;p&gt;Relationships? Seems like no. Work? Also seems like no, lots of work doesn't make use of a high IQ that people enjoy nonetheless. Accomplishment? Strikes me as most likely of the three, but it's also very relative.&lt;p&gt;And another thought,&lt;p&gt;Asking why smart people aren't happier is a &lt;i&gt;bit&lt;/i&gt; like asking why people who can jump high aren't more empathetic. There's no direct link between the two, you have to dip out to the material conditions. Like: someone who can jump high is fitter &gt; fitter people are healthier &gt; healthier people have more mental time to be empathetic with &gt; people who can jump high are more empathetic.
For intelligence, we say smart people are happier. Same thing, happiness is not directly correlated. Instead: Smart people are better able to create the outcomes they want &gt; They select outcomes that make them happy &gt; Their environment makes them happy &gt; Smart people are happier.
(These are illustrations of the idea, not actual logical chains or claims.)&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2025 19:54:21 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45827102</link><dc:creator>Ardon</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45827102</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45827102</guid></item><item><title>New comment by timenotwasted in "New gel restores dental enamel and could revolutionise tooth repair"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I feel like I've been reading this exact same article for the last 15 years.. I find it very difficulty to parse what is real and what is vaporware in the medical breakthroughs community.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2025 19:52:06 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45827075</link><dc:creator>timenotwasted</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45827075</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45827075</guid></item><item><title>New comment by IAmBroom in "Norway reviews cybersecurity after remote-access feature found in Chinese buses"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I work in rail safety. Two major non-Chinese train companies attempted to merge a few years ago, explicitly to build a company that could compete with China's national company, and provide safer alternatives to state-sponsored cyberhacking of Western rail.&lt;p&gt;It fell down to an anti-monopoly decision by a single person in the EU ministry, who killed the proposal. Several attempts were made to streamline the merger, but she wouldn't budge.&lt;p&gt;As a result, CRCC continues to win contracts abroad, largely (it is believed) by undercutting competition. IP theft is known to be one objective of their at-loss or low-profit contracts (I've been involved in fighting that, specifically).&lt;p&gt;It's hardly a stretch to imagine that having control of the rail in countries that might oppose you militarily is strategically huge.&lt;p&gt;This article is about busways, but the parallels are obvious.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2025 18:04:54 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45825901</link><dc:creator>IAmBroom</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45825901</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45825901</guid></item><item><title>New comment by estimator7292 in "Ask HN: My family business runs on a 1993-era text-based-UI (TUI). Anybody else?"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Many (most?) older retail businesses still use TUIs. They're reliable, consistent, and &lt;i&gt;orders of magnitude&lt;/i&gt; faster than GUI systems.&lt;p&gt;When I worked ar Sherwin Williams, I got good enough with the TUI that customers could rattle off their orders while I punch it into the computer in real time.&lt;p&gt;It's absolutely crazy that a well designed TUI is &lt;i&gt;so&lt;/i&gt; much faster. It turns out that if you &lt;i&gt;never&lt;/i&gt; change the UI and &lt;i&gt;every&lt;/i&gt; menu item &lt;i&gt;always&lt;/i&gt; has the same hotkey, navigating the software becomes muscle memory and your speed is only limited by how fast you can physically push the buttons.&lt;p&gt;The program had many menu options added and removed over the decades, but the crucial part is that the hotkeys and menu indexes &lt;i&gt;never, ever&lt;/i&gt; changed. Once you learn that you can pop into a quick order menu with this specific sequence of five keys, you just automatically open the right menu the moment a customer walks up. No thought, just pure reflex.&lt;p&gt;UX absolutely peaked with TUIs several decades ago. No graphical interface I've ever seen comes even close to the raw utility and speed of these finely tuned TUIs. There is a very, &lt;i&gt;very&lt;/i&gt; good reason that the oldest and wealthiest retail businesses still use this ancient software. It works, and it's staggeringly effective, and any conceivable replacement will only be worse. There simply is no effective way to improve it.&lt;p&gt;Edit: I will say that these systems take time and effort to learn. You have to commit these UI paths to memory, which isn't too hard, but in order to be maximally effective, you also have to memorize a lot of product metadata. But the key is that it really doesn't take longer than your ordinary training period to become minimally effective. After that, you just pick up the muscle memory as you go. It's pretty analogous to learning touch typing without trying. Your hands just learn where the keys are and after enough time your brain translates words into keystrokes without active thought.&lt;p&gt;It's a beautiful way to design maximally effective software. We've really lost something very important with the shift to GUI and the shunning of text mode.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2025 15:54:15 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45824268</link><dc:creator>estimator7292</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45824268</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45824268</guid></item><item><title>New comment by ItsBob in "I’m worried that they put co-pilot in Excel"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;It's not as black-and-white as "Brenda good, AI bad". It's much more nuanced than this.&lt;p&gt;When it comes to (traditional) coding, for the most part, when I program a function to do X, every single time I run that function from now until the heat death of the sun, it will &lt;i&gt;always&lt;/i&gt; produce Y. Forever! When it does, we understand why, and when it doesn't, we also &lt;i&gt;can&lt;/i&gt; understand why it didn't!&lt;p&gt;When I use AI to perform X, every single time I run that AI from now until the heat death of the sun it will &lt;i&gt;maybe&lt;/i&gt; produce Y. Forever! When it does, we don't understand why, and when it doesn't, we also don't understand why!&lt;p&gt;We know that Brenda might screw up sometimes but she doesn't run at the speed of light, isn't able to produce a thousand lines of Excel Macro in 3 seconds, doesn't hallucinate (well, let's hope she doesn't), can follow instructions etc. If she does make a mistake, we can find it, fix it, ask her what happened etc. before the damage is too great.&lt;p&gt;In short: when AI does &lt;i&gt;anything&lt;/i&gt; at all, we only have, at best, a rough approximation of why it did it. With Brenda, it only takes a couple of questions to figure it out!&lt;p&gt;Before anyone says I'm against AI, I love it and am neck-deep in it all day when programming (not vibe-coding!) so I have a full understanding of what I'm getting myself into but I also know its limitations!&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2025 13:58:18 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45822873</link><dc:creator>ItsBob</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45822873</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45822873</guid></item><item><title>New comment by elevatortrim in "I’m worried that they put co-pilot in Excel"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;No contradiction here:&lt;p&gt;When we say “machine”, we mean deterministic algorithms and predictable mechanisms.&lt;p&gt;Generative AI is neither of those things (in theory it is deterministic but not for any practical applications).&lt;p&gt;If we order by predictability:&lt;p&gt;Quick Sort &gt; Brenda &gt; Gen AI&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2025 13:45:42 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45822754</link><dc:creator>elevatortrim</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45822754</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45822754</guid></item><item><title>New comment by cjrp in "UPS plane crashes near Louisville airport"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;The AVHerald is usually the best source for these things, rather than MSM: &lt;a href="https://avherald.com/h?article=52f5748f&amp;opt=0" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://avherald.com/h?article=52f5748f&amp;opt=0&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;&gt; Ground observers reported the aircraft had been delayed for about two hours for work on the left hand engine (engine #1), the engine #1 separated during the takeoff run, the center engine emitted streaks of flames, the aircraft impacted a UPS warehouse and ploughed through other facilities before coming to rest in a large plume of fire and smoke.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2025 09:53:54 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45821227</link><dc:creator>cjrp</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45821227</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45821227</guid></item><item><title>New comment by Anduia in "Developers are choosing older AI models"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;To the authors of the site, please know that your current "Cookiebot by Usercentrics" is old and pretty much illegal. You shouldn't need to click 5 times to "Reject all" if accepting all is one click. Newer versions have a "Deny" button.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2025 08:32:56 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45820748</link><dc:creator>Anduia</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45820748</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45820748</guid></item><item><title>New comment by xivzgrev in "Zohran Mamdani wins the New York mayoral race"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I'll give you one reason, among many, it wasn't a failure. It made it illegal to deny people health insurance coverage based on pre existing conditions. That was a big step forward in a broken system to restore some humanity to the system.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2025 06:12:53 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45819816</link><dc:creator>xivzgrev</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45819816</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45819816</guid></item><item><title>New comment by jordanb in "Direct File won't happen in 2026, IRS tells states"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Money well spent&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.yahoo.com/news/opinion-makers-turbotax-gave-trump-210621550.html?guccounter=1" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://www.yahoo.com/news/opinion-makers-turbotax-gave-trum...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2025 03:56:47 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45818849</link><dc:creator>jordanb</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45818849</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45818849</guid></item><item><title>New comment by michaelbarton in "Zohran Mamdani wins the New York mayoral race"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I hope this win signals (to both parties) that voters are receptive and will get engaged when a clear message is presented about cost of living and quality of life issues. Some of which are taken for granted in most other western countries.&lt;p&gt;I’m no political wonk, and I’m curious what others with more insight might say about his ability to fund and implement his polices.&lt;p&gt;I’m reminided of Obama and his hopeful message but he was mostly stymied on policy goals. Specifically Obamacare as an example ended up being watered down&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2025 03:19:39 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45818599</link><dc:creator>michaelbarton</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45818599</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45818599</guid></item><item><title>New comment by yosame in "Uncle Sam wants to scan your iris and collect your DNA, citizen or not"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Hilariously, this is the second Sam that wants to collect everyones iris's for nefarious purposes&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2025 00:52:33 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45817776</link><dc:creator>yosame</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45817776</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45817776</guid></item><item><title>New comment by someperson in "Google Removed 749M Anna's Archive URLs from Its Search Results"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Feels weird to say but I have found using Yandex of all places an excellent search engine for content that get taken down by DMCA requests.&lt;p&gt;Eg if you want to watch a movie that's not on Netflix using a web stream the search results are far better.&lt;p&gt;Feels like Google circa 2005.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2025 00:13:02 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45817472</link><dc:creator>someperson</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45817472</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45817472</guid></item><item><title>New comment by agluszak in "Google Removed 749M Anna's Archive URLs from Its Search Results"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Anna's archive has already fulfilled G's needs (training Gemini) so now it's time to pretend it never existed ;)&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 23:52:54 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45817305</link><dc:creator>agluszak</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45817305</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45817305</guid></item></channel></rss>