<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>Hacker News: Best Comments</title><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/bestcomments</link><description>Hacker News RSS</description><docs>https://hnrss.org/</docs><generator>hnrss v2.1.1</generator><lastBuildDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 00:01:23 +0000</lastBuildDate><ns0:link href="https://hnrss.org/bestcomments" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item><title>New comment by throwaway713 in "Collaboration sucks"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&gt; Every time you see collaboration happening, speak up and destroy it. Say “there are too many people involved. X, you are the driver, you decide.” (This is a great way to make friends btw).&lt;p&gt;Corollary for managers: Do &lt;i&gt;not&lt;/i&gt; say "it's your call", then once the decision has been made (and you skipped all the meetings pertaining to that decision), comment about how you would have done it differently and then retroactively request your report to go back and make changes. This is a great way to lose employees.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 11 Nov 2025 20:53:31 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45892683</link><dc:creator>throwaway713</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45892683</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45892683</guid></item><item><title>New comment by simianparrot in "iPhone Pocket"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I got excited for a moment, thought it was a new line of iPhone Mini -- you know, the actual handheld iPhones. I still use my 13 Mini.&lt;p&gt;This was the biggest letdown of clicking a link since my last Rickroll in the early 2000's&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 11 Nov 2025 19:41:45 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45891834</link><dc:creator>simianparrot</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45891834</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45891834</guid></item><item><title>New comment by phkahler in "FFmpeg to Google: Fund us or stop sending bugs"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;From TFA this was telling:&lt;p&gt;Thus, as Mark Atwood, an open source policy expert, pointed out on Twitter, he had to keep telling Amazon to not do things that would mess up FFmpeg because, he had to keep explaining to his bosses that “They are not a vendor, there is no NDA, we have no leverage, your VP has refused to help fund them, and they could kill three major product lines tomorrow with an email. So, stop, and listen to me … ”&lt;p&gt;I agree with the headline here. If Google can pay someone to find bugs, they can pay someone to fix them. How many time have managers said "Don't come to me with problems, come with solutions"&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 11 Nov 2025 19:41:20 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45891830</link><dc:creator>phkahler</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45891830</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45891830</guid></item><item><title>New comment by tempestn in "iPhone Pocket"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Had to double check the date here. This really is indistinguishable from an April 1 post.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 11 Nov 2025 18:47:58 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45891190</link><dc:creator>tempestn</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45891190</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45891190</guid></item><item><title>New comment by perihelions in "iPhone Pocket"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&gt; &lt;i&gt;"Greater China"&lt;/i&gt;&lt;p&gt;Irredentist pro-war language, Tim Cook? I am so done with Apple. They knew what they did when they chose the words; they certainly spent thousands of hours deliberating them.&lt;p&gt;This is Lebensraum with Chinese Characteristics.&lt;p&gt;&gt; &lt;i&gt;"The term is often used to avoid invoking sensitivities over the political status of Taiwan.[16] Contrastingly, it has been used in reference to Chinese irredentism in nationalist contexts, such as the notion that China should reclaim its "lost territories" to create a Greater China.[17][18]"&lt;/i&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Greater_China" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Greater_China&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 11 Nov 2025 15:27:44 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45888370</link><dc:creator>perihelions</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45888370</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45888370</guid></item><item><title>New comment by davidmurdoch in "iPhone Pocket"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Had to make sure it wasn't April 1st.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 11 Nov 2025 14:45:01 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45887806</link><dc:creator>davidmurdoch</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45887806</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45887806</guid></item><item><title>New comment by fxtentacle in "iPhone Pocket"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Awww... I was so much hoping for an iPhone that will fit into my pocket. The 1st iPhone SE was the perfect form factor. But no, Apple's phones just had to grow and grow and grow like cancer ...&lt;p&gt;In my opinion, the fact that Apple is now selling a bag to carry your oversized phone around in, is an admission that they failed to make phones that are convenient to carry.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 11 Nov 2025 14:41:57 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45887773</link><dc:creator>fxtentacle</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45887773</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45887773</guid></item><item><title>New comment by EdgeExplorer in "OpenAI may not use lyrics without license, German court rules"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;The obsession with protecting access to lyrics is one of the strangest long-running legal battles to me. I will skip tracks on Spotify sometimes specifically because there are no lyrics available. Easy access to lyrics is practically an advertisement for the music. Why do record companies not want lyrics freely available? In most cases, it means they aren't available at all. How is that a good business decision?&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 11 Nov 2025 14:34:57 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45887701</link><dc:creator>EdgeExplorer</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45887701</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45887701</guid></item><item><title>New comment by jordanb in "The kind of company I want to be a part of"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;This is the Californian Ideology in a blog post. The implication that title and intro mean to imply is working for companies that build products that are not evil and hostile to their users.&lt;p&gt;But the call to action is to.. embed logic in the programs to pluralize properly (in English).&lt;p&gt;It's possible to write evil software that pluralizes words. It's possible to write beneficial software that does not pluralize words. This blog post is about the color of the bikeshed next to the torment nexus.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 11 Nov 2025 14:09:36 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45887441</link><dc:creator>jordanb</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45887441</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45887441</guid></item><item><title>New comment by janeway in "The 'Toy Story' You Remember"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;This topic is fascinating to me. The Toy Story film workflow is a perfect illustration of intentional compensation: artists pushed greens in the digital master because 35 mm film would darken and desaturate them. The aim was never neon greens on screen, it was colour calibration for a later step. Only later, when digital masters were reused without the film stage, did those compensating choices start to look like creative ones.&lt;p&gt;I run into this same failure mode often. We introduce purposeful scaffolding in the workflow that isn’t meant to stand alone, but exists solely to ensure the final output behaves as intended. Months later, someone is pitching how we should “lean into the bold saturated greens,” not realising the topic only exists because we specifically wanted neutral greens in the final output. The scaffold becomes the building.&lt;p&gt;In our work this kind of nuance isn’t optional, it is the project. If we lose track of which decisions are compensations and which are targets, outcomes drift badly and quietly, and everything built after is optimised for the wrong goal.&lt;p&gt;I’d genuinely value advice on preventing this. Is there a good name or framework for this pattern? Something concise that distinguishes a process artefact from product intent, and helps teams course-correct early without sounding like a semantics debate?&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 11 Nov 2025 11:55:17 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45886316</link><dc:creator>janeway</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45886316</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45886316</guid></item><item><title>New comment by jacquesm in "How I fell in love with Erlang"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;It's funny how HN goes through these Erlang cycles. It's a long standing tradition, starting off with 'Erlang Day': &lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/front?day=2009-03-11"&gt;https://news.ycombinator.com/front?day=2009-03-11&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;Erlang gets a lot of stuff right for scalable web based stuff, and even though there are many of its influences that have by now made it into other languages and eco systems it is still amazing to me that such a well thought out system is run with such incredible modesty. You'll never see the people behind Erlang be confrontational or evangelists, they just do what they're good at and it is up to you whether you adopt it or not. And that is an interesting thing: the people that are good at this are writing code, not evangelizing. If I had to reboot my career I'd pick this eco system over anything else, it has incredible staying power, handles backwards compatibility issues with grace and has a community that you can be proud of joining. Modest, competent, and with a complete lack of drama.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 11 Nov 2025 10:15:58 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45885799</link><dc:creator>jacquesm</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45885799</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45885799</guid></item><item><title>New comment by lifthrasiir in "SoftBank sells its entire stake in Nvidia"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Note the first line:&lt;p&gt;&gt; SoftBank said Tuesday it has sold its entire stake in U.S. chipmaker Nvidia for $5.83 billion as the Japanese giant looks to capitalize its “all in” bet on ChatGPT maker OpenAI.&lt;p&gt;They are switching gears, not exiting, folks.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 11 Nov 2025 09:08:35 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45885409</link><dc:creator>lifthrasiir</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45885409</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45885409</guid></item><item><title>New comment by blopker in "AI documentation you can talk to, for every repo"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I took a look at a project I maintain[0], and wow. It's so wrong in every section I saw. The generated diagrams make no sense. The text sections take implementation details that don't matter and present them to the user like they need to know them. It's also outdated.&lt;p&gt;I hope actual users never see this. I dread thinking about having to go around to various LLM generated sites to correct documentation I never approved of to stop confusing users that are tricked into reading it.&lt;p&gt;[0]: &lt;a href="https://deepwiki.com/blopker/codebook" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://deepwiki.com/blopker/codebook&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 11 Nov 2025 07:16:05 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45884860</link><dc:creator>blopker</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45884860</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45884860</guid></item><item><title>New comment by ProllyInfamous in "Warren Buffett's final shareholder letter [pdf]"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&gt;Greatness does not come about through accumulating great amounts of money, great amounts of publicity or great power in government. When you help someone in any of thousands of ways, you help the world. Kindness is costless but also priceless. Whether you are religious or not, it’s hard to beat The Golden Rule as a guide to behavior.&lt;p&gt;&gt;I write this as one who has been thoughtless countless times and made many mistakes but also became very lucky in learning from some wonderful friends how to behave better (still a long way from perfect, however). Keep in mind that the cleaning lady is as much a human being as the Chairman.&lt;p&gt;&gt;I wish all who read this a very happy Thanksgiving. Yes, even the jerks; it’s never too late to change. Remember to thank America for maximizing your opportunities. But it is – inevitably – capricious and sometimes venal in distributing its rewards.&lt;p&gt;&gt;Choose your heroes very carefully and then emulate them. You will never be perfect, but you can always be better.&lt;p&gt;God speed, dearest Oracle of Omaha.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 11 Nov 2025 04:32:38 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45884137</link><dc:creator>ProllyInfamous</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45884137</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45884137</guid></item><item><title>New comment by chongli in "Time to start de-Appling"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Who would want to be an iron clad gate keeper when the world is descending into authoritarianism?&lt;/i&gt;&lt;p&gt;Powerful people don't think this way. They think they can leverage the authoritarian regime to their own advantage. They're biased to ignore risks and seek out opportunities. That's what got them to their position of success!&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 11 Nov 2025 04:25:25 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45884105</link><dc:creator>chongli</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45884105</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45884105</guid></item><item><title>New comment by gyomu in "I hate screenshots of text"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Like other commenters point out, automatic OCR on Apple platforms is a godsend, and it's such a great use of our modern AI capabilities that it should be a standard feature in every document viewer on every platform.&lt;p&gt;Another thing I wish was more common is metadata in screenshots, especially on phones. Eg if I take a screenshot of a picture in Instagram, I wish a URL of the picture was embedded (eg instagram.com/p/ABCD1234/). If I take a screenshot in the browser, include the URL that's being viewed (+ path to the DOM element in the viewport). If I take a screenshot in a maps app, include the bounding coordinates. If I take a screenshot in a PDF viewer, include a SHA1 hash of the document being viewed + offset in the document so that if I send the screenshot to someone else with the same document, it can seamlessly link to it. Etc etc.&lt;p&gt;There are probably privacy concerns to solve here, but no idea is new in computer science and I'm pretty sure some grad student somewhere has already explored the topic in depth (it just never made it to mainstream computing platforms).&lt;p&gt;It feels like screenshots have become the de facto common denominator in our mobile computing era, since platforms have abstracted files away from us. Lots of people who have only ever used phones as their main computing devices are confused when it comes to files, but everyone seems to understand screenshots.&lt;p&gt;Also, necessary shout out to Screenshot Conf! &lt;a href="https://screenshot.arquipelago.org" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://screenshot.arquipelago.org&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 11 Nov 2025 02:16:01 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45883398</link><dc:creator>gyomu</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45883398</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45883398</guid></item><item><title>New comment by zmmmmm in "Time to start de-Appling"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I know this is a tangent but honestly, this is why the Google decision to de-openify Android is &lt;i&gt;insane&lt;/i&gt; even from Google's point of view. Who would want to be an iron clad gate keeper when the world is descending into authoritarianism? You just paint a giant target on your back for the authoritarians to come after.&lt;p&gt;If Apple had supported open iCloud alternatives for backup and other services from day one, it woudn't even be a discussion now. The UK probably wouldn't have thought of the idea of mandating against E2E encryption because it would be self evident it would actually just churn people to alternatives where they have less leverage and visibility. But Apple couldn't resist bricking up the walled garden and now it's hostile to both them and their users, and to be honest, everyone on the planet since it is obvious that once this happens in the UK it will be silly for every government everywhere not to follow suit.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 11 Nov 2025 00:14:32 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45882625</link><dc:creator>zmmmmm</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45882625</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45882625</guid></item><item><title>New comment by gyomu in "Vibe Code Warning – A personal casestudy"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&gt; is it about doing, or is it about getting things done?&lt;p&gt;No, this is a false dichotomy and slippery slope dangerous thinking.&lt;p&gt;It’s about building a world where we can all live in and find meaning, joy, dignity, and fulfillment, which requires a balance between pursuing the ends and preserving the means as worthwhile human pursuits.&lt;p&gt;If I am eating a delicious meal but the people preparing it had a miserable time, or it was prepared entirely by robots controlled by nefarious people using the profits to harm society, I don’t want it.&lt;p&gt;Human society and civilization is for the benefit of humans, not for filling checkboxes above all else.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2025 21:42:50 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45881333</link><dc:creator>gyomu</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45881333</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45881333</guid></item><item><title>New comment by tcoff91 in "The lazy Git UI you didn't know you need"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I was a big fan of a good keyboard-driven git TUI like magit, neogit, lazygit, etc... (as long as you learn the CLI first and understand it).&lt;p&gt;Now I no longer directly use git, but instead use jujutsu (jj).&lt;p&gt;Once I became very proficient in the jj cli, I picked up jjui: &lt;a href="https://github.com/idursun/jjui" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://github.com/idursun/jjui&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;Also, as splitting commits is an extremely frequent operation, this neovim plugin is really nice: &lt;a href="https://github.com/julienvincent/hunk.nvim" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://github.com/julienvincent/hunk.nvim&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;Also this neovim plugin is amazing for resolving jj conflicts: &lt;a href="https://github.com/rafikdraoui/jj-diffconflicts" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://github.com/rafikdraoui/jj-diffconflicts&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;Now with jj instead of git I edit the commit graph as effortlessly as if I am moving lines of code around a file in my editor.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2025 19:46:02 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45880047</link><dc:creator>tcoff91</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45880047</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45880047</guid></item><item><title>New comment by lampiaio in "Rewilding the Internet"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&gt; scrolls down to read more&lt;p&gt;&gt; "subscribe" popup interrupts my reading&lt;p&gt;&gt; ctrl-w&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2025 19:39:03 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45879949</link><dc:creator>lampiaio</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45879949</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45879949</guid></item><item><title>New comment by ebbi in "Time to start de-Appling"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Taking inspiration from the East India Company, Apple should colonize the UK and take over the government - the iGovernment, if you will.&lt;p&gt;Citizens will regain their right to e2ee privacy, they will not have to deal with voting for mediocre politicians to lead them. Instead, Tim Cook will be their new leader, and every morning over the mandatory installation of HomePods in each home, citizens will be greeted with an ecstatic "Good morning!" to get them energized for the day ahead.&lt;p&gt;Voting will be done via iPhones, where FaceID will verify the eligibility of the voter before the vote has been submitted.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2025 19:26:06 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45879770</link><dc:creator>ebbi</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45879770</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45879770</guid></item><item><title>New comment by HiPhish in "Reminder to passengers ahead of move to 100% digital boarding passes"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&gt; but will instead need to use the digital boarding pass generated in their “myRyanair” app during check-in to board their Ryanair flight.&lt;p&gt;And of course it's only possible using a specific proprietary app. You'd think a penny-pinching company would want to use open standard to save money instead of develop a custom app, right? I'm 100% sure this is done intentionally to scoop up as much personal data from their customers.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2025 18:43:31 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45879273</link><dc:creator>HiPhish</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45879273</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45879273</guid></item><item><title>New comment by nickcw in "Time to start de-Appling"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Very clever image and caption (right at the bottom of the page)&lt;p&gt;&gt; Header image by me: Alan Turing memorial, Manchester, where he reminds you why keeping data private can be a matter of life and death.&lt;p&gt;The image shows a close up of a statue of Alan Turing, his hand holding an apple.&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Alan_Turing#Death" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Alan_Turing#Death&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2025 17:47:20 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45878537</link><dc:creator>nickcw</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45878537</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45878537</guid></item><item><title>New comment by codexb in "Time to start de-Appling"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Sounds more like people need to de-UK. It's going to be a problem with any company or technology.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2025 16:44:28 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45877765</link><dc:creator>codexb</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45877765</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45877765</guid></item><item><title>New comment by sho_hn in "LLMs are steroids for your Dunning-Kruger"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I'm not sure this is something I really worry about. Whenever I use an LLM I feel dumber, not smarter; there's a sensation of relying on a crutch instead of having done the due diligence of learning something myself. I'm less confident in the knowledge and less likely to present it as such. Is anyone really cocksure on the basis of LLM received knowledge?&lt;p&gt;&gt; As I ChatGPT user I notice that I’m often left with a sense of certainty.&lt;p&gt;They have almost the opposite effect on me.&lt;p&gt;Even with knowledge from books or articles I've learned to multi-source and question things, and my mind treats the LLMs as a less reliable averaging of sources.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2025 15:46:53 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45877036</link><dc:creator>sho_hn</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45877036</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45877036</guid></item><item><title>New comment by konimex in "XSLT RIP"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&gt; &lt;a href="https://dbushell.com" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://dbushell.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;Heh, I honestly thought the domain name stood for "D-Bus Hell" and not their own name.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2025 08:32:59 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45873792</link><dc:creator>konimex</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45873792</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45873792</guid></item><item><title>New comment by koito17 in "XSLT RIP"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I was hoping the site itself would be an XML document. Thankfully, it &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; an XML document.&lt;p&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;  % curl https://xslt.rip/
  &lt;?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?&gt;
  &lt;?xml-stylesheet href="/index.xsl" type="text/xsl"?&gt;
  &lt;html&gt;
    &lt;head&gt;
      &lt;title&gt;XSLT.RIP&lt;/title&gt;
    &lt;/head&gt;
    &lt;body&gt;
      &lt;h1&gt;If you're reading this, XSLT was killed by Google.&lt;/h1&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Thoughts and prayers.&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Rest in peace.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/body&gt;
  &lt;/html&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2025 07:46:51 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45873491</link><dc:creator>koito17</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45873491</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45873491</guid></item><item><title>New comment by SoftTalker in "LLM policy?"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I think everything has a growing problem with LLM/AI generated content. Emails, blog posts, news articles, research papers, grant applications, business proposals, music, art, pretty much everything you can think of.&lt;p&gt;There’s already more human produced content in the world than anyone could ever hope to consume, we don’t need more from AI.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2025 03:34:48 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45872106</link><dc:creator>SoftTalker</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45872106</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45872106</guid></item><item><title>New comment by windowshopping in "Work after work: Notes from an unemployed new grad watching the job market break"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Two initial thoughts:&lt;p&gt;1. This author's writing is extremely, uncommonly good. Good enough to write a book and have it sell. "Competing with the past of the economy," "residual behaviour of a world that treated labour as sacred," "immigration without immigrants" -- there are many elegant turns of phrase here. This is a very skilled writer.&lt;p&gt;2. His resume is designed poorly. Have a look. I'm not surprised his job search has been unsuccessful when his resume looks like an essay. OP, you gotta cut that text down by like 70% and put more highlights. This is the world of tiktok and instagram reels.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2025 01:46:56 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45871320</link><dc:creator>windowshopping</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45871320</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45871320</guid></item><item><title>New comment by paulhebert in "Ask HN: What Are You Working On? (Nov 2025)"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I recently launched a daily word puzzle!&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://tiledwords.com" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://tiledwords.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;It’s inspired by tile placement board games like Patchwork and crosswords. You rotate and move tiles to rebuild a broken crossword.&lt;p&gt;It’s free, web based, and responsive.&lt;p&gt;I currently have several hundred daily players and growing. My wife and I create the puzzles and I’m continuing to fix bugs and add new features.&lt;p&gt;I just launched a ”community puzzle” feature to let players help build new puzzles.&lt;p&gt;I’d love to know what you think!&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 09 Nov 2025 23:41:15 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45870446</link><dc:creator>paulhebert</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45870446</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45870446</guid></item></channel></rss>