<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>Hacker News: Best Comments</title><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/bestcomments</link><description>Hacker News RSS</description><docs>https://hnrss.org/</docs><generator>hnrss v2.1.1</generator><lastBuildDate>Sun, 05 Oct 2025 23:59:13 +0000</lastBuildDate><ns0:link href="https://hnrss.org/bestcomments" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item><title>New comment by StopDisinfo910 in "Fire destroys S. Korean government's cloud storage system, no backups available"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;The issue here is not refusing to use a foreign third party. That makes sense.&lt;p&gt;The issue is mandating the use of remote storage and not backing it up. That’s insane. It’s like the most basic amount of preparation you do. It’s recommended to even the smallest of companies specifically because a fire is a risk.&lt;p&gt;That’s gross mismanagement.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 05 Oct 2025 21:19:32 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45485382</link><dc:creator>StopDisinfo910</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45485382</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45485382</guid></item><item><title>New comment by msbhvn in "Fire destroys S. Korean government's cloud storage system, no backups available"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Woah, read the timeline at the top of this. The fire happened the very day the government ordered onsite inspection was supposed to start due to Chinese/NK hacking.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 05 Oct 2025 20:16:24 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45484838</link><dc:creator>msbhvn</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45484838</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45484838</guid></item><item><title>New comment by eCa in "Fire destroys S. Korean government's cloud storage system, no backups available"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Agree completely that it's absolute wild to run such a system without backups. But at this point no government should keep critical data on foreign cloud storage.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 05 Oct 2025 20:14:47 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45484825</link><dc:creator>eCa</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45484825</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45484825</guid></item><item><title>New comment by kristianc in "Fire destroys S. Korean government's cloud storage system, no backups available"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;The government official who insisted that commercial AWS/GCP/Azure couldn't possibly be trusted with keeping the information will be keeping their head low for a few days then...&lt;p&gt;"The Interior Ministry explained that while most systems at the Daejeon data center are backed up daily to separate equipment within the same center and to a physically remote backup facility, the G-Drive’s structure did not allow for external backups."&lt;p&gt;This is absolutely wild.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 05 Oct 2025 20:02:45 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45484718</link><dc:creator>kristianc</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45484718</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45484718</guid></item><item><title>New comment by jn78 in "Fire destroys S. Korean government's cloud storage system, no backups available"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://phrack.org/issues/72/7_md#article" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://phrack.org/issues/72/7_md#article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 05 Oct 2025 19:45:47 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45484582</link><dc:creator>jn78</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45484582</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45484582</guid></item><item><title>New comment by patel011393 in "Why are hyperlinks blue? (2021)"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;They're blue because computer scientist Ben Schneiderman made them blue using research from 1985:&lt;p&gt;" In 1985, a group of students at the University of Maryland, mentored by computer science professor Ben Shneiderman , conducted a series of experiments to study the impact of different hyperlink colors on user experience. They were eager to determine which color would be the most effective in terms of visibility and readability.&lt;p&gt;The experiments revealed interesting findings. While red highlighting made the links more noticeable, it negatively affected users' ability to read and comprehend the surrounding text. On the other hand, blue emerged as the clear winner. It was dark enough to be visible against a white background and light enough to stand out on a black background. Most importantly, it did not interfere with users' retention of the text's context."&lt;p&gt;Mozille should really do better research before posting histories like this. It's easy to overlook the impact of academic research in tech.&lt;p&gt;Source:&lt;p&gt;Barooah, S. (2023, June 09). Why Were Hyperlinks Chosen To Be Blue? Retrieved from &lt;a href="https://www.newspointapp.com/english/tech/why-were-hyperlinks-chosen-to-be-blue/articleshow/100877379.cms" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://www.newspointapp.com/english/tech/why-were-hyperlink...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 05 Oct 2025 19:13:26 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45484317</link><dc:creator>patel011393</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45484317</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45484317</guid></item><item><title>New comment by yongjik in "Fire destroys S. Korean government's cloud storage system, no backups available"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;It's even worse.  According to other articles [1], the total data of "G drive" was 858 TB.&lt;p&gt;It's almost farcical to calculate, but AWS S3 has pricing of about $0.023/GB/month, which means the South Korean government could have reliable multi-storage backup of the whole data at about $20k/month.  Or about $900/month if they opted for "Glacier deep archive" tier ($0.00099/GB/month).&lt;p&gt;They did have backup of the data ... in the same server room that burned down [2].&lt;p&gt;[1] &lt;a href="https://www.hankyung.com/article/2025100115651" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://www.hankyung.com/article/2025100115651&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;[2] &lt;a href="https://www.hani.co.kr/arti/area/area_general/1221873.html" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://www.hani.co.kr/arti/area/area_general/1221873.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;(both in Korean)&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 05 Oct 2025 18:20:00 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45483858</link><dc:creator>yongjik</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45483858</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45483858</guid></item><item><title>New comment by PeterStuer in "Fire destroys S. Korean government's cloud storage system, no backups available"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I'm sure they had dozens of process heavy cybersecurity committees producing hundreds if not thousands of powerpoints and word documents outlining procedures and best practices over the last decade.&lt;p&gt;There is this weird divide between the certified class of non-technical consultants and actual overworked and pushed to corner cut techs.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 05 Oct 2025 17:53:08 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45483680</link><dc:creator>PeterStuer</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45483680</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45483680</guid></item><item><title>New comment by blibble in "Link Khan: Activision-Blizzard buyout is 'harming both gamers and developers'"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;the game pass domination strategy was always going to fail in a world where Steam exists&lt;p&gt;it must be very frustrating for Microsoft&lt;p&gt;their usual tactic of buying out the competition isn't an option because Gabe Newell is already a billionare (and a gamer), who won't sell for any price&lt;p&gt;and their backup strategy of tightening the screws of their competition on Windows can't work either, because he's funded a credible (almost) replacement for Windows&lt;p&gt;so for once they have to compete on fair terms&lt;p&gt;and when they do that: they lose&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 05 Oct 2025 16:53:01 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45483124</link><dc:creator>blibble</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45483124</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45483124</guid></item><item><title>New comment by jakebasile in "Retiring Test-Ipv6.com"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I work with the engineer behind this (different team, but we interact semi-often and work on overlapping projects), but had no idea it was him until I looked at the little copyright notice in the footer. He is a fascinating guy and a fantastic engineer (one of those 10x engineers you hear about) while being humble and always willing to help out.&lt;p&gt;Thanks for the site for the last 15 years, it's helped me a number of times.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 05 Oct 2025 15:08:29 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45482061</link><dc:creator>jakebasile</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45482061</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45482061</guid></item><item><title>New comment by pavlov in "Personal data storage is an idea whose time has come"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;&gt; “Applying for a job or apartment or anything today means creating endless pointless copies of your pesonal information in databases across the world that will eventually be neglected, hacked, exploited, sold off etc”&lt;/i&gt;&lt;p&gt;This problem is practically fixed in the EU (to the extent that legislation can fix it). Data protection laws have enough teeth that real companies can’t afford to keep or sell customer information illegally.&lt;p&gt;But people only see the tip of the iceberg and think EU data protection is something to do with annoying cookie banners. We need to do a better job of celebrating Europe’s real achievements in making the digital world better for its citizens. Instant zero-fee bank transfers are another example.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 05 Oct 2025 13:15:00 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45481258</link><dc:creator>pavlov</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45481258</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45481258</guid></item><item><title>New comment by InMice in "Personal data storage is an idea whose time has come"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Among the first page and 2nd page (top 60) there is always atleast 1 post about how we're gonnna "take back the web" or make it back into some form of our 90s millenial nostalgia memories, self hosting, federated this or that, etc etc.&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile - Nothing changes, everything generally gets worse and younger generations come into the world with no memories of the 90s internet or the world before mobile devices or surveillence everywhere.&lt;p&gt;Applying for a job or apartment or anything today means creating endless pointless copies of your pesonal information in databases across the world that will eventually be neglected, hacked, exploited, sold off etc&lt;p&gt;I dont know the way out if there is one, I guess we can keep fantasizing and thinking about it. It just feels like it would be easier to get the earth to start spinning the other way sometimes.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 05 Oct 2025 11:43:27 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45480798</link><dc:creator>InMice</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45480798</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45480798</guid></item><item><title>New comment by adzm in "What .NET 10 GC changes mean for developers"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;A hobby audio and text analysis application I've written, with no specific concern for low level performance other than algorithmically, runs 4x as fast in .net10 vs .net8. Pretty much every optimization discussed here applies to that app. Great work, kudos to the dotnet team. C# is, imo, the best cross platform GC language. I really can't think of anything that comes close in terms of performance, features, ecosystem, developer experience.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 05 Oct 2025 09:05:49 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45480096</link><dc:creator>adzm</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45480096</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45480096</guid></item><item><title>New comment by keiferski in "Americans increasingly see legal sports betting as a bad thing for society"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;The legalization and popularity of gambling is more than just an immoral activity that has negative societal effects. It’s reflective of people losing hope in the system’s ability to make their lives better.&lt;p&gt;Gambling thrives in contexts where a ladder to success doesn’t exist or is perceived as not existing. If hard work or time doesn’t make your life better, then fate is just chance, and you might as well throw your money at something that has the possibility of making your rich, no matter how tiny that likelihood.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 05 Oct 2025 07:19:07 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45479541</link><dc:creator>keiferski</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45479541</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45479541</guid></item><item><title>New comment by dwedge in "Way past its prime: how did Amazon get so rubbish?"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I bought a $120 book from Amazon a couple of months ago, internationally, and they sent the wrong book.&lt;p&gt;I told them, and they said they'd refund it, don't need to send it back, and they'd even add $15 credit.&lt;p&gt;The refund never arrived so a few weeks later I got in touch again and they said I need to send it back if I want a refund. They told me the previous CSR had lied to improve ratings. I asked who I can complain to and they said nobody and closed the chat. I reopened it, restarted the refund, it was accepted and then 2 hours later I got an email saying that unless I sent them ID my refund would be rejected and that I can "no longer contact them" about this refund. I ignored that email, sent the book back and got the refund.&lt;p&gt;Another time I bought a Samsung Fold and it cracked down the middle. I told Amazon and they said they'll refund it under warranty. I sent it back and got a warning that if I return anything else in "non original condition" I'd be banned. Even though it was a warranty return.&lt;p&gt;That level of service would have been totally unheard of for Amazon 5 years ago.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 05 Oct 2025 07:03:54 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45479461</link><dc:creator>dwedge</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45479461</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45479461</guid></item><item><title>New comment by angarg12 in "Americans increasingly see legal sports betting as a bad thing for society"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I left my home country over 10 years ago, and ever since I've travelled back once every 1 or 2 years.&lt;p&gt;Since 4-5 years ago I started to notice these betting houses cropping up where my family and friends live. They are impossible to miss, with big pictures of different sports and no windows.&lt;p&gt;The most important thing to notice is where these place are and are not. They proliferate in working class and less well off neighborhoods, while they tend to be absent from more affluent ones.&lt;p&gt;These places get a lot of foot traffic, all the locals barely making ends meet, blowing a few tens of euros here and there, with the eventual payoff. It's not difficult to hear stories of people getting into the deep end and developing a real addiction with devastating consequences.&lt;p&gt;And it's not only the business itself, but what they attract. All sort of sketchy characters frequent these places, and tend to attract drugs, violence...&lt;p&gt;Legal or not these places make the communities they inhabit worse, not better. I personally would be very happy if family didn't have to live exposed to them.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 05 Oct 2025 05:43:22 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45479082</link><dc:creator>angarg12</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45479082</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45479082</guid></item><item><title>New comment by jagrsw in "$912 energy independence without red tape"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;As someone with an electrician's ticket (non-practicing, but the exam was no joke), this is a "not-so-good" idea.&lt;p&gt;A 3kW inverter powering a fridge through extension cords (fridges/compressors can have serious inrush current). You can't just snake "yolo" cables through a house for anything drawing serious amps (say, more than 5).&lt;p&gt;I'm willing to bet zero impedance or insulation/continuity tests were done. I hope the inverter has the RCD protection included.&lt;p&gt;This "works" 99.9% of the time. Now multiply 0.1% by every person who sees this and thinks it's a clever hack.&lt;p&gt;Update: He's plugging an extension cord directly into the inverter's output terminals? A 3kW inverter at 120V can push 25A continuously (and likely no RCD in the path). That can melt a 10/15A cord. The inverter's own breaker (say, 30/40A) is there to protect the inverter, not the cord. The cord may "become" the fuse long before the breaker trips on an overload (it doesn't trip at 30A instantly, more like at 100-200A if it's equivalent to EU class B/C).&lt;p&gt;Update2: I'm against overregulation and panicing at every perceived threat, but I must say, I wouldn't mind an inspection taking a look for the sake of neighbors.&lt;p&gt;Update3: The PDF (&lt;a href="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0746/0415/1079/files/POW-LVM3K-24V-H_User_Manual_V1.3.0929.pdf" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0746/0415/1079/files/POW-L...&lt;/a&gt;) says that the AC input "maximum bypass overload current" is 40A. If he plugs the inverter into a wall outlet for charging/bypass, it will let his appliances pull 40A through a standard 15A socket. The main apartment panel will eventually trip, hopefully.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 04 Oct 2025 22:39:19 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45477383</link><dc:creator>jagrsw</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45477383</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45477383</guid></item><item><title>New comment by keiferski in "Flock's gunshot detection microphones will start listening for human voices"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;It’s pretty depressing to see every ostensibly American value be replaced by profit-driven utilitarianism. “It improves X problem marginally and it makes money, so why not?” seems to be the reasoning for just about everything anymore. No discussion of values, of the society we want to build, or anything else. That’s the world the tech industry is building.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 04 Oct 2025 19:35:12 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45476002</link><dc:creator>keiferski</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45476002</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45476002</guid></item><item><title>New comment by Aurornis in "How I influence tech company politics as a staff software engineer"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&gt; 1. If your manager has something in particular they want you to do, you should do it.&lt;p&gt;This point seems obvious, but it's one topics I've had to coach many early career people on over and over again.&lt;p&gt;Many of the people who were having difficulties or heading toward PIP could be turned around by implementing a simple loop where they:&lt;p&gt;1. Ask their manager for the top priority, explicitly. Re-confirm the top priority every time you encounter a question about what to work on or new information that might change the situation.&lt;p&gt;2. Write it down. Put it somewhere visible. Check it every morning. Remind yourself about the top priority.&lt;p&gt;3. Do the top priority until it's done. Confirm that your manager agrees that it's done when you think it's done.&lt;p&gt;It sounds simple to those of us who internalized these loops early in our careers, but some people don't see it so clearly until it's laid out for them. They get distracted, go on side quests, take too many tasks from people who aren't their manager, or avoid their manager's requests in favor of a task they find more interesting.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 04 Oct 2025 17:26:22 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45474998</link><dc:creator>Aurornis</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45474998</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45474998</guid></item><item><title>New comment by scottydelta in "Flock's gunshot detection microphones will start listening for human voices"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&gt; You're thinking Chinese surveillance&lt;p&gt;&gt; US-based surveillance helps victims and prevents more victims&lt;p&gt;— Garry Tan, Sept 03, 2025, YC CEO while defending Flock on X.&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://xcancel.com/garrytan/status/1963310592615485955" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://xcancel.com/garrytan/status/1963310592615485955&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;I admire Garry but not sure why there can’t be a line that we all agree not to cross. No weapon has ever been made that was not used to harm humanity.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 04 Oct 2025 17:19:05 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45474912</link><dc:creator>scottydelta</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45474912</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45474912</guid></item><item><title>New comment by softwaredoug in "How I influence tech company politics as a staff software engineer"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;IMO the best you can do:&lt;p&gt;- Ship often to prod (don’t do theoretical work).&lt;p&gt;- Ship wins (as defined by generally acceptable metrics.)&lt;p&gt;- Have someone in management or a PM who is good at selling your wins&lt;p&gt;Even here, though, you will run into problems. There is always a new VP or leader looking to make an impact. Because you maintain the current systems your team is engaging in WrongThink and new VP has shiny new RightThink (AI, etc). As soon as your code hits prod you have “legacy” code.&lt;p&gt;New VP can make promises of future, theoretical riches that you can’t compete with, as you maintain the boring, current reality. Reality is not sexy or interesting. You’re in the old guard now.&lt;p&gt;A lot simply boils down to patronage. Making your higher up VP look successful and being in a position to move with them to their new company.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 04 Oct 2025 16:42:19 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45474627</link><dc:creator>softwaredoug</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45474627</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45474627</guid></item><item><title>New comment by lkrubner in "The collapse of the econ PhD job market"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;"Ordinary people—who watched their rent, groceries, and gas bills skyrocket—saw a profession more invested in protecting Democratic policy narratives than in telling the truth. The result is a self-inflicted torching of trust."&lt;p&gt;This post is ridiculously partisan. The head of the Fed was Republican, the majority of the Fed has always been Republican, the money-printing response to the Covid-19 pandemic began in 2020 when the President was a Republican, the majority of all economists are Republican, but somehow this writer blames this on Democrats? The result is a self-inflicted torching of trust.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 04 Oct 2025 16:39:14 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45474603</link><dc:creator>lkrubner</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45474603</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45474603</guid></item><item><title>New comment by getnormality in "How I influence tech company politics as a staff software engineer"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;It seems like this post can be summarized as follows:&lt;p&gt;1. If your manager has something in particular they want you to do, you should do it.&lt;p&gt;2. If your manager &lt;i&gt;doesn't&lt;/i&gt; have something in particular they want you to do, you should figure out what they will want you to do in the &lt;i&gt;future&lt;/i&gt;, and make any necessary preparations so that it will be doable when they want it.&lt;p&gt;I'd say it's good advice. The only thing I would add is that managers and leadership are &lt;i&gt;sometimes&lt;/i&gt; happy to be given something different than what they &lt;i&gt;asked for&lt;/i&gt;, so long as it's still what they &lt;i&gt;wanted&lt;/i&gt; at a higher level. This is risky, but success can be a fast track to respect and autonomy.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 04 Oct 2025 15:54:24 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45474227</link><dc:creator>getnormality</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45474227</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45474227</guid></item><item><title>New comment by simianparrot in "Sora Update #1"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&gt;  In particular, we'd like to acknowledge the remarkable creative output of Japan--we are struck by how deep the connection between users and Japanese content is!&lt;p&gt;Translation from snake speech bs: We've been threatened by Japanese artists via their lawyers that unless we remove the "Ghibli" feature that earned us so much money, and others like it, we're going to get absolutely destroyed in court.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 04 Oct 2025 09:05:51 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45471885</link><dc:creator>simianparrot</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45471885</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45471885</guid></item><item><title>New comment by ACCount37 in "Answering questions about Android developer verification"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Yep, it's as bad as everyone expected it to be. "We aren't taking away sideloading, we're just going to fully control it now! No Google-unapproved code on user devices! For security reasons!"&lt;p&gt;Chrome isn't enough. We need Android to get clawed away from Google too.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 04 Oct 2025 06:59:55 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45471186</link><dc:creator>ACCount37</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45471186</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45471186</guid></item><item><title>New comment by jcz_nz in "Asked to do something illegal at work? Here's what these software engineers did"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;At the very least, these folks need to have their names permanently attached to this atrocity. These weren’t decisions made by “a corporation” - these people sat across a meeting room table and actually concluded that targeting breast cancer patients was an acceptable means to an end.&lt;p&gt;Lori A. Beer was the CIO at the time.  Now at JP Morgan.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 04 Oct 2025 00:22:37 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45469309</link><dc:creator>jcz_nz</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45469309</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45469309</guid></item><item><title>New comment by mmastrac in "Zig builds are getting faster"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;LLVM is a trap. You bootstrap extra fast, you get all sorts of optimization passes and platforms for free, but you lose out on the ability to tune the final optimization passes and performance of the linking stages.&lt;p&gt;I think we'll see cranelift take off in Rust quite soon, though I also think it wouldn't be the juggernaut of a language if they hadn't stuck with LLVM those early years.&lt;p&gt;Go seems to have made the choice long ago to eschew outsourcing of codegen and linking and done well for it.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 04 Oct 2025 00:18:35 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45469281</link><dc:creator>mmastrac</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45469281</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45469281</guid></item><item><title>New comment by jcz_nz in "Asked to do something illegal at work? Here's what these software engineers did"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;In 2010 WellPoint was found to be automatically targeting insurance policies of women with breast cancer for cancellation, using any pretext.   Angela Braly was the CEO at the time, now at ExxonMobile.  WellPoint was the second largest health insurer in the US at the time.
This required a lot of business analysis and software development - and people had to realize what this code was doing. I’m guessing bonuses were paid on the back of the “savings” this generated.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 04 Oct 2025 00:17:45 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45469276</link><dc:creator>jcz_nz</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45469276</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45469276</guid></item><item><title>New comment by HumblyTossed in "LoRA Without Regret"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;The name gets me every single time. Always think it’s going to be about radio LoRa&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2025 23:05:06 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45468827</link><dc:creator>HumblyTossed</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45468827</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45468827</guid></item><item><title>New comment by renhanxue in "Offline card payments should be possible no later than 1 July 2026"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I'm Swedish and if someone insists on doing a transaction using cash when Swish or card is available, I'd immediately start to wonder if it's for some kind of more or less shady reason, probably tax evasion at the very least.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2025 22:59:34 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45468787</link><dc:creator>renhanxue</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45468787</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45468787</guid></item></channel></rss>