<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>Hacker News: Best Comments</title><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/bestcomments</link><description>Hacker News RSS</description><docs>https://hnrss.org/</docs><generator>hnrss v2.1.1</generator><lastBuildDate>Sat, 29 Nov 2025 01:03:50 +0000</lastBuildDate><ns0:link href="https://hnrss.org/bestcomments" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item><title>New comment by grishka in "Molly: An Improved Signal App"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&gt; What "proprietary blobs" does Signal have?&lt;p&gt;As they say in the Github readme, FCM and Google Maps.&lt;p&gt;FCM doesn't technically &lt;i&gt;require&lt;/i&gt; a blob — it's just that Google wants you to think it does. I reverse engineered their library and it turned out to be a criminally over-engineered wrapper around two broadcast receivers. So, the Mastodon app is proudly the first app ever to both support FCM push notifications, &lt;i&gt;and&lt;/i&gt; be 100% open-source.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 19:20:08 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46081855</link><dc:creator>grishka</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46081855</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46081855</guid></item><item><title>New comment by minimaxir in "28M Hacker News comments as vector embedding search dataset"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Don't use all-MiniLM-L6-v2 for new vector embeddings datasets.&lt;p&gt;Yes, it's the open-weights embedding model used in all the tutorials and it &lt;i&gt;was&lt;/i&gt; the most pragmatic model to use in sentence-transformers when vector stores were in their infancy, but it's old and does not implement the newest advances in architectures and data training pipelines, and it has a low context length of 512 when embedding models can do 2k+ with even more efficient tokenizers.&lt;p&gt;For open-weights, I would recommend EmbeddingGemma (&lt;a href="https://huggingface.co/google/embeddinggemma-300m" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://huggingface.co/google/embeddinggemma-300m&lt;/a&gt;) instead which has incredible benchmarks and a 2k context window: although it's larger/slower to encode, the payoff is worth it. For a compromise, bge-base-en-v1.5 (&lt;a href="https://huggingface.co/BAAI/bge-base-en-v1.5" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://huggingface.co/BAAI/bge-base-en-v1.5&lt;/a&gt;) or nomic-embed-text-v1.5 (&lt;a href="https://huggingface.co/nomic-ai/nomic-embed-text-v1.5" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://huggingface.co/nomic-ai/nomic-embed-text-v1.5&lt;/a&gt;) are also good.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 19:14:51 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46081800</link><dc:creator>minimaxir</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46081800</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46081800</guid></item><item><title>New comment by elevation in "Bringing Sexy Back. Internet surveillance has killed eroticism"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&gt; She demanded that I apologize to the women&lt;p&gt;This is antisocial advice.  It's beyond inappropriate to use the pretense of apology to announce your intimate fantasies to strangers.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 18:43:13 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46081476</link><dc:creator>elevation</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46081476</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46081476</guid></item><item><title>New comment by mjr00 in "Bringing Sexy Back. Internet surveillance has killed eroticism"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;The main thing I get out of this article is how easy it is to get trapped in a bubble thanks to algorithmic social media.&lt;p&gt;For the most part, sexy never left, and statistics bear this out. OnlyFans brings in enormous amount of revenue, even after an expensive, failed attempt to be not-just-a-porn-site. Hypersexualized gacha games are pulling in tens of millions of dollars per month, and not just for men; the women-targeted &lt;i&gt;Love and Deepspace&lt;/i&gt; had over $50 million in revenue in October. Marvel Rivals, criticized in some circles (such as the social circles of those in the article) for being an oversexualized "gooner game" has remained in the top 10 games played on Steam since its release a year ago. And nothing drives it home more than stumbling across the shady side of YouTube and finding videos in the "woman with large breasts not wearing a bra does something mundane" genre with multiple millions of views.&lt;p&gt;&gt; I choose these examples from my personal life because they express sentiments that were once the kind of stuff I encountered only in the messy battlegrounds of Twitter, amid discussions about whether Sabrina Carpenter is being oversexualized, whether kinks are akin to a sexual orientation, whether a woman can truly consent in an age-gap relationship, and whether exposure to sex scenes in movies violates viewer consent.&lt;p&gt;Ultimately, these are the kind of things discussed only by a small, vocal, very online (some might say &lt;i&gt;terminally&lt;/i&gt; online) minority. To think that they represent more than a tiny fraction of the world is, again, reflective of how easy it is to get trapped into online echo chambers.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 18:00:50 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46081037</link><dc:creator>mjr00</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46081037</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46081037</guid></item><item><title>New comment by simianparrot in "A Remarkable Assertion from A16Z"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Keep this in mind if you _ever_ feel tempted to take A16Z seriously. Absolute charlatans and clowns.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 14:30:45 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46078969</link><dc:creator>simianparrot</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46078969</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46078969</guid></item><item><title>New comment by jsheard in "A Remarkable Assertion from A16Z"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Since the commit history is public, there's a much easier way to tell that AI had a hand in writing that list.&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/a16z-infra/reading-list/commit/93bc3abb04e241ccc1e6b79f4f698247177fb765" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://github.com/a16z-infra/reading-list/commit/93bc3abb04...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;&gt; opus descriptions in cursor, raw&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 14:14:44 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46078827</link><dc:creator>jsheard</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46078827</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46078827</guid></item><item><title>New comment by SiempreViernes in "EU Council Approves New "Chat Control" Mandate Pushing Mass Surveillance"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Well, the impression of speed is mainly in the head of the headline writers.&lt;p&gt;What has actually happened is that after about three years of faffing about the Council finally decided on it negotiation position begore the Coreper 2 meeting last week, thought it seems they ran put of time at actual the meeting and had to have the formal approval this week.&lt;p&gt;The Council is only one of three parties that draft new laws, so now there's are still several rounds of negotiations left.&lt;p&gt;Nothing substantial has happened to the three texts since last week, it's just that "chat control is back" drives traffic and "Council preparatory body formally approves draft position that got consensus previously but didn't formally get passed because people were fighting over Ukraine stuff for too long" doesn't.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 11:23:41 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46077663</link><dc:creator>SiempreViernes</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46077663</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46077663</guid></item><item><title>New comment by piker in "EU Council Approves New "Chat Control" Mandate Pushing Mass Surveillance"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Even living nearby in the UK it blows my mind how quickly the EU proposes, kills and then revives and passes controversial legislation in such a short timeframe.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 10:57:03 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46077508</link><dc:creator>piker</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46077508</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46077508</guid></item><item><title>New comment by whizzter in "250MWh 'Sand Battery' to start construction in Finland"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;For reference, this city is about as north as Anchorage Alaska and today they got less than 7 hours of sunlight and it'll continue to decrease for the next 3 weeks.&lt;p&gt;The Nordic countries generally still wants to increase their wind and solar power, but the big issue during winters is when there's cold air high pressure systems we get neither sun nor wind, having an energy storage that can hold up to 5 days worth of energy should help us nudge past them.&lt;p&gt;Hydro-energy exist (mainly Sweden and Norway, but I think some in Finland as well), but it's fairly built out so stable non-fossil power needs to be nuclear, or wind/sun + storage (that hasn't been good enough so far).&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2025 23:12:21 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46074012</link><dc:creator>whizzter</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46074012</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46074012</guid></item><item><title>New comment by andy99 in "LinkedIn is loud, and corporate is hell"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Is there some legitimate thing people are doing on LinkedIn that the crap is getting in the way of? One can make a profile and (thought it’s terrible for this) search for jobs without ever scrolling the feed. If you don’t like it just don’t use it.&lt;p&gt;It feels like complaining that the strip bar has alcohol and nudity everywhere, why are you there?&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2025 22:03:20 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46073603</link><dc:creator>andy99</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46073603</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46073603</guid></item><item><title>New comment by nrclark in "Same-day upstream Linux support for Snapdragon 8 Elite Gen 5"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;If anybody in Qualcomm leadership is reading this thread: this is a good start, and I applaud you for it. There is also a lot more to do if you're serious about growing your market penetration beyond phones.&lt;p&gt;The drivers might be up on LKML, but they're not mainlined yet. And this is just gen5. It would be great if you could fix your gen4 and 4.5 drivers, so that people building products with your chips weren't stuck on an orphaned vendor kernel that doesn't even upstream to your public fork.&lt;p&gt;Also your boot-chain is still closed and proprietary, and completely different than the one used by all other ARM vendors. Being the special snowflake is not helping your business or your customers.&lt;p&gt;And don't even get me started on Gunyah and GearVM, or on the proprietary, locked nature of your BSP, or how far behind TI and NXP you are on software quality and ease of use. Maybe also consider releasing some actual documentation on your chips.&lt;p&gt;I know multiple developers who have sworn off Qualcomm and will never design with your chips again at any price point. Your closed-off support model is 100% the culprit, and it hurts your core business. Any software support revenue that you managage to extract comes at the cost of goodwill and future chip sales.&lt;p&gt;Your chips are good - best in the industry. If you can up your software game to match, you'll really meet your potential.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2025 21:14:35 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46073287</link><dc:creator>nrclark</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46073287</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46073287</guid></item><item><title>New comment by coffeecoders in "We're losing our voice to LLMs"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I actually think we’re overestimating how much of "losing our voice" is caused by LLMs. Even before LLMs, we were doing the same tweet-sized takes, the same medium-style blog posts and the same corporate tone.&lt;p&gt;Ironically, LLMs might end up forcing us back toward more distinct voices because sameness has become the default background.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2025 16:40:53 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46070898</link><dc:creator>coffeecoders</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46070898</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46070898</guid></item><item><title>New comment by ricardo81 in "We're losing our voice to LLMs"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I deleted my Facebook account a couple of years ago and my Twitter one yesterday.&lt;p&gt;It's not just LLMs, it's how the algorithms promote engagement. i.e. rage bait, videos with obvious inaccuracies etc. Who gets rewarded, the content creators and the platform. Engaging with it just seems to accentuate the problem.&lt;p&gt;There needs to be algorithms that promote cohorts and individuals preferences.&lt;p&gt;Just because I said to someone 'Brexit was dumb', I don't expect to get fed 1000 accounts talking about it 24/7. It's tedious and unproductive.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2025 16:01:14 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46070473</link><dc:creator>ricardo81</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46070473</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46070473</guid></item><item><title>New comment by m4r1k in "TPUs vs. GPUs and why Google is positioned to win AI race in the long term"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Google's real moat isn't the TPU silicon itself—it's not about cooling, individual performance, or hyper-specialization—but rather the massive parallel scale enabled by their OCS interconnects.&lt;p&gt;To quote The Next Platform: "An Ironwood cluster linked with Google’s absolutely unique optical circuit switch interconnect can bring to bear 9,216 Ironwood TPUs with a combined 1.77 PB of HBM memory... This makes a rackscale Nvidia system based on 144 “Blackwell” GPU chiplets with an aggregate of 20.7 TB of HBM memory look like a joke."&lt;p&gt;Nvidia may have the superior architecture at the single-chip level, but for large-scale distributed training (and inference) they currently have nothing that rivals Google's optical switching scalability.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2025 15:42:27 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46070265</link><dc:creator>m4r1k</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46070265</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46070265</guid></item><item><title>New comment by Orygin in "The current state of the theory that GPL propagates to AI models"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Great article but I don't really agree with their take on GPL regarding this paragraph:&lt;p&gt;&gt; The spirit of the GPL is to promote the free sharing and development of software [...] the reality is that they are proceeding in a different vector from the direction of code sharing idealized by GPL. If only the theory of GPL propagation to models walks alone, in reality, only data exclusion and closing off to avoid litigation risks will progress, and there is a fear that it will not lead to the expansion of free software culture.&lt;p&gt;The spirit of the GPL is the freedom of the user, not the code being freely shared. The virality is a byproduct to ensure the software is not stolen from their users. If you just want your code to be shared and used without restrictions, use MIT or some other license.&lt;p&gt;&gt; What is important is how to realize the “freedom of software,” which is the philosophy of open source&lt;p&gt;Freedom of software means nothing. Freedoms are for humans not immaterial code. Users get the freedom to enjoy the software how they like. Washing the code through an AI to purge it from its license goes against the open source philosophy. (I know this may be a mistranslation, but it goes in the same direction as the rest of the article).&lt;p&gt;I also don't agree with the arguments that since a lot of things are included in the model, the GPL code is only a small part of the whole, and that means it's okay. Well if I take 1 GPL function and include it in my project, no matter its size, I would have to license as GPL. Where is the line? Why would my software which only contains a single function not be fair use?&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2025 14:52:17 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46069783</link><dc:creator>Orygin</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46069783</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46069783</guid></item><item><title>New comment by cobertos in "Mixpanel Security Breach"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I _hate_ how this is written. At no point does it disclose explicitly:&lt;p&gt;* What systems were accessed&lt;p&gt;* What information was potentially exposed&lt;p&gt;* Just how "proactively" they've been about this (no timeline)&lt;p&gt;* Numbers... The scale of any of it&lt;p&gt;---&lt;p&gt;Some comments from quoted portions of article&lt;p&gt;&gt; Mixpanel detected a smishing campaign ...&lt;p&gt;Doesn't give any details on who the companion targeted, or how, or how widespread.&lt;p&gt;&gt; We took comprehensive steps to contain and eradicate unauthorized access and secure impacted user accounts.&lt;p&gt;So there was definitely _some_ sort of unauthorized access, but doesn't say to which accounts or in what systems&lt;p&gt;&gt; Performed global password resets for all Mixpanel employees&lt;p&gt;So... definitely sounds like they expected compromise of Mixpanel employee credentials&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2025 08:48:32 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46067189</link><dc:creator>cobertos</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46067189</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46067189</guid></item><item><title>New comment by jetsnoc in "Tell HN: Happy Thanksgiving"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Sixteen years here, and the half-life decay of this community has been slower than anywhere else. That takes real, consistent work, and we have been lucky to have it. Through good times and rough ones, including the loss of Aaron Swartz (who I only knew of through HN), this has stayed a place for real conversation.&lt;p&gt;The grit, curiosity, and people building things have always been inspiring.&lt;p&gt;Thanks for all the discussions over the years.&lt;p&gt;Happy Thanksgiving!&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2025 05:52:21 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46066132</link><dc:creator>jetsnoc</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46066132</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46066132</guid></item><item><title>New comment by quantummagic in "Migrating the main Zig repository from GitHub to Codeberg"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Codes of conduct are perfunctory virtue signalling.  Do we really need a unique set of "rules" posted on every project?  They all sound like they were written by the same AI bot.  That said, it's telling that the Zig leader can't even follow them.  The rules should just be taken down.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2025 05:03:52 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46065858</link><dc:creator>quantummagic</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46065858</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46065858</guid></item><item><title>New comment by ericpruitt in "Migrating the main Zig repository from GitHub to Codeberg"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Amusingly, this post violates Zig's own code of conduct: &lt;a href="https://ziglang.org/code-of-conduct" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://ziglang.org/code-of-conduct&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;&gt; Examples of behavior that contribute to creating a positive environment include:&lt;p&gt;&gt; - Using welcoming and inclusive language.&lt;p&gt;&gt; - Being respectful of differing viewpoints and experiences.&lt;p&gt;&gt; - Showing empathy towards others.&lt;p&gt;&gt; - Showing appreciation for others’ work.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2025 04:49:02 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46065778</link><dc:creator>ericpruitt</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46065778</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46065778</guid></item><item><title>New comment by ssivark in "Migrating the main Zig repository from GitHub to Codeberg"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&gt;  created by monkeys&lt;p&gt;I don't particularly care for either Zig or Github, but...&lt;p&gt;they do precisely cite the technical issues. That snippet links to a Github discussion comment &lt;a href="https://github.com/actions/runner/issues/3792#issuecomment-3182746514" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://github.com/actions/runner/issues/3792#issuecomment-3...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;(reproduced below)&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;"The bug in this "safe sleep" script is obvious from looking at it: if the process is not scheduled for the one-second interval in which the loop would return (due to $SECONDS having the correct value), then it simply spins forever. That can easily happen on a CI machine under extreme load. When this happens, it's pretty bad: it completely breaks a runner until manual intervention. On Zig's CI runner machines, we observed multiple of these processes which had been running for hundreds of hours, silently taking down two runner services for weeks."&lt;/i&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;"I don't understand how we got here. Even ignoring the pretty clear bug, what makes this Bash script "safer" than calling into the POSIX standard sleep utility? It doesn't seem to solve any problem; meanwhile, it's less portable and needlessly eats CPU time by busy-waiting."&lt;/i&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;"The sloppy coding which is evident here, as well as the inaction on core Actions bugs (in line with the decay in quality of almost every part of GitHub's product), is forcing the Zig project to strongly consider moving away from GitHub Actions entirely. With this bug, and many others (severe workflow scheduling issues resulting in dozens of timeouts; logs randomly becoming inaccessible; random job cancellations without details; perpetually "pending" jobs), we can no longer trust that Actions can be used to implement reliable CI infrastructure. I personally would seriously encourage other projects, particularly any using self-hosted runners, to look carefully at the stability of Actions and ask themselves whether it is a solution worth sticking with long-term when compared with alternatives."&lt;/i&gt;&lt;p&gt;----&lt;p&gt;I agree that the writing in the blog post is more colorful than precise, but sanitizing every bit of expression dulls the internet. Humans invented language for a reason.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2025 04:36:06 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46065705</link><dc:creator>ssivark</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46065705</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46065705</guid></item><item><title>New comment by johnfn in "Migrating the main Zig repository from GitHub to Codeberg"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&gt; it’s abundantly clear that the talented folks who used to work on the product have moved on to bigger and better things, with the remaining losers eager to inflict some kind of bloated, buggy JavaScript framework on us in the name of progress.&lt;p&gt;&gt; More importantly, Actions is created by monkeys&lt;p&gt;This writing really does not reflect well on Zig. If you have technical issues with Github, fine: cite them. But leave ad hominems like "losers" and "monkeys" out of it.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2025 03:47:02 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46065366</link><dc:creator>johnfn</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46065366</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46065366</guid></item><item><title>New comment by nxobject in "Green card interviews end in handcuffs for spouses of U.S. citizens"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;A note that it's easy to "overstay" a visa when waiting for a green card interview - the wait times are often in the 6-16 month range, and if you leave the country you'll be considered to have abandoned your "petition to adjust status". It's a catch-22, and it looks like the only recourse is for an immigration lawyer to file a habeas corpus petition in federal court.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2025 02:51:31 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46065016</link><dc:creator>nxobject</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46065016</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46065016</guid></item><item><title>New comment by quirino in "Migrating the main Zig repository from GitHub to Codeberg"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&gt; As a bonus, we look forward to fewer violations (exhibit A, B, C) of our strict no LLM / no AI policy,&lt;p&gt;Hilarious how the offender on "exhibit A" [1] is the same one from the other post that made the frontpage a couple of days ago [2].&lt;p&gt;[1] &lt;a href="https://github.com/ziglang/zig/issues/25974" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://github.com/ziglang/zig/issues/25974&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;[2] &lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46039274"&gt;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46039274&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2025 02:50:30 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46065008</link><dc:creator>quirino</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46065008</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46065008</guid></item><item><title>New comment by munchler in "Migrating the main Zig repository from GitHub to Codeberg"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;It’s more likely that most of them are competent professionals doing their best in an impersonal corporate environment, just like the rest of us.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2025 02:44:21 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46064970</link><dc:creator>munchler</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46064970</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46064970</guid></item><item><title>New comment by decimalenough in "Bring bathroom doors back to hotels"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I once stayed at a very boutiquey, avant-garde hotel with a platonic friend. We had booked a twin room with separate beds, but what I did not expect was that the shower cubicle, with clear glass on all three sides, would be placed between the beds.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2025 02:41:47 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46064952</link><dc:creator>decimalenough</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46064952</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46064952</guid></item><item><title>New comment by munchler in "Migrating the main Zig repository from GitHub to Codeberg"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Calling the people who work on GitHub “losers” is not cool.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2025 02:33:44 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46064895</link><dc:creator>munchler</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46064895</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46064895</guid></item><item><title>New comment by SoKamil in "Migrating the main Zig repository from GitHub to Codeberg"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&gt; As a bonus, we look forward to fewer violations (exhibit A, B, C) of our strict no LLM / no AI policy, which I believe are at least in part due to GitHub aggressively pushing the “file an issue with Copilot” feature in everyone’s face.&lt;p&gt;Also, the big part of that issue is people are incentivized to make their GitHub profile look good to have a higher chance of getting hired. Any non-mainstream platform is not as compelling to get social credits.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2025 02:16:53 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46064782</link><dc:creator>SoKamil</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46064782</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46064782</guid></item><item><title>New comment by majormajor in "Bring bathroom doors back to hotels"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I don't think that adds up.&lt;p&gt;"Staying in a hotel with a romantic partner and/or family" is &lt;i&gt;at least&lt;/i&gt; as primary a use case for hotels as "staying in a hotel with a platonic friend" and is still a scenario where you want a door but is NOT a scenario where "just get separate rooms" is a logical conclusion. "Get the hell out of that hotel and complain about it to everyone you know," on the other hand, is.&lt;p&gt;The much more specific way to target platonic buddies/coworkers from sharing a room would be &lt;i&gt;eliminating rooms with two beds&lt;/i&gt; since the "couple" scenario would generally be perfectly happy with that still.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2025 01:10:25 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46064316</link><dc:creator>majormajor</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46064316</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46064316</guid></item><item><title>New comment by preommr in "Gemini CLI tips and tricks for agentic coding"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I am not doing any of this.&lt;p&gt;It becomes obsolete in literally weeks, and it also doesn't work 80% of the time. Like why write a mcp server for custom tasks when I don't know if the llm is going to reliably call it.&lt;p&gt;My rule for AI has been steadfast for months (years?) now. I write (myself, not AI because then I spend more time guiding the AI instead of thinking about the problem) documentation for myself (templates, checklist, etc.). I give ai a chance to one-shot it in seconds, if it can't, I am either review my documentation or I just do it manually.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2025 00:24:15 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46063949</link><dc:creator>preommr</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46063949</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46063949</guid></item><item><title>New comment by meisel in "Bring bathroom doors back to hotels"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;While we’re at it, bring back shower doors/curtains. It’s such a pain having this huge puddle outside the shower just because they decided it shouldn’t have one. It’s not so common to be missing one in US hotels, but it’s common internationally.&lt;p&gt;Edit: apparently the virus has spread, and some US hotels now don’t have them&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2025 00:21:52 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46063921</link><dc:creator>meisel</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46063921</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46063921</guid></item></channel></rss>