<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>Hacker News: Best Comments</title><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/bestcomments</link><description>Hacker News RSS</description><docs>https://hnrss.org/</docs><generator>hnrss v2.1.1</generator><lastBuildDate>Sat, 24 Jan 2026 00:29:36 +0000</lastBuildDate><ns0:link href="https://hnrss.org/bestcomments" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item><title>New comment by thewebguyd in "Microsoft gave FBI set of BitLocker encryption keys to unlock suspects' laptops"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&gt; Any power users who prefer their own key management should follow the steps to enable Bitlocker without uploading keys to a connected Microsoft account.&lt;p&gt;Except the steps to to that are disable bitlocker, create a local user account (assuming you initially signed in with a Microsoft account because Ms now forces it on you for home editions of windows), delete your existing keys from OneDrive, then re-encrypt using your local account and make sure not to sign into your Microsoft account or link it to Windows again.&lt;p&gt;A much more sensible default would be to give the user a choice right from the beginning much like how Apple does it. When you go through set up assistant on mac, it doesn't assume you are an idiot and literally asks you up front "Do you want to store your recovery key in iCloud or not?"&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 19:01:23 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46736345</link><dc:creator>thewebguyd</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46736345</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46736345</guid></item><item><title>New comment by ferrouswheel in "Microsoft gave FBI set of BitLocker encryption keys to unlock suspects' laptops"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;It's interesting how many comments these days are like, "well of course".&lt;p&gt;Back in the day hackernews had some fire and resistance.&lt;p&gt;Too many tech workers decided to rollover for the government and that's why we are in this mess now.&lt;p&gt;This isn't an argument about law, it's about designing secure systems. And lazy engineers build lazy key escrow the government can exploit.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 18:30:45 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46735925</link><dc:creator>ferrouswheel</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46735925</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46735925</guid></item><item><title>New comment by ppchain in "Proof of Corn"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;The point they seem to be making is that AI can "orchestrate" the real world even if it can't interact physically. I can definitely believe that in 2026 someone at their computer with access to money can send the right emails and make the right bank transfers to get real people to grow corn for you.&lt;p&gt;However even by that metric I don't see how Claude is doing that. Seth is the one researching the suppliers "with the help of" Claude. Seth is presumably the one deciding when to prompt Claude to make decisions about if they should plant in Iowa in how many days. I think I could also grow corn if someone came and asked me well defined questions and then acted on what I said. I might even be better at it because unlike a Claude output I will still be conscious in 30 seconds.&lt;p&gt;That is a far cry from sitting down at a command like and saying "Do everything necessary to grow 500 bushels of corn by October".&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 18:29:50 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46735913</link><dc:creator>ppchain</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46735913</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46735913</guid></item><item><title>New comment by Aurornis in "Microsoft gave FBI set of BitLocker encryption keys to unlock suspects' laptops"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;FYI BitLocker is on by default in Windows 11. The defaults will also upload the BitLocker key to a Microsoft Account if available.&lt;p&gt;This is why the FBI can compel Microsoft to provide the keys. It's possible, perhaps even likely, that the suspect didn't even know they had an encrypted laptop. Journalists love the "Microsoft &lt;i&gt;gave&lt;/i&gt;" framing because it makes Microsoft sound like they're handing these out because they like the cops, but that's not how it works. If your company has data that the police want and they can get a warrant, you have no choice but to give it to them.&lt;p&gt;This makes the privacy purists angry, but in my opinion it's the reasonable default for the average computer user. It protects their data in the event that someone steals the laptop, but still allows them to recover their own data later from the hard drive.&lt;p&gt;Any power users who prefer their own key management should follow the steps to enable Bitlocker without uploading keys to a connected Microsoft account.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 18:11:28 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46735691</link><dc:creator>Aurornis</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46735691</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46735691</guid></item><item><title>New comment by mediaman in "Gas Town's agent patterns, design bottlenecks, and vibecoding at scale"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I don't get the widespread hatred of Gas Town. If you read Steve's writeup, it's clear that this is a big fun experiment.&lt;p&gt;It pushes and crosses boundaries, it is a mixture of technology and art, it is provocative. It takes stochastic neural nets and mashes them together in bizarre ways to see if anything coherent comes out the other end.&lt;p&gt;And the reaction is a bunch of Very Serious Engineers who cross their arms and harumph at it for being Unprofessional and Not Serious and Not Ready For Production.&lt;p&gt;I often feel like our industry has lost its sense of whimsy and experimentation from the early days, when people tried weird things to see what would work and what wouldn't.&lt;p&gt;Maybe it's because we also have suits telling us we have to use neural nets everywhere for everything Or Else, and there's no sense of fun in that.&lt;p&gt;Maybe it's the natural consequence of large-scale professionalization, and stock option plans and RSUs and levels and sprints and PMs, that today's gray hoodie is just the updated gray suit of the past but with no less dryness of imagination.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 17:18:13 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46735034</link><dc:creator>mediaman</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46735034</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46735034</guid></item><item><title>New comment by cranx in "Replacing Protobuf with Rust"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I find the title a bit misleading. I think it should be titled It’s Faster to Copy Memory Directly than Send a Protobuf. Which then seems rather obvious that removing a serialization and deserialization step reduces runtime.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 12:04:58 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46731510</link><dc:creator>cranx</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46731510</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46731510</guid></item><item><title>New comment by Version467 in "AI Usage Policy"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;The biggest surprise to me with all this low-quality contribution spam is how little shame people apparently have. I have a handful of open source contributions. All of them are for small-ish projects and the complexity of my contributions are in the same ball-park as what I work on day-to-day. And even though I am relatively confident in my competency as a developer, these contributions are probably the most thoroughly tested and reviewed pieces of code I have ever written. I just really, really don't want to bother someone with low quality "help" who graciously offers their time to work on open source stuff.&lt;p&gt;Other people apparently don't have this feeling at all. Maybe I shouldn't have been surprised by this, but I've definitely been caught off guard by it.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 11:29:40 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46731238</link><dc:creator>Version467</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46731238</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46731238</guid></item><item><title>New comment by 01jonny01 in "Updates to our web search products and  Programmable Search Engine capabilities"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Google quietly announced that Programmable Search (ex-Custom Search) won’t allow new engines to “search the entire web” anymore. New engines are capped at searching up to 50 domains, and existing full-web engines have until Jan 1, 2027 to transition.&lt;p&gt;If you actually need whole-web search, Google now points you to an “interest form” for enterprise solutions (Vertex AI Search etc.), with no public pricing and no guarantee they’ll even reply.&lt;p&gt;This seems like it effectively ends the era of indie / niche search engines being able to build on Google’s index. Anything that looks like general web search is getting pushed behind enterprise gates.&lt;p&gt;I haven’t seen much discussion about this yet, but for anyone who built a small search product on Programmable Search, this feels like a pretty big shift.&lt;p&gt;Curious if others here are affected or already planning alternatives.&lt;p&gt;UPDATE: I logged into Programmable Search and the message is even more explicit: Full web search via the "Search the entire web" feature will be discontinued within the next year. Please update your search engine to specify specific sites to search. With this link: &lt;a href="https://support.google.com/programmable-search/answer/12397162" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://support.google.com/programmable-search/answer/123971...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 09:38:02 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46730437</link><dc:creator>01jonny01</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46730437</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46730437</guid></item><item><title>New comment by ivan_gammel in "Proton Spam and the AI Consent Problem"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I think we must make it clear that this is not related to AI at all, even if the product in question is AI-related.&lt;p&gt;It is a very common problem with modern marketing teams, that have zero empathy for customers (even if they have one, they will never push back on whatever insane demands come from senior management). This is why any email subscription management interface now is as bloated as a dead whale. If too many users unsubscribe, they just add one more category and “accidentally” opt-in everyone.&lt;p&gt;It’s a shame that Proton marketing team is just like every other one. Maybe it’s a curse of growing organization and middle management creep. The least we can do is push back as customers.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 07:57:13 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46729756</link><dc:creator>ivan_gammel</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46729756</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46729756</guid></item><item><title>New comment by chc4 in "Proton Spam and the AI Consent Problem"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I saw a Mastodon tweet a while ago, which went something like:&lt;p&gt;Do tech companies understand consent?:&lt;p&gt;- [ ] Yes&lt;p&gt;- [ ] Ask me again in a few days&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 07:28:34 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46729548</link><dc:creator>chc4</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46729548</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46729548</guid></item><item><title>New comment by ori_b in "Capital One to acquire Brex for $5.15B"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I guess it's not a bad Brexit.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 23:19:48 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46726383</link><dc:creator>ori_b</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46726383</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46726383</guid></item><item><title>New comment by indiantinker in "I was banned from Claude for scaffolding a Claude.md file?"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Once men turned their thinking over to machines in the hope that this would set them free.
But that only permitted other men with machines to enslave them.
Frank Herbert, Dune, 1965&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 22:39:09 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46726046</link><dc:creator>indiantinker</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46726046</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46726046</guid></item><item><title>New comment by crazygringo in "Show HN: isometric.nyc – giant isometric pixel art map of NYC"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I just want to say this isn't just amazing -- it's my new favorite map of NYC.&lt;p&gt;It's genuinely astonishing how much &lt;i&gt;clearer&lt;/i&gt; this is than a traditional satellite map -- how it has just the right amount of complexity. I'm looking at areas I've spent a lot of time in, and getting an even better conceptual understanding of the physical layout than I've ever been able to get from satellite (technically airplane) images. This hits the perfect "sweet spot" of detail with clear "cartoon" coloring.&lt;p&gt;I see a lot of criticism here that this isn't "pixel art", so maybe there's some better term to use. I don't know what to call this precise style -- it's almost pixel art without the pixels? -- but I love it. Serious congratulations.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 22:14:23 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46725805</link><dc:creator>crazygringo</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46725805</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46725805</guid></item><item><title>New comment by i_am_proteus in "GPTZero finds 100 new hallucinations in NeurIPS 2025 accepted papers"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&gt;this error does make me pause to wonder how much of the rest of the paper used AI assistance&lt;p&gt;And this is what's operative here. The error spotted, the entire &lt;i&gt;class&lt;/i&gt; of error spotted, is easily checked/verified by a non-domain expert.  These are the errors we can confirm readily, with obvious and unmistakable signature of hallucination.&lt;p&gt;If these are the only errors, we are not troubled. However: we do not know if these are the only errors, they are merely a signature that the paper was submitted without being thoroughly checked for hallucinations. They are a signature that some LLM was used to generate parts of the paper and the responsible authors used this LLM without care.&lt;p&gt;Checking the rest of the paper requires domain expertise, perhaps requires an attempt at reproducing the authors' results. That the rest of the paper is now in doubt, and that this problem is so widespread, threatens the validity of the fundamental activity these papers represent: research.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 19:49:42 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46724294</link><dc:creator>i_am_proteus</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46724294</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46724294</guid></item><item><title>New comment by j2kun in "GPTZero finds 100 new hallucinations in NeurIPS 2025 accepted papers"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I spot-checked one of the flagged papers (from Google, co-authored by a colleague of mine)&lt;p&gt;The paper was &lt;a href="https://openreview.net/forum?id=0ZnXGzLcOg" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://openreview.net/forum?id=0ZnXGzLcOg&lt;/a&gt; and the problem flagged was "Two authors are omitted and one (Kyle Richardson) is added. This paper was published at ICLR 2024." I.e., for one cited paper, the author list was off and the venue was wrong. And this citation was mentioned in the background section of the paper, and not fundamental to the validity of the paper. So the citation was not fabricated, but it was incorrectly attributed (perhaps via use of an AI autocomplete).&lt;p&gt;I think there are some egregious papers in their dataset, and this error does make me pause to wonder how much of the rest of the paper used AI assistance. That said, the "single error" papers in the dataset seem similar to the one I checked: relatively harmless and minor errors (which would be immediately caught by a DOI checker), and so I have to assume some of these were included in the dataset mainly to amplify the author's product pitch. It succeeded.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 18:52:28 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46723555</link><dc:creator>j2kun</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46723555</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46723555</guid></item><item><title>New comment by owenversteeg in "In Europe, wind and solar overtake fossil fuels"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;The only asterisk this time is that this is electricity, not energy. Still impressive, but electricity is only 22% of total energy use, so they are at about 12% of the total for the EU and 7.8% for Europe.&lt;p&gt;For that, you want this graph: &lt;a href="https://ourworldindata.org/grapher/energy-consumption-by-source-and-country?country=~OWID_EU27" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://ourworldindata.org/grapher/energy-consumption-by-sou...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;Fun to play around with, you can also change the selection to view the world, US, China, individual EU countries etc.&lt;p&gt;You can see that this the gain in renewables in the EU has been mainly at the expense of coal (down &gt;50% as a share of total energy use in 10 years), gas (down 4%), and nuclear (down 20%.) Oil use as a share of the total is up by 5%.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 17:44:54 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46722628</link><dc:creator>owenversteeg</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46722628</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46722628</guid></item><item><title>New comment by mortsnort in "Qwen3-TTS family is now open sourced: Voice design, clone, and generation"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;They were just waiting for someone in the comments to ask!&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 16:26:54 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46721415</link><dc:creator>mortsnort</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46721415</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46721415</guid></item><item><title>New comment by kokey in "In Europe, wind and solar overtake fossil fuels"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Every time, over the years, that there has been some kind of headline saying renewables have overtaken fossil fuels, when you look at it a bit more closely there is always a big 'but'.   For example, it was compared to coal (not taking into account electricity from gas), or it was for one day, or it was a percentage of new installations, or it excludes winter, includes nuclear etc.&lt;p&gt;This time, however, it looks like it's actually true and that's just for wind and solar.   This is incredible, and done through slowly compounding gains that didn't cause massive economic hardships along the way.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 16:06:59 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46721116</link><dc:creator>kokey</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46721116</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46721116</guid></item><item><title>New comment by testing22321 in "In Europe, wind and solar overtake fossil fuels"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Solar prices in the US are criminal, protecting oil and gas who bought all the politicians.&lt;p&gt;Canada here. 7.6kw on our roof for $0 out of pocket thanks to $5k grant and $8k interest free loan.&lt;p&gt;It makes 7.72Mwh per year, worth $1000. Tight valley, tons of snow.
We put that on the loan for 8 years, then get $1000 per year free money for 20 years or so. Biggest no brainer of all time.&lt;p&gt;Dad in Victoria Australia just got 10.6kw fully installed and operational for $4000 AUD. ($2,700 USD)&lt;p&gt;Australia has so much electricity during the day they’re talking about making I free for everyone in the middle of the day.&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-03/energy-retailers-offer-free-power-three-hours-dmo/105965472#:~:text=The%20Solar%20Sharer%20scheme%20is%20a%20federal,power%20is%20being%20fed%20into%20the%20grid" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-03/energy-retailers-offe...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 15:38:57 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46720675</link><dc:creator>testing22321</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46720675</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46720675</guid></item><item><title>New comment by cogman10 in "GPTZero finds 100 new hallucinations in NeurIPS 2025 accepted papers"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Yuck, this is going to really harm scientific research.&lt;p&gt;There is already a problem with papers falsifying data/samples/etc, LLMs being able to put out plausible papers is just going to make it worse.&lt;p&gt;On the bright side, maybe this will get the scientific community and science journalists to finally take reproducibility more seriously.  I'd love to see future reporting that instead of saying "Research finds amazing chemical x which does y" you see "Researcher reproduces amazing results for chemical x which does y.  First discovered by z".&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 15:34:40 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46720609</link><dc:creator>cogman10</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46720609</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46720609</guid></item><item><title>New comment by koliber in "We will ban you and ridicule you in public if you waste our time on crap reports"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I've seen an interesting behavior in India. If I ask someone on the street for directions, they will always give me an answer, even if they don't know. If they don't know, they'll make something up.&lt;p&gt;This was strange. I asked a lot of Indian people about it and they said that it has to do with "saving face". Saying "I don't know" is a disgraceful thing. So if someone does not know the answer, they make something up instead.&lt;p&gt;Have you seen this?&lt;p&gt;This behavior appears in software projects as well. It's difficult to work like this.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 13:02:29 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46718693</link><dc:creator>koliber</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46718693</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46718693</guid></item><item><title>New comment by mixedbit in "We will ban you and ridicule you in public if you waste our time on crap reports"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Long time ago Sourceforge and then GitHub promoted into the current default the model of open source distribution which is not sustainable and I doubt it is something that the founding fathers of Free Software/Open Source had in mind. Open source licenses are about freedom of using and modifying software. The movement grew out of frustration that commercial software cannot be freely improved and fixed by the user to better fit the user's needs. To create Free software, you ship sources together with your binaries and one of the OSI-approved licenses, that is all. The currently default model of having an open issue tracker, accepting third party pull requests, doing code reviews, providing support by email or chat, timely security patches etc, has nothing to do with open source and is not sustainable. This is OK if it is done for a hobby project as long as the author is having fun doing this work, but as soon as the software is used for commercial, production critical systems, the default expectation that authors will be promptly responding to new GitHub issues, bug reports and provide patches for free is insane. This is software support, it is a job, it should be paid.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 12:22:54 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46718329</link><dc:creator>mixedbit</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46718329</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46718329</guid></item><item><title>New comment by MarginalGainz in "eBay explicitly bans AI "buy for me" agents in user agreement update"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;This ban isn't about 'fairness' or bot protection; it's about protecting the Impression Funnel.&lt;p&gt;Marketplaces like eBay are designed to monetize 'Wandering Attention'—sponsored listings, 'customers also bought', and sidebar ads.&lt;p&gt;An AI Agent represents 'Laser Focused Attention'. It executes a transaction with zero wandering. It effectively turns the marketplace into a commoditized backend database / dumb pipe.&lt;p&gt;From a Growth/Unit Economics perspective, an AI Agent is a nightmare customer. It has zero probability of impulse buying and generates zero ad revenue. They are banning them to save their business model, not their inventory.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 12:14:36 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46718266</link><dc:creator>MarginalGainz</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46718266</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46718266</guid></item><item><title>New comment by freakynit in "We will ban you and ridicule you in public if you waste our time on crap reports"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Indian here (~15+ years in tech). I've seen this behavior a lot, and unfortunately, I did some of this myself earlier in my career.&lt;p&gt;Based on my own experience, here are a few reasons (could be a lot more):&lt;p&gt;1. Unlike most developed countries, in India (and many other develping countries), people in authority are expected to be respected unconditinally(almost). Questioning a manager, teacher, or senior is often seen as disrespect or incompetence. So, instead of asking for clarification, many people just "do something" and hope it is acceptable. You can think of this as a lighter version of Japanese office culture, but not limited to office... it's kind of everywhere in society.&lt;p&gt;2. Our education system mainly rewards results, not how good or well-thought-out the results are. Sure, better answers get more marks, but the gap between "okay" and "excellent" is usually not emphasized much. This comes from scale problems (huge number of students), very low median income (~$2400/year), and poorly trained teachers, especially outside big cities. Many teachers themselves memorize answers and expect matching output from students. This is slowly improving, but the damage is already there.&lt;p&gt;3. Pay in India is still severely (serioualy low, with 12-14+ hour work days, even more than 996 culture of China) low for most people, and the job market is extremely competitive. For many students and juniors, having a long list of "projects", PRs, or known names on their resume most often the only way to stand out. Quantity often wins over quality. With LLMs, this problem just got amplified.&lt;p&gt;Advice: If you want better results from Indian engineers(or designers or anyone else really), especially juniors (speaking as of now, things might change in near future), try to reduce the "authority" gap early on. Make it clear you are approachable and that asking questions is expected. For the first few weeks, work closely with them in the style you want them to follow.. they usually adapt very fast once they feel safe to do so.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 12:06:41 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46718190</link><dc:creator>freakynit</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46718190</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46718190</guid></item><item><title>New comment by causalscience in "We will ban you and ridicule you in public if you waste our time on crap reports"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&gt; Indian students&lt;p&gt;Is this cultural? I ran a small business some years ago (later failed) and was paying for contract work to various people. At the I perceived the pattern that Indian contractors would never ever ask for clarifications, would never say they didn't know something, would never say they didn't understand something, etc. Instead they just ran with whatever they happened to have in their mind, until I called them out. And if they did something poorly and I didn't call them out they'd never do back as far as I can tell and wonder "did I get it right? Could I have done better?". I don't get this attitude - at my day job I sometimes "run with it" but I periodically check with my manager to make sure "hey this is what you wanted right?". There's little downside to this.&lt;p&gt;Your comment reminded me of my experience, in the sense that they're both a sort of "fake it till you make it".&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 11:30:10 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46717860</link><dc:creator>causalscience</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46717860</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46717860</guid></item><item><title>New comment by nchmy in "We will ban you and ridicule you in public if you waste our time on crap reports"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I've been helping a bit with OWASP documentation lately and there's been a surge of Indian students eagerly opening nonsensical issues and PRs and all of the communication and code is clearly 100% LLMs. They'll even talk back and forth with each other. It's a huge headache for the maintainers.&lt;p&gt;I suggested following what Ghostty does where everything starts as discussions - only maintainers create issues, and PRs can only come from issues. It seems like this would deter these sorts of lazy efforts.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 11:12:37 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46717706</link><dc:creator>nchmy</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46717706</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46717706</guid></item><item><title>New comment by Shank in "Your app subscription is now my weekend project"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;First of all, I’m skeptical about these being free. Time isn’t free, and the tokens to make these projects certainly weren’t free.&lt;p&gt;Second of all, all of these SaaS apps that don’t actually have a need for recurring charge probably should be paid one time. I don’t use Loom — I use CleanShot X and it was a one-time $30 payment and has a lot of great features I benefit from. I can’t reimplement it in $30 of tokens or $30 of my time.&lt;p&gt;But for an app whose use case doesn’t change and is recurring for no reason? Yeah there’s probably not much value in recurring payments outside of wanting to support the developer. I pay a lot of indie devs out of the goodness of my heart, and I’ll continue to do that.&lt;p&gt;But the value for “SaaS apps” without clear monthly costs should have always been under scrutiny.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 10:17:48 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46717351</link><dc:creator>Shank</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46717351</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46717351</guid></item><item><title>New comment by mcv in "Your brain on ChatGPT: Accumulation of cognitive debt when using an AI assistant"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;This seems to confirm my feeling when using AI too much. It's easy to get started, but I can feel my brain engaging less with the problem than I'm used to. It can form a barrier to real understanding, and keeps me out of my flow.&lt;p&gt;I recently worked on something very complex I don't think I would have been able to tackle as quickly without AI; a hierarchical graph layout algorithm based on the Sugiyama framework, using Brandes-Köpf for node positioning. I had no prior experience with it (and I went in clearly underestimating how complex it was), and AI was a tremendous help in getting a basic understanding of the algorithm, its many steps and sub-algorithms, the subtle interactions and unspoken assumptions in it. But letting it write the actual code was a mistake. That's what kept me from understanding the intricacies, from truly engaging with the problem, which led me to keep relying on the AI to fix issues, but at that point the AI clearly also had no real idea what it was doing, and just made things worse.&lt;p&gt;So instead of letting the AI see the real code, I switched from the Copilot IDE plugin to the standalone Copilot 365 app, where it could explain the principles behind every step, and I would debug and fix the code and develop actual understanding of what was going on. And I finally got back into that coding flow again.&lt;p&gt;So don't let the AI take over your actual job, but use it as an interactive encyclopedia. That works much better for this kind of complex problem.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 08:16:21 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46716528</link><dc:creator>mcv</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46716528</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46716528</guid></item><item><title>New comment by Animats in "Significant US farm losses persist, despite federal assistance"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Much of this is an antitrust problem.&lt;p&gt;The inputs to farming, especially seeds, fertilizer and machinery, are controlled by monopolies and near-monopolies. There have been too many mergers.&lt;p&gt;On the sell side, there's monopsony or near-monopsony, with very few big buyers.[1] Farmers are caught in the middle, with little pricing power on either side.&lt;p&gt;There's not much question about this. There are antitrust cases, but with weak penalties and weak enforcement.&lt;p&gt;[1] &lt;a href="https://equitablegrowth.org/competitive-edge-big-ags-monopsony-problem-how-market-dominance-harms-u-s-workers-and-consumers/" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://equitablegrowth.org/competitive-edge-big-ags-monopso...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 08:01:49 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46716459</link><dc:creator>Animats</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46716459</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46716459</guid></item><item><title>New comment by csours in "Significant US farm losses persist, despite federal assistance"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Of all the guns that rural Americans love, the humble foot-gun is the most beloved.&lt;p&gt;---&lt;p&gt;Someone else can argue the morality, ethics, economics, and politics of it all, but VERY simply, US Federal Government Agencies are machines for redistributing wealth from cities to rural areas.&lt;p&gt;Rural America voted quite heavily to stop those subsidies. That's what efficiency means.&lt;p&gt;---&lt;p&gt;Maturity means suspending judgement and listening to people you disagree with, but I feel that's very out of style these days.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 03:58:30 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46715137</link><dc:creator>csours</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46715137</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46715137</guid></item></channel></rss>