<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>Hacker News: Best Comments</title><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/bestcomments</link><description>Hacker News RSS</description><docs>https://hnrss.org/</docs><generator>hnrss v2.1.1</generator><lastBuildDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 00:13:53 +0000</lastBuildDate><ns0:link href="https://hnrss.org/bestcomments" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item><title>New comment by signal11 in "The struggle of resizing windows on macOS Tahoe"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Tahoe is a macOS mis-step on par with  Windows 8 or Windows Vista. If you’re from Apple and reading this, my feedback is pretty succinct: “I don’t recommend others upgrade. I wish I didn’t.”&lt;p&gt;Luckily for Apple, Windows 11 is not exactly in a position to attract switchers.&lt;p&gt;Let’s see if Apple can turn things around. iOS 8+ did improve on iOS 7’s worst bits.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 21:22:10 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46580225</link><dc:creator>signal11</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46580225</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46580225</guid></item><item><title>New comment by voxleone in "I dumped Windows 11 for Linux, and you should too"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;It’s worth acknowledging the real challenges raised in this thread: desktop Linux still has rough edges for some use cases, hardware support isn’t always perfect, and niche professional software may lack native support or require workarounds. But these obstacles are not intrinsic technical limitations so much as ecosystem and investment gaps, areas where community projects, standards efforts, and wider adoption could drive improvement without sacrificing freedom.&lt;p&gt;Viewed through the lens of digital autonomy and citizenship, the question isn’t simply “Is Linux perfect?” but rather: Do we want our fundamental computing environment to be ultimately under our control, or controlled by private interests with their own incentives?&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 16:33:26 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46577139</link><dc:creator>voxleone</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46577139</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46577139</guid></item><item><title>New comment by Y_Y in "Gentoo Linux 2025 Review"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&gt; The Gentoo Foundation took in $12,066 in fiscal year 2025 (ending 2025/06/30); the dominant part (over 80%) consists of individual cash donations from the community. On the SPI side, we received $8,471 in the same period as fiscal year 2025; also here, this is all from small individual cash donations.&lt;p&gt;It's crazy how projects this large and influential can get by on so little cash. Of course a lot of people are donating their very valuable labour to the project, but the ROI from Gentoo is incredible compared to what it costs to do anything in commercial software.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 13:17:48 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46575496</link><dc:creator>Y_Y</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46575496</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46575496</guid></item><item><title>New comment by embedding-shape in "Don't fall into the anti-AI hype"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&gt; But what was the fire inside you, when you coded till night to see your project working? It was building.&lt;p&gt;I feel like this is not the same for everyone. For some people, the "fire" is literally about "I control a computer", for others "I'm solving a problem for others", and yet for others "I made something that made others smile/cry/feel emotions" and so on.&lt;p&gt;I think there is a section of programmer who actually do like the actual typing of letters, numbers and special characters into a computer, and for them, I understand LLMs remove the fun part. For me, I initially got into programming because I wanted to ruin other people's websites, then I figured out I needed to know how to build websites first, then I found it more fun to create and share what I've done with others, and they tell me what they think of it. That's my "fire". But I've met so many people who doesn't care an iota about sharing what they built with others, it matters nothing to them.&lt;p&gt;I guess the conclusion is, not all programmers program for the same reason, for some of us, LLMs helps a lot, and makes things even more fun. For others, LLMs remove the core part of what makes programming fun for them. Hence we get this constant back and forth of "Can't believe others can work like this!" vs "I can't believe others aren't working like this!", but both sides seems to completely miss the other side.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 11:27:32 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46574664</link><dc:creator>embedding-shape</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46574664</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46574664</guid></item><item><title>New comment by adityaathalye in "Don't fall into the anti-AI hype"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Don't fall into the "Look ma, no hands" hype.&lt;p&gt;Antirez + LLM + CFO = Billion Dollar Redis company, quite plausibly.&lt;p&gt;/However/ ...&lt;p&gt;As for the delta provided by an LLM to Antirez, outside of Redis (and outside of any problem space he is already intimately familiar with), an Apples to Apples comparison would be he trying this on an equally complex codebase he has no idea about. I'll bet... what Antirez can do with Redis and LLMs (certainly useful, huge Quality of Life improvement to Antirez), he cannot even begin to do with (say) Postgres.&lt;p&gt;The only way to get there with (say) Postgres, would be to /know/ Postgres. And pretty much everyone, no matter how good, cannot get there with code-reading alone. With software at least, we need to develop a mental model of the thing by futzing about with the thing in deeply meaningful ways.&lt;p&gt;And most of us day-job grunts are in the latter spot... working in some grimy legacy multi-hundred-thousand line code-mine, full of NPM vulns, schelpping code over the wall to QA (assuming there is even a QA), and basically developing against live customers --- "learn by shipping", as they say.&lt;p&gt;I &lt;i&gt;do&lt;/i&gt; think LLMs are wildly interesting technology, however they are poor utility for non-domain-experts. If organisations want to &lt;i&gt;profit&lt;/i&gt; from the fully-loaded cost of LLM technology, they better also invest heavily in staff training and development.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 11:10:58 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46574537</link><dc:creator>adityaathalye</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46574537</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46574537</guid></item><item><title>New comment by systemf_omega in "Don't fall into the anti-AI hype"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;What I don't understand about this whole "get on board the AI train or get left behind" narrative, what advantage does an early adopter have for AI tools?&lt;p&gt;The way I see it, I can just start using AI once they get good enough for my type of work. Until then I'm continuing to learn instead of letting my brain atrophy.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 11:05:07 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46574491</link><dc:creator>systemf_omega</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46574491</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46574491</guid></item><item><title>New comment by patcon in "A battle over Canada’s mystery brain disease"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I grew up in New Brunswick. It is a strange place politically.&lt;p&gt;I find it wild that the BBC never mentioned the most glaring underbelly of this:&lt;p&gt;New Brunswicks most significant employer for the past 100 years is Irving Oil &amp; Irving Paper and Irving Forestry. They are different arms of a privately held family-run business, run by the descendants of the original founder (whose records are not as public as a traded company), in charge of the main industries of the province. They owned every newspaper in the province, and are known to be adversarial to any community paper, starting new papers just to drive out of business the small upstarts they don't own -- I've seen it play out in my community. People are literally afraid to criticize this family publicly, because they fund SO MUCH of the nonprofit sector. If you are trying to get a project off the ground, you can't look sideways at them or your project will be buried. And their papers certainly won't speak kindly of your criticism.&lt;p&gt;And most glaringly, one of their ex-Vice Presidents was premier of the province during this time.&lt;p&gt;So there is an extra level of concern that some locals have about the optics of the province shutting down the research.&lt;p&gt;The Irving family is highly manipulative of political affairs, and imho have held the province back for decades (e.g. influencing what schools get funded/built, to create the working stock that support their businesses, etc)&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 08:22:14 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46573684</link><dc:creator>patcon</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46573684</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46573684</guid></item><item><title>New comment by russdill in "My Home Fibre Network Disintegrated"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;If you buy a consumer product labeled "military grade" you are buying snake oil. And not just snake oil, incredibly over priced snake oil.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 05:11:43 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46572873</link><dc:creator>russdill</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46572873</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46572873</guid></item><item><title>New comment by hermanzegerman in "Private equity firms acquired more than 500 autism centers in past decade: study"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;We already know that Private Equity kills people in the hospitals [1] and nursing homes [2] for profit. So why do we continue to allow them to operate Healthcare facilities?&lt;p&gt;[1] &lt;a href="https://jamanetwork.com/journals/jama/fullarticle/2813379" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://jamanetwork.com/journals/jama/fullarticle/2813379&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;[2] &lt;a href="https://www.nber.org/papers/w28474" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://www.nber.org/papers/w28474&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:28:08 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46571460</link><dc:creator>hermanzegerman</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46571460</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46571460</guid></item><item><title>New comment by drakeballew in "Show HN: I used Claude Code to discover connections between 100 books"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;This is a beautiful piece of work. The actual data or outputs seem to be more or less...trash? Maybe too strong a word. But perhaps you are outsourcing too much critical thought to a statistical model. We are all guilty of it. But some of these are egregious, obviously referential LLM dog. The world has more going on than whatever these models seem to believe.&lt;p&gt;Edit/update: if you are looking for the phantom thread between texts, believe me that an LLM cannot achieve it. I have interrogated the most advanced models for hours, and they cannot do the task to any sort of satisfactory end that a smoked-out half-asleep college freshman could. The models don't have sufficient capacity...yet.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 00:20:11 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46571393</link><dc:creator>drakeballew</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46571393</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46571393</guid></item><item><title>New comment by wmf in "NASA announces unprecedented return of sick ISS astronaut and crew"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;How could you keep calm so far away&lt;/i&gt;&lt;p&gt;By going through a ten-year process that selects for calm people.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 10 Jan 2026 21:19:47 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46570021</link><dc:creator>wmf</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46570021</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46570021</guid></item><item><title>New comment by rickcarlino in "I replaced Windows with Linux and everything's going great"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Linux is one of the last strong defenses for the idea that people should control the computers they own. On desktops and servers, root access is normal, and attempts to take it away do not work because software freedom is well established. On phones, that never happened. There is no real, mainstream “Linux for mobile,” and the result is a world of locked-down platforms where things like “sideloading” are treated as scary security risks instead of basic user rights. This makes it much easier for lawmakers to argue for removing root access on mobile devices, even though the same idea would be unrealistic on desktop systems.&lt;p&gt;A great deal of gratitude is owed to all the people who volunteer their free time to create the stable desktop environment we have free access to on Linux in 2026.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 10 Jan 2026 20:01:19 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46569371</link><dc:creator>rickcarlino</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46569371</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46569371</guid></item><item><title>New comment by heliumtera in "AI is a business model stress test"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Tailwind Labs relied on a weird monetization scheme. 
Revenue was proportional to the pain of using the framework. The sudden improvement in getting desired UI without relying on pre-built templates killed Tailwind Labs.&lt;p&gt;There are many initiatives in a similar spot, improving your experience at using Next.js would hurt Vercel. 
Making GitHub actions runners more reliable, stable and economical would hurt Microsoft. 
Improving accessibility to compute power would hurt Amazon, Microsoft and Google. 
Improving control and freedom over your device would hurt apple and Google.&lt;p&gt;Why should we be sympathetic to the middleman again?&lt;p&gt;If suddenly CSS became pleasant to use, Tailwind would be in a rough spot. See the irony?&lt;p&gt;"Give everything away for free and this people will leave technology", geohot said something like this and I truly appreciate. Technology will heal finally&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 10 Jan 2026 18:14:21 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46568338</link><dc:creator>heliumtera</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46568338</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46568338</guid></item><item><title>New comment by drivebyhooting in "AI is a business model stress test"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;In my opinion LLMs are intellectual property theft. Just as if I started distributing copies of books. This substantially reduces the incentive for the creation of new IP.&lt;p&gt;All written text, art work, etc needs to come imbued with a GPL style license: if you train your model on this, your weights and training code must be published.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 10 Jan 2026 17:46:16 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46568004</link><dc:creator>drivebyhooting</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46568004</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46568004</guid></item><item><title>New comment by blauditore in "I replaced Windows with Linux and everything's going great"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&gt;unify the look and feel of mobile and desktop&lt;p&gt;Lol, that's what Microsoft tried 10+ years ago and everybody gave them shit for it, especially Apple fans. Now Apple is "inventing" this again.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 10 Jan 2026 17:20:55 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46567691</link><dc:creator>blauditore</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46567691</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46567691</guid></item><item><title>New comment by epolanski in "Microsoft May Have Created the Slowest Windows in 25 Years with Windows 11"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I liked the path windows was going in late 2010s. WSL, power toys, many great utils, great performance.&lt;p&gt;But it has since then stalled and got increasingly worse. Especially with this AI shoving everywhere, not even mentioning getting ads at some point in notifications and start menu.&lt;p&gt;I'm not particularly in love with MacOS either (but have no realistic alternative on my MacBooks).&lt;p&gt;I'm more and more inclined of switching my desktop (my main working machine) to Omarchy, two coworkers in my team use it and love it and seems the sweet spot for what I need as a dev without the annoyance of Windows or the god awful macos.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 10 Jan 2026 17:05:49 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46567504</link><dc:creator>epolanski</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46567504</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46567504</guid></item><item><title>New comment by toddmorey in "I replaced Windows with Linux and everything's going great"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Commercial OSes (both Windows and MacOS) now feel so insanely agenda driven, and the agenda no longer feels like anything close to making the user happy and productive. For Mac, it feels like Apple wants to leverage what came out of VisionOS and unify the look and feel of mobile and desktop--two things no one asked for. For Windows, it feels like ads for their partners and ensuring they don't fumble the ai/agent transition the way they did with mobile.&lt;p&gt;Linux is SUCH a breath of fresh air. No one wants it to be anything other than what you want it to be. Modern desktop Linux has a much improved out of the box experience with good support for all the hardware I've thrown at it. And Claude Code makes it very fast and trivial to personalize, adapt, automate, etc.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 10 Jan 2026 16:36:44 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46567137</link><dc:creator>toddmorey</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46567137</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46567137</guid></item><item><title>New comment by peanut-walrus in "I replaced Windows with Linux and everything's going great"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I've been a Linux admin for 25 years but up until a few months ago my personal computer has been windows (gaming desktop) or Mac (laptop).&lt;p&gt;I decided to give desktop Linux another shot and I'm glad I did. I was prepared for a lot of jankiness but figured I have enough experience to fix whatever needs fixing. Surprisingly, this has not been the case at all, the PC has been not only as stable as Windows or Mac but also performs better and is much more comfortable and intuitive to use. I never really want to "work on" my personal computer, I want it to just be there for me reliably. I've always had a soft spot for free software, but I just couldn't justify the effort until now.&lt;p&gt;So I guess this is my love letter to all the devs that have made the modern Linux desktop possible. Even compared to just a few years ago, the difference is immense. Keep up the good work.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 10 Jan 2026 16:35:30 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46567123</link><dc:creator>peanut-walrus</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46567123</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46567123</guid></item><item><title>New comment by bwb in "ChatGPT Health is a marketplace, guess who is the product?"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;ChatGPT has made a material difference in my ability to understand health problems, test results, and to communicate with doctors effectively. My wife and I were talking last night about how helpful it was in 2025. I hope that it continues to be good at this.&lt;p&gt;I want regulators to keep an eye on this and make smart laws. I don't want it to go away, as its value is massive in my life.&lt;p&gt;(One example, if you are curious: I've been doing rehab for a back injury for about 10 years. I worked with a certified trainer/rehab professional for many years and built a program to keep me as pain-free as possible. I rebuilt the entire thing with ChatGPT/Gemini about 6 weeks ago, and I've had less pain than at any other point in my life. I spent at least 12 hours working with AI to test and research every exercise, and I've got some knowledge to help guide me, but I was amazed by how far it has come in 12 months. I ran the results by a trainer to double-check it was well thought out.)&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 10 Jan 2026 14:03:10 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46565806</link><dc:creator>bwb</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46565806</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46565806</guid></item><item><title>New comment by tunapizza in "Eulogy for Dark Sky, a data visualization masterpiece (2023)"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Fortunately someone recreated a clone at &lt;a href="https://merrysky.net" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://merrysky.net&lt;/a&gt;, which was featured [1] on HN some time ago.&lt;p&gt;I've used it daily since.&lt;p&gt;[1] &lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=34155191"&gt;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=34155191&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 10 Jan 2026 13:41:29 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46565679</link><dc:creator>tunapizza</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46565679</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46565679</guid></item><item><title>New comment by Fiveplus in "Allow me to introduce, the Citroen C15"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;The C15 represents a time when a vehicle was a tool. I feel vehicles want to turn into a subscription service these days.&lt;p&gt;I still see these running in rural Spain and France, usually held together with wire and hope, clocking like what 400k+ km? The XUD diesel engines are practically unkillable. They have no ECU to brick, no adblue sensors to fail and put the car into limp mode and thankfully none of those DRM locked headlights.&lt;p&gt;The argument for the countryside need of a modern SUV usually cites reliability and safety, and in 2026, modern complexity is the enemy of reliability. If your C15 breaks down in a field, you can fix it with a wrench. If your Range Rover breaks down in a field because a sensor in the air suspension noticed a voltage variance...you are stranded until a tow truck takes it to a dealer.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 10 Jan 2026 13:08:38 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46565404</link><dc:creator>Fiveplus</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46565404</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46565404</guid></item><item><title>New comment by dependsontheq in "Cloudflare CEO on the Italy fines"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Let's be a bit more honest here, I think the Italian law is badly defined, but I also think the american perspective is wrong.&lt;p&gt;We (all tech people everywhere me included) argued for a lot of time for free speech on the internet, but the result currently is that we built a system that is free speech for Russian and Chinese bots and actors. In Europe we are under daily attack from Russian accounts that spread massive amounts of desinformation, deep fakes, just emotional appeals with the goal of destroying liberal democracy. The US government is actively trying to support them by fighting against any kind of European rules and spreading their part of desinformation.&lt;p&gt;This is not about normal politics, Europe is under siege.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 10 Jan 2026 09:45:17 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46564265</link><dc:creator>dependsontheq</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46564265</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46564265</guid></item><item><title>New comment by Elfener in "Changes to Android Open Source Project"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I like the android way of security, where "rooting" your device to install updates is insecure, but using a horrifyingly out-of-date android (because your manufacturer, the only one who can update your device, didn't bother) is secure.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 10 Jan 2026 08:35:56 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46563924</link><dc:creator>Elfener</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46563924</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46563924</guid></item><item><title>New comment by tanvach in "Start your meetings at 5 minutes past"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;During the pandemic, we had a natural experiment at my previous company. Our org had started an org wise auto ‘meeting starts 5 minute past’ while others had the traditional meetings start on the hour.&lt;p&gt;Also conveniently, we also had the calendar data for internal meetings, internal VC software (not zoom) db that logs the participants when they join and leave meetings and employee function db.&lt;p&gt;I was serendipitously the lead DS for analyzing the effectiveness of the ‘starting 5 minutes past’. After joining and cleaning a lot of the data, the data showed:&lt;p&gt;1) at the start of the trial, meetings ended on time. Then after few weeks it slip to ending late, negating the usefulness. Other orgs did not see meetings running late.
2) ICs tend to stick around and over run meetings, while managers tend to leave meetings on time.
3) if I remember right, we had a survey data that showed pretty clearly that managers prefer the ‘starting 5 minutes past’ while ICs do not care or have negative sentiment.&lt;p&gt;The biggest predictor for people who prefer starting late is how crowded their schedules are. Managers tend to have very crowded schedules which means they want a break between meetings, while ICs prefer not having to waste time waiting.&lt;p&gt;In the end we reverted back to normal schedule. It was just easier for busy people to bounce early.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 10 Jan 2026 06:18:08 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46563275</link><dc:creator>tanvach</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46563275</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46563275</guid></item><item><title>New comment by g947o in "Oh My Zsh adds bloat"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I use oh my zsh for exactly one reason: I can get a good shell experience out of the box and immediately start working on stuff productively, whether it's a new machine, a new remote host or a container.&lt;p&gt;I could spend hours figuring out all those things, bit I'd rather use that time for something more important.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 10 Jan 2026 04:58:06 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46562912</link><dc:creator>g947o</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46562912</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46562912</guid></item><item><title>New comment by tomeraberbach in "How Markdown took over the world"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I added Markdown support to Google Docs as a 20% project. Honestly honored to be included in this Markdown history :)&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 10 Jan 2026 01:49:17 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46561911</link><dc:creator>tomeraberbach</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46561911</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46561911</guid></item><item><title>New comment by aidenn0 in "“Erdos problem #728 was solved more or less autonomously by AI”"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;How do you verify that the AI translation to Lean is a correct formalization of the problem?  In other fields, generative AI is very good at making up plausible sounding lies, so I'm wondering how likely that is for this usage.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 10 Jan 2026 01:38:50 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46561826</link><dc:creator>aidenn0</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46561826</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46561826</guid></item><item><title>New comment by exegete in "Start your meetings at 5 minutes past"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;We do this at my work and guess what - meetings tend to run 5 minutes late because everyone knows the next meeting doesn’t start until 5 past.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 10 Jan 2026 01:28:37 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46561749</link><dc:creator>exegete</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46561749</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46561749</guid></item><item><title>New comment by maxwells-daemon in "“Erdos problem #728 was solved more or less autonomously by AI”"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I work at Harmonic, the company behind Aristotle.&lt;p&gt;To clear up a few misconceptions:&lt;p&gt;- Aristotle uses modern AI techniques heavily, including language modeling.&lt;p&gt;- Aristotle can be guided by an informal (English) proof. If the proof is correct, Aristotle has a good chance at translating it into Lean (which is a strong vote of confidence that your English proof is solid). I believe that's what happened here.&lt;p&gt;- Once a proof is formalized into Lean (assuming you have formalized the statement correctly), there is no doubt that the proof is correct. This is the core of our approach: you can do a lot of (AI-driven) search, and once you find the answer you are certain it's correct no matter how complex the solution is.&lt;p&gt;Happy to answer any questions!&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 10 Jan 2026 01:03:26 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46561569</link><dc:creator>maxwells-daemon</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46561569</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46561569</guid></item><item><title>New comment by MyFirstSass in "“Erdos problem #728 was solved more or less autonomously by AI”"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Based on Tao’s description of how the proof came about - a human is taking results backwards and forwards between two separate AI tools and using an AI tool to fill in gaps the human found?&lt;p&gt;I don’t think it can really be said to have occurred autonomously then?&lt;p&gt;Looks more like a 50/50 partnership with a super expert human one the one side which makes this way more vague in my opinion - and in line with my own AI tests, ie. they are pretty stupid even OPUS 4.5 or whatever unless you're already an expert and is doing boilerplate.&lt;p&gt;EDIT: I can see the title has been fixed now from solved to "more or less solved" which is still think is a big stretch.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 10 Jan 2026 00:21:51 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46561268</link><dc:creator>MyFirstSass</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46561268</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46561268</guid></item></channel></rss>