<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>Hacker News: Best Comments</title><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/bestcomments</link><description>Hacker News RSS</description><docs>https://hnrss.org/</docs><generator>hnrss v2.1.1</generator><lastBuildDate>Mon, 13 Oct 2025 00:31:25 +0000</lastBuildDate><ns0:link href="https://hnrss.org/bestcomments" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item><title>New comment by Podrod in "No I don't want to turn on Windows Backup with One Drive"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I used to use Windows Backup with One Drive years ago but it just really pissed me off, especially with how My Documents is handled.&lt;p&gt;There was that time I discovered several GB of screenshots had been automatically saved to My Pictures from some setting they snuck into the printscreen screen grab tool and then that of course those were automatically uploaded to the cloud. After disabling the option it would sometimes reenable itself.&lt;p&gt;And game devs throwing random shit into My Documents was also fun. Ubisoft were terrible for this, after playing a game I'd notice a bunch of cache files they dumped into My Docs being uploaded. I mean putting save games and config files inside my docs is annoying enough, random cache files is just taking the piss.&lt;p&gt;Also windows backup would mess up my desktop between systems on occasion which was also very fun!&lt;p&gt;I disabled most of the shit but it was still annoying on occasion. Then a year or two ago I solved the problem by just using Linux for 90% of things, Mint at first but now Fedora, and grudgingly booting back into Windows for the other 10% of my needs.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 12 Oct 2025 16:22:13 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45559376</link><dc:creator>Podrod</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45559376</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45559376</guid></item><item><title>New comment by EvanAnderson in "Jeep pushed software update that bricked all 2024 Wrangler 4xe models"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;This is chilling (from &lt;a href="https://www.jlwranglerforums.com/forum/threads/2024-4xe-loss-of-motive-power-after-10-10-25-ota-update.157939/" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://www.jlwranglerforums.com/forum/threads/2024-4xe-loss...&lt;/a&gt;):&lt;p&gt;&gt; On my drive home I abruptly had absolutely no acceleration, the gear indicator on the dash started flashing, the power mode indicator disappeared, an alert said shift into park and press the brake + start button, and the check engine light and red wrench lights came on. I was still able to steer and brake with power steering and brakes for maybe 30 seconds before those went out too. After putting it into park and pressing the brake and start button it started back up and I could drive it normally for a little bit, but it happened two more times on my 1.5 mi drive home.&lt;p&gt;If that happened on the highway I could easily see people being killed.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 12 Oct 2025 14:57:49 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45558660</link><dc:creator>EvanAnderson</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45558660</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45558660</guid></item><item><title>New comment by renehsz in "Ask HN: Abandoned/dead projects you think died before their time and why?"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;The Plan 9 operating system.&lt;p&gt;It's the closest thing to a Unix successor we ever got, taking the "everything is a file" philosophy to another level and allowing to easily share those files over the network to build distributed systems. Accessing &lt;i&gt;any&lt;/i&gt; remote resources is easy and robust on Plan9, meanwhile on other systems we need to install specialized software with bad interoperability for each individual use case.&lt;p&gt;Plan9 also had some innovative UI features, such as mouse chording to edit text, nested window managers, the Plumber to run user-configurable commands on known text patterns system-wide, etc.&lt;p&gt;Its distributed nature &lt;i&gt;should&lt;/i&gt; have meant it's perfect for today's world with mobile, desktop, cloud, and IoT devices all connected to each other. Instead, we're stuck with operating systems that were never designed for that.&lt;p&gt;There are still active forks of Plan9 such as 9front, but the original from Bell Labs is dead. The reasons it died are likely:&lt;p&gt;- Legal challenges (Plan9 license, pointless lawsuits, etc.) meant it wssn't adopted by major players in the industry.&lt;p&gt;- Plan9 was a distributed OS during a time when having a local computer became popular and affordable, while using a terminal to access a centrally managed computer fell out of fashion (though the latter sort of came back in a worse fashion with cloud computing).&lt;p&gt;- Bad marketing and posing itself as merely a research OS meant they couldn't capitalize on the .com boom.&lt;p&gt;- AT&amp;T lost its near endless source of telephone revenue. Bell Labs was sold multiple times over the coming years, a lot of the Unix/Plan9 guys went to other companies like Google.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 12 Oct 2025 11:44:23 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45557467</link><dc:creator>renehsz</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45557467</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45557467</guid></item><item><title>New comment by jwr in "Anthropic's Prompt Engineering Tutorial (2024)"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I find the word "engineering" used in this context extremely annoying. There is no "engineering" here. Engineering is about applying knowledge, laws of physics, and rules learned over many years to predictably design and build things. This is throwing stuff at the wall to see if it sticks.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 12 Oct 2025 09:10:07 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45556685</link><dc:creator>jwr</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45556685</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45556685</guid></item><item><title>New comment by zaptheimpaler in "Ask HN: Abandoned/dead projects you think died before their time and why?"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Adobe Flash / Shockwave. After all these decades, I've yet to see a tool that makes it as easy to make games or multimedia as Flash did. One of many reminders recently (many others in politics) that humanity doesn't just inevitably or linearly move forward in any domain, or even 2 steps forward 1 step back. Some things are just lost to time - maybe rediscovered in a century, maybe never.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 12 Oct 2025 08:20:53 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45556394</link><dc:creator>zaptheimpaler</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45556394</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45556394</guid></item><item><title>New comment by Animats in "Ask HN: Abandoned/dead projects you think died before their time and why?"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;- Photon, the graphical interface for QNX. Oriented more towards real time (widgets included gauges) but good enough to support two different web browsers. No delays. This was a real time operating system.&lt;p&gt;- MacOS 8. Not the Linux thing, but Copeland. This was a modernized version of the original MacOS, continuing the tradition of no command line. Not having a command line forces everyone to get their act together about how to install and configure things. Probably would have eased the tradition to mobile. A version was actually shipped to developers, but it had to be covered up to justify the bailout of Next by Apple to get Steve Jobs.&lt;p&gt;- Transaction processing operating systems. The first one was IBM's Customer Information Control System. A transaction processor is a kind of OS where everything is like a CGI program - load program, do something, exit program. Unix and Linux are, underneath, terminal oriented time sharing systems.&lt;p&gt;- IBM MicroChannel. Early minicomputer and microcomputer designers thought "bus", where peripherals can talk to memory and peripherals look like memory to the CPU. Mainframes, though, had "channels", simple processors which connected peripherals to the CPU. Channels could run simple channel programs, and managed device access to memory. IBM tried to introduce that with the PS2, but they made it proprietary and that failed in the marketplace. Today, everything has something like channels, but they're not a unified interface concept that simplifies the OS.&lt;p&gt;- CPUs that really hypervise properly. That is, virtual execution environments look just like real ones. 
IBM did that in VM, and it worked well because channels are a good abstraction for both a real machine and a VM. Storing into device registers to make things happen is not. x86 has added several layers below the "real machine" layer, and they're all hacks.&lt;p&gt;- The Motorola 680x0 series. Should have been the foundation of the microcomputer era, but it took way too long to get the MMU out the door. The original 68000 came out in 1978, but then Motorola fell behind.&lt;p&gt;- Modula. Modula 2 and 3 were reasonably good languages. Oberon was a flop. DEC was into Modula, but Modula went down with DEC.&lt;p&gt;- XHTML. Have you ever read the parsing rules for HTML 5, where the semantics for bad HTML were formalized? Browsers should just punt at the first error, display an error message, and render the rest of the page in Times Roman.
Would it kill people to have to close their tags properly?&lt;p&gt;- Word Lens. Look at the world through your phone, and text is translated, standalone, on the device. No Internet connection required. Killed by Google in favor of hosted Google Translate.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 12 Oct 2025 07:24:22 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45556053</link><dc:creator>Animats</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45556053</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45556053</guid></item><item><title>New comment by coreyhn in "Ask HN: Abandoned/dead projects you think died before their time and why?"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Yahoo pipes. It was so great at creating rss feeds and custom workflows. There are replacements now like Zapier and n8n but loved that. Also google reader which is mentioned multiple times already.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 12 Oct 2025 03:07:30 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45554825</link><dc:creator>coreyhn</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45554825</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45554825</guid></item><item><title>New comment by forgotoldacc in "Microsoft only lets you opt out of AI photo scanning 3x a year"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;This is Microsoft. They have a proven record of turning these toggles back on automatically without your consent.&lt;p&gt;So you can opt out of them taking all of your most private moments and putting them into a data set that will be leaked, but you can only opt out 3 times. What are the odds a "bug" (feature) turns it on 4 times? Anything less than 100% is an underestimate.&lt;p&gt;And what does a disclaimer mean, legally speaking? They won't face any consequences when they use it for training purposes. They'll simply deny that they do it. When it's revealed that they did it, they'll say sorry, that wasn't intentional. When it's revealed to be intentional, they'll say it's good for you so be quiet.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 12 Oct 2025 03:05:50 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45554816</link><dc:creator>forgotoldacc</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45554816</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45554816</guid></item><item><title>New comment by BirAdam in "Ask HN: Abandoned/dead projects you think died before their time and why?"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Google Wave.&lt;p&gt;Edit: you asked why. I first saw it at SELF where Chris DiBona showed it to me and a close friend. It was awesome. Real time translation, integration of various types of messaging, tons of cool capabilities, and it was fully open source. What made it out of Google was a stripped down version of what I was shown, the market rejected it, and it was a sad day. Now, I am left with JIRA, Slack, and email. It sucks.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 12 Oct 2025 02:43:19 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45554716</link><dc:creator>BirAdam</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45554716</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45554716</guid></item><item><title>New comment by userbinator in "Testing two 18 TB white label SATA hard drives from datablocks.dev"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Reading the part about using foam to make these drives quieter, and the link to the author's other article about putting drives on foam, makes me write this obligatory warning: hard drives do &lt;i&gt;not&lt;/i&gt; like non-rigid mounting. Yes, the servo can usually still position the heads on the right track (since it's a servo), but power dissipation will be higher, performance will be lower, and you may get more errors with a non-rigid mount. Around 20 years ago it was a short-lived fad in the silent-PC community to suspend drives on rubber bands, and many of those who did that experienced unusually short drive lifetimes and very high seek error rates. Elasticity is the worst, since it causes the actuator arm to oscillate. The ideal mount is as rigid as possible.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 12 Oct 2025 02:24:53 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45554612</link><dc:creator>userbinator</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45554612</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45554612</guid></item><item><title>New comment by ipsum2 in "Meta Superintelligence Labs' first paper is about RAG"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;This has nothing to do with superintelligence, it's just the people that were working on the paper prior to the re-org happened to publish after the name change.&lt;p&gt;Though it is notable that contrary to many (on HN and Twitter) that Meta would stop publishing papers and be like other AI labs (e.g. OpenAI). They're continued their rapid pace of releasing papers AND open source models.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 12 Oct 2025 01:00:25 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45554169</link><dc:creator>ipsum2</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45554169</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45554169</guid></item><item><title>New comment by godelski in "Meta Superintelligence Labs' first paper is about RAG"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;It's kinda funny, Meta has long had some of the best in the field, but left them untapped. I really think if they just took a step back and stop being so metric focused and let their people freely explore then they'd be winning the AI race. But with this new team, I feel like meta mostly hired the people who are really good at gaming the system. The people that care more about the money than the research.&lt;p&gt;A bit of this is true at every major lab. There's tons of untapped potential. But these organizations are very risk adverse. I mean why not continue with the strategy that got us to the point we're at in the first place. Labs used to hire researchers and give them a lot of free reign. But those times ended and AI progress also slowed down. Maybe if you want to get ahead you gotta stop thinking like everyone else&lt;p&gt;Well meta... you can "hold me hostage" for a lot cheaper than those guys. I'm sure this is true for hundreds of passionate ML researchers. I'd take a huge pay cut to have autonomy and resources. I know for a fact there's many working at Mets right now that would do the same. Do maybe if you're going to throw money at the problem, diversify a bit and look back at what made SV what it is today and what made AI take leaps forward&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 12 Oct 2025 00:55:34 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45554147</link><dc:creator>godelski</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45554147</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45554147</guid></item><item><title>New comment by brandonb927 in "Ask HN: Abandoned/dead projects you think died before their time and why?"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Google Reader: I will forever be salty about how Google killed something that likely required very little maintenance in the long run. It could have stayed exactly the same for a decade and I wouldn't have cared because I use an RSS reader exactly the same way I do that I did back in 2015.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 12 Oct 2025 00:50:47 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45554121</link><dc:creator>brandonb927</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45554121</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45554121</guid></item><item><title>New comment by Aurornis in "Microsoft only lets you opt out of AI photo scanning 3x a year"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;They could have avoided the negative press by changing the requirement to be that you can’t re-enable the feature after switching it off 3 times per year.&lt;p&gt;It’s not hard to guess the problem: Steady state operation will only incur scanning costs for newly uploaded photos, but toggling the feature off and then on would trigger a rescan of every photo in the library. That’s a potentially very expensive operation.&lt;p&gt;If you’ve ever studied user behavior you’ve discovered situations where users toggle things on and off in attempts to fix some issue. Normally this doesn’t matter much, but when a toggle could potentially cost large amounts of compute you have to be more careful.&lt;p&gt;For the privacy sensitive user who only wants to opt out this shouldn’t matter. Turn the switch off, leave it off, and it’s not a problem. This is meant to address the users who try to turn it off and then back on every time they think it will fix something. It only takes one bad SEO spam advice article about “How to fix _____ problem with your photos” that suggests toggling the option to fix some problem to trigger a wave of people doing it for no reason.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 12 Oct 2025 00:47:58 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45554101</link><dc:creator>Aurornis</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45554101</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45554101</guid></item><item><title>New comment by haunter in "Ask HN: Abandoned/dead projects you think died before their time and why?"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Vine. It was already pretty big back in 2013
but
Twitter had no idea what to do with it. TikTok actually launched just a few months before Vine was shut down and erased from the internet.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 11 Oct 2025 23:06:09 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45553492</link><dc:creator>haunter</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45553492</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45553492</guid></item><item><title>New comment by Terr_ in "People regret buying Amazon smart displays after being bombarded with ads"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;We're way overdue to abolish the DMCA, in particular the "anti-circumvention" felonies.&lt;p&gt;It shouldn't be a crime for me to customize the product I purchased. Or to sell people a kit to do the customization themselves.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 11 Oct 2025 21:44:38 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45552967</link><dc:creator>Terr_</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45552967</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45552967</guid></item><item><title>New comment by bayindirh in "Microsoft only lets you opt out of AI photo scanning 3x a year"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Did anyone notice that Microsoft never replied any of the asked questions, but deflected them?&lt;p&gt;They are exactly where I left them 20 years ago.&lt;p&gt;It's very sad that I can't stop using them &lt;i&gt;again&lt;/i&gt; for doing this.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 11 Oct 2025 20:27:44 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45552411</link><dc:creator>bayindirh</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45552411</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45552411</guid></item><item><title>New comment by themafia in "Microsoft only lets you opt out of AI photo scanning 3x a year"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;"You can only turn off this setting 3 times a year."&lt;p&gt;Astonishing.  They clearly feel their users have no choice but to accept this onerous and ridiculous requirement.  As if users wouldn't understand that they'd have to go way out of their way to write the code which enforces this outcome.  All for a feature which provides me dubious benefit.  I know who the people in my photographs are.  Why is Microsoft so eager to also be able to know this?&lt;p&gt;Privacy legislation is clearly lacking.  This type of action should bring the hammer down swiftly and soundly upon these gross and inappropriate corporate decision makers.  Microsoft has needed that hammer blow for quite some time now.  This should make that obvious.  I guess I'll hold my breath while I see how Congress responds.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 11 Oct 2025 20:02:22 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45552226</link><dc:creator>themafia</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45552226</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45552226</guid></item><item><title>New comment by whatshisface in "Tennessee man arrested, accused of threatening a shooting, after posting meme"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I think this is an example of using slow trials as a nonjudicial weapon. The defendant did not break the law and isn't likely to be convicted (at least not on appeal), but they can hold him in jail for months because they got mad at his Facebook post.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 11 Oct 2025 18:53:36 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45551642</link><dc:creator>whatshisface</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45551642</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45551642</guid></item><item><title>New comment by hddherman in "Testing two 18 TB white label SATA hard drives from datablocks.dev"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Hello, author here! It's a nice surprise to notice my own post here, but the timing is unfortunate as I'm shuffling things around on my home server and will accidentally/intentionally take it offline for a bit.&lt;p&gt;Here's a Wayback Machine copy of the page when that does happen: &lt;a href="https://web.archive.org/web/20251006052340/https://ounapuu.ee/posts/2025/10/06/datablocks-white-label-drives/" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://web.archive.org/web/20251006052340/https://ounapuu.e...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 11 Oct 2025 18:24:52 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45551414</link><dc:creator>hddherman</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45551414</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45551414</guid></item><item><title>New comment by unleaded in "GNU Health"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;There was a guy on reddit a few years ago who started a dental practice with entirely open-source software and his own EHR system. Really interesting stuff, don't think anyone's posted about it here. Can't view his reddit history but he must still be using it, last commit 1 week ago.&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/linux/comments/p5phju/progress_report_starting_a_new_nontechnology/" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://www.reddit.com/r/linux/comments/p5phju/progress_repo...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/linux/comments/x2mls1/update_starting_a_new_nontechnology_company_using/" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://www.reddit.com/r/linux/comments/x2mls1/update_starti...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 11 Oct 2025 18:12:18 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45551308</link><dc:creator>unleaded</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45551308</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45551308</guid></item><item><title>New comment by tptacek in "Vibing a non-trivial Ghostty feature"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Tip: I very often use AI for inspiration. In this case, I ended up keeping a lot (not all) of the UI code it made, but I will very often prompt an agent, throw away everything it did, and redo it myself (manually!). I find the "zero to one" stage of creation very difficult and time consuming and AI is excellent at being my muse.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;p&gt;This right here is the single biggest win for coding agents. I see and directionally agree with all the concerns people have about maintainability and sprawl in AI-mediated projects. I don't care, though, because the moment I can get a project up on its legs, to where I can interact with some substantial part of its functionality and refine it, I'm off to the races. It's getting to that golden moment that constitutes 80% of what's costly about programming for me.&lt;p&gt;This is the part where I simply don't understand the objections people have to coding agents. It seems so self-evidently valuable --- even if you do nothing else with an agent, even if you literally throw all the code away.&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;PS&lt;/i&gt;&lt;p&gt;Put a weight on that bacon!&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 11 Oct 2025 16:57:30 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45550683</link><dc:creator>tptacek</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45550683</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45550683</guid></item><item><title>New comment by rkagerer in "Windows Subsystem for FreeBSD"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I realize not everyone will care about this, but I find the naming for these WSL-like subsystems is confusingly backwards.  i.e. It should have been Linux Subsystem for Windows, or Window's Subsystem for [Linux | FreeBSD | etc].&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 11 Oct 2025 16:19:29 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45550334</link><dc:creator>rkagerer</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45550334</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45550334</guid></item><item><title>New comment by Avicebron in "Superpowers: How I'm using coding agents in October 2025"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I often feel these types of blogposts would be more helpful if they demonstrated someone using the tools to build something non-trivial.&lt;p&gt;Is Claude really "learning new skills" when you feed it a book, or does it present it like that because you're prompting encourages that sort of response-behavior.  I feel like it has to demo Claude with the new skills and Claude without.&lt;p&gt;Maybe I'm a curmudgeon but most of these types of blogs feel like marketing pieces with the important bit is that so much is left unsaid and not shown, that it comes off like a kid trying to hype up their own work without the benefit of nuance or depth.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 11 Oct 2025 13:37:18 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45549036</link><dc:creator>Avicebron</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45549036</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45549036</guid></item><item><title>New comment by sillyfluke in "Daniel Kahneman opted for assisted suicide in Switzerland"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;The parent described someone who went above and beyond the norm of other members in his community in his constant positive interaction with his neighbors, collegues, and former students. It is highly likely this kind of person would give a considerable shit if he knew he would become a nightmare for the same community.&lt;p&gt;There may be others reading in the thread who also can relate to the personality of the teacher and may care about their affect on others when they are "not themselves".&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 11 Oct 2025 12:27:03 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45548635</link><dc:creator>sillyfluke</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45548635</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45548635</guid></item><item><title>New comment by AQuantized in "Daniel Kahneman opted for assisted suicide in Switzerland"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&gt; You really don't want to end up with dementia and related illnesses, it totally sours everyone's view of you.&lt;p&gt;This seems like such an absurd conclusion to this, as though the opinions of other people of you are what matter when you functionally lose your personhood and then die.&lt;p&gt;Maybe a better focus would be that there often isn't a good way for a community to manage a person who suddenly becomes irrational because of an illness.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 11 Oct 2025 12:21:03 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45548598</link><dc:creator>AQuantized</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45548598</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45548598</guid></item><item><title>New comment by alberth in "AV2 video codec delivers 30% lower bitrate than AV1, final spec due in late 2025"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Will streaming services ever stop over-compressing their content?&lt;p&gt;I have a top-of-the-line 4K TV and gigabit internet, yet the compression artifacts make everything look like putty.&lt;p&gt;Honestly, the best picture quality I’ve ever seen was over 20 years ago using simple digital rabbit ears.&lt;p&gt;You especially notice the compression on gradients and in dark movie scenes.&lt;p&gt;And yes — my TV is fully calibrated, and I’m paying for the highest-bandwidth streaming tier.&lt;p&gt;Not my tv, but a visual example: &lt;a href="https://www.reddit.com/media?url=https%3A%2F%2Fpreview.redd.it%2Fwhat-is-causing-this-effect-and-is-there-a-way-to-fix-it-v0-r3f37nsyc3dc1.jpeg%3Fwidth%3D640%26crop%3Dsmart%26auto%3Dwebp%26s%3Dcfbe08390ef6d224a1338323d4279aa8394b10c9" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://www.reddit.com/media?url=https%3A%2F%2Fpreview.redd....&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 11 Oct 2025 12:18:46 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45548583</link><dc:creator>alberth</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45548583</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45548583</guid></item><item><title>New comment by anilgulecha in "Daniel Kahneman opted for assisted suicide in Switzerland"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I'm part of the Jain community in Bangalore, and the version of this in society exists, called Sallekhna [1], a tradition that's developed over millennia, and this is venerated and celebrated.&lt;p&gt;The philosophical underpinning is giving up of materialness. The practicality of the 5 instances that I witnessed over the past year - typical terminal individuals choose this. They pass away surrounded by loved ones (they typically medicate for any pain, and the body starts shutting down when food and water stops). This is observed with somberness, but celebrated as very positive act.&lt;p&gt;When someone starts this process, it's a unique experience speaking with them, as there's usually nothing that comes up, and the moment does not really lend itself to small talk :)&lt;p&gt;[1] &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sallekhana" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sallekhana&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 11 Oct 2025 11:06:07 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45548178</link><dc:creator>anilgulecha</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45548178</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45548178</guid></item><item><title>New comment by lordnacho in "Daniel Kahneman opted for assisted suicide in Switzerland"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I had an old teacher who died almost a year ago.&lt;p&gt;Great guy, very sociable, knew everyone in the little town he lived in. Kept in touch with a lot of students. Good neighbour, friendly guy who'd talk to everyone.&lt;p&gt;He got Alzheimers. He started forgetting stuff, and it frustrated him. He got caught driving dangerously, and cursed the doctor who took away his license.&lt;p&gt;He argued with me about the state of some chicken he wanted to cook. I told him "this is pink all over, you have to cook it more". He got angry. I understood he'd become like this to everyone.&lt;p&gt;He pissed off everyone on his street, and all police, medical and social workers sent to help him. The disease made him blow up every relationship he had with anyone that he didn't know well, like me and a couple of colleagues.&lt;p&gt;He got found in his house, having left the gas on, endangering the whole street. He ended up in a care home, not knowing who he was, or who I was.&lt;p&gt;If he'd been run over by a car, or died of a heart attack at the age of 80, people he knew would remember him as that nice old guy who had a dog and made a lot of art, and was friendly to everyone. Instead he was that 83 year old guy who pissed off everyone, nearly blew up the neighbourhood, and drove like a maniac.&lt;p&gt;You really don't want to end up with dementia and related illnesses, it totally sours everyone's view of you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 11 Oct 2025 10:35:11 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45548022</link><dc:creator>lordnacho</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45548022</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45548022</guid></item><item><title>New comment by kqr in "Ryanair flight landed at Manchester airport with six minutes of fuel left"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;In safety-critical systems, we distinguish between &lt;i&gt;accidents&lt;/i&gt; (actual loss, e.g. lives, equipment, etc.) and &lt;i&gt;hazardous states&lt;/i&gt;. The equation is&lt;p&gt;hazardous state + environmental conditions = accident&lt;p&gt;Since we can only control the system, and not its environment, we focus on preventing hazardous states, rather than accidents. If we can keep the system out of all hazardous states, we also avoid accidents. (Trying to prevent accidents while not paying attention to hazardous states amounts to relying on the environment always being on our side, and is bound to fail eventually.)&lt;p&gt;One such hazardous state we have defined in aviation is "less than N minutes of fuel remaining when landing". If an aircraft lands with less than N minutes of fuel on board, it would only have taken bad environmental conditions to make it crash, rather than land. Thus we design commercial aviation so that planes always have N minutes of fuel remaining when landing. If they don't, that's a big deal: they've entered a hazardous state, and we never want to see that. (I don't remember if N is 30 or 45 or 60 but somewhere in that region.)&lt;p&gt;For another example, one of my children loves playing around cliffs and rocks. Initially he was very keen on promising me that he wouldn't fall down. I explained the difference between accidents and hazardous states to him in childrens' terms, and he realised slowly that he cannot control whether or not he has an accident, so it's a bad idea to promise me that he won't have an accident. What he can control is whether or not bad environmental conditions lead to an accident, and he does that by keeping out of hazardous states. In this case, the hazardous state would be standing less than a child-height within a ledge when there is nobody below ready to catch. He can promise me to avoid that, and that satisfies me a lot more than a promise to not fall.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 11 Oct 2025 06:28:47 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45547079</link><dc:creator>kqr</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45547079</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45547079</guid></item></channel></rss>