<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>Hacker News: Best Comments</title><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/bestcomments</link><description>Hacker News RSS</description><docs>https://hnrss.org/</docs><generator>hnrss v2.1.1</generator><lastBuildDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2025 00:05:11 +0000</lastBuildDate><ns0:link href="https://hnrss.org/bestcomments" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item><title>New comment by eutropia in "Rubygems.org AWS Root Access Event – September 2025"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;They buried the lede...&lt;p&gt;Arko wanted a copy of the HTTP Access logs from rubygems.org so his consultancy could monetize the data, after RC determined they didn't really have the budget for secondary on-call.&lt;p&gt;Then after they removed him as a maintainer he logged in and changed the AWS root password.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2025 18:05:59 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45531051</link><dc:creator>eutropia</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45531051</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45531051</guid></item><item><title>New comment by miguelgrinberg in "Python 3.14 is here. How fast is it?"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;You have made my day, sir. :)&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2025 17:59:48 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45530977</link><dc:creator>miguelgrinberg</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45530977</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45530977</guid></item><item><title>New comment by nadermx in "Python 3.14 is here. How fast is it?"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Tangential, but I practically ow my life to this guy.  He wrote the flask mega tutorial in what I followed religiously to launch my first website.  Then right before launch, in the most critical part of my entire application; piping a fragged file in flask.  He answered my stackoverflow question, I put his fix live, and the site went viral.  Here's the link for posterity's sake &lt;a href="https://stackoverflow.com/a/34391304/4180276" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://stackoverflow.com/a/34391304/4180276&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2025 17:17:24 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45530499</link><dc:creator>nadermx</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45530499</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45530499</guid></item><item><title>New comment by simonw in "A small number of samples can poison LLMs of any size"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;This looks like a bit of a bombshell:&lt;p&gt;&gt; It reveals a surprising finding: in our experimental setup with simple backdoors designed to trigger low-stakes behaviors, poisoning attacks require a near-constant number of documents regardless of model and training data size. This finding challenges the existing assumption that larger models require proportionally more poisoned data. Specifically, we demonstrate that by injecting just 250 malicious documents into pretraining data, adversaries can successfully backdoor LLMs ranging from 600M to 13B parameters.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2025 16:36:52 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45530023</link><dc:creator>simonw</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45530023</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45530023</guid></item><item><title>New comment by ertgbnm in "The great software quality collapse or, how we normalized catastrophe"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Unrelated but my current AI text flag is the use of "It's not X. It's Y."&lt;p&gt;It's become so repetitive recently. Examples from this post alone:&lt;p&gt;1. "This isn't about AI. The quality crisis started years before ChatGPT existed."&lt;p&gt;2. "The degradation isn't gradual—it's exponential."&lt;p&gt;3. "These aren't feature requirements. They're memory leaks that nobody bothered to fix."&lt;p&gt;4. "This wasn't sophisticated. This was Computer Science 101 error handling that nobody implemented."&lt;p&gt;5. "This isn't an investment. It's capitulation."&lt;p&gt;6. "senior developers don't emerge from thin air. They grow from juniors who:"&lt;p&gt;7. "The solution isn't complex. It's just uncomfortable."&lt;p&gt;Currently this rhetorical device is like nails on a chalkboard for me.&lt;p&gt;Anyway, this isn't a critique of your point. It's pedantry from me. :)&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2025 15:25:24 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45529020</link><dc:creator>ertgbnm</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45529020</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45529020</guid></item><item><title>New comment by throw-10-8 in "The React Foundation"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Vercel being involved is a huge red flag.&lt;p&gt;NextJS is a pile of garbage, and their platform is absurdly expensive and leans heavily on vendor lock in.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2025 09:20:07 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45525339</link><dc:creator>throw-10-8</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45525339</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45525339</guid></item><item><title>New comment by LaurensBER in "A competitor crippled a $23.5M bootcamp by becoming a Reddit moderator"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Moderation on Reddit has been questionable for a long time and its killing the site. To give some examples:&lt;p&gt;- /r/energy used to ban everyone in favour of nuclear energy&lt;p&gt;- If you post on /r/conservative you can expect to receive a bunch of bans from unrelated (popular) subs. Doesn't matter what you posted, being associated with that subs "taints" your account enough for some moderators.&lt;p&gt;- /r/UnitedKingdom banned me for critizing a government welfare program&lt;p&gt;- /r/assassinscreed banned me for critizing a character in their latest game&lt;p&gt;For me it makes sense that the smaller subreddits should have the freedom to moderate as they want but the larger reddits should aim to at allow opposing viewpoints to prevent echo chambers from forming. Moderation should be focused on quality, not on viewpoints. Obviously it goes without saying that threats of violence and celebration of murder have no place on any platform.&lt;p&gt;The irony is that all this censoring just creates a backlash and further polarisation. If you are only allowed to discuss certain subjects on a "left" space you both create the illusion that the left only cares about a subset of topics and by banning people you create resentment that drives them towards (more welcoming) extreme spaces.&lt;p&gt;There's many factors that form the political preferences and opinions of the younger generation but it would not suprise me if for a subset (young college educated males?) of them Reddit heavily contributes towards increased polarisation.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2025 07:41:51 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45524713</link><dc:creator>LaurensBER</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45524713</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45524713</guid></item><item><title>New comment by rossant in "Two things LLM coding agents are still bad at"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Recently, I asked Codex CLI to refactor some HTML files. It didn't literally copy and pasted snippets here and there as I would have done myself, it rewrote them from memory, removing comments in the process. There was a section with 40 successive &lt;a href...&gt; links with complex URLs.&lt;p&gt;A few days later, just before deployment to production, I wanted to double check all 40 links. First one worked. Second one worked. Third one worked. Fourth one worked. So far so good. Then I tried the last four. Perfect.&lt;p&gt;Just to be sure, I proceeded with the fifth one. 404. Huh. Weird. The domain was correct though and the URL seemed reasonable.&lt;p&gt;I tried the other 31 links. ALL of them 404ed. I was totally confused. The domain was always correct. It seemed highly suspicious that all websites would have had moved internal URLs at the same time. I didn't even remember that this part of the code had gone through an LLM.&lt;p&gt;Fortunately, I could retrieve the old URLs on old git commits. I checked the URLs carefully. The LLM had HALLUCINATED most of the path part of the URLs! Replacing things like domain.com/this-article-is-about-foobar-123456/ by domain.com/foobar-is-so-great-162543/...&lt;p&gt;These kinds of very subtle and silently introduced mistakes are quite dangerous. Be careful out there!&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2025 06:56:32 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45524410</link><dc:creator>rossant</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45524410</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45524410</guid></item><item><title>New comment by SequoiaHope in "Discord says 70k users may have had their government IDs leaked in breach"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;It is a common misconception that facts are reported because they are surprising. Facts are reported because they are important. More and more governments are passing age verification laws which put exactly this data in to the hands of even more shady private companies. This breach serves as evidence that those laws are misguided, and spreading news of this event may help build public support for those efforts.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2025 06:10:31 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45524117</link><dc:creator>SequoiaHope</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45524117</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45524117</guid></item><item><title>New comment by safety1st in "A competitor crippled a $23.5M bootcamp by becoming a Reddit moderator"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Reddit has a moderation problem, and it's a big one.&lt;p&gt;They've now been asked to appear in front of Congress to address concerns about politically motivated violence being incited through their platform: &lt;a href="https://oversight.house.gov/release/chairman-comer-invites-ceos-of-discord-steam-twitch-and-reddit-to-testify-on-radicalization-of-online-forum-users/" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://oversight.house.gov/release/chairman-comer-invites-c...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;Personally I believe I've seen more people in the past few years wish a politically motivated death on somebody else via Reddit, than I have anywhere else in my life.&lt;p&gt;Now if it was "just" the incitements to violence, or if it was "just" the libeling of random businesses, that would be one thing. But the fact that BOTH types of illegal speech are becoming a problem at the same time suggests to me that Reddit's failure to moderate is systemic and total.&lt;p&gt;It is becoming exhausting watching all of these tech companies commit crimes, or enable someone else to do so, and getting off with a slap on the wrist.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2025 05:06:07 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45523732</link><dc:creator>safety1st</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45523732</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45523732</guid></item><item><title>New comment by neilv in "A competitor crippled a $23.5M bootcamp by becoming a Reddit moderator"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I don't know about this particular case, but, generally... bad actor subreddit moderators have been an occasional thing for well over a decade.&lt;p&gt;And it's also been widely known for that long that Reddit is an influential venue in which to take over a corner -- for marketing or propaganda.&lt;p&gt;What's an equal concern to me is how &lt;i&gt;insufficiently resilient&lt;/i&gt; Reddit collectively appears to be, in face of this.&lt;p&gt;A bad actor mod of a popular subreddit can persist for years, visibly, without people managing either to oust the mod, or to take down the sub's influence.&lt;p&gt;(Subreddit peasants sometimes migrate to a new sub over bad mods, but the old sub usually remains, still with a healthy brand.  And still with a lot of members, who (speculating) maybe don't want to possibly miss out on something in the bad old sub, or didn't know what's going on, or the drama they noticed in their feed wasn't worth their effort to do the clicks to unjoin from the sub in question.)&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2025 02:38:43 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45522926</link><dc:creator>neilv</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45522926</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45522926</guid></item><item><title>New comment by fny in "A competitor crippled a $23.5M bootcamp by becoming a Reddit moderator"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;If you really cared, this should have started with: "I am stepping down as the moderator..."&lt;p&gt;Even though you have counter claims, you moderating &lt;i&gt;the forum&lt;/i&gt; for your industry is problematic. You also seem keen to chime in about a competitor when you should be impartial and allow users to discuss their experiences alone.&lt;p&gt;Yes there are two sides to every story, but in no universe should you be the mod of that subreddit.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2025 01:41:28 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45522560</link><dc:creator>fny</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45522560</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45522560</guid></item><item><title>New comment by tifik in "Discord says 70k users may have had their government IDs leaked in breach"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I don't know if I just became cynical and jaded, but is this really surprising to anyone in any way? Any time I give out my personal information to anyone for any reason, I basically treat it as 'any member of public can now access it'.&lt;p&gt;Even if a service doesn't have it in their TOS that they sell it to 3rd parties, they might do it anyway, or there will, sooner or later, be a breach of their poorly secured system.&lt;p&gt;To make it clear - I don't particularly blame any one corporation, this is a systemic issue of governments not having/not enforcing serious security measures. I just completely dropped the expectation of my information being private, and for the very few bits that I do actually want to stay private, I just don't, or allow anyone to, digitalize or reproduce them at all in any way.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2025 01:13:00 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45522379</link><dc:creator>tifik</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45522379</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45522379</guid></item><item><title>New comment by LennyHenrysNuts in "WinBoat: Windows apps on Linux with seamless integration"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;And I had to come here to find out what it actually was. Why don't project pages ever actually tell you what it is, what it does and how it does it?&lt;p&gt;Half the time it's something like "Plorglewurzle leverages your big data block chain to provide sublinear microservices to Azure Cloud infrastructures"&lt;p&gt;At least this one kind of shows you having to install Windows.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2025 01:06:27 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45522341</link><dc:creator>LennyHenrysNuts</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45522341</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45522341</guid></item><item><title>New comment by gruez in "OpenAI, Nvidia fuel $1T AI market with web of circular deals"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;For an interesting interpretation of the recent AMD-OpenAI deal, see Matt Levine's column from a few days ago:&lt;p&gt;&gt; OpenAI: We would like six gigawatts worth of your chips to do inference.&lt;p&gt;&gt; AMD: Terrific. That will be $78 billion. How would you like to pay?&lt;p&gt;&gt; OpenAI: Well, we were thinking that we would announce the deal, and that would add $78 billion to the value of your company, which should cover it.&lt;p&gt;&gt; AMD: …&lt;p&gt;&gt; OpenAI: …&lt;p&gt;&gt; AMD: No I’m pretty sure you have to pay for the chips.&lt;p&gt;&gt; OpenAI: Why?&lt;p&gt;&gt; AMD: I dunno, just seems wrong not to.&lt;p&gt;&gt; OpenAI: Okay. Why don’t we pay you cash for the value of the chips, and you give us back stock, and when we announce the deal the stock will go up and we’ll get our $78 billion back.&lt;p&gt;&gt; AMD: Yeah I guess that works though I feel like we should get some of the value?&lt;p&gt;&gt; OpenAI: Okay you can have half. You give us stock worth like $35 billion and you keep the rest.&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/opinion/newsletters/2025-10-06/openai-is-good-at-deals" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://www.bloomberg.com/opinion/newsletters/2025-10-06/ope...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://archive.is/tS5sy" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://archive.is/tS5sy&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2025 00:19:58 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45522103</link><dc:creator>gruez</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45522103</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45522103</guid></item><item><title>New comment by Angostura in "OpenAI, Nvidia fuel $1T AI market with web of circular deals"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;This reminds me of around 2002 when I wrote an article looking at how all the web behemoths at the time were claiming profitability through ad sales, but actually the vast majority of ads were from one web behemoth advertising on an other's site and vice versa.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2025 00:15:35 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45522071</link><dc:creator>Angostura</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45522071</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45522071</guid></item><item><title>New comment by WA in "One-man campaign ravages EU 'Chat Control' bill"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I love it. Especially since:&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;&gt; The campaign has irked some recipients. “In terms of dialog within a democracy, this is not a dialog,” said Lena Düpont, a German member of the European People’s Party group and its home affairs spokesperson, of the mass emails.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;p&gt;It is a dialog. Millions are against it, a few (powerful people) in favor. The powerful are too detached from reality and consider this "not a dialog".&lt;p&gt;On a meta level, it even gives them a taste of the millions of messages that‘d get flagged false positively monthly, overwhelming police and other systems.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2025 20:15:58 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45520114</link><dc:creator>WA</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45520114</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45520114</guid></item><item><title>New comment by oli5679 in "One-man campaign ravages EU 'Chat Control' bill"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;One interesting anecdote about this bill was that the European Commission allegedly funded digital advertisements promoting it, targeting specific political demographics, which is something that could possibly be prohibited by their own regulations.&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://noyb.eu/en/noyb-files-complaint-against-eu-commission-over-targeted-chat-control-ads" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://noyb.eu/en/noyb-files-complaint-against-eu-commissio...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://eur-lex.europa.eu/EN/legal-content/summary/transparency-and-targeting-of-political-advertising.html" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://eur-lex.europa.eu/EN/legal-content/summary/transpare...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2025 19:40:33 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45519805</link><dc:creator>oli5679</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45519805</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45519805</guid></item><item><title>New comment by userbinator in "WinBoat: Windows apps on Linux with seamless integration"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Missed opportunity to call it "Linux Subsystem for Windows", or LSW in short.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2025 19:31:45 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45519727</link><dc:creator>userbinator</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45519727</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45519727</guid></item><item><title>New comment by oneplane in "WinBoat: Windows apps on Linux with seamless integration"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;This is just a Windows VM with extra tooling. Makes it look slick, doesn't make it "Windows apps on Linux".&lt;p&gt;Similar projects exist for gaming for example Looking Glass, which also uses a Windows VM on KVM (the "Windows in Docker" thing is a bit of a lie, Windows doesn't run in the container, Windows runs on KVM on the host kernel).&lt;p&gt;UX wise, this is similar to RAIL.&lt;p&gt;That's not to say that this isn't neat, but it's also not something new (we still have two flavours: API simulation/re-implementation and running the OS [windows]). If this was a new, third flavour, that would be quite the news (in-place ABI translation?).&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2025 18:44:40 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45519278</link><dc:creator>oneplane</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45519278</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45519278</guid></item><item><title>New comment by HanClinto in "The RSS feed reader landscape"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I still miss Google Reader. I loved the social aspects, where I could repost my favorite articles (with comments about them), and friends could easily subscribe to my feed and comment on my shares. It was a really great social network for sharing blog posts and articles. I credit the demise of Google Reader with a lot of the downfall of the Old Web.&lt;p&gt;Since then, social sharing platforms are motivated to keep you on their platform. I recently ran an experiment on Facebook, where I posted a link to a content creator's video on YouTube with a lot of my thoughts about it.&lt;p&gt;I then downloaded the same video from YouTube and uploaded it to Facebook (this particular creator didn't upload his content to Facebook directly), and posted the &lt;i&gt;exact same text content&lt;/i&gt; (but this time, hid the link the the source video in a comment).&lt;p&gt;The post where I downloaded + reposted the video got about 1000x more views than the one where I linked to the source.&lt;p&gt;On top of that, Facebook will often hide the link to the source video unless I click "Show all comments" (rather than the default "Show most relevant").&lt;p&gt;Facebook deprioritizes (shadowbans?) posts that link off of their platform, and it starts feeling like a stagnant pond. It's frustrating that it's difficult to share insightful blog posts on that platform, and I'm feeling pretty done with it.&lt;p&gt;Getting a good RSS reader isn't the part that I'm looking for -- I want the easy social aspect that Google Reader and Google+ gave me.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2025 16:35:49 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45518009</link><dc:creator>HanClinto</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45518009</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45518009</guid></item><item><title>New comment by Aurornis in "Synology reverses policy banning third-party HDDs"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&gt; What is interesting here is that Synology leadership is quite technical&lt;p&gt;Vagueposting out of necessity: I worked at a different company that made popular consumer products and had leadership with technical backgrounds. That company also went through a period of trying to lock down the platform for profits, which everyone hated.&lt;p&gt;The root cause was that the technical leadership had started to think two things: That their customers were so loyal to the brand that they wouldn’t leave, and that the customers weren’t smart enough to recognize that the artificial restrictions had no real basis in reality.&lt;p&gt;I remember attending a meeting where the CEO bragged about a decision he made that arbitrarily worsened a product for consumers. He laughed that people still bought it and loved it. “Can you believe that? They’ll buy anything we tell them to.” was the paraphrased statement I remember.&lt;p&gt;Of course, the backlash came when they pushed too hard. Fortunately this company recognized what was going on and the CEO moved on to other matters, leaving product choices back to the teams. I wonder if something similar happened with Synology.&lt;p&gt;Regarding employee morale: It was very depressing for me during this period to open Hacker News and see threads complaining about my employer. I can confirm that it spurred a job search for me.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2025 14:00:01 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45516301</link><dc:creator>Aurornis</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45516301</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45516301</guid></item><item><title>New comment by SkipperCat in "SEC approves Texas Stock Exchange, first new US integrated exchange in decades"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;The Miami stock exchange (MIAX) has their matching engines colocated in Equinix's NY4 data center in Secaucus NJ, much like many other exchanges.  I would not be surprised if TXSE does the same.&lt;p&gt;Many trading firms already have their trading engines in that data center and I would assume TXSE would want quick access to that order flow and this might be easier if they are in NY4.&lt;p&gt;Of course, they may want to have their colo facilities in TX in their own data center, that way they can rent out space and make some extra revenue, but then they'd have to build that out.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2025 12:20:26 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45515354</link><dc:creator>SkipperCat</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45515354</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45515354</guid></item><item><title>New comment by cozzyd in "SEC approves Texas Stock Exchange, first new US integrated exchange in decades"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Hope they have ample backup power&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2025 12:14:27 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45515303</link><dc:creator>cozzyd</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45515303</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45515303</guid></item><item><title>New comment by 1gn15 in "One-man campaign ravages EU 'Chat Control' bill"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Thanks Joachim! Still frustrating that Politico still implies that the bill has any power to stop CSAM, given that everyone who wants to trade it will obviously just use another layer of encryption.&lt;p&gt;&gt; The campaign has irked some recipients. “In terms of dialog within a democracy, this is not a dialog,” said Lena Düpont, a German member of the European People’s Party group and its home affairs spokesperson, of the mass emails.&lt;p&gt;What is a dialog, then? A dialogue between well-connected lobbyists and bureaucrats, and everyone else should just shut up and take it?&lt;p&gt;Or, or, "normal people" sending emails only for the lawmakers to go "thanks for the feedback, we're doing it anyway"?&lt;p&gt;&gt; One EU diplomat said some EU member countries are now more hesitant to support Denmark’s proposal, at least in part because of the campaign: “There is a clear link.”&lt;p&gt;&gt; Ella Jakubowska, head of policy at digital rights group EDRi, said “This campaign seems to have raised the topic high up the agenda in member states where there was previously little to no public debate."&lt;p&gt;This is amazing, and makes me regain a bit of (much destroyed) faith in democracy.&lt;p&gt;&gt; But Danish Justice Minister Peter Hummelgaard, one of the loudest proponents of tough measures to get child abuse material off online platforms, said in a statement that his proposal is far more balanced than the Commission’s original version and would mean that scanning would only happen as a last resort.&lt;p&gt;If the option is there, it will be abused.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2025 11:26:05 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45514883</link><dc:creator>1gn15</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45514883</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45514883</guid></item><item><title>New comment by jacquesm in "Synology reverses policy banning third-party HDDs"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;What is interesting here is that Synology leadership is quite technical and there was no acquisition or other big event that I am aware of that resulted in this strategy. It was a complete own goal and as predictable as could be. Synology apparently wasn't aware of what their brand values were as perceived by their loyal customers and that's the kind of move you make at your peril. I'll be surprised if they survive this in the longer term, regardless of the reversal they've shown they do not have their customers interests at heart at all. It's dumber that it even seems: they were raking in a substantial amount of money precisely because of this one factor, and they pretty much shot the goose that was laying the golden eggs.&lt;p&gt;I've been a loyal customers of theirs and wasn't even looking at other options but there won't be another cent of mine going to Synology. I was already miffed at their mark-up for a little bit of memory before this happened. It is a matter of time before they crash and I don't want to end up with an unsupported piece of hardware. Trust is everything in the storage business.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2025 10:59:41 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45514686</link><dc:creator>jacquesm</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45514686</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45514686</guid></item><item><title>New comment by osivertsson in "Synology reverses policy banning third-party HDDs"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;When leadership makes decisions that are so out of touch with their customers it also severely impacts &lt;i&gt;internal&lt;/i&gt; morale.&lt;p&gt;Yeah, so they reversed eventually. But the technical and support people at Synology probably tried to fight this and lost. That feeling of being ignored despite having given this company your everything for many years. I bet many woke up feeling that the magic that made Synology a good place to work is gone.&lt;p&gt;My guess is they will continue to lose the most valuable employees unless they replace management with some internally well-respected staff that understands their customers well.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2025 09:01:23 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45513826</link><dc:creator>osivertsson</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45513826</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45513826</guid></item><item><title>New comment by tkgally in "Vibe engineering"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Around the time GPT-4 was released in early 2023, a similar issue arose with another profession: translation. It was at that point that machine translation between languages like English and Japanese (the language pair I have worked with) started to approach human level for the first time.&lt;p&gt;I took part in a lot of discussions then with other professional translators, and the reaction of many was similar to that of some of the commenters here: not only were they discouraged because their hard-earned language and translation skills no longer seemed needed, but using LLMs as assistants took the enjoyable challenge out of the translation process.&lt;p&gt;Nearly everyone I spoke with then worked from home as a freelancer, carefully crafting one translation at a time. They didn’t like the idea of becoming managers of large-scale translation projects, even if it meant they would be able to apply their higher-order intercultural communication skills.&lt;p&gt;I do only a little professional translation myself now, but I try to keep up with AI developments and I often use translation tasks to test the latest models and frameworks. Over the past few months, I have vibe-coded some multi-LLM translation systems where texts were passed through multiple models that checked, critiqued, and improved each other’s translations. For the texts I tried them on, the results were much better than any single-LLM translation, approaching the level of the very best human translation. The API calls weren’t cheap, but for high-stakes translations such a system would more than pay for itself.&lt;p&gt;When designing that “vibe translation” system, I did apply my experience as a translator, similarly to what Simon is recommending programmers do now with vibe engineering. At this stage in my life (I’m sixty-eight), I am fine with that. But if LLMs had arrived when I was, say, just five or ten years into my translation career and still proud of my nuts-and-bolts skills, I might very well have looked for another career rather than becoming a vibe translator.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2025 07:50:31 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45513288</link><dc:creator>tkgally</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45513288</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45513288</guid></item><item><title>New comment by simonw in "Vibe engineering"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I'm really sorry to hear this, because part of my goal here is to help push back against the idea that "programming skills are useless now, anyone can get an LLM to write code for them".&lt;p&gt;I think existing software development skills get a whole lot &lt;i&gt;more&lt;/i&gt; valuable with the addition of coding agents. You can take everything you've learned up to this point and accelerate the impact you can have with this new family of tools.&lt;p&gt;I said a version of this in the post:&lt;p&gt;&gt; AI tools &lt;i&gt;amplify existing expertise&lt;/i&gt;. The more skills and experience you have as a software engineer the faster and better the results you can get from working with LLMs and coding agents.&lt;p&gt;A brand new vibe coder may be able to get a cool UI out of ChatGPT, but they're not going to be able to rig up a set of automated tests with continuous integration and continuous deployment to a Kubernetes cluster somewhere. They're also not going to be able to direct three different agents at once in different areas of a large project that they've designed the architecture for.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2025 05:03:05 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45512258</link><dc:creator>simonw</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45512258</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45512258</guid></item><item><title>New comment by subarctic in "Vibe engineering"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I just feel so discouraged reading this somehow. I used to have this hard-to-get, in-demand skill that paid lots of money and felt like even though programming languages, libraries and web frameworks were always evolving I could always keep up because I'm smart. But now with these people like Simon Willison writing about the new way of coding with these agents and multiple streams of work going on at a time and it sounding like this is the future, I just feel discouraged because it sounds like so much work and I've tried using coding agents and they help a bit, but I find it way less fun to be waiting around for agents to do stuff and it's way harder to get into flow state managing multiple of these things. It makes me want to move into something completely different like sales&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2025 04:32:25 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45512098</link><dc:creator>subarctic</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45512098</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45512098</guid></item></channel></rss>