<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>Hacker News: Best Comments</title><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/bestcomments</link><description>Hacker News RSS</description><docs>https://hnrss.org/</docs><generator>hnrss v2.1.1</generator><lastBuildDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 23:43:27 +0000</lastBuildDate><ns0:link href="https://hnrss.org/bestcomments" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item><title>New comment by comte7092 in "I'm returning my Framework 16"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I appreciate the authors thoughtful review here, but I can’t help but be frustrated by the constant lack of understanding of the core value proposition of framework both in this post and in many comments here on hn.&lt;p&gt;Frequently the author brings up that for 2,000 euros they expect a premium experience, but no where is there an evaluation of the value granted by upgradability and repeatability of the machine, and only briefly is there mention of the configurability.&lt;p&gt;People (not necessarily the author, but likely many commentators that make similar complains about the frameworks price) will lament how manufacturers don’t have upgradable ram, etc and then turn around and are upset at the bulkiness of a repairable laptop, or the price.&lt;p&gt;I think ultimately what frustrates me is that people don’t consider the ability to repair or upgrade your machine part of a “premium” experience, but that’s is just something I have to accept. I think it is unfortunate that our consumerist culture places so little value on it though.&lt;p&gt;Rergardless, what I feel like we see here (along with a lack of scale from a small company) is the core tradeoffs that we’d have to make to get back repairability, etc. framework certainly isn’t above criticism, but if you don’t care about these things then why look at this machine? A large established brand is always going to offer a a better value on the things you care about.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 17:34:42 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46377476</link><dc:creator>comte7092</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46377476</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46377476</guid></item><item><title>New comment by barrkel in "Avoid Mini-Frameworks"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&gt; &lt;i&gt;real and only difference between a library and a framework, is whether it introduces new concepts&lt;/i&gt;&lt;p&gt;This isn't what is normally understood in software engineering by those terms.&lt;p&gt;A library is something you call.&lt;p&gt;A framework is some kind of application scaffolding that normally calls you.&lt;p&gt;You can use more than one library. You normally only have one framework in-process.&lt;p&gt;I found the blog post a little hard to parse. Is it an argument against wrapping frameworks, or wrapping libraries?&lt;p&gt;I agree that wrapping frameworks is fraught with danger. I can't quite agree for wrapping libraries. Wrapping libraries makes a lot of sense if you're only using a tiny fraction of the library functionality, the breadth of the wrapper's API is much smaller than the library's API, wrapping it enables you to substitute it (whether for a smaller / faster / whatever dependency in the future, or for testing, etc.), and so on.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 13:00:31 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46375199</link><dc:creator>barrkel</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46375199</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46375199</guid></item><item><title>New comment by Arch-TK in "Some Epstein file redactions are being undone"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;It sets a bad precedent to call things like this hacks.&lt;p&gt;Firstly, calling this redaction implies that the data is missing, and calling what was done "unredacting" is akin to saying someone "decrypted" a cryptographic hash function.&lt;p&gt;Nobody unredacted anything here, they merely discovered that it hadn't been redacted, and simply looked like it was redacted.&lt;p&gt;Calling this a hack places responsibility on the people who discovered the information, rather than on the people were put in charge of handling the redaction and screwed it up.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 12:48:31 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46375128</link><dc:creator>Arch-TK</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46375128</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46375128</guid></item><item><title>New comment by heavyset_go in "Some Epstein file redactions are being undone"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I want to believe this is malicious compliance.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 06:02:08 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46372914</link><dc:creator>heavyset_go</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46372914</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46372914</guid></item><item><title>New comment by vincengomes in "Some Epstein file redactions are being undone"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;"Never interrupt your enemy when he is making a mistake" -  Napoleon Bonaparte&lt;p&gt;Let all the files get released first.&lt;p&gt;Then show your hacks.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 04:20:05 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46372417</link><dc:creator>vincengomes</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46372417</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46372417</guid></item><item><title>New comment by wateralien in "Unifi Travel Router"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I never travel without my GL-AXT1800. Saved me so many times: &lt;a href="https://www.gl-inet.com/products/gl-axt1800/" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://www.gl-inet.com/products/gl-axt1800/&lt;/a&gt;
I’m actually on it right now.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 01:06:19 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46371338</link><dc:creator>wateralien</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46371338</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46371338</guid></item><item><title>New comment by kburman in "I didn't realize my LG TV was spying on me until I turned off Live Plus"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;My rule for modern TVs:
1. Never connect the TV panel itself to the internet. Keep it air-gapped. Treat it solely as a dumb monitor.&lt;p&gt;2. Use an Apple TV for the "smart" features.&lt;p&gt;3. Avoid Fire TV, Chromecast, or Roku.&lt;p&gt;The logic is simple, Google (Chromecast) and Amazon (Fire TV) operate on the same business model as the TV manufacturers subsidized hardware in exchange for user data and ad inventory. Apple is the only mainstream option where the hardware cost covers the experience, rather than your viewing habits subsidizing the device.&lt;p&gt;[Copied my comment from here: &lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46268844#46271740"&gt;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46268844#46271740&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 23:10:11 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46370577</link><dc:creator>kburman</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46370577</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46370577</guid></item><item><title>New comment by WarOnPrivacy in "Texas app store age verification law blocked by federal judge"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Judge Robert Pitman said that it violates the First Amendment and is "more likely than not - unconstitutional."&lt;p&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;    The Act is akin to a law that would require every bookstore to verify
    the age of every customer at the door and, for minors, require parental
    consent before the child or teen could enter and again when they try to
    purchase a book.
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
We enjoy 1A protections of speech and assembly. When we consider our rights, the productive, default position is that government is told no (when it wants to restrict us).&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 23:04:01 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46370528</link><dc:creator>WarOnPrivacy</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46370528</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46370528</guid></item><item><title>New comment by mlissner in "X-ray: a Python library for finding bad redactions in PDF documents"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Cool to see this here. It’s funny because we do so many huge, complex, multiyear  projects at Free Law Project, but this is the most viral any of our work has ever gone!&lt;p&gt;Anyway, I made X-ray to analyze the millions of documents we have in CourtListener so that we can try to educate people about the issue.&lt;p&gt;The analysis was fun. We used S3 batch jobs to analyze millions of documents in a matter of minutes, but we haven’t done the hard part of looking at the results and reporting them out. One day.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 23:03:44 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46370525</link><dc:creator>mlissner</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46370525</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46370525</guid></item><item><title>New comment by qbow883 in "We replaced H.264 streaming with JPEG screenshots (and it worked better)"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Setting aside the various formatting problems and the LLM writing style, this just seems all kinds of wrong throughout.&lt;p&gt;&gt; “Just lower the bitrate,” you say. Great idea. Now it’s 10Mbps of blocky garbage that’s still 30 seconds behind.&lt;p&gt;10Mbps should be &lt;i&gt;way&lt;/i&gt; more than enough for a mostly static image with some scrolling text. (And 40Mbps are ridiculous.) This is very likely to be caused by bad encoding settings and/or a bad encoder.&lt;p&gt;&gt; “What if we only send keyframes?”
The post goes on to explain how this does not work because some other component needs to see P-frames. If that is the case, just configure your encoder to have very short keyframe intervals.&lt;p&gt;&gt; And the size! A 70% quality JPEG of a 1080p desktop is like 100-150KB. A single H.264 keyframe is 200-500KB.&lt;p&gt;A single H.264 keyframe can be whatever size you want, *depending on how you configure your encoder*, which was apparently never seriously attempted. Why are we badly reinventing MJPEG instead of configuring the tools we already have? Lower the bitrate and keyint, use a better encoder for higher quality, lower the frame rate if you need to. (If 10 fps JPEGs are acceptable, surely you should try 10 fps H.264 too?)&lt;p&gt;But all in all the main problem seems to be squeezing an entire video stream through a single TCP connection. There are plenty of existing solutions for this. For example, this article never mentions DASH, which is made for these exact purposes.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 21:38:47 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46369771</link><dc:creator>qbow883</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46369771</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46369771</guid></item><item><title>New comment by auxiliarymoose in "We replaced H.264 streaming with JPEG screenshots (and it worked better)"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;They shared the polling code in the article. It doesn't request another jpeg until the previous one finishes downloading. UDP is not necessary to write a loop.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 21:06:33 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46369456</link><dc:creator>auxiliarymoose</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46369456</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46369456</guid></item><item><title>New comment by mikepavone in "We replaced H.264 streaming with JPEG screenshots (and it worked better)"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&gt; When the network is bad, you get... fewer JPEGs. That’s it. The ones that arrive are perfect.&lt;p&gt;This would make sense... if they were using UDP, but they are using TCP. All the JPEGs they send will get there eventually (unless the connection drops). JPEG does not fix your buffering and congestion control problems. What presumably happened here is the way they implemented their JPEG screenshots, they have some mechanism that minimizes the number of frames that are in-flight. This is not some inherent property of JPEG though.&lt;p&gt;&gt; And the size! A 70% quality JPEG of a 1080p desktop is like 100-150KB. A single H.264 keyframe is 200-500KB. We’re sending LESS data per frame AND getting better reliability.&lt;p&gt;h.264 has better coding efficiency than JPEG. For a given target size, you should be able to get better quality from an h.264 IDR frame than a JPEG. There is no fixed size to an IDR frame.&lt;p&gt;Ultimately, the problem here is a lack of bandwidth estimation (apart from the sort of binary "good network"/"cafe mode" thing they ultimately implemented). To be fair, this is difficult to do and being stuck with TCP makes it a bit more difficult. Still, you can do an initial bandwidth probe and then look for increasing transmission latency as a sign that the network is congested. Back off your bitrate (and if needed reduce frame rate to maintain sufficient quality) until transmission latency starts to decrease again.&lt;p&gt;WebRTC will do this for you if you can use it, which actually suggests a different solution to this problem: use websockets for dumb corporate network firewall rules and just use WebRTC everything else&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 20:00:15 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46368838</link><dc:creator>mikepavone</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46368838</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46368838</guid></item><item><title>New comment by antirez in "Fabrice Bellard Releases MicroQuickJS"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;If this had been available in 2010, Redis scripting would have been JavaScript and not Lua. Lua was chosen based on the implementation requirements, not on the language ones... (small, fast, ANSI-C). I appreciate certain ideas in Lua, and people love it, but I was never able to &lt;i&gt;like&lt;/i&gt; Lua, because it departs from a more Algol-like syntax and semantics without good reasons, for my taste. This creates friction for newcomers. I love friction when it opens new useful ideas and abstractions that are worth it, if you learn SmallTalk or FORTH and for some time you are lost, it's part of how the languages are different. But I think for Lua this is not true enough: it feels like it departs from what people know without good reasons.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 19:49:27 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46368706</link><dc:creator>antirez</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46368706</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46368706</guid></item><item><title>New comment by adamjs in "We replaced H.264 streaming with JPEG screenshots (and it worked better)"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;They might want to check out what VNC has been doing since 1998– keep the client-pull model, break the framebuffer up into tiles and, when client requests an update, perform a diff against last frame sent, composite the updated tiles client-side. (This is what VNC falls back to when it doesn’t have damage-tracking from the OS compositor)&lt;p&gt;This would really cut down on the bandwidth of static coding terminals where 90% of screen is just cursor flashing or small bits of text moving.&lt;p&gt;If they really wanted to be ambitious they could also detect scrolling and do an optimization client-side where it translates some of the existing areas (look up CopyRect command in VNC).&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 19:30:23 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46368519</link><dc:creator>adamjs</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46368519</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46368519</guid></item><item><title>New comment by groundzeros2015 in "Fabrice Bellard Releases MicroQuickJS"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;For all the praise he gets here, few seem interested in his methods: writing complete programs, based on robust computer science, with minimal dependencies and tooling.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 19:13:23 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46368341</link><dc:creator>groundzeros2015</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46368341</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46368341</guid></item><item><title>New comment by ddtaylor in "Fabrice Bellard Releases MicroQuickJS"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Fabrice Bellard is widely considered one of the most productive and versatile programmers alive:&lt;p&gt;- FFmpeg: &lt;a href="https://bellard.org" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://bellard.org&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;- QEMU: &lt;a href="https://bellard.org/qemu/" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://bellard.org/qemu/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;- JSLinux: &lt;a href="https://bellard.org/jslinux/" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://bellard.org/jslinux/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;- TCC: &lt;a href="https://bellard.org/tcc/" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://bellard.org/tcc/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;- QuickJS: &lt;a href="https://bellard.org/quickjs/" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://bellard.org/quickjs/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;Legendary.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 18:45:15 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46367994</link><dc:creator>ddtaylor</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46367994</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46367994</guid></item><item><title>New comment by pizlonator in "Fabrice Bellard Releases MicroQuickJS"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;This engine restricts JS in all of the ways I wished I could restrict the language back when I was working on JSC.&lt;p&gt;You can’t restrict JS that way on the web because of compatibility. But I totally buy that restricting it this way for embedded systems will result in something that sparks joy&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 18:41:14 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46367946</link><dc:creator>pizlonator</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46367946</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46367946</guid></item><item><title>New comment by cmarschner in "Some Epstein file redactions are being undone"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Befuddling that this happened again. It’s not the first time&lt;p&gt;- Paul Manafort court filing (U.S., 2019)
Manafort’s lawyers filed a PDF where the “redacted” parts were basically black highlighting/boxes over live text. Reporters could recover the hidden text (e.g., via copy/paste).&lt;p&gt;- TSA “Standard Operating Procedures” manual (U.S., 2009)
A publicly posted TSA screening document used black rectangles that did not remove the underlying text; the concealed content could be extracted. This led to extensive discussion and an Inspector General review.&lt;p&gt;- UK Ministry of Defence submarine security document (UK, 2011)
A MoD report had “redacted” sections that could be revealed by copying/pasting the “blacked out” text—because the text was still present, just visually obscured.&lt;p&gt;- Apple v. Samsung ruling (U.S., 2011)
A federal judge’s opinion attempted to redact passages, but the content was still recoverable due to the way the PDF was formatted; copying text out revealed the “redacted” parts.&lt;p&gt;- Associated Press + Facebook valuation estimate in court transcript (U.S., 2009)
The AP reported it could read “redacted” portions of a court transcript by cut-and-paste (classic overlay-style failure). Secondary coverage notes the mechanism explicitly.&lt;p&gt;A broader “history of failures” compilation (multiple orgs / years)
The PDF Association collected multiple incidents (including several above) and describes the common failure mode: black shapes drawn over text without deleting/sanitizing the underlying content.
&lt;a href="https://pdfa.org/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/High-Security-PDF-Redactions-v4a_2.pdf" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://pdfa.org/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/High-Security-PD...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 18:11:17 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46367613</link><dc:creator>cmarschner</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46367613</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46367613</guid></item><item><title>New comment by InsideOutSanta in "How did DOGE disrupt so much while saving so little?"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Perhaps because disrupting things was the actual goal, rather than saving money. DOGE was highly effective in harming the entities meant to oversee Musk's companies, stealing information about union organizing and labor complaints, reducing the government's ability to collect taxes, and destroying its regulatory capacity.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 18:11:14 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46367611</link><dc:creator>InsideOutSanta</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46367611</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46367611</guid></item><item><title>New comment by Fiveplus in "Meta is using the Linux scheduler designed for Valve's Steam Deck on its servers"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Valve is practically singlehandedly dragging the Linux ecosystem forward in areas that nobody else wanted to touch.&lt;p&gt;They needed Windows games to run on Linux so we got massive Proton/Wine advancements. They needed better display output for the deck and we got HDR and VRR support in wayland. They also needed smoother frame pacing and we got a scheduler that Zuck is now using to run data centers.&lt;p&gt;Its funny to think that Meta's server efficiency is being improved because Valve paid Igalia to make Elden Ring stutter less on a portable Linux PC. This is the best kind of open source trickledown.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 17:46:01 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46367336</link><dc:creator>Fiveplus</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46367336</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46367336</guid></item><item><title>New comment by ZeroCool2u in "Meta is using the Linux scheduler designed for Valve's Steam Deck on its servers"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Igalia is a bit unique as it serves as a single corporate entity for organizing a lot of sponsored work on the Linux kernel and open source projects. You'll notice in their blog posts they have collaborations with a number of other large companies seeking to sponsor very specific development work. For example, Google works with them a lot. I think it really just simplifies a lot of logistics for paying folks to do this kind of work, plus the Igalia employees can get shared efficiency's and savings for things like benefits etc.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 17:37:14 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46367263</link><dc:creator>ZeroCool2u</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46367263</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46367263</guid></item><item><title>New comment by gmd63 in "Inside CECOT – 60 Minutes [video]"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Larry Ellison is using his bags to purchase lies and silence.&lt;p&gt;No economy can be in true equilibrium when the consumers send profits to be spent in unforeseen and unrelated ways like this. Every purchase carries potentially immense future costs that are almost completely opaque.&lt;p&gt;Free market maximalists need to confront this fact before praying at the altar of complete deregulation, and every consumer should pay more attention to who they are buying from.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 16:18:18 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46366530</link><dc:creator>gmd63</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46366530</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46366530</guid></item><item><title>New comment by evan_ in "Inside CECOT – 60 Minutes [video]"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;The whole thing is poorly-conceived and obviously false but I just have to call this out-&lt;p&gt;&gt; Of the 252 Venezuelans sent to CECOT, we say nearly half have no criminal histories. In other words, more than half do have criminal histories. We should spend a beat explaining this.&lt;p&gt;The story isn't that people found guilty of crimes went to jail, the story is that half weren't even charged with crimes! That's the whole point of the story! We should not be aiming for a balanced diet of criminals and not-criminals in our government-sponsored foreign death camps!&lt;p&gt;The fact that they exist at all is an affront to humanity, but to say "it's OK because a slim majority &lt;i&gt;deserve&lt;/i&gt; it"- I just don't know what to say.&lt;p&gt;&gt; We then say that only 8 of the 252 have been sentenced in America for violent offenses. But what about charged?&lt;p&gt;What about charged? What does charged with a crime have to do with anything? Why bring that up at all? Do we send people to prison because they were charged with a crime? Is Bari Weiss a newborn baby who has never heard about the presumption of innocence?&lt;p&gt;I feel sick.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 15:04:55 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46365815</link><dc:creator>evan_</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46365815</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46365815</guid></item><item><title>New comment by dcminter in "Ryanair fined €256M over ‘abusive strategy’ to limit ticket sales by OTAs"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;"O’Leary accused the travel agent industry of scamming and ripping off unsuspecting consumers by charging extra fees and markups on ticket prices."&lt;/i&gt;&lt;p&gt;That is ... pretty rich.&lt;p&gt;A couple of years ago I was going to go see my brother in the UK who lived near Stansted. As such Ryanair would have been the most convenient airline. The shere number of dark patterns I encountered trying to book the ticket was such that when  I got to the payment page and they tried to coax me into using my local currency instead of GBP and hid a £20 spread in the exchange rate I rage quit. I should have known better even then, but now I will only use them if I have literally no other choice. With luck that means "never."&lt;p&gt;I'm always happy to see the various EU competition authorities pushing back on this kind of thing.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 11:26:19 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46364427</link><dc:creator>dcminter</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46364427</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46364427</guid></item><item><title>New comment by Doches in "10 years bootstrapped: €6.5M revenue with a team of 13"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&gt; We're not bragging (okay, we're bragging a little) but it turns out that not burning through VC cash on ping-pong tables and "growth at all costs" actually works.&lt;p&gt;Have an internet fist-bump from a fellow successful bootstrapper; this is the way, and you're calling it out!&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 10:57:25 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46364290</link><dc:creator>Doches</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46364290</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46364290</guid></item><item><title>New comment by isodev in "iOS 26.3 brings AirPods-like pairing to third-party devices in EU under DMA"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;It’s fascinating the kind of cool features we can have when products are made to be useful, with their target user in mind. Go EU!&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 08:16:57 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46363454</link><dc:creator>isodev</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46363454</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46363454</guid></item><item><title>New comment by cdrnsf in "Inside CECOT – 60 Minutes [video]"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;She was hired following the acquisition of Paramount to do things exactly like this. She's not a journalist.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 01:08:20 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46361258</link><dc:creator>cdrnsf</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46361258</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46361258</guid></item><item><title>New comment by slg in "Inside CECOT – 60 Minutes [video]"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I'm reminded of the Letter on Justice and Open Debate[1] that Bari Weiss signed only a few years ago, now she's spiking stories like this one on CECOT for showing the current administration in a negative light.&lt;p&gt;I also wonder if this story will get the type of leeway to stay on HN to collect the 200+ upvotes and 300+ comments of that previous example or if it will be flagged off the front page within minutes like so many other similar stories.&lt;p&gt;EDIT: No idea how long this post actually lasted, but checking in an hour later to see this has been flagged completely off the first 10 pages of HN despite getting close to that 200 point total.&lt;p&gt;[1] - &lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=23759283"&gt;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=23759283&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 01:06:14 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46361248</link><dc:creator>slg</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46361248</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46361248</guid></item><item><title>New comment by scratchyone in "Inside CECOT – 60 Minutes [video]"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I have a feeling this will get DMCA-ed off of Internet Archive in an attempt to suppress it. Here's the infohash of the archive.org torrent download for future reference, this should allow the file to be retrieved in any torrent client as long as someone in the world is seeding it still.&lt;p&gt;8105370ed7dba50dc7ec659fd67550569b4dd8a0&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 00:55:58 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46361169</link><dc:creator>scratchyone</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46361169</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46361169</guid></item><item><title>New comment by dogman144 in "Flock Exposed Its AI-Powered Cameras to the Internet. We Tracked Ourselves"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Was fortunate to talk to a security lead who built the data-driven policing network for a major American city that was an early adopter. ALPR vendors like Flock either heavily augment and/or anchor the tech setups.&lt;p&gt;What was notable to me is the following, and it’s why I think a career spent on either security researching, or going to law school and suing, these vendors into the ground over 20 years would be the ultimate act of civil service:&lt;p&gt;1. It’s not just Flock cams. It’s the data eng into these networks - 18 wheeler feed cams, flock cams, retail user nest cams, traffic cams, ISP data sales&lt;p&gt;2. All in one hub, all searchable by your local PD and also the local PD across state lines who doesn’t like your abortion/marijuana/gun/whatever laws, and relying on:&lt;p&gt;3. The PD to setup and maintain proper RBAC in a nationwide surveillance network that is 100%, for sure, no doubt about it (wait how did that Texas cop track the abortion into Indiana/Illinois…?), configured for least privilege.&lt;p&gt;4. Or if the PD doesn’t want flock in town, they reinstall cameras against the ruling (Illinois iirc?) or just say “we have the feeds for the DoT cameras in/out of town and the truckers through town so might as well have control over it, PD!”&lt;p&gt;Layer the above with the current trend in the US, and 2025 model Nissan uploading stop-by-stop geolocation and telematics to cloud (then, sold into flock? Does even knowing for sure if it does or doesn’t even matter?)&lt;p&gt;Very bad line of companies. Again all is from primary sources who helped implement it over the years. If you spend enough time at cybersecurity conferences you’ll meet people with these jobs.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 23:42:16 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46360624</link><dc:creator>dogman144</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46360624</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46360624</guid></item></channel></rss>