<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>Hacker News: Best Comments</title><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/bestcomments</link><description>Hacker News RSS</description><docs>https://hnrss.org/</docs><generator>hnrss v2.1.1</generator><lastBuildDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 23:45:45 +0000</lastBuildDate><ns0:link href="https://hnrss.org/bestcomments" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item><title>New comment by simonw in "CBP is monitoring US drivers and detaining those with suspicious travel patterns"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;License plate scanners are one of the most under-appreciated violations of personal privacy that exist today.&lt;p&gt;It's not just government use either. There are private companies that scan vast numbers of license plates (sometimes by driving around parking lots with a camera), build a database of what plate was seen where at what time, then sell access to both law enforcement and I believe private investigators.&lt;p&gt;Want to know if your spouse is having an affair? Those databases may well have the answer.&lt;p&gt;Here is a Wired story from 2014 about Vigilant Solutions, founded in 2009: &lt;a href="https://www.wired.com/2014/05/license-plate-tracking/" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://www.wired.com/2014/05/license-plate-tracking/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;I believe Vigilant only provide access to law enforcement, but Digital Recognition Network sell access to others as well: &lt;a href="https://drndata.com/about/" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://drndata.com/about/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;Good Vice story about that: &lt;a href="https://www.vice.com/en/article/i-tracked-someone-with-license-plate-readers-drn/" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://www.vice.com/en/article/i-tracked-someone-with-licen...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 20:28:56 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45997278</link><dc:creator>simonw</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45997278</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45997278</guid></item><item><title>New comment by hypeatei in "CBP is monitoring US drivers and detaining those with suspicious travel patterns"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;It's been fascinating watching the party of "small government" turn into one that supports ever expanding powers of a three letter agency whose job is &lt;i&gt;supposed to be&lt;/i&gt; patrolling the border. It's like a new 9/11 Patriot act moment, except it's only one side supporting it this time.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 20:19:15 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45997140</link><dc:creator>hypeatei</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45997140</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45997140</guid></item><item><title>New comment by ceroxylon in "Nano Banana Pro"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Google has been stomping around like Godzilla this week, and this is the first time I decided to link my card to their AI studio.&lt;p&gt;I had seen people saying that they gave up and went to another platform because it was "impossible to pay". I thought this was strange, but after trying to get a working API key for the past half hour, I see what they mean.&lt;p&gt;Everything is set up, I see a message that says "You're using Paid API key [NanoBanano] as part of [NanoBanano]. All requests sent in this session will be charged." Go to prompt, and I get a "permission denied" error.&lt;p&gt;There is no point in having impressive models if you make it a chore for me to -give you my money-&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 18:15:32 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45995765</link><dc:creator>ceroxylon</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45995765</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45995765</guid></item><item><title>New comment by 24t in "Android/Linux Dual Boot"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&gt; sideloading&lt;p&gt;It's called installing. Language matters and I see no reason to concede this point in Google's favour.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 09:59:32 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45990978</link><dc:creator>24t</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45990978</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45990978</guid></item><item><title>New comment by unbolted3032 in "Verifying your Matrix devices is becoming mandatory"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I decommissioned my server 3 months ago and migrated my community back to IRC. I still had the IRC Podman containers kicking around, so that was easy.&lt;p&gt;I dealt with ~monthly issues around my devices not being correctly verified, messages not correctly decrypting, and various other rough UX edges. There seemed to be a lot of velocity in the beginning but the last couple of years have addressed approximately nothing in terms of the UX and it's a crying shame as Matrix/Element (I no longer fully understand the difference/relationship between these entities) had a lot of potential.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 02:13:20 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45988038</link><dc:creator>unbolted3032</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45988038</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45988038</guid></item><item><title>New comment by vinkelhake in "Gaming on Linux has never been more approachable"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I recently had my Framework Desktop delivered. I didn't plan on using it for gaming, but I figured I should at least try. My experience thus far:&lt;p&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;    * I installed Fedora 43 and it (totally unsurprisingly) worked great.
    * I installed Steam from Fedora's software app, and that worked great as well.
    * I installed Cyberpunk 2077 from Steam, and it just... worked.
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
Big thanks to Valve for making this as smooth as it was. I was able to go from no operating system to Cyberpunk running with zero terminals open or configs tweaked.&lt;p&gt;I later got a hankering to play Deus Ex: Mankind Divided. This time, the game would not work and Steam wasn't really forthcoming with showing logs. I figured out how to see the logs, and then did what you do these days - I showed the logs to an AI. The problem, slightly ironically, with MD is that it has a Linux build and Steam was trying to run that thing by default. The Linux build (totally unsurprisingly) had all kinds of version issues with libraries. The resolution there was just to tell Steam to run the Windows build instead and that worked great.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 23:47:02 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45986917</link><dc:creator>vinkelhake</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45986917</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45986917</guid></item><item><title>New comment by ronsor in "Gaming on Linux has never been more approachable"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Community forums/support from big companies like Microsoft and Adobe tend to be completely useless. In most cases, all threads follow the same flow:&lt;p&gt;* Question with reasonable amount of detail.&lt;p&gt;* A reply from some "Community Helper" (Rank: Gold): "did you try reading the help files?"&lt;p&gt;* Another person with a "Staff" badge: "this isn't our department"&lt;p&gt;[Thread closed.]&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 22:05:04 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45985945</link><dc:creator>ronsor</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45985945</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45985945</guid></item><item><title>New comment by crote in "Loose wire leads to blackout, contact with Francis Scott Key bridge"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I &lt;i&gt;strongly&lt;/i&gt; recommend watching/reading the entire report, or the summary by Sal Mercogliano of What's Going On In Shipping [0].&lt;p&gt;Yes, the loose wire was the &lt;i&gt;immediate&lt;/i&gt; cause, but there was far more going wrong here. For example:&lt;p&gt;- The transformer switchover was set to manual rather than automatic, so it didn't automatically fail over to the backup transformer.&lt;p&gt;- The crew did not routinely train transformer switchover procedures.&lt;p&gt;- The two generators were both using a single non-redundant fuel pump (which was never intended to supply fuel to the generators!), which did not automatically restart after power was restored.&lt;p&gt;- The main engine automatically shut down when the primary coolant pump lost power, rather than using an emergency water supply or letting it overheat.&lt;p&gt;- The backup generator did not come online in time.&lt;p&gt;It's a classic Swiss Cheese model. A &lt;i&gt;lot&lt;/i&gt; of things had to go wrong for this accident to happen. Focusing on that one wire isn't going to solve all the other issues. Wires, just like all other parts, &lt;i&gt;will&lt;/i&gt; occasionally fail. One wire failure should never have caused an incident of this magnitude. Sure, there should probably be slightly better procedures for checking the wiring, but next time it'll be a failed sensor, actuator, or controller board.&lt;p&gt;If we don't focus on providing and ensuring a defense-in-depth, we &lt;i&gt;will&lt;/i&gt; sooner or later see another incident like this.&lt;p&gt;[0]: &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=znWl_TuUPp0" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=znWl_TuUPp0&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 21:57:54 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45985858</link><dc:creator>crote</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45985858</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45985858</guid></item><item><title>New comment by hifix in "Microsoft AI CEO pushes back against critics after recent Windows AI backlash"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&gt; The fact that people are unimpressed that we can have a fluent conversation with a super smart AI that can generate any image/video is mindblowing to me.&lt;p&gt;It's not that people are unimpressed with AI - they're just tired of constantly being bombarded with it, and it sneaking its way into where it's not wanted. 
"Generate any image you want!" "Analyse this thing with AI!" gets pretty tiring.&lt;p&gt;If I want AI I'll actively seek it out and use it - otherwise, jog on.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 21:04:47 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45985168</link><dc:creator>hifix</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45985168</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45985168</guid></item><item><title>New comment by nverba in "Cognitive and mental health correlates of short-form video use"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;As someone who pays for YouTube, I don't understand why I can't disable shorts fully. They already have my money. What more do they want?&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 20:59:09 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45985084</link><dc:creator>nverba</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45985084</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45985084</guid></item><item><title>New comment by energy123 in "Europe is scaling back GDPR and relaxing AI laws"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I've stopped thinking of regulations as a single dial, where more regulations is bad or less regulations is bad. It entirely depends on what is being regulated and how. Some areas need more regulations, some areas need less. Some areas need altered regulation. Some areas have just the right regulations. Most regulations can be improved, some more than others.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 20:29:46 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45984688</link><dc:creator>energy123</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45984688</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45984688</guid></item><item><title>New comment by rckt in "Europe is scaling back GDPR and relaxing AI laws"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I get that too many regulations is a bad thing. But when we talk privacy and personal data there should be no gray zone. It has to be black and white. When I see a stupid cookie banner I search for "Reject all". There's no some data that companies can collect and process without my consent, they just shouldn't be able to collect anything without me actively opting in. Business never respects anything, but profits. Seeing news about relaxing these laws with the "AI" going after this leaves a bitter taste. And with them also trying to push the Chat Control thing, it gets even worse.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 20:03:56 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45984395</link><dc:creator>rckt</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45984395</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45984395</guid></item><item><title>New comment by nico in "Building more with GPT-5.1-Codex-Max"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&gt; Claude basically disregards your instructions (CLAUDE.md) entirely&lt;p&gt;A friend of mine tells Claude to always address him as “Mr Tinkleberry”, he says he can tell when Claude is not paying attention to the instructions on CLAUDE.md when Claude stops calling him “Mr Tinkleberry” consistently&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 19:09:14 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45983698</link><dc:creator>nico</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45983698</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45983698</guid></item><item><title>New comment by johnfn in "Building more with GPT-5.1-Codex-Max"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I've been using a lot of Claude and Codex recently.&lt;p&gt;One huge difference I notice between Codex and Claude code is that, while Claude basically disregards your instructions (CLAUDE.md) entirely, Codex is extremely, painfully, doggedly persistent in following every last character of them - to the point that i've seen it work for 30 minutes to convolute some solution that was only convoluted because of some sentence I threw in the instructions I had completely forgotten about.&lt;p&gt;I imagine Codex as the "literal genie" - it'll give you exactly what you asked for. EXACTLY. If you ask Claude to fix a test that accidentally says assert(1 + 1 === 3), it'll say "this is clearly a typo" and just rewrite the test. Codex will rewrite the entire V8 engine to break arithmetic.&lt;p&gt;Both these tools have their uses, and I don't think one approach is universally better. Because Claude just hacks its way to a solution, it is really fast, so I like using it for iterate web work, where I need to tweak some styles and I need a fast iterative loop. Codex is much worse at that because it takes like 5 minutes to validate everything is correct. Codex is much better for longer, harder tasks that have to be correct -- I can just write some script to verify that what it did work, and let it spin for 30-40 minutes.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 18:56:34 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45983533</link><dc:creator>johnfn</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45983533</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45983533</guid></item><item><title>New comment by danishSuri1994 in "Europe is scaling back GDPR and relaxing AI laws"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I sympathize with the startup argument: heavy compliance costs can stifle early innovation. But the solution shouldn’t be “weaker rules.” It should be smarter rules, clearer safe harbors for small actors, browser-level consent primitives for users, and stronger enforcement against dark-pattern CMPs. That keeps privacy meaningful without killing small businesses.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 18:43:43 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45983324</link><dc:creator>danishSuri1994</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45983324</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45983324</guid></item><item><title>New comment by amluto in "Building more with GPT-5.1-Codex-Max"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I would love to see all the big players put 1% of the effort they put into model training into making the basic process of paying and signing in suck less.&lt;p&gt;Claude: they barely have a signin system at all. Multiple account support doesn’t exist. The minimum seat count for business is nonsense.  The data retention policies are weak.&lt;p&gt;OpenAI: Make ZDR a thing you can use or buy without talking to sales, already. And for those using containers or a remote system or really anything other than local development with the codex CLI, you really really need to fix this bug.  I bet Codex could do at least the client part for you!&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/openai/codex/issues/2798" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://github.com/openai/codex/issues/2798&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;(Hint: Claude Code gets this right by default, despite the fact that everything else about Claude sign-in is a joke.)&lt;p&gt;Google: get all your B2B AI product managers in one room and tell them that they need to make one single product menu on one single webpage with all the pricing on &lt;i&gt;that page&lt;/i&gt; and that the Google Cloud people are not permitted to make anything that isn’t actually logically Google Cloud depend on Google Cloud Billing.  Your product cannot compete with OpenAI or Anthropic if people need to ask an LLM to figure out what your product is and if your own fancy LLMs can’t give a straight answer.  My company pays for a non-Google product primarily because it’s too complicated to pay for the Google product!  Right now, trying to use Google’s AI is like trying to ride Bay Area public transit before the Clipper Card.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 18:41:27 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45983286</link><dc:creator>amluto</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45983286</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45983286</guid></item><item><title>New comment by orev in "What Killed Perl?"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;The backwards incompatibility of Perl 6 absolutely killed Perl.&lt;p&gt;There are many languages still in use today that have all kinds of warts and ugliness, but they remain in use because they still have momentum and lots of legacy things built in them. So being ugly or old isn’t enough of a factor for people to abandon something in droves.&lt;p&gt;Once you need to rewrite everything, there’s no reason to stay with something you know since you need to fully retool anyway.&lt;p&gt;As a Perl programmer since v5 was released, the confusion around 6 completely destroyed almost everyone’s enthusiasm, and immediately caused all new projects to avoid Perl. It seemed like 5 had reached the end of the line, and 6 was nowhere to be found. Nobody wants to gamble so many hours of their lives, and the future of their business, on such an uncertain environment.&lt;p&gt;If Perl 6 had any visible movement within the first few years, it might have survived, but it was a good decade before they even admitted Perl 6 might take longer than expected, and then more time after that before they admitted it should have been a new language. 6 was interesting for language geeks, and they probably did some cool things, but you can’t run a large popular project like it’s a small research project. That completely destroyed all momentum in the community. Perl 5 development only resumed far too late, after the writing was already on the wall.&lt;p&gt;Both Bill Gates and Linus understand backwards compatibility as a sacrosanct principle. Python only just barely survived the jump from 2 to 3. JavaScript can only survive this because there’s no other option in a browser.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 18:08:42 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45982756</link><dc:creator>orev</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45982756</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45982756</guid></item><item><title>New comment by bnchrch in "Thunderbird adds native Microsoft Exchange email support"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;While its been a long time since Ive used Thunderbird, I just wanted to take the time to publicly say thank you.&lt;p&gt;Many HNers probably wont (or cant) remember the world of desktop mail clients but basically during the height of MSFT dominance there was only one real mail client: Outlook. Which Microsoft was starting to monetize heavily, ignore UX, and keep it windows only (cant blame them for that).&lt;p&gt;Then Thunderbird arrived on the scene, an OSS mail client that beat the pants off of Outlook in features, spam detection, IMAP support and a bunch of other things.&lt;p&gt;And it was free.&lt;p&gt;And you could use it on any machine.&lt;p&gt;This was a huge moment for OSS.&lt;p&gt;We owe a lot of credit to Mozilla and Thunderbird for rescuing us from a closed source world.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 17:26:21 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45982201</link><dc:creator>bnchrch</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45982201</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45982201</guid></item><item><title>New comment by radicalbyte in "Europe is scaling back GDPR and relaxing AI laws"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;There has been a change in the community here over the last decade, we've lost a lot of the hacker spirit and have a larger proportion of "chancers", people who are only in tech to "get rich quick". The legacy of ZIRP combined with The Social Network marketing.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 16:16:21 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45981361</link><dc:creator>radicalbyte</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45981361</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45981361</guid></item><item><title>New comment by purple_turtle in "The peaceful transfer of power in open source projects"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&gt; I'm begging project leaders everywhere - please read up on the social contract and the consent of the governed.&lt;p&gt;I do not need consent as I am not governing anyone like king or president governs.&lt;p&gt;If someone is using my project they are also not really entitled to anything, beyond what stated in license and similar documents if any.&lt;p&gt;If they dislike it, they can fork my project and go away.&lt;p&gt;If someone wants to be entitled to anything, they are free to make a contract and pay for service they desire. But while many are happy to demand nearly noone is willing to help. Or even fork project.
Instead they make entitled demand and treat open source developers as servants or slaves or their pets.&lt;p&gt;No, you are not entitled to your preferred governance model to be used in my software project.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 14:55:19 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45980305</link><dc:creator>purple_turtle</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45980305</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45980305</guid></item><item><title>New comment by Havoc in "A $1k AWS mistake"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;These sort of things show up about once a day between the three big cloud subreddit. Often with larger amounts&lt;p&gt;And it’s always the same - clouds refuse to provide anything more than alerts (that are delayed) and your only option is prayer and begging for mercy.&lt;p&gt;Followed by people claiming with absolute certainty that it’s literally technically impossible to provide hard capped accounts to tinkerers despite there being accounts like that in existence already (some azure accounts are hardcapped by amount but ofc that’s not loudly advertised).&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 11:22:53 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45978260</link><dc:creator>Havoc</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45978260</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45978260</guid></item><item><title>New comment by Groxx in "I just want working RCS messaging"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Yeah... I just started getting back into building sms/mms/rcs apps on Android and oh boy.  It's much more of a mess than I expected, and much more "oh so it's basically just Google now, and they seem to be trying to lock it down further" than I expected (or hoped).&lt;p&gt;And you can't even implement it yourself because it requires special permissions on Android, which you can only get if you're a carrier/oem-blessed app.  And the early "you'll be able to build other apps, there will be an API like this: &lt;a href="https://github.com/android-rcs/rcsjta" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://github.com/android-rcs/rcsjta&lt;/a&gt;" promises (which would put it on par with sms/mms) never materialized, despite a reference implementation that did exactly that over a decade ago.&lt;p&gt;At this point I'm just totally against RCS and I'm intentionally turning it off.  Why hand &lt;i&gt;all&lt;/i&gt; of your messaging communications over to Google, when they've got such a consistent history of being hostile?  We're much better off going back to telling people not to use sms (or mms or rcs) at all because it's insecure.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 07:50:42 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45976915</link><dc:creator>Groxx</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45976915</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45976915</guid></item><item><title>New comment by spyridonas in "Show HN: I made a down detector for down detector"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;As a European solo developer, I’ve switched entirely to European alternatives for all my infrastructure since the beginning of the year.&lt;p&gt;Cloudflare &gt; Bunny.net&lt;p&gt;AWS &gt; Hetzner&lt;p&gt;Business email &gt; Infomaniak&lt;p&gt;Not a single client site has experienced downtime, and it feels great to finally decouple from U.S. services.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 07:39:20 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45976849</link><dc:creator>spyridonas</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45976849</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45976849</guid></item><item><title>New comment by abalone in "Cloudflare outage on November 18, 2025 post mortem"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I’ve led multiple incident responses at a FAANG, here’s my take. The fundamental problem here is not Rust or the coding error. The problem is:&lt;p&gt;1. Their bot management system is designed to push a configuration out to their entire network rapidly. This is necessary so they can rapidly respond to attacks, but it creates risk as compared to systems that roll out changes gradually.&lt;p&gt;2. Despite the elevated risk of system wide rapid config propagation, it took them 2 hours to identify the config as the proximate cause, and another hour to roll it back.&lt;p&gt;SOP for stuff breaking is you roll back to a known good state. If you roll out gradually and your canaries break, you have a clear signal to roll back. Here was a special case where they needed their system to rapidly propagate changes everywhere, which is a huge risk, but didn’t quite have the visibility and rapid rollback capability in place to match that risk.&lt;p&gt;While it’s certainly useful to examine the root cause in the code, you’re never going to have defect free code. Reliability isn’t just about avoiding bugs. It’s about understanding how to give yourself clear visibility into the relationship between changes and behavior and the rollback capability to quickly revert to a known good state.&lt;p&gt;Cloudflare has done an amazing job with availability for many years and their Rust code now powers 20% of internet traffic. Truly a great team.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 05:04:38 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45976044</link><dc:creator>abalone</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45976044</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45976044</guid></item><item><title>New comment by eastdakota in "Cloudflare outage on November 18, 2025 post mortem"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Well… we have a culture of transparency we take seriously. I spent 3 years in law school that many times over my career have seemed like wastes but days like today prove useful. I was in the triage video bridge call nearly the whole time. Spent some time after we got things under control talking to customers. Then went home. I’m currently in Lisbon at our EUHQ. I texted John Graham-Cumming, our former CTO and current Board member whose clarity of writing I’ve always admired. He came over. Brought his son (“to show that work isn’t always fun”). Our Chief Legal Officer (Doug) happened to be in town. He came over too. The team had put together a technical doc with all the details. A tick-tock of what had happened and when. I locked myself on a balcony and started writing the intro and conclusion in my trusty BBEdit text editor. John started working on the technical middle. Doug provided edits here and there on places we weren’t clear. At some point John ordered sushi but from a place with limited delivery selection options, and I’m allergic to shellfish, so I ordered a burrito. The team continued to flesh out what happened. As we’d write we’d discover questions: how could a database permission change impact query results? Why were we making a permission change in the first place? We asked in the Google Doc. Answers came back. A few hours ago we declared it done. I read it top-to-bottom out loud for Doug, John, and John’s son. None of us were happy — we were embarrassed by what had happened — but we declared it true and accurate. I sent a draft to Michelle, who’s in SF. The technical teams gave it a once over. Our social media team staged it to our blog. I texted John to see if he wanted to post it to HN. He didn’t reply after a few minutes so I did. That was the process.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 00:38:43 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45974320</link><dc:creator>eastdakota</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45974320</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45974320</guid></item><item><title>New comment by porphyra in "Blender 5.0"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Blender is really an amazing case study of open source software. Apart from the Linux kernel and web browsers/tools, it is perhaps the only open source software that managed to beat all the commercial software in its niche. It has rendered Maya nearly obsolete.&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile, in other niches, Microsoft Office still beats open source office suites like LibreOffice; Photoshop isn't about to give up its crown to GIMP; Lightroom isn't losing to Darktable; and FreeCAD isn't even in the rear view mirror of Solidworks.&lt;p&gt;I wonder what will be the next category of open source to pull ahead? Godot is rapidly gaining users/mindshare while Unity seems to be collapsing, but Unreal is still the king of game engines for now. Krita is a viable alternative for digital painting.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 00:20:12 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45974156</link><dc:creator>porphyra</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45974156</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45974156</guid></item><item><title>New comment by ojosilva in "Cloudflare outage on November 18, 2025 post mortem"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;This is the multi-million dollar .unwrap() story. In a critical path of infrastructure serving a significant chunk of the internet, calling .unwrap() on a Result means you're saying "this can never fail, and if it does, crash the thread immediately."The Rust compiler forced them to acknowledge this could fail (that's what Result is for), but they explicitly chose to panic instead of handle it gracefully. This is textbook "parse, don't validate" anti-pattern.&lt;p&gt;I know, this is "Monday morning quarterbacking", but that's what you get for an outage this big that had me tied up for half a day.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 00:10:04 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45974052</link><dc:creator>ojosilva</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45974052</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45974052</guid></item><item><title>New comment by eastdakota in "Cloudflare outage on November 18, 2025 post mortem"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Because we initially thought it was an attack. And then when we figured it out we didn’t have a way to insert a good file into the queue. And then we needed to reboot processes on (a lot) of machines worldwide to get them to flush their bad files.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 00:07:27 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45974030</link><dc:creator>eastdakota</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45974030</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45974030</guid></item><item><title>New comment by gucci-on-fleek in "Cloudflare outage on November 18, 2025 post mortem"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&gt; This showed up to Internet users trying to access our customers' sites as an error page indicating a failure within Cloudflare's network.&lt;p&gt;As a visitor to random web pages, I definitely appreciated this—much better than their completely false “checking the security of your connection” message.&lt;p&gt;&gt; The issue was not caused, directly or indirectly, by a cyber attack or malicious activity of any kind. Instead, it was triggered by a change to one of our database systems' permissions&lt;p&gt;Also appreciate the honesty here.&lt;p&gt;&gt; On 18 November 2025 at 11:20 UTC (all times in this blog are UTC), Cloudflare's network began experiencing significant failures to deliver core network traffic. […]&lt;p&gt;&gt; Core traffic was largely flowing as normal by 14:30. We worked over the next few hours to mitigate increased load on various parts of our network as traffic rushed back online. As of 17:06 all systems at Cloudflare were functioning as normal.&lt;p&gt;Why did this take so long to resolve? I read through the entire article, and I understand &lt;i&gt;why&lt;/i&gt; the outage happened, but when most of the network goes down, why wasn't the first step to revert any recent configuration changes, even ones that seem unrelated to the outage? (Or did I just misread something and this was explained somewhere?)&lt;p&gt;Of course, the correct solution is always obvious in retrospect, and it's impressive that it only took 7 minutes between the start of the outage and the incident being investigated, but it taking a further 4 hours to resolve the problem and 8 hours total for everything to be back to normal isn't great.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 23:53:52 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45973896</link><dc:creator>gucci-on-fleek</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45973896</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45973896</guid></item><item><title>New comment by SerCe in "Cloudflare outage on November 18, 2025 post mortem"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;As always, kudos for releasing a post mortem in less than 24 hours after the outage, very few tech organisations are capable of doing this.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 23:51:06 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45973869</link><dc:creator>SerCe</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45973869</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45973869</guid></item></channel></rss>