<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>Hacker News: Best Comments</title><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/bestcomments</link><description>Hacker News RSS</description><docs>https://hnrss.org/</docs><generator>hnrss v2.1.1</generator><lastBuildDate>Thu, 24 Jul 2025 05:22:52 +0000</lastBuildDate><ns0:link href="https://hnrss.org/bestcomments" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item><title>New comment by wrs in "I watched Gemini CLI hallucinate and delete my files"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Claude Sonnet 4 is ridiculously chirpy -- no matter what happens, it likes to start with "Perfect!" or "You're absolutely right!" and everything! seems to end! with an exclamation point!&lt;p&gt;Gemini Pro 2.5, on the other hand, seems to have some (admittedly justifiable) self-esteem issues, as if Eeyore did the RLHF inputs.&lt;p&gt;"I have been debugging this with increasingly complex solutions, when the original problem was likely much simpler. I have wasted your time."&lt;p&gt;"I am going to stop trying to fix this myself. I have failed to do so multiple times. It is clear that my contributions have only made things worse."&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 23 Jul 2025 00:59:40 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44654681</link><dc:creator>wrs</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44654681</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44654681</guid></item><item><title>New comment by isatty in "We built an air-gapped Jira alternative for regulated industries"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&gt; The interesting part: our air-gapped deployment actually runs faster than our SaaS version.&lt;p&gt;This is the least surprising thing I’ve read all day.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 23 Jul 2025 00:15:47 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44654441</link><dc:creator>isatty</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44654441</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44654441</guid></item><item><title>New comment by nsypteras in "The United States withdraws from UNESCO"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;1984: U.S. withdraws.
2003: U.S. rejoins.
2011: U.S. stops paying dues after Palestine joins.
2017: U.S. announces withdrawal (effective end of 2018).
2023: U.S. rejoins, pledges to repay dues.
2025: U.S announces withdrawal&lt;p&gt;Seems to be a revolving door&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 22 Jul 2025 15:29:48 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44648359</link><dc:creator>nsypteras</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44648359</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44648359</guid></item><item><title>New comment by mattlutze in "How to Firefox"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I am surprised how many people have so many problems with Firefox.&lt;p&gt;I've never felt impeded by loading speeds, and my ADHD regularly has me forgetting to restart it, to the tune of 100+ tabs open across multiple desktops. My wimply little MacBook Pro doesn't seem to mind.&lt;p&gt;The only downside I've found is that, because so many people just default to "Chrome or nothing," there's occasionally sites that have bugs because, like was the case in the 90s with Internet Explorer, the site developers took the idiomatic Chrome way of building a feature instead of something universal.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 22 Jul 2025 13:00:03 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44646335</link><dc:creator>mattlutze</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44646335</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44646335</guid></item><item><title>New comment by cyp0633 in "Complete silence is always hallucinated as "ترجمة نانسي قنقر" in Arabic"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;The same happens with whisper-large-v3 on Chinese transcription: silence is transcribed to something like "please upvote, share and favourite this video". I suspect they trained the model on some random YouTube video without carefully picking really useful data.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 22 Jul 2025 06:52:14 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44643922</link><dc:creator>cyp0633</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44643922</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44643922</guid></item><item><title>New comment by nomel in "What went wrong inside recalled Anker PowerCore 10000 power banks?"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I work in manufacturing in the US. Incoming quality control, for Chinese vendors, is &lt;i&gt;necessarily&lt;/i&gt; set up with zero-trust. This isn't a "trust but verify" sort of thing, it's strictly "do not trust". Assume that, at every step of the chain, there will be a lie: change of process, material change, collected data, and that the product being given to you is even yours (delivering a knockoff at the final step, and reselling yours on the gray market).&lt;p&gt;This is all common knowledge, proven by example after example that it's &lt;i&gt;necessary&lt;/i&gt; to have zero trust. It's truly an adversarial system. All the extra engineering effort for IQC is still cheaper. And, there's rarely an alternative to the amazing manufacturing ecosystem that is China.&lt;p&gt;After tracking down several of these types of issues, it appears that the Chabuduo mindset [1] is a very real thing.&lt;p&gt;[1] &lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=32465780"&gt;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=32465780&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 21 Jul 2025 20:57:02 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44640329</link><dc:creator>nomel</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44640329</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44640329</guid></item><item><title>New comment by yegle in "What went wrong inside recalled Anker PowerCore 10000 power banks?"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;FWIW this has caused a big storm in China. The root of the issue is known to be caused by the battery cell vendor Amprius changing the battery design w/o notifying the power bank manufacturers. AFAIKT Amprius lost the 3C certification (a certification in China) because of this incident.&lt;p&gt;This is one of the Chinese reports on the issue: 
&lt;a href="https://m.thepaper.cn/newsDetail_forward_31048287" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://m.thepaper.cn/newsDetail_forward_31048287&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;Excerpt from the report above (translated using Google):&lt;p&gt;&gt; The Paper learned from an insider that Anker Innovations' battery cell supplier is already a leading battery cell supplier in the industry, and did not inform customers after it changed materials. In addition to Anker Innovations, the supplier also cooperates with leading power bank brands, so the impact is huge. Although Anker Innovations did not name the supplier, an insider pointed out that the supplier was Amprius.&lt;p&gt;UPDATE:&lt;p&gt;There's an exclusive interview by 36kr with one of Anker's VPs:&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://m.36kr.com/p/3365435892680709" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://m.36kr.com/p/3365435892680709&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 21 Jul 2025 19:58:01 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44639759</link><dc:creator>yegle</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44639759</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44639759</guid></item><item><title>New comment by npsomaratna in "“Dynamic programming” is not referring to “computer programming”"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Sri Lankan here. I used to compete in the IOI (International Olympiad in Informatics), back in the '90s.&lt;p&gt;I aced the competition in Sri Lanka, but I failed to win a medal the first time I competed internationally. I solved several problems with recursion, but these failed to complete within the strict time limits allowed.&lt;p&gt;One of the contestants from another country told me: "You needed dynamic programming to solve problems 1 and 5." I then spent the next year trying to figure out what dynamic programming was. The folks over here weren't familiar with the term. In fact, I was often asked "did you mean dynamic memory allocation?"&lt;p&gt;After a while, I managed to find a book that talked about dynamic programming, and I was like "Oh, it's recursion + storing results" and "Ah, you can also do this iteratively in certain circumstances"&lt;p&gt;Bottom line, armed with this new knowledge, I ended up winning a gold medal at IOI 2001. Fun times.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 21 Jul 2025 05:34:38 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44632078</link><dc:creator>npsomaratna</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44632078</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44632078</guid></item><item><title>New comment by dehrmann in "AI is killing the web – can anything save it?"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&gt; With fewer visitors, Stack Overflow is seeing fewer questions posted on its message boards&lt;p&gt;When you operate a community that's hostile to questions that have already been answered, are poorly researched, or are homework, don't be surprised when people start taking those questions elsewhere, and don't be surprised when they start asking their &lt;i&gt;good&lt;/i&gt; questions elsewhere, too.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 20 Jul 2025 20:53:14 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44629225</link><dc:creator>dehrmann</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44629225</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44629225</guid></item><item><title>New comment by georgecmu in "New colors without shooting lasers into your eyes"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;For whatever reason, evolution decided those wavelengths should be overlapping. For example, M cones are most sensitive to 535 nm light, while L cones are most sensitive to 560 nm light. But M cones are still stimulated quite a lot by 560 nm light—around 80% of maximum.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;p&gt;The reason is simple: genes coding the long wave opsins (light-sensitive proteins) in these cones have diverged from copies of the same original gene. The evolution of this is very interesting.&lt;p&gt;Mammals in general have only two types of cones: presumably they lost full color vision in the age of dinosaurs since they were primarily small nocturnal animals or lived in habitats with very limited light (subterranean, piles of leaves, etc.) Primates are the notable exception, and have evolved the third type of cone, enabling trichromatic color vision, as a result of their fruitarian specialization and co-evolution with the tropical fruit trees (same as birds, actually).&lt;p&gt;So, what's interesting is that New World and Old World primates evolved this cone independently. In Old World primates the third cone resulted from a gene duplication event on the X chromosome, giving rise to two distinct (but pretty similar) opsin genes, with sensitivity peaks at very close wavelengths. As a note, because these genes sit on the X chromosome, colorblindness (defects in one or both of these genes) is much more likely to happen in males.&lt;p&gt;New World primates have a single polymorphic opsin gene on the X chromosome, with different alleles coding for different sensitivities. So, only some (heterozygous) females in these species typically have full trichromatic vision, while males and the unlucky homozygous females remain dichromatic.&lt;p&gt;Decent wikipedia article on the subject: &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Evolution_of_color_vision_in_primates" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Evolution_of_color_vision_in_p...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;Types of opsins in vertebrates:
&lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Vertebrate_visual_opsin" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Vertebrate_visual_opsin&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 20 Jul 2025 20:30:04 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44629021</link><dc:creator>georgecmu</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44629021</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44629021</guid></item><item><title>New comment by layer8 in "The bewildering phenomenon of declining quality"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Many comments here are arguing that quality has actually gone up over the past decades. However, a common experience for me is that I own something of good quality from 5/10/15 years ago and now buy the successor model from the same brand, but the product has gotten worse, being cheaper made. And I have a hard time finding a replacement that matches the quality of the old version. It’s a regularly reoccurring frustration.&lt;p&gt;My suspicion is that when products are successful and mature but reach market saturation, profit growth pressure leads to cutting some corners on every iteration, and hence to a slow decline in quality over the years.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 20 Jul 2025 11:42:47 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44624220</link><dc:creator>layer8</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44624220</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44624220</guid></item><item><title>New comment by progval in "Local LLMs versus offline Wikipedia"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;An unreliable computer treated as a god by a pre-information-age society sounds like a Star Trek episode.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 19 Jul 2025 20:54:06 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44619294</link><dc:creator>progval</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44619294</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44619294</guid></item><item><title>New comment by miiiiiike in "Valve confirms credit card companies pressured it to delist certain adult games"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Look. Ignore the content. Why the fuck do we allow credit card companies have a say in how we spend our money?&lt;p&gt;Fraud? Abuse? Fine, let me put cash onto a card and if that card gets stolen, oh well, my loss. Mastercard should have no say in what what speech is considered acceptable outside of their offices. We don't care what execs at a water company think? Why do we care about the people at Mastercard?&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 19 Jul 2025 01:02:30 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44611570</link><dc:creator>miiiiiike</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44611570</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44611570</guid></item><item><title>New comment by ijk in "Valve confirms credit card companies pressured it to delist certain adult games"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;One factor is the ongoing campaigns from number of moral crusading groups who lobby them to cut off payment processing for things they don't approve of. NCOSE has been working for decades on the project, and targeting credit card companies has been a successful tactic for them for a decade or so.&lt;p&gt;[1] &lt;a href="https://www.eff.org/deeplinks/2020/12/visa-and-mastercard-are-trying-dictate-what-you-can-watch-pornhub" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://www.eff.org/deeplinks/2020/12/visa-and-mastercard-ar...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;[2] &lt;a href="https://www.newsweek.com/why-visa-mastercard-being-blamed-onlyfans-banning-explicit-content-pornography-1621570" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://www.newsweek.com/why-visa-mastercard-being-blamed-on...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;[3] &lt;a href="https://scholarworks.iu.edu/dspace/bitstreams/761eb6c3-9377-4ced-9287-5733293063bf/download" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://scholarworks.iu.edu/dspace/bitstreams/761eb6c3-9377-...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 19 Jul 2025 00:50:45 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44611517</link><dc:creator>ijk</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44611517</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44611517</guid></item><item><title>New comment by spiralcoaster in "My favorite use-case for AI is writing logs"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&gt; The amount of cognitive overhead in this deceptively simple log is several levels deep: you have to first stop to type logger.info (or is it logging.info? I use both loguru and logger depending on the codebase and end up always getting the two confused.) Then, the parentheses, the f-string itself, and then the variables in brackets. Now, was it your_variable or your_variable_with_edits from five lines up? And what’s the syntax for accessing a subset of df.head again?&lt;p&gt;What you're describing is called: programming. This can't be serious. What about the cognitive overhead of writing a for loop? You have to remember what's in the array you're iterating over, how that array interacts with maybe other parts of the code base, and oh man, what about those pesky indices! Does it start at 0 or 1? I can't take it! AI save me!&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 18 Jul 2025 00:36:19 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44599922</link><dc:creator>spiralcoaster</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44599922</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44599922</guid></item><item><title>New comment by thr0waway001 in "Anthropic tightens usage limits for Claude Code without telling users"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&gt; One user, who asked not to be identified, said it has been impossible to advance his project since the usage limits came into effect.&lt;p&gt;Vibe limit reached. Gotta start doing some thinking.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 17 Jul 2025 22:06:08 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44598772</link><dc:creator>thr0waway001</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44598772</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44598772</guid></item><item><title>New comment by twalkz in "ChatGPT agent: bridging research and action"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;The "spreadsheet" example video is kind of funny: guy talks about how it normally takes him 4 to 8 hours to put together complicated, data-heavy reports. Now he fires off an agent request, goes to walk his dog, and comes back to a downloadable spreadsheet of dense data, which he pulls up and says "I think it got 98% of the information correct... I just needed to copy / paste a few things. If it can do 90 - 95% of the time consuming work, that will save you a ton of time"&lt;p&gt;It feels like either finding that 2% that's off (or dealing with 2% error) will be the time consuming part in a lot of cases. I mean, this is nothing new with LLMs, but as these use cases encourage users to input more complex tasks, that are more integrated with our personal data (and at times money, as hinted at by all the "do task X and buy me Y" examples), "almost right" seems like it has the potential to cause a lot of headaches. Especially when the 2% error is subtle and buried in step 3 of 46 of some complex agentic flow.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 17 Jul 2025 17:27:06 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44595791</link><dc:creator>twalkz</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44595791</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44595791</guid></item><item><title>New comment by hollywood_court in "Ex-Waymo engineers launch Bedrock Robotics to automate construction"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I work for a home builder. Our single biggest problem is finding and hiring quality contractors that have enough skilled tradesmen.&lt;p&gt;There are dozens of electrical contractors in my area. But only two that perform work to our standards.&lt;p&gt;There is only one HVAC company that can meet our standards. Same for all of the other skilled trades.&lt;p&gt;Our framing crew is the best within a 75 mile radius. Other builders are constantly trying to poach them from us. We keep throwing money at them to prevent them from going to another builder.&lt;p&gt;Non skilled labor like landscaping and pest control are a dime a dozen. I just fired our main pesticide and herbicide contractor today because they couldn’t get it together.&lt;p&gt;Of course I had them replaced before I fired them but I had almost 20 options to choose from.&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately I can’t say the same about all of the skilled contractors.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 17 Jul 2025 00:55:52 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44588579</link><dc:creator>hollywood_court</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44588579</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44588579</guid></item><item><title>New comment by palata in "Linux Reaches 5% Desktop Market Share in USA"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I agree with your points, except this:&lt;p&gt;&gt; thanks to the Steam Deck [...] but I would be reluctant to call that Linux Desktop anymore than I would call Android an uptick for Linux.&lt;p&gt;The Steam Deck very much runs Linux Desktop. Android runs the Linux kernel, but &lt;i&gt;everything else&lt;/i&gt; is different. SteamOS is a Linux distribution based on Arch. If you run your Steam Deck in "desktop mode", it is very much a Linux Desktop (with a read-only system and A/B updates etc, but still).&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 16 Jul 2025 12:13:20 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44581343</link><dc:creator>palata</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44581343</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44581343</guid></item><item><title>New comment by nerdjon in "Linux Reaches 5% Desktop Market Share in USA"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I have to wonder how much of this is people switching to Linux vs the larger trend of people not having traditional computers to begin with.&lt;p&gt;Outside of gamers, I don't know anyone that has a computer at home that is not their work laptop if they have one. At least in my circle everyone I know has moved to their general computing being on phones and tablets which is not captured here. So is a solid chunk of this the people that would have already had Linux desktops continuing to have theirs since they would likely be the same people (more technical, needing to do tasks not possible on phones and tablets) less likely to be making that switch.&lt;p&gt;Basically if the higher percent is due to less desktops overall instead of a major uptick in Linux desktops, it is not really much to celebrate.&lt;p&gt;Given these numbers are percents I would be very curious.&lt;p&gt;Now yes there is a clear uptick thanks to the Steam Deck (however with Microsoft pushing their optimized for gaming Windows it will be interesting to see if that continues or goes backwards). But I would be reluctant to call that Linux Desktop anymore than I would call Android an uptick for Linux.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 16 Jul 2025 11:53:47 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44581195</link><dc:creator>nerdjon</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44581195</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44581195</guid></item><item><title>New comment by theandrewbailey in "Linux Reaches 5% Desktop Market Share in USA"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I work in the refurb division of an e-waste recycling company. Due to licensing costs and our certifications, we can't sell anything with Windows. My coworkers install Ubuntu, but I install Linux Mint. We don't have any clue if people keep using Linux or install Windows, but it's cool to think we're helping to move this needle.&lt;p&gt;Edit: might as well link to the merch: &lt;a href="https://www.ebay.com/str/evolutionecycling" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://www.ebay.com/str/evolutionecycling&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 16 Jul 2025 10:57:48 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44580803</link><dc:creator>theandrewbailey</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44580803</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44580803</guid></item><item><title>New comment by ReadCarlBarks in "Where's Firefox going next?"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Thank you for loving Firefox - &lt;a href="https://connect.mozilla.org/t5/discussions/m/m-p/16863/highlight/true#M7430" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://connect.mozilla.org/t5/discussions/m/m-p/16863/highl...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 16 Jul 2025 07:30:46 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44579635</link><dc:creator>ReadCarlBarks</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44579635</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44579635</guid></item><item><title>New comment by idle_zealot in "Where's Firefox going next?"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I know there are plenty of more serious issues people have with Mozilla's direction and focus, but patronizing stuff like this really grinds my gears.&lt;p&gt;&gt; Which animal best represents your Firefox browsing style? [List of emoji animals]&lt;p&gt;The marketing/PR trend of speaking to communities as though they're kindergartners is distracting and off-putting. This is the most egregious part but the whole post has a similar tone.&lt;p&gt;I'll note that I'm not saying outreach should necessarily be professional or devoid of fun/humor. There's just a sterile, saccharine way about Mozilla's community engagement that evokes artificiality.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 16 Jul 2025 06:43:48 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44579387</link><dc:creator>idle_zealot</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44579387</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44579387</guid></item><item><title>New comment by JumpCrisscross in "Where's Firefox going next?"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Are Mozilla’s donations still roughly equal to their CEO’s compensation [1][2]?&lt;p&gt;[1] &lt;a href="https://www.mozilla.org/en-US/foundation/annualreport/2024/article/financing-an-open-internet-mozillas-path-forward/" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://www.mozilla.org/en-US/foundation/annualreport/2024/a...&lt;/a&gt; &lt;i&gt;”$7.8M in donations from the public, grants from foundations, and government funding” in 2023&lt;/i&gt;&lt;p&gt;[2] &lt;a href="https://assets.mozilla.net/annualreport/2022/mozilla-fdn-990-ty22-public-disclosure.pdf" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://assets.mozilla.net/annualreport/2022/mozilla-fdn-990...&lt;/a&gt; &lt;i&gt;$6.9mm in 2022, page 7&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 16 Jul 2025 00:08:36 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44577295</link><dc:creator>JumpCrisscross</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44577295</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44577295</guid></item><item><title>New comment by asimpleusecase in "Show HN: I built this to talk Danish to my girlfriend – works with any language"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I’m sure she is a lovely person, but I don’t really have a need to text your girlfriend.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 15 Jul 2025 14:06:33 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44571318</link><dc:creator>asimpleusecase</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44571318</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44571318</guid></item><item><title>New comment by mg in "LLM Inevitabilism"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;In the 90s a friend told me about the internet. And that he knows someone who is in a university and has access to it and can show us. An hour later, we were sitting in front of a computer in that university and watched his friend surfing the web. Clicking on links, receiving pages of text. Faster than one could read. In a nice layout. Even with images. And links to other pages. We were shocked. No printing, no shipping, no waiting. This was the future. It was inevitable.&lt;p&gt;Yesterday I wanted to rewrite a program to use a large library that would have required me to dive deep down into the documentation or read its code to tackle my use case. As a first try, I just copy+pasted the whole library and my whole program into GPT 4.1 and told it to rewrite it using the library. It succeeded at the first attempt. The rewrite itself was small enough that I could read all code changes in 15 minutes and make a few stylistic changes. Done. Hours of time saved. This is the future. It is inevitable.&lt;p&gt;PS: Most replies seem to compare my experience to experiences that the responders have with agentic coding, where the developer is iteratively changing the code by chatting with an LLM. I am not doing that. I use a "One prompt one file. No code edits." approach, which I describe here:&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.gibney.org/prompt_coding" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://www.gibney.org/prompt_coding&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 15 Jul 2025 05:41:36 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44568158</link><dc:creator>mg</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44568158</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44568158</guid></item><item><title>New comment by lsy in "LLM Inevitabilism"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I think two things can be true simultaneously:&lt;p&gt;1. LLMs are a new technology and it's hard to put the genie back in the bottle with that. It's difficult to imagine a future where they don't continue to exist in some form, with all the timesaving benefits and social issues that come with them.&lt;p&gt;2. Almost three years in, companies investing in LLMs have not yet discovered a business model that justifies the massive expenditure of training and hosting them, the majority of consumer usage is at the free tier, the industry is seeing the first signs of pulling back investments, and model capabilities are plateauing at a level where most people agree that the output is trite and unpleasant to consume.&lt;p&gt;There are many technologies that have seemed inevitable and seen retreats under the lack of commensurate business return (the supersonic jetliner), and several that seemed poised to displace both old tech and labor but have settled into specific use cases (the microwave oven). Given the lack of a sufficiently profitable business model, it feels as likely as not that LLMs settle somewhere a little less remarkable, and hopefully less annoying, than today's almost universally disliked attempts to cram it everywhere.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 15 Jul 2025 05:33:27 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44568114</link><dc:creator>lsy</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44568114</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44568114</guid></item><item><title>New comment by somenameforme in "The new literalism plaguing today’s movies"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Fun fact: movie sales, in terms of tickets sold, peaked in 2002. [1] All the 'box office records' since then are the result of charging way more to a continually plummeting audience size.&lt;p&gt;And this is highly relevant for things like this. People often argue that if movies were so bad then people would stop watching them, unaware that people actually have stopped watching them!&lt;p&gt;Even for individual movies. For all the men-in-spandex movies, the best selling movie (by tickets sold) in modern times is Titanic, 27 years ago.&lt;p&gt;[1] - &lt;a href="https://www.the-numbers.com/market/" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://www.the-numbers.com/market/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 15 Jul 2025 04:23:05 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44567805</link><dc:creator>somenameforme</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44567805</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44567805</guid></item><item><title>New comment by pm90 in "Cognition (Devin AI) to Acquire Windsurf"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I think the amount of turmoil around these deals is giving more weight to the possibility that we’re in a massive bubble thats quite divorced from any kind of fundamentals. Sooner or later the bubbles gonna burst.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 14 Jul 2025 19:38:52 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44564397</link><dc:creator>pm90</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44564397</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44564397</guid></item><item><title>New comment by potato3732842 in "Oakland cops gave ICE license plate data; SFPD also illegally shared with feds"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;The law enforcement agencies which behaved the way law enforcement agencies always behave and did what anyone with even the slightest familiarity with how law enforcement acts thought they would do with the data.  This outcome was 1000% predictable even if the details were not.&lt;p&gt;If you're gonna be angry at someone be angry at the people among us were in favor of the creation of this data set because they foolishly thought it would be used to combat mundane property crime or because perhaps they thought that subjecting motorists to an increased dragnet would be a good thing for alternative transportation, or some other cause, think that they have done no wrong despite warnings of the potential for something like this being raised way back when the cameras and the ALPRs were being put up.&lt;p&gt;These things will keep happening until it is no longer socially acceptable to advocate for the creation of data collection programs that are a necessary precondition.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 14 Jul 2025 16:35:54 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44562124</link><dc:creator>potato3732842</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44562124</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44562124</guid></item></channel></rss>