<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>Hacker News: Best Comments</title><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/bestcomments</link><description>Hacker News RSS</description><docs>https://hnrss.org/</docs><generator>hnrss v2.1.1</generator><lastBuildDate>Fri, 22 Aug 2025 00:22:48 +0000</lastBuildDate><ns0:link href="https://hnrss.org/bestcomments" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item><title>New comment by dcastonguay in "I forced every engineer to take sales calls and they rewrote our platform"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&gt; At the end of it, they were sketching a completely different architecture without my "PMing". Because they finally understood who was actually using our product.&lt;p&gt;I cannot help but read this whole experience as: “We forced an engineer to take sales calls and we found out that the issue was that our PMs are doing a terrible job communicating between customer and engineering, and our DevOps engineer is more capable/actionable at turning customer needs into working solutions.”&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 21 Aug 2025 16:17:52 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44974574</link><dc:creator>dcastonguay</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44974574</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44974574</guid></item><item><title>New comment by jqpabc123 in "AWS CEO says using AI to replace junior staff is 'Dumbest thing I've ever heard'"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;He wants educators to instead teach “how do you think and how do you decompose problems”&lt;/i&gt;&lt;p&gt;Ahmen! I attend this same church.&lt;p&gt;My favorite professor in engineering school always gave open book tests.&lt;p&gt;In the real world of work, everyone has full access to all the available data and information.&lt;p&gt;Very few jobs involve paying someone simply to look up data in a book or on the internet. What they will pay for is someone who can analyze, understand, reason and apply data and information in unique ways needed to solve problems.&lt;p&gt;Doing this is called "engineering". And this is what this professor taught.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 21 Aug 2025 13:18:36 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44972416</link><dc:creator>jqpabc123</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44972416</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44972416</guid></item><item><title>New comment by mccoyb in "Sequoia backs Zed"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I love the spirit of Zed. From the principles to the low-level implementation details, it all screams "good taste". It's immensely interesting as an object of study (the code is great, from GPUI all the way up).&lt;p&gt;Having said that, I don't think an editor should be VC backed. It's the obvious pragmatic choice to get a team together to support a thing, but I'm concerned by it.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 20 Aug 2025 16:13:29 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44963229</link><dc:creator>mccoyb</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44963229</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44963229</guid></item><item><title>New comment by tptacek in "Vendors that treat single sign-on as a luxury feature"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;This pops up on HN about once a year, and it's worth calling out that the SSO tax has mostly nothing to do with technology or with support costs and mostly everything to do with market segmentation. One of the clearest segmentation signals you get is that bigger, less price-sensitive customers all require SSO (because their SOC2 attestations require it).&lt;p&gt;You can get irritated about pricing systems that soak price-insensitive customers, but remember that the big price-insensitive customers pay for the price-sensitive customers, which is why this kind of segmentation is practically universal.&lt;p&gt;Previously, on this, from me:&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=29892664"&gt;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=29892664&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 19 Aug 2025 20:21:03 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44955882</link><dc:creator>tptacek</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44955882</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44955882</guid></item><item><title>New comment by racemic in "Counter-Strike: A billion-dollar game built in a dorm room"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I've lurked on HN for years, but I had to create an account just to respond to your post. I operated these servers – perhaps my handle is still familiar. I remember you for sure! I'm touched that you and so many others still have fond memories of that time.&lt;p&gt;It was such a gratifying experience to build out that server network and the accompanying integrations that attracted so many and built such a great community. I miss the days in college when I had time to work on stuff like that just for the love of it. I hope you are doing well!&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 19 Aug 2025 05:45:42 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44948602</link><dc:creator>racemic</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44948602</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44948602</guid></item><item><title>New comment by rimunroe in "Counter-Strike: A billion-dollar game built in a dorm room"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I will forever mourn the general demise of server browsers. Too many games require you to use matchmaking systems, which means it's very hard to build up a small community in-game anymore. You either have to rely on forming small parties with people you've stumbled upon one by one, or you have to seek out people from some much larger area like Reddit or Discord. It takes a lot of the serendipity out of the experience. Without a small community it becomes much harder to ensure you're not playing with people who make the game less fun by whatever metric you care about.&lt;p&gt;I used to be an admin on a group of about 18 or so connected Counter-Strike 1.6 servers called T3Houston*. We ran modified versions of various Warcraft 3 mods which added persistent XP/leveling, as well as integration with an external item store and player database the owner maintained. Most of those servers were filled to the brim during peak US gaming times, and our forum was quite active.&lt;p&gt;There aren't many games these days where you could do something like that. I discovered the community because one day I was just looking for a server with open slots for me to join. I was fairly skeptical of whatever a Warcraft mod would be like, but ended up enjoying it so I added it to my favorites. Eventually I got to know the regulars and joined the forum. Notably, the place felt far less toxic than the average server I'd join back then. I can completely believe this is just me looking at the past through rose tinted glasses, but it feels like the general toxicity has gotten worse at the same time as we've lost a lot of tools to manage it.&lt;p&gt;* If anyone else here remembers the name T3Houston: hi! I'm Stealth Penguin&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 18 Aug 2025 19:27:03 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44944319</link><dc:creator>rimunroe</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44944319</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44944319</guid></item><item><title>New comment by ofou in "Anna's Archive: An Update from the Team"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Shadow libraries maintainers deserve a Nobel prize for their contributions to humanity. Satoshi would be proud.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 18 Aug 2025 17:51:00 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44943389</link><dc:creator>ofou</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44943389</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44943389</guid></item><item><title>New comment by simpaticoder in "Open hardware desktop 3D printing is dead?"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;The real story here is that IP ownership is capital-intensive when it shouldn't be. Open-source and community-led IP contributions are grossly under-protected because of this, and those with capital become unopposed predators. This is a special-case of the more general observation that the justice system is capital-intensive when it shouldn't be. The answer is something you very rarely hear: the US (especially) needs justice system reform with an eye toward making actions take 100x less time and 100x less money, approaching free for consumer and IP actions. Given the advent of computers, the internet, video conferencing,  it is outrageous how much of the current system requires physical paper, physical presence in a courtroom. It is outrageous how the slowness and cost of the system itself is used by the wealthy to bully the poor.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 15 Aug 2025 12:47:53 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44911707</link><dc:creator>simpaticoder</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44911707</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44911707</guid></item><item><title>New comment by godelski in "Streaming services are driving viewers back to piracy"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Piracy also offers:&lt;p&gt;0. Ability to watch offline!&lt;p&gt;1. Ability to fix subtitle issues with minimal tweeks like change size or moving location.&lt;p&gt;1.2 Ability to get subtitles if they aren't offered (or offered in your language)&lt;p&gt;2. Ability to normalize audio.&lt;p&gt;3. Ability to buffer videos when on a poor connection.&lt;p&gt;4. Ability to create collections, organize, and track your movie as you wish&lt;p&gt;5. Arbitrary number of user accounts&lt;p&gt;6. Multicast streams to watch the same show across different devices regardless of if someone has an account or not (see JellyFin's SyncPlay)&lt;p&gt;7. No big organization tracking you and selling your data to the highest bidder&lt;p&gt;There's more, but honestly pirating is just a better experience. I can't tell you how many times Netflix has fucked up the subtitles so they are covering half my screen. There's tons of little issues like that that are just random and the only option is to just not watch Netflix (or pick your streaming service) that day.&lt;p&gt;Besides that, for the price of a yearly subscription you can build a NAS that can do all this for you and you get to keep the movies. Instead of having a monthly fee you can progressively add more drives and this can also be used for all your other things. Pictures, home videos, games (you can make a Steam cache), your local AI models, or whatever else you want. With $1k you can build a pretty good system, though that's 3 years of 4k Netflix, so not the cheap route in the short term.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 15 Aug 2025 00:36:37 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44907384</link><dc:creator>godelski</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44907384</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44907384</guid></item><item><title>New comment by ryandrake in "Streaming services are driving viewers back to piracy"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Piracy offers:&lt;p&gt;1. Unrestricted access to an absolutely huge library of movies, music and TV shows, nearly unlimited. Certainly not limited by opaque "licensing deals" between various companies.&lt;p&gt;2. Highest resolution/bitrate/quality that was available at the time of the work's original release.&lt;p&gt;3. No arbitrary device/OS limitations.&lt;p&gt;4. Can watch/listen/download from any location on earth with sufficient bandwidth.&lt;p&gt;I didn't even mention that it's free or that there are no ads, because that's pretty much the least important attribute to me. If any company came out with a service that offered those four points, I'd probably be willing to pay a lot for it. How much? Who knows, we don't know how much this is worth because nobody is even trying to offer it.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 14 Aug 2025 21:40:36 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44906021</link><dc:creator>ryandrake</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44906021</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44906021</guid></item><item><title>New comment by deeg in "Steve Wozniak: Life to me was never about accomplishment, but about happiness"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Woz gave a lecture in one of my classes years ago and I came away impressed.  He was obviously a brilliant engineer.  "Naivete" is generally used in a negative manner but he had just enough naivete to get through life happy.  He talked about all the chips he redesigned as a teen and it did not sound like bragging at all.  We need more Woz's and less Jobs in this world.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 14 Aug 2025 19:02:19 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44904277</link><dc:creator>deeg</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44904277</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44904277</guid></item><item><title>New comment by crooked-v in "Streaming services are driving viewers back to piracy"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;To really sum it all up in one place, check out the absurdity of the official guide on where to watch the Pokemon cartoon: &lt;a href="https://www.pokemon.com/us/animation/where-to-watch-pokemon-episodes-movies" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://www.pokemon.com/us/animation/where-to-watch-pokemon-...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;And that doesn't even actually list the movies, which are even more fragmented.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 14 Aug 2025 18:21:14 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44903818</link><dc:creator>crooked-v</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44903818</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44903818</guid></item><item><title>New comment by canyon289 in "Gemma 3 270M: Compact model for hyper-efficient AI"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Hi all, I built these models with a great team. They're available for download across the open model ecosystem so give them a try! I built these models with a great team and am thrilled to get them out to you.&lt;p&gt;From our side we designed these models to be strong for their size out of the box, and with the goal you'll all finetune it for your use case. With the small size it'll fit on a wide range of hardware and cost much less to finetune. You can try finetuning them yourself in a free colab in under 5 minutes&lt;p&gt;For picking a Gemma size this is a video I recorded for the 1b to 27b sizes earlier this year, 270m being the newest addition&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=qcjrduz_YS8" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=qcjrduz_YS8&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;Hacker News Disclaimer
I really like working at Google so with that; All my opinions here are my own, I'm a researcher so I'll largely focus on technical questions, and I'll share what I can.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 14 Aug 2025 16:14:07 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44902240</link><dc:creator>canyon289</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44902240</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44902240</guid></item><item><title>New comment by BallsInIt in "Blood oxygen monitoring returning to Apple Watch in the US"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Software patents are a scourge.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 14 Aug 2025 15:22:23 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44901499</link><dc:creator>BallsInIt</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44901499</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44901499</guid></item><item><title>New comment by ACS_Solver in "Arch shares its wiki strategy with Debian"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;The Arch wiki is one of the best things the Linux community has produced. It's like a modern, improved and more complete version of TLDP.&lt;p&gt;I haven't even used Arch on any of my machines but can't count how many times I've found their wiki useful for my workstations, servers and even custom Yocto-built systems. Arch supports many ways of doing a thing, so whatever tool I'm dealing with, Arch probably supports that and documents it on the wiki. And Arch makes few changes from upstream so the wiki instructions are often applicable on any distro. Sure, it takes some familiarity to recognize when something is e.g. Debian-specific and should be done in a Debian way, but as a user fairly familiar with Linux, I often find Arch to be the best source of documentation.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 14 Aug 2025 11:35:16 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44899196</link><dc:creator>ACS_Solver</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44899196</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44899196</guid></item><item><title>New comment by Shank in "Facial recognition vans to be rolled out across police forces in England"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;The UK is quickly deploying surveillance state technology that people once decried China for. Whether or not this is ethical or useful, I wish the hypocrisy would be acknowledged. The OSA, the Apple encryption demands, LFR, …, it’s clearly a trend. Has society really become this dangerous that we must deploy these things?&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 13 Aug 2025 13:23:41 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44888128</link><dc:creator>Shank</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44888128</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44888128</guid></item><item><title>New comment by JohnMakin in "Why are there so many rationalist cults?"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;One of a few issues I have with groups like these, is that they often confidently and aggressively spew a set of beliefs that on their face logically follow from one another, until you realize they are built on a set of axioms that are either entirely untested or outright nonsense. This is common everywhere, but I feel especially pronounced in communities like this. It also involves quite a bit of navel gazing that makes me feel a little sick participating in.&lt;p&gt;The smartest people I have ever known have been profoundly unsure of their beliefs and what they know. I immediately become suspicious of anyone who is very certain of something, especially if they derived it on their own.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 12 Aug 2025 15:45:44 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44877844</link><dc:creator>JohnMakin</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44877844</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44877844</guid></item><item><title>New comment by jraph in "StarDict sends X11 clipboard to remote servers"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;“the plans and the demolition orders have been on display at the local planning office on Alpha Centauri for fifty of your Earth years. If you can't be bothered to take an interest in local affairs...”&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Z1Ba4BbH0oY" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Z1Ba4BbH0oY&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 12 Aug 2025 08:34:11 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44873825</link><dc:creator>jraph</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44873825</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44873825</guid></item><item><title>New comment by gmueckl in "GitHub is no longer independent at Microsoft after CEO resignation"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;This comment comes some 15 years late. Microsoft runs the biggest org on github and has open sourced a lot of their own code under permissive licenses.&lt;p&gt;IE has been dead and buried for ages. Edge doesn't have even close to the same market share and is based on Chromium.&lt;p&gt;They build more and more of their own UIs on Electron.&lt;p&gt;I honestly don't remember when they tried to snare someone to use proprietary extensions to something open. I probably have missed a few instances.&lt;p&gt;Long story short: MS isn't a saint. They are a business. And they have behaved relatively nice for so long that some young adults don't know any other side of MS now.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 11 Aug 2025 20:21:27 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44868993</link><dc:creator>gmueckl</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44868993</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44868993</guid></item><item><title>New comment by meindnoch in "GitHub is no longer independent at Microsoft after CEO resignation"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Microsoft being the cool guys? The &lt;i&gt;cool guys&lt;/i&gt;? Mwuhahahhaa.&lt;p&gt;This gave me the good belly laugh I needed.&lt;p&gt;For the last 25 years, Microsoft was known for:&lt;p&gt;- being the no. 1 enemy of free software&lt;p&gt;- shipping the worst web browser in existence, despite 80%+ market share&lt;p&gt;- making corrupt deals with governments around the world to tie them to their office software suite&lt;p&gt;- creating vendor-locked proprietary extensions to kill open technologies (ActiveX plugins, Silverlight, C++/CLI, MSJVM, etc.)&lt;p&gt;- making cringe hardware that basically noone purchased (Zune, Windows Phone)&lt;p&gt;The last time they might have been considered the "cool guys" was sometime in the 90s.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 11 Aug 2025 20:07:30 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44868845</link><dc:creator>meindnoch</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44868845</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44868845</guid></item><item><title>New comment by bArray in "Wikipedia loses challenge against Online Safety Act"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&gt; The government told the BBC it welcomed the High Court's judgment, "which will help us continue our work implementing the Online Safety Act to create a safer online world for everyone".&lt;p&gt;Demonstrably false. It creates a safer online world for &lt;i&gt;some&lt;/i&gt;.&lt;p&gt;&gt; In particular the foundation is concerned the extra duties required - if Wikipedia was classed as Category 1 - would mean it would have to verify the identity of its contributors, undermining their privacy and safety.&lt;p&gt;Some of the articles, which contain factual information, are damning for the UK government. It lists, for example, political scandals [1] [2]. Or information regarding hot topics such as immigration [3], information that the UK government want to strictly control (abstracting away from whether this is rightfully or wrongfully).&lt;p&gt;I can tell you what will (and has already) happened as a result:&lt;p&gt;1. People will use VPNs and any other available methods to avoid restrictions placed on them.&lt;p&gt;2. The next government will take great delight in removing this law as an easy win.&lt;p&gt;3. The likelihood of a British constitution is increasing, which would somewhat bind future parliaments.&lt;p&gt;[1] &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_political_scandals_in_the_United_Kingdom" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_political_scandals_in_...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;[2] &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Category:Labour_Party_(UK)_scandals" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Category:Labour_Party_(UK)_sca...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;[3] &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Modern_immigration_to_the_United_Kingdom" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Modern_immigration_to_the_Unit...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 11 Aug 2025 18:11:54 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44867467</link><dc:creator>bArray</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44867467</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44867467</guid></item><item><title>New comment by 827a in "GitHub is no longer independent at Microsoft after CEO resignation"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;My deepest concern at this time isn't that AI eventually gets written down to nothing; because I don't think it will. Its that these companies are so scared of being out-competed by an AI-first competitor that they're willing to make deep sacrifices to their core businesses just to effectively virtue signal that they're AI first and unable to be out-competed.&lt;p&gt;It is deeply concerning because all things point to reality shaking out with irony. None of these big tech companies have leveraged AI to build anything remotely interesting from a product perspective. Its truly astounding how bad they are at it. Apple has nothing, Microsoft wants to put spyware on every Windows computer and builds the worst coding agent on the market despite having privileged access to every line of source code ever written, Meta put a chatbot in Whatsapp then decided paying researchers ten mil would solve their problems, Google has world-class research teams that have produced unbelievable models, without any plan at all on how those make it into their products beyond forcing a chat window into Google Drive.&lt;p&gt;Their fear is going to lose them everything. Its a fascinating inversion of the early internet problem, where companies who were unwilling to innovate got out-competed. Everyone learned that lesson and decided "we'll never be unwilling to innovate ever again"; but now their core product stable undergoes constant churn that is pissing off customers and driving competition to eat their lunch.&lt;p&gt;There is long-term, durable beauty in investing majority effort into making Github the single best place to host and organize code. That need is never going away. There is also necessity in ensuring it has an AI strategy in a post-AI world, no one doubts that, but its a matter of proportion and humility. Microsoft/Github will never build AI products that lead the market. Its not a technology problem; its an organizational and political one. But that's ok, because they could dominate the market with the world's best code hosting platform, an average AI strategy, and a library of integrations with the rest of the frontier world.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 11 Aug 2025 17:46:59 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44867153</link><dc:creator>827a</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44867153</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44867153</guid></item><item><title>New comment by pjmlp in "GitHub is no longer independent at Microsoft after CEO resignation"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I think that just like it happened with Apple after they made it out of bankruptcy, Microsoft being the cool guys phase is slowly over.&lt;p&gt;Xamarin is no more, after the whole MAUI rewrite without backwards compatibility to Xamarin.Forms, killing VS4Mac, shortly after having rewriten the underlying Xamarin based IDE into Mac, what survives is a subset of Xamarin tech for mobile and WebAssembly workloads.&lt;p&gt;.NET is now cross platform, but only as long as it doesn't hurt VS sales, with GUI workloads, profilers, still being mostly Windows only, and partially supported on VSCode, which also has the same VS license.&lt;p&gt;A proper cross platform IDE experience requires getting Rider.&lt;p&gt;Then there is the issue they seem to be shoting into all directions, with GUI frameworks, Web, Blazor, Aspire, to see what sticks.&lt;p&gt;Github even with the previous CEO was already a delivery mechanism for Azure and AI efforts, now it will be full steam ahead, as per new org chart.&lt;p&gt;VC++ after betting other compilers in C++20 support, seems to have lost its resources struggling  to deliver C++23, and also probably affected by the Secure Future Initiative, and decisions for safer languages.&lt;p&gt;But hey 4 trillion valuation, so from shareholders point of view, everything is going great.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 11 Aug 2025 17:06:58 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44866666</link><dc:creator>pjmlp</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44866666</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44866666</guid></item><item><title>New comment by msk-lywenn in "36B solar mass black hole at centre of the Cosmic Horseshoe gravitational lens"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;With good quantization, I bet we can get it down to 8B and it will easily fit on consumer grade galaxy.&lt;p&gt;(Sorry, I had to, with all the AI flood, I really was about to skip this info after the first 3 characters)&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 11 Aug 2025 15:29:04 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44865256</link><dc:creator>msk-lywenn</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44865256</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44865256</guid></item><item><title>New comment by Igrom in "I tried every todo app and ended up with a .txt file"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Reading through the comments under this thread, there are many users who swear by a plain text file, but who then build quite a lot of snowflake software to regain functionality offered by more structured TODO applications. That includes:&lt;p&gt;- having your computer alert you to things that come up&lt;p&gt;- being able to tag notes&lt;p&gt;- being able to add events to a calendar&lt;p&gt;- being able to set priority of tasks&lt;p&gt;- expecting prioritized/currently relevant tasks to be at the top of the agenda&lt;p&gt;- being able to add recurring tasks&lt;p&gt;- full-text search (grepping)&lt;p&gt;- formatting features (markdown)&lt;p&gt;Some of the laborious (or, in my opinion, plain unholy) solutions include:&lt;p&gt;- feeding TODOs to an LLM to filter for the currently relevant ones and send Telegram notifications&lt;p&gt;- hand-copying currently relevant tasks to the top of the TODO list&lt;p&gt;- running a script on a VPS to sync notifications&lt;p&gt;- set up cron job with git commit&lt;p&gt;- writing post-it notes by hand&lt;p&gt;I would encourage everyone to try out emacs with org-mode. It takes some time to get used to the editor and its keybindings (though provisions exist for vim users), but _every_ item on the list above is handled out of the box, or is offered through a free and maintained plugin.&lt;p&gt;The author of the OP claims to have tried _every_ todo app, and has afterwards moved (regressed?) to writing notes in a plain text file, but there is a path extending from this point that the author has not walked yet. I strongly suggest that, especially for people with a computing or technical background, it is an undisputed upgrade. &lt;a href="https://doc.norang.ca/org-mode.html" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://doc.norang.ca/org-mode.html&lt;/a&gt; being the bible, of course.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 11 Aug 2025 15:13:04 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44865065</link><dc:creator>Igrom</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44865065</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44865065</guid></item><item><title>New comment by nickslaughter02 in "Wikipedia loses challenge against Online Safety Act"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Wikimedia should block UK access. That will get the attention of media and popularity contest politicians might change their mind.&lt;p&gt;Remember the "Repeal the Online Safety Act" petition? It has gotten over half a million signatures and the response from the government was a loud "no".&lt;p&gt;&gt; The Government has no plans to repeal the Online Safety Act, and is working closely with Ofcom to implement the Act as quickly and effectively as possible to enable UK users to benefit from its protections.&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://petition.parliament.uk/petitions/722903" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://petition.parliament.uk/petitions/722903&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 11 Aug 2025 13:27:51 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44863835</link><dc:creator>nickslaughter02</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44863835</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44863835</guid></item><item><title>New comment by canyon289 in "Ask HN: How can ChatGPT serve 700M users when I can't run one GPT-4 locally?"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I work at Google on these systems everyday (caveat this is my own words not my employers)). So I simultaneously can tell you that its smart people really thinking about every facet of the problem, and I can't tell you much more than that.&lt;p&gt;However I can share this written by my colleagues! You'll find great explanations about accelerator architectures and the considerations made to make things fast.&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://jax-ml.github.io/scaling-book/" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://jax-ml.github.io/scaling-book/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;In particular your questions are around inference which is the focus of this chapter
&lt;a href="https://jax-ml.github.io/scaling-book/inference/" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://jax-ml.github.io/scaling-book/inference/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;Edit:
Another great resource to look at is the unsloth guides. These folks are incredibly good at getting deep into various models and finding optimizations, and they're very good at writing it up. Here's the Gemma 3n guide, and you'll find others as well.&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://docs.unsloth.ai/basics/gemma-3n-how-to-run-and-fine-tune"&gt;https://docs.unsloth.ai/basics/gemma-3n-how-to-run-and-fine-...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 08 Aug 2025 19:47:42 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44840935</link><dc:creator>canyon289</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44840935</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44840935</guid></item><item><title>New comment by beeflet in "GPT-5"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Perhaps it is not possible to simulate higher-level intelligence using a stochastic model for predicting text.&lt;p&gt;I am not an AI researcher, but I have friends who do work in the field, and they are not worried about LLM-based AGI because of the diminishing returns on results vs amount of training data required. Maybe this is the bottleneck.&lt;p&gt;Human intelligence is markedly different from LLMs: it requires far fewer examples to train on, and generalizes way better. Whereas LLMs tend to regurgitate solutions to solved problems, where the solutions tend to be well-published in training data.&lt;p&gt;That being said, AGI is not a necessary requirement for AI to be totally world-changing. There are possibly applications of existing AI/ML/SL technology which could be more impactful than general intelligence. Search is one example where the ability to regurgitate knowledge from many domains is desirable&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 07 Aug 2025 18:17:24 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44828331</link><dc:creator>beeflet</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44828331</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44828331</guid></item><item><title>New comment by highfrequency in "GPT-5"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;It is frequently suggested that once one of the AI companies reaches an AGI threshold, they will take off ahead of the rest. It's interesting to note that at least so far, the trend has been the opposite: as time goes on and the models get better, the performance of the different company's gets clustered closer together. Right now GPT-5, Claude Opus, Grok 4, Gemini 2.5 Pro all seem quite good across the board (ie they can all basically solve moderately challenging math and coding problems).&lt;p&gt;As a user, it feels like the race has never been as close as it is now. Perhaps dumb to extrapolate, but it makes me lean more skeptical about the hard take-off / winner-take-all mental model that has been pushed.&lt;p&gt;Would be curious to hear the take of a researcher at one of these firms - do you expect the AI offerings across competitors to become more competitive and clustered over the next few years, or less so?&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 07 Aug 2025 18:05:12 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44828137</link><dc:creator>highfrequency</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44828137</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44828137</guid></item><item><title>New comment by DecoPerson in "Emailing a one-time code is worse than passwords"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;The attack pattern is:&lt;p&gt;1) User goes to BAD website and signs up.&lt;p&gt;2) BAD website says “We’ve sent you an email, please enter the 6-digit code! The email will come from GOOD, as they are our sign-in partner.”&lt;p&gt;3) BAD’s bots start a “Sign in with email one-time code” flow on the GOOD website using the user’s email.&lt;p&gt;4) GOOD sends a one-time login code email to the user’s email address.&lt;p&gt;5) The user is very likely to trust this email, because it’s from GOOD, and why would GOOD send it if it’s not a proper login?&lt;p&gt;6) User enters code into BAD’s website.&lt;p&gt;7) BAD uses code to login to GOOD’s website as the user. BAD now has full access to the user’s GOOD account.&lt;p&gt;This is why “email me a one-time code” is one of the worst authentication flows for phishing. It’s just so hard to stop users from making this mistake.&lt;p&gt;“Click a link in the email” is a tiny bit better because it takes the user straight to the GOOD website, and passing that link to BAD is more tedious and therefore more suspicious. However, if some popular email service suddenly decides your login emails or the login link within should be blocked, then suddenly many of your users cannot login.&lt;p&gt;Passkeys is the way to go. Password manager support for passkeys is getting really good. And I assure you, all passkeys being lost when a user loses their phone is far, far better than what’s been happening with passwords. I’d rather granny needs to visit the bank to get access to her account again, than someone phishes her and steals all her money.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 07 Aug 2025 03:37:03 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44820331</link><dc:creator>DecoPerson</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44820331</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44820331</guid></item></channel></rss>