<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>Hacker News: Best Comments</title><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/bestcomments</link><description>Hacker News RSS</description><docs>https://hnrss.org/</docs><generator>hnrss v2.1.1</generator><lastBuildDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 23:42:25 +0000</lastBuildDate><ns0:link href="https://hnrss.org/bestcomments" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item><title>New comment by fainpul in "alpr.watch"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;For years I've thought about doing an "art project" to make people more aware of the fact they are being observed – but I never actually got up and did it.&lt;p&gt;The idea was to seek spots in the city where public web cams are pointed at, and paint QR codes on the ground at those spots (using a template), linking to the camera stream. So when curious passerbys scan the code, they see themselves in a camera stream and feel "watched".&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 18:19:46 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46292120</link><dc:creator>fainpul</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46292120</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46292120</guid></item><item><title>New comment by gkoberger in "Mozilla appoints new CEO Anthony Enzor-Demeo"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Having worked at Mozilla a while ago, the CEO role is one I wouldn't wish on my worst enemy. Success is oddly defined: it's a non-profit (well, a for-profit owned by a non-profit) that needs to make a big profit in a short amount of time. And anything done to make that profit will annoy the community.&lt;p&gt;I hope Anthony leans into what makes Mozilla special. The past few years, Mozilla's business model has been to just meekly "us-too!" trends... IoT, Firefox OS, and more recently AI.&lt;p&gt;What Mozilla is good at, though, is taking complex things the average user doesn't really understand, and making it palpable and safe. They did this with web standards... nobody cared about web standards, but Mozilla focused on usability.&lt;p&gt;(Slide aside, it's not a coincidence the best CEO Mozilla ever had was a designer.)&lt;p&gt;I'm not an AI hater, but I don't think Mozilla can compete here. There's just too much good stuff already, and it's not the type of thing Mozilla will shine with.&lt;p&gt;Instead, if I were CEO, I'd go the opposite way: I'd focus on privacy. Not AI privacy, but privacy in general. Buy a really great email provider, and start to own "identity on the internet". As there's more bots and less privacy, identity is going to be incredibly important over the years.. and right now, Google defacto owns identity. Make it free, but also give people a way to pay.&lt;p&gt;Would this work? I don't know. But like I said, it's not a job I envy.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 17:56:50 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46291798</link><dc:creator>gkoberger</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46291798</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46291798</guid></item><item><title>New comment by MathiasPius in "Pricing Changes for GitHub Actions"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Introducing a separate charge specifically targeting those of your customers who choose to self-host your hilariously fragile infrastructure is certainly a choice.. And one I assume is in no way tied to adoption/usage-based KPIs.&lt;p&gt;Of course, if you can just fence in your competition and charge admission, it'd be silly to invest time in building a superior product.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 17:46:00 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46291634</link><dc:creator>MathiasPius</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46291634</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46291634</guid></item><item><title>New comment by perlgeek in "Mozilla appoints new CEO Anthony Enzor-Demeo"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;They also have the "extensions that can do &lt;i&gt;real&lt;/i&gt; ad blocking" angle.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 14:18:40 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46288761</link><dc:creator>perlgeek</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46288761</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46288761</guid></item><item><title>New comment by tchalla in "Children with cancer scammed out of millions fundraised for their treatment"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;The root cause of the problem is that parents and children need to raise funds for cancer treatment in the first place.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 08:42:45 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46286208</link><dc:creator>tchalla</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46286208</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46286208</guid></item><item><title>New comment by isoprophlex in "JetBlue flight averts mid-air collision with US Air Force jet"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;We have the best mid-air collisions. Noone does it better, or so people tell me. We don't do sleepy silent disappearances over the Bermuda Triangle, that's SAD!! We blow em up, BIGLY, in someone else's airspace. A great PRESIDENT knows how to WIN at mid-air collisions. Thank you for your attention to this matter.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 08:09:42 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46286005</link><dc:creator>isoprophlex</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46286005</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46286005</guid></item><item><title>New comment by Animats in "Children with cancer scammed out of millions fundraised for their treatment"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;"The campaigns with the biggest apparent international reach were under the name of an organisation called Chance Letikva (Chance for Hope, in English) - registered in Israel and the US."&lt;p&gt;Chance Letikva is registered with the US IRS as a charity. They've filed a Form 990. Location is Brooklyn, NY. [1] Address is listed. It's a small house. It's also incorporated as CHANCE LETIKVA, INC. in New York State. Address matches. Names of officers not given. There's one name in the IRS filing, listed as the president.&lt;p&gt;Web site "&lt;a href="https://chanceletikva.org" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://chanceletikva.org&lt;/a&gt;" has been "suspended". Domain is still registered, via Namecheap.&lt;p&gt;Some on the ground digging and subpoenas should reveal who's behind this.&lt;p&gt;[1] &lt;a href="https://projects.propublica.org/nonprofits/organizations/852049371" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://projects.propublica.org/nonprofits/organizations/852...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 07:45:57 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46285838</link><dc:creator>Animats</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46285838</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46285838</guid></item><item><title>New comment by t0mas88 in "JetBlue flight averts mid-air collision with US Air Force jet"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;It's expected for military operations to fly without transponder, they don't want to have their location visible. But it's crazy that they're also doing it in Curacao controlled airspace without agreeing a restricted area.&lt;p&gt;Even for training they set up restricted/military areas in airspace all the time. Not doing it here, in allied (Curacao is part of the kingdom of the Netherlands) airspace is unacceptable. They could have coordinated this in the normal ways so ATC would route civilian traffic around the military operations or talk to the military controllers (who can see both types of traffic) before sending an aircraft through the shared airspace.&lt;p&gt;This isn't new, it's how military operations are done all the time.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 07:13:52 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46285687</link><dc:creator>t0mas88</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46285687</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46285687</guid></item><item><title>New comment by tekno45 in "Ford kills the All-Electric F-150"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;The F-150 is a great power bank that comes with a very useful set of 4 tires and a steering wheel for a truly portable charging experience.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 03:11:16 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46284308</link><dc:creator>tekno45</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46284308</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46284308</guid></item><item><title>New comment by malvim in "JetBlue flight averts mid-air collision with US Air Force jet"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;They could also not invade a country that did nothing to attack them, but I guess that’s asking too much.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 02:32:21 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46284037</link><dc:creator>malvim</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46284037</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46284037</guid></item><item><title>New comment by jofer in "Economics of Orbital vs. Terrestrial Data Centers"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;What really worries me is that I keep hearing "cooling is cheap and easy in space!" in a lot of these conversations, and it couldn't be farther from the truth.  Cooling is _really_ hard and can't use efficient (i.e. advection-based air or water cooling) approaches and are limited to dramatically less efficient radiative cooling.   It doesn't matter that space is cold because cooling is damned hard in a vacuum.&lt;p&gt;The article makes this point, but it's relatively far in and I felt it was worth making again.&lt;p&gt;With that said, my employer now appears to be in this business, so I guess if there's money there, we can build the satellites.  (Note: opinions my own) I just don't see how it makes sense from a practical technical perspective.&lt;p&gt;Space is a much harder place to run datacenters.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 23:22:55 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46282374</link><dc:creator>jofer</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46282374</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46282374</guid></item><item><title>New comment by btown in "Upcoming Changes to Let's Encrypt Certificates"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;The certificate lifetime decrease, to 45 days, was discussed in: &lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46117126"&gt;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46117126&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;This isn't LE's decision: a 47 day max was voted on by the CA/Browser Forum.&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.digicert.com/blog/tls-certificate-lifetimes-will-officially-reduce-to-47-days" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://www.digicert.com/blog/tls-certificate-lifetimes-will...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://cabforum.org/2025/04/11/ballot-sc081v3-introduce-schedule-of-reducing-validity-and-data-reuse-periods/" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://cabforum.org/2025/04/11/ballot-sc081v3-introduce-sch...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://groups.google.com/a/groups.cabforum.org/g/servercert-wg/c/bvWh5RN6tYI?pli=1" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://groups.google.com/a/groups.cabforum.org/g/servercert...&lt;/a&gt; - public votes of all members, which were unanimously Yes or Abstain.&lt;p&gt;IMO this is a policy change that can Break the Internet, as many archived/legacy sites on old-school certificates may not be able to afford the upfront tech or ongoing labor to transition from annual to effectively-monthly renewals, and will simply be shut down.&lt;p&gt;And, per other comments, this will make LE the only viable option to modernize, and thus much more of a central point of failure than before.&lt;p&gt;But Let's Encrypt is not responsible for this move, and did not vote on the ballot.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 20:31:30 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46280171</link><dc:creator>btown</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46280171</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46280171</guid></item><item><title>New comment by pedrozieg in "Umbrel – Personal Cloud"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;A decade of “personal cloud box” attempts has shown that the hard part isn’t the hardware, it’s the long-term social contract. Synology/WD/My Cloud/etc all eventually hit the same wall: once the company pivots or dies, you’re left with a sealed brick that you don’t fully control, holding the most irreplaceable thing you own: your data. If you’re going to charge an Apple-like premium on commodity mini-PC hardware, you really have to over-communicate what happens if Umbrel-the-company disappears or changes direction: how do I keep using this thing in 5–10 years without your cloud, your app store, your updates?&lt;p&gt;The interesting opportunity here isn’t selling a fancy N100 box, it’s turning “self-hosted everything” into something your non-technical friend could actually live with. That’s mostly about boring stuff: automatic off-site backup that isn’t tied to one vendor, painless replacement/restore if the hardware dies, and clear guarantees about what runs locally vs phoning home. If Umbrel leans into being forkable and portable across generic hardware, it has a shot at being trusted infrastructure instead of just another pretty NAS that people regret once the marketing site goes dark.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 20:13:07 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46279893</link><dc:creator>pedrozieg</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46279893</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46279893</guid></item><item><title>New comment by ryandrake in "“Super secure” messaging app leaks everyone's phone number"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I love the quote the article starts with:&lt;p&gt;&gt; Neither of us had prior experience developing mobile apps, but we thought, “Hey, we’re both smart. This shouldn’t be too difficult.”&lt;p&gt;I think, 40 years from now when we're writing about this last decade or so of software development, this quote is going to sum it all up.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 19:53:36 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46279569</link><dc:creator>ryandrake</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46279569</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46279569</guid></item><item><title>New comment by jotux in "US Tech Force"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&gt;What is the expected compensation for participants? Compensation varies based on experience level and agency placement. Annual salaries are expected to be in the approximate range of $150,000 to $200,000. Benefits include health insurance, retirement plans, paid time off, and eligibility for performance-based awards.&lt;p&gt;&gt;Tech Force will primarily recruit early-career technologists&lt;p&gt;So "early-career" but they're going to get paid GS-14/15 pay[1] in DC? New grad engineers in DC are going to be GS-7/9 at best. This is either a blatant lie, or created by someone who has no idea of how federal pay works (or both).&lt;p&gt;As an aside, I was a fed for &gt;10 years and left last year for industry but stay in touch with friends still working federal jobs. Before this administration recruiting was extremely difficult and candidate quality was low. I've heard that it's nearly impossible now and in the last 18 months they've only been able to hire a single person. Federal jobs used to be considered stable, with good benefits, but low pay. Now they're unstable, the current administration is actively working to make benefits worse, and the pay is still really low.&lt;p&gt;[1] &lt;a href="https://www.opm.gov/policy-data-oversight/pay-leave/salaries-wages/salary-tables/25Tables/html/DCB.aspx" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://www.opm.gov/policy-data-oversight/pay-leave/salaries...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 18:13:29 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46278164</link><dc:creator>jotux</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46278164</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46278164</guid></item><item><title>New comment by JumpCrisscross in "Pro-democracy HK tycoon Jimmy Lai convicted in national security trial"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;One of the dark consequences of America losing its city-upon-a-hill aspirations is we're less able to effectively call out evil abroad. Jimmy Lai should not have been allowed to this quietly.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 16:50:47 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46276939</link><dc:creator>JumpCrisscross</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46276939</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46276939</guid></item><item><title>New comment by peppersghost93 in "Thousands of U.S. farmers have Parkinson's. They blame a deadly pesticide"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;You should consider dropping that instinct. If you look into how corporations have behaved historically you'd assume evil until proven innocent. Especially US corps.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 15:36:30 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46275843</link><dc:creator>peppersghost93</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46275843</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46275843</guid></item><item><title>New comment by zug_zug in "Thousands of U.S. farmers have Parkinson's. They blame a deadly pesticide"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Reminds me of "cancer alley" [1].&lt;p&gt;As somebody who's looked in to this a bit, the deeper I dug the more I ultimately moved toward the conclusion (reluctantly) that indeed big corporations are the baddies. I have an instinct to steel-math both sides, but not every issue has two compelling sides to it...&lt;p&gt;One example of them clearly being the baddies is them paying people to social media astroturf to defend the roundup pesticide online [2].&lt;p&gt;1. &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cancer_Alley" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cancer_Alley&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;2. &lt;a href="https://galiherlaw.com/media-manipulation-comes-out-during-monsanto-roundup-lawsuit/#:~:text=Monsanto%20Kept%20Watch%20Lists%20on%20Pesticide%20Friends,including%20journalists%2C%20politicians%2C%20and%20certain%20interest%20groups." rel="nofollow"&gt;https://galiherlaw.com/media-manipulation-comes-out-during-m...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 15:18:18 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46275591</link><dc:creator>zug_zug</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46275591</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46275591</guid></item><item><title>New comment by 827a in "It seems that OpenAI is scraping [certificate transparency] logs"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Thousands&lt;/i&gt; of systems, from Google to script kiddies to OpenAI to nigerian call scammers to cybersecurity firms, actively watch the certificate transparency logs for exactly this reason. Yawn.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 15:08:49 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46275459</link><dc:creator>827a</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46275459</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46275459</guid></item><item><title>New comment by fny in "Roomba maker goes bankrupt, Chinese owner emerges"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I'm all for antitrust, but it's a shame the Amazon acquisition was blocked.[0]&lt;p&gt;iRobot was in a distressed state then, and immediately laid of 1/3 of staff when the deal fell through. I knew a survivor of that mess. Now this.&lt;p&gt;0: &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/1/29/24034201/amazon-irobot-acquisition-over-antitrust-regulator-scrutiny" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://www.theverge.com/2024/1/29/24034201/amazon-irobot-ac...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;0: &lt;a href="https://archive.is/rBn7z" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://archive.is/rBn7z&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 13:55:12 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46274568</link><dc:creator>fny</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46274568</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46274568</guid></item><item><title>New comment by vjk800 in "If AI replaces workers, should it also pay taxes?"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Tractors largely replaced human labour in farming about a hundred years ago. Should we have started taxing tractors?&lt;p&gt;I really have difficulties seeing AI as anything else than yet another type of machinery. If your argument is "but it's replacing ALMOST ALL human labour" - well, the same argument was valid for tractors a hundred years ago (when almost everyone was employed in agriculture).&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 13:22:16 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46274171</link><dc:creator>vjk800</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46274171</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46274171</guid></item><item><title>New comment by komali2 in "I'm Kenyan. I don't write like ChatGPT, ChatGPT writes like me"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&gt; There were unspoken rules, commandments passed down from teacher to student, year after year. The first commandment? Thou shalt begin with a proverb or a powerful opening statement. “Haste makes waste,” we would write, before launching into a tale about rushing to the market and forgetting the money. The second? Thou shalt demonstrate a wide vocabulary. You didn’t just ‘walk’; you ‘strode purposefully’, ‘trudged wearily’, or ‘ambled nonchalantly’. You didn’t just ‘see’ a thing; you ‘beheld a magnificent spectacle’. Our exercise books were filled with lists of these “wow words,” their synonyms and antonyms drilled into us like multiplication tables.&lt;p&gt;Well, this is very interesting, because I'm a native English speaker that studied writing in university, and the deeper I got into the world of literature, the further I was pushed towards simpler language and shorter sentences. It's all Hemingway now, and if I spot an adverb or, lord forbid, a "proceeded to," I feel the pain in my bones.&lt;p&gt;The way ChatGPT writes drives me insane. As for the author, clearly they're very good, but I prefer a much simpler style. I feel like the big boy SAT words should pop out of the page unaccompanied, just one per page at most.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 13:11:24 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46274042</link><dc:creator>komali2</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46274042</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46274042</guid></item><item><title>New comment by mort96 in "I'm Kenyan. I don't write like ChatGPT, ChatGPT writes like me"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&gt; I even checked one of his responses in WhatsApp if it's AI by asking the Meta AI whether it's AI written, and Meta AI also agreed that it's AI written&lt;p&gt;I will never understand why some people apparently think asking a chat bot whether text was written by a chat bot is a reasonable approach to determining whether text was written by a chat bot.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 12:55:22 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46273888</link><dc:creator>mort96</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46273888</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46273888</guid></item><item><title>New comment by kqr in "Roomba maker goes bankrupt, Chinese owner emerges"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Our household (and I suspect many with us) bought a Roomba specifically to not give the Chinese government a roving camera in our home. Ouch!&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 12:40:19 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46273716</link><dc:creator>kqr</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46273716</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46273716</guid></item><item><title>New comment by cs702 in "Roomba maker goes bankrupt, Chinese owner emerges"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;According to the Financial Times, Roomba has sold more than 40 million robotic devices, most of them robotic vacuum cleaners.[a]&lt;p&gt;Many of those vacuum cleaners have cameras, can move around on their own, and are connected to the Internet. If they're taken offline, they stop working. Many have microphones too.&lt;p&gt;The new Chinese owner will get control of a network of tens of millions Internet-connected, autonomously mobile, camera/microphone-equipped robots already inside people's homes and offices.&lt;p&gt;More than 40 million &lt;i&gt;is a lot&lt;/i&gt;. For comparison, the US has ~132 million households.&lt;p&gt;---&lt;p&gt;[a] &lt;a href="https://www.ft.com/content/239d4720-aee4-443d-a761-1bd8bb1a1923" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://www.ft.com/content/239d4720-aee4-443d-a761-1bd8bb1a1...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 12:08:11 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46273432</link><dc:creator>cs702</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46273432</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46273432</guid></item><item><title>New comment by vintermann in "Avoid UUID Version 4 Primary Keys in Postgres"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;A prime example of premature optimization.&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Permanent identifiers should not carry data&lt;/i&gt;. This is like the cardinal sin of data management. You always run into situations where the thing you thought, "surely this never changes, so it's safe to squeeze into the ID to save a lookup". Then people suddenly find out they have a new gender identity, and they need a last final digit in their ID numbers too.&lt;p&gt;Even if nothing changes, you can run into trouble. Norwegian PNs have your birth date (in DDMMYY format) as the first six digits. Surely that doesn't change, right? Well, wrong, since although the date doesn't change, your knowledge of it might. Immigrants who didn't know their exact date of birth got assigned 1. Jan by default... And then people with actual birthdays on 1 Jan got told, "sorry, you can't have that as birth date, we've run out of numbers in that series!"&lt;p&gt;Librarians in the analog age can be forgiven for cramming data into their identifiers, to save a lookup. When the lookup is in a physical card catalog, that's somewhat understandable (although you bet they could run into trouble over it too). But when you have a powerful database at your fingertips, use it! Don't make decisions you will regret just to shave off a couple of milliseconds!&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 12:02:03 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46273383</link><dc:creator>vintermann</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46273383</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46273383</guid></item><item><title>New comment by doener in "If AI replaces workers, should it also pay taxes?"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;No, not the AI. Just the owner
of means of production like AI.&lt;p&gt;The fact that capital owners successfully avoid contributing to the financing of our states and social systems is, in my view, one of the fundamental problems of our time.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 10:08:17 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46272492</link><dc:creator>doener</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46272492</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46272492</guid></item><item><title>New comment by benzible in "AI agents are starting to eat SaaS"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I'm CTO at a vertical SaaS company, paired with a product-focused CEO with deep domain expertise. The thesis doesn't match my experience.&lt;p&gt;For one thing, the threat model assumes customers can build their own tools. Our end users can't. Their current "system" is Excel. The big enterprises that employ them have thousands of devs, but two of them explicitly cloned our product and tried to poach their own users onto it. One gave up. The other's users tell us it's crap. We've lost zero paying subscribers to free internal alternatives.&lt;p&gt;I believe that agents are a multiplier on existing velocity, not an equalizer. We use agents heavily and ship faster than ever. We get a lot of feedback from users as to what the internal tech teams are shipping and based on this there's little evidence of any increase in velocity from them.&lt;p&gt;The bottleneck is still knowing what to build, not building. A lot of the value in our product is in decisions users don't even know we made for them. Domain expertise + tight feedback loop with users can't be replicated by an internal developer in an afternoon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 07:45:57 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46271523</link><dc:creator>benzible</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46271523</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46271523</guid></item><item><title>New comment by simonjgreen in "Roomba maker goes bankrupt, Chinese owner emerges"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;This is the cost of complacency. They were ahead for so long then the likes of Roborock just left them in the dirt. I remember the first time I tried one of the Roborock devices, and until then I have been a long time Roomba user (like, 20 years). I just couldn’t believe how much better it was. And iRobot just stubbornly refused to iterate on their fundamental products.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 07:38:01 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46271463</link><dc:creator>simonjgreen</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46271463</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46271463</guid></item><item><title>New comment by palcu in "Elevated errors across many models"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Hello, I'm one of the engineers who worked on the incident. We have mitigated the incident as of 14:43 PT / 22:43 UTC. Sorry for the trouble.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 14 Dec 2025 22:56:34 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46268013</link><dc:creator>palcu</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46268013</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46268013</guid></item></channel></rss>