<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>Hacker News: Best Comments</title><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/bestcomments</link><description>Hacker News RSS</description><docs>https://hnrss.org/</docs><generator>hnrss v2.1.1</generator><lastBuildDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2025 00:22:37 +0000</lastBuildDate><ns0:link href="https://hnrss.org/bestcomments" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item><title>New comment by jrockway in "Let's Not Encrypt (2019)"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I think that if we didn't do TLS, every ISP would be injecting ads into websites these days.  Making it difficult for middle-of-the-road interlopers is a good thing. ISPs don't want the customer service burden of proxy configurations and custom certs (god knows your IT department hates the support aspect of this tampering), so TLS keeps us free of excessive advertising.  (Of course, they like do tampering with DNS which is why we have to do DNS-over-HTTPS. If you make it easy to tamper with your traffic, your ISP has a good business case to tamper with your traffic.  Sad but true.)&lt;p&gt;I'm not as convinced as the author is that nation states can easily tamper with certificates these days.  I am not sure how much CT checking we do before each page load, but either nation states are compelling the issue of certs that aren't in the CT database, or they are and you can just get a list of who the nation states are spying on.  Seems like less of a problem than it was a decade ago.&lt;p&gt;The author seems to miss the one guarantee that certificates provide; "the same people that controlled this site on $ISSUANCE_DATE control the site right now".  That can be a useful guarantee.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2025 14:11:15 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45580233</link><dc:creator>jrockway</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45580233</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45580233</guid></item><item><title>New comment by sgarland in "Why is everything so scalable?"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;THANK YOU. People look at me like I’m insane when I tell them that their overly-complicated pipeline could be easily handled by a couple of beefy servers. Or at best, they’ll argue that “this way, they don’t have to manage infrastructure.” Except you do - you absolutely do. It’s just been partially abstracted away, and some parts like OS maintenance are handled (not that that was ever the difficult part of managing servers), but you absolutely need to configure and monitor your specific XaaS you’re renting.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2025 12:55:19 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45579468</link><dc:creator>sgarland</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45579468</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45579468</guid></item><item><title>New comment by BirAdam in "Why is everything so scalable?"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Just to be honest for a bit here... we also should be asking what kind of scale?&lt;p&gt;Quite a while ago, before containers were a thing at all, I did systems for some very large porn companies. They were doing streaming video at scale before most, and the only other people working on video at that scale were Youtube.&lt;p&gt;The general setup for the largest players in that space was haproxy in front of nginx in front of several PHP servers in front of a MySQL database that had one primary r/w with one read only replica. Storage (at that time) was usually done with glusterfs. This was scalable enough at the time for hundreds of thousands of concurrent users, though the video quality was quite a bit lower than what people expect today.&lt;p&gt;Today at AWS, it is easily possible for people to spend a multiple of the cost of that hardware setup every month for far less compute power and storage.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2025 12:35:50 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45579298</link><dc:creator>BirAdam</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45579298</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45579298</guid></item><item><title>New comment by frameset in "KDE celebrates the 29th birthday and kicks off the yearly fundraiser"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I'm absolutely loving KDE since I returned to desktop Linux after a long absence.&lt;p&gt;What really shocks me is how few of the big distros make KDE a default or "first class" DE choice. If I was a novice user coming from Windows, I'd much prefer KDE, which if you stick to the GUI is very navigable and similar in some ways.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2025 11:34:46 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45578777</link><dc:creator>frameset</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45578777</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45578777</guid></item><item><title>New comment by daan-k in "Dutch government takes control of Chinese-owned chipmaker Nexperia"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Some new information has just emerged in the Dutch press.&lt;p&gt;According to a just published article by the NRC newspaper [0], the owner wanted to use Nexperia's funds to finance another business (WingSkySemi) which was in financial trouble. He would have done this by making Nexperia place large orders for wafers it did not need. The article mentions Nexperia only requiring $70-80 million in wafers, while Nexperia would have ordered wafers from WingSkySemi with a value of $200 million.&lt;p&gt;In order to achieve this, the owner is said to have put strawmen without financial experience in place and fire European directors. When other directors raised the alarm about this, they were fired according to the article.  
This issue was raised to the Dutch government, which then intervened.&lt;p&gt;Have a look at the original article through google translate, it provides a lot of interesting and important details to this story.&lt;p&gt;[0] &lt;a href="https://www.nrc.nl/nieuws/2025/10/14/chinese-topman-gebruikte-geld-van-nexperia-voor-zijn-chinese-chipfabriek-a4909538" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://www.nrc.nl/nieuws/2025/10/14/chinese-topman-gebruikt...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2025 10:48:27 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45578443</link><dc:creator>daan-k</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45578443</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45578443</guid></item><item><title>New comment by perching_aix in "New York Times, AP, Newsmax and others say they won't sign new Pentagon rules"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&gt; Chief Pentagon spokesman Sean Parnell said (...) "This has caused reporters to have a full blown meltdown, crying victim online."&lt;p&gt;Interesting use of language... seems like the mask is coming off everywhere now, not just where I live (Hungary).&lt;p&gt;I've been intentionally skipping on a lot of our local political reporting, so I was really quite surprised to see recently how lowbrow the language used by politicians, specifically those in power, has gotten these days. Especially how flagrant they are about it too.&lt;p&gt;This &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; a very meta, and to many I'm sure trivial, thing to take issue with, yes, but if those in authority are this unashamedly drunk on power, and look down on those they rule over so openly, I'd really question how fit they are to represent people's collective best interest.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2025 10:18:47 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45578256</link><dc:creator>perching_aix</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45578256</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45578256</guid></item><item><title>New comment by varun_chopra in "Why the push for Agentic when models can barely follow a simple instruction?"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Marketing is being done really well in 2025, with brands injecting themselves into conversations on Reddit, LinkedIn, and every other public forum. [1]&lt;p&gt;CEOs, AI "thought leaders," and VCs are advertising LLMs as magic, and tools like v0 and Lovable as the next big thing. Every response from leaders is some variation of &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=w61d-NBqafM" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=w61d-NBqafM&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;On the ground, we know that creating CLAUDE.md or cursorrules basically does nothing. It’s up to the LLM to follow instructions, and it does so based on RNG as far as I can tell. I have very simple, basic rules set up that are never followed. This leads me to believe everyone posting on that thread on Cursor is an amateur.&lt;p&gt;Beyond this, if you’re working on novel code, LLMs are absolutely horrible at doing anything. A lot of assumptions are made, non-existent libraries are used, and agents are just great at using tokens to generate no tangible result whatsoever.&lt;p&gt;I’m at a stage where I use LLMs the same way I would use speech-to-text (code) - telling the LLM exactly what I want, what files it should consider, and it adds _some_ value by thinking of edge cases I might’ve missed, best practices I’m unaware of, and writing better grammar than I do.&lt;p&gt;Edit:&lt;p&gt;[1] To add to this, any time you use search or Perplexity or what have you, the results come from all this marketing garbage being pumped into the internet by marketing teams.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2025 08:04:43 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45577405</link><dc:creator>varun_chopra</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45577405</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45577405</guid></item><item><title>New comment by vayup in "Don’t Look Up: Sensitive internal links in the clear on GEO satellites [pdf]"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Some of the stuff that was extracted from the unencrypted traffic in the link:&lt;p&gt;- T-Mobile backhaul: Users' SMS, voice call contents and internet traffic content in plain text.&lt;p&gt;- AT&amp;T Mexico cellular backhaul: Raw user internet traffic&lt;p&gt;- TelMex VOIP on satellite backhaul: Plaintext voice calls&lt;p&gt;- U.S. military: SIP traffic exposing ship names&lt;p&gt;- Mexico government and military: Unencrypted intra-government traffic&lt;p&gt;- Walmart Mexico: Unencrypted corporate emails, plaintext credentials to inventory management systems, inventory records transferred and updated using FTP&lt;p&gt;This is insane!&lt;p&gt;While it is important to work on futuristic threats such as Quantum cryptanalysis, backdoors in standardized cryptographic protocols, etc. - the unfortunate reality is that the vast majority of real-world attacks happen because basic protection is not enabled. Good reminder not take our eyes off the basics.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2025 04:57:13 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45576404</link><dc:creator>vayup</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45576404</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45576404</guid></item><item><title>New comment by lkey in "New York Times, AP, Newsmax and others say they won't sign new Pentagon rules"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;It's a great thing they are not backing down. Given how many institutions have complied in advance, we need as many exemplars of better behaviour as possible.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2025 04:27:10 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45576255</link><dc:creator>lkey</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45576255</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45576255</guid></item><item><title>New comment by jampa in "Palisades Fire suspect's ChatGPT history to be used as evidence"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;The headline and article try to bias and frame the story to make people question: "Is OpenAI snitching on me?"&lt;p&gt;In reality, Uber records and conflicting statements incriminated him. He seems to be the one who provided the ChatGPT record to try to prove that the fire was unintentional.[1]&lt;p&gt;&gt; He was visibly anxious during that interview, according to the complaint. His efforts to call 911 and his question to ChatGPT about a cigarette lighting a fire indicated that he wanted to create a more innocent explanation for the fire's start and to show he tried to assist with suppression, the complaint said.&lt;p&gt;[1] &lt;a href="https://apnews.com/article/california-wildfires-palisades-los-angeles-deb1c78c1d83d233cf3b540644814ea2" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://apnews.com/article/california-wildfires-palisades-lo...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2025 03:41:57 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45576039</link><dc:creator>jampa</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45576039</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45576039</guid></item><item><title>New comment by mikewarot in "America is getting an AI gold rush instead of a factory boom"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Having worked in a job shop, a factory that did gears down to quantity one, I became quite aware of the differences between IT, my previous job, and actual physical production.&lt;p&gt;The machine tools were all made 50+ years ago. Changing &lt;i&gt;anything&lt;/i&gt; was a dangerous thing to do, because you might cause jobs that have known and reliable setups that are done a few times a year in quantity, to fail, erasing the profits for the job, and possibly losing customers.&lt;p&gt;The rush to fill brand new high energy intensive data centers with hardware that has commercially useful lifetimes measured in months (instead of decades for machine tools) seems quite short sighted to me.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2025 03:21:00 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45575908</link><dc:creator>mikewarot</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45575908</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45575908</guid></item><item><title>New comment by aquova in "Sony PlayStation 2 fixing frenzy"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I've seen a few posters ask already, so I figured I'd answer what the PS2 analog button's function was.&lt;p&gt;The button switches between two modes of the analog joysticks, either to behave with their normal functionality, or to simply be a digital input (so just round all movement to either up/down/left/right). For PS2 games, you typically wouldn't want to do this. Instead, the functionality exists because the PS2 was backwards compatible with PS1 titles. The original PS1 controller didn't have analog sticks at all, just the D-Pad for navigation. After a few years (and the success of Nintendo's N64 analog controller) Sony released a revised version of the controller that included two joysticks, which their controllers still mimic to this day. However, those PS1 games released prior to the analog controller wouldn't always behave correctly if you tried to use an analog input scheme, so Sony added a mode to allow the Joysticks to function the same as the D-Pad, in case players preferred it.&lt;p&gt;Other fun fact, the analog controller was not the same as their more famous Dualshock controller. There was a short-lived PS1 Dual Analog controller which just added the joysticks. It only lasted a few months before Sony replaced it with one that supported rumble functionality (also after being inspired by the N64), this was the Dualshock.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2025 01:04:00 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45575097</link><dc:creator>aquova</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45575097</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45575097</guid></item><item><title>New comment by SchemaLoad in "NanoChat – The best ChatGPT that $100 can buy"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Everything is unless your app is a React todolist or leatcode questions.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 13 Oct 2025 22:42:33 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45574114</link><dc:creator>SchemaLoad</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45574114</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45574114</guid></item><item><title>New comment by bognition in "Uv overtakes pip in CI"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;This shouldn’t be a surprise to anyone who has been using Python and has tried uv.&lt;p&gt;Python dependency management and environments have been a pain for 15 years. Poetry was nice but slow and sometimes difficult.&lt;p&gt;Uv is lightning fast and damn easy to use. It’s so functional and simple.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 13 Oct 2025 22:41:03 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45574104</link><dc:creator>bognition</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45574104</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45574104</guid></item><item><title>New comment by gyomu in "NanoChat – The best ChatGPT that $100 can buy"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&gt; the repo is too far off the data distribution&lt;p&gt;ah, this explains why these models have been useless to me this whole time. everything i do is just too far off the data distribution!&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 13 Oct 2025 22:02:35 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45573816</link><dc:creator>gyomu</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45573816</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45573816</guid></item><item><title>New comment by itopaloglu83 in "Dutch government takes control of Chinese-owned chipmaker Nexperia"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Everybody is a fan of free access and capital markets, until a foreign entity purchases something of importance.&lt;p&gt;It’s a continuation of recent trends and closing markets.&lt;p&gt;Nobody in their sane mind would allow a company like ASML or the likes to be purchased by competitors.&lt;p&gt;But the irony is that when a non-European entity were to do something like this, e.g. nationalize their oil or mining etc. industry or a firm, the whole hell would brake loose.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 13 Oct 2025 21:51:46 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45573735</link><dc:creator>itopaloglu83</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45573735</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45573735</guid></item><item><title>New comment by tehnub in "NanoChat – The best ChatGPT that $100 can buy"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Interesting exchange on the use of AI coding tools:&lt;p&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;    curious how much did you write the code by hand of it?

    Karpathy: Good question, it's basically entirely hand-written (with tab autocomplete). I tried to use claude/codex agents a few times but they just didn't work well enough at all and net unhelpful, possibly the repo is too far off the data distribution.
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;a href="https://x.com/karpathy/status/1977758204139331904" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://x.com/karpathy/status/1977758204139331904&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 13 Oct 2025 21:26:58 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45573521</link><dc:creator>tehnub</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45573521</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45573521</guid></item><item><title>New comment by legitster in "America's future could hinge on whether AI slightly disappoints"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Anecdotally, our company's next couple quarters are projected to be a bloodbath. Spending is down everywhere, nearly all of our customers are pushing for huge cuts to their contracts, and in turn literally any costs we can jettison to keep jobs is being pushed through. We're hearing the same from our customers.&lt;p&gt;AI has been the only new investment our company has made (half hearted at that). I definitely get the sense that everyone pretending things are fine to investors, meanwhile they are playing musical chairs.&lt;p&gt;Back in my economics classes at college, a professor pointed out that a stock market can go up for two reasons: On one hand, the economy is legitimately growing and shares are becoming more valuable. But on the other hand, people and corporations could be cutting spending en masse so there's extra cash to flood the stock markets and drive up prices regardless of future earnings.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 13 Oct 2025 20:06:57 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45572772</link><dc:creator>legitster</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45572772</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45572772</guid></item><item><title>New comment by kswzzl in "Software update bricks some Jeep 4xe hybrids over the weekend"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;My 4xe died in my driveway on Saturday after the update. Let me explain, from the perspective of a 4xe owner, how bad the response has been from Jeep/Stellantis:&lt;p&gt;- As of Monday 8am ET, zero legitimate communication from any Jeep-related accounts on any social media platform, or any other form of acknowledgement from the company (unless I've missed something?)&lt;p&gt;- I only found out about the issue after finally searching a few Jeep groups on Facebook (of all places) to see if anyone else was experiencing the weird failure mode I was after the update.&lt;p&gt;- The only remotely-official info was from a 'JeepCares' account (which is ran by Jeep) on some random off-roading forum? We were seriously all living off of screenshots from this forum, and the advice coming from the JeepCares accounts was contradictory: they claimed that the Uconnect update was separate from the telematics update, and that there was no way to stop the telematics update if the vehicle received it. Later they gave advice to defer the Uconnect update, making it sound like they were coupled.&lt;p&gt;- Due to the lack of info from Jeep, people were coming up with all kinds of "if you reboot Uconnect while the Jeep's in ACC mode, it clears the check engine light". This probably did clear the CEL but didn't fix the fault.&lt;p&gt;- There is no way to tell if you received the bad update.&lt;p&gt;- There is no way to tell if you received the 'fix' either.&lt;p&gt;- Dealerships have literally no idea what is going on.&lt;p&gt;- You're basically at risk of your Jeep going limp (power loss, unable to safely make it to the shoulder) and being stranded on the highway, even as I write this.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 13 Oct 2025 16:34:51 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45570343</link><dc:creator>kswzzl</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45570343</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45570343</guid></item><item><title>New comment by jim201 in "Android's sideloading limits are its most anti-consumer move"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Antitrust action is badly needed in this area. It is ridiculous that I need permission from my device manufacturer to install software on hardware I own. There is no viable alternative than to live in Apple and Google’s ecosystems. This duopoly cannot be allowed to keep this much control of the mobile platforms.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 13 Oct 2025 16:34:15 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45570331</link><dc:creator>jim201</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45570331</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45570331</guid></item><item><title>New comment by HiPhish in "Android's sideloading limits are its most anti-consumer move"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;We need to stop calling it "sideloading", we should call it freely installing software. The term "sideloading" makes it sound shady and hacky when in reality it is what we have been able to do on our computers since forever. These are not phones, they are computers shaped like phones, computer which we fully bought with our money, and I we shall install what we want on our own computers.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 13 Oct 2025 16:27:27 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45570232</link><dc:creator>HiPhish</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45570232</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45570232</guid></item><item><title>New comment by itg in "Android's sideloading limits are its most anti-consumer move"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Installing any app I want outside the Play Store was the primary reason I decided to go with Android, despite most of the people I know using iPhones. If I can't do this anymore, I may as well switch and be able to use iMessage and FaceTime with them.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 13 Oct 2025 16:13:33 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45570037</link><dc:creator>itg</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45570037</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45570037</guid></item><item><title>New comment by MountDoom in "Smartphones and being present"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I always felt that I'm spending too much time in front of a computer, but it was at least somewhat meaningful because I had opportunities to create: write code, blog, and so on.&lt;p&gt;When smartphones came out, I made a decision early on that I'm just not going to use them in a way that makes my internet footprint follow me everywhere I go. I set them up using a throwaway email account, turned off almost all notifications, and added just family and real-world friends. I think this served me well for nearly two decades. I really only use my phone for maps, photos, and maybe 2-5 messages a day. I honestly never found myself in a situation where I thought to myself, "gosh, I wish I could read my e-mail right now".&lt;p&gt;But in the past five years, there's been this mounting pressure from app vendors to make sure I can no longer enjoy that. Every other time a friend sends me a web link, I get a popup that detects I'm on mobile and demands I install an app. And they increasingly can't be dismissed, so if I want to view that URL, I need to mail it to myself and open it on a desktop.&lt;p&gt;If you work for a place that does that, I just hope you stub your toe every morning.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 13 Oct 2025 15:44:38 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45569646</link><dc:creator>MountDoom</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45569646</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45569646</guid></item><item><title>New comment by twobitshifter in "No science, no startups: The innovation engine we're switching off"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Not why it can’t be done so much as why it isn’t done. Share buybacks allow companies to reward executives directly as their compensation is tied to stock price. If we started not doing that, the priorities might shift, but those executives like things the way they are.&lt;p&gt;Before Tim Cook Apple had never done a buyback - Jobs was always thinking Apple could do better with the money in R&amp;D than paying off shareholders. Wall Street did not approve of this position, but Jobs wasn’t one to listen to anybody, so it did not matter. Most CEOs are not going to take such a strong position when they, the stockholders, and every other executive can be guaranteed a financial reward through a buyback.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 13 Oct 2025 15:38:44 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45569567</link><dc:creator>twobitshifter</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45569567</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45569567</guid></item><item><title>New comment by graypegg in "Smartphones and being present"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&gt; The first way is to not have recommendation media (think Instagram, TikTok, and all the rest). I'm pro deleting these accounts completely, because it's really easy to re-download the apps on a whim, or *visit them in-browser.*&lt;p&gt;Tiktok having a borderline unusable web app has done wonders for me. I'll end up on it because someone sent me a link, I can watch that ONE video, a single time, before normally I get a spot-the-boat style captcha or an "install the app" modal. Even trying to get past that point, it feels like the site is somehow falling apart at the seams as you navigate around. I know the concept is "well people will install the app then" but that's also annoyingly frictionful.&lt;p&gt;They unintentionally made the most literal social media experience: some one sends me media, I watch it once, I leave before the site crumbles to pieces like an ancient tomb that was only held together by a load-bearing dog video.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 13 Oct 2025 15:13:30 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45569230</link><dc:creator>graypegg</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45569230</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45569230</guid></item><item><title>New comment by terminalshort in "No science, no startups: The innovation engine we're switching off"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&gt; In the 20th century, U.S. companies put their excess profits into corporate research labs. Basic research in the U.S. was done in at Dupont, Bell Labs, IBM, AT&amp;T, Xerox, Kodak, GE, et al. This changed in 1982, when the Securities and Exchange Commission ruled that it was legal for companies to buy their own stock (reducing the number of shares available to the public and inflating their stock price.) Very quickly Basic Science in corporate research all but disappeared. Companies focused on Applied Research to maximize shareholder value. In its place, Theory and Basic research is now done in research universities.&lt;p&gt;I'm not seeing how you get from share buybacks to a shift in priorities in corporate research.  If there's a fundamental reason why it can't be done now how it was before the 80's it's not that.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 13 Oct 2025 15:06:06 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45569133</link><dc:creator>terminalshort</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45569133</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45569133</guid></item><item><title>New comment by 0x37 in "Modern Linux tools"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;These may be objectively superior (I haven't tested), but I have come to realize (like so many others) that if you ever change your OS installation, set up VMs, or SSH anywhere, preferring these is just an uphill battle that never ends. I don't want to have to set these up in every new environment I operate in, or even use a mix of these on my personal computer and the traditional ones elsewhere.&lt;p&gt;Learn the classic tools, learn them well, and your life will be much easier.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 13 Oct 2025 11:35:54 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45567223</link><dc:creator>0x37</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45567223</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45567223</guid></item><item><title>New comment by wolvesechoes in "Free software hasn't won"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I am baffled that people in this thread write something along "well, depends what you call &lt;i&gt;win&lt;/i&gt;" - the goal of Free Software is quite clear. The goal is freedom, computing freedom, freedom of the software user. It is very easy to notice that in 2025 users have less freedom even if they run some Libre Linux distro on their Thinkpads than they had running Win98, because of everything that happens OUTSIDE PC software ecosystem (phones, SaaS etc), and even inside PC world things sometimes are not obvious.&lt;p&gt;Free Software is losing, simple as that. Even with Kubernetes, as the goal was never to provide free labor and free software infra to companies.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 13 Oct 2025 07:50:38 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45565847</link><dc:creator>wolvesechoes</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45565847</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45565847</guid></item><item><title>New comment by Doxin in "Dutch government takes control of Chinese-owned chipmaker Nexperia"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Some more context from a dutch news source[0]:&lt;p&gt;The ministry of economic affairs intervened out of a fear that crucial technological skills and capacities will leave the Netherlands and Europe. The ministry stated in a press release[1] that there was a threat of a "knowledge leak" (w/e that means exactly) and a possible threat to the European economy.&lt;p&gt;After this intervention the Dutch government can now stop or reverse decisions within the company. That's only allowed if those decisions are harmful to the interests of the company, or for the future of the company as a Dutch or European business, or to the retaining of this crucial value chain for europe.&lt;p&gt;The company can appeal this decision in court.&lt;p&gt;For context, the law that allows this all to happen was passed in 1952 and has never before been used. As much as I think our government is currently ran by a bunch of nincompoops, I am inclined to believe that something &lt;i&gt;quite&lt;/i&gt; significant was about to happen for this law to get invoked. What exactly that was can for now only be speculated about.&lt;p&gt;I can recommend you run google translate (or equivalent) on the press release. It's as close as you can get to the source of this news for now. I can only imagine the government is going to be having plenty of debates on the topic coming up, seeing as this is a &lt;i&gt;very&lt;/i&gt; rare use of a &lt;i&gt;very&lt;/i&gt; heavy-handed tool.&lt;p&gt;[0] &lt;a href="https://nos.nl/artikel/2586270-kabinet-grijpt-hard-in-bij-chipfabrikant-nexperia" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://nos.nl/artikel/2586270-kabinet-grijpt-hard-in-bij-ch...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;[1] &lt;a href="https://www.rijksoverheid.nl/actueel/nieuws/2025/10/12/wet-beschikbaarheid-goederen-ingezet-door-minister-van-economische-zaken" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://www.rijksoverheid.nl/actueel/nieuws/2025/10/12/wet-b...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 13 Oct 2025 07:41:49 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45565790</link><dc:creator>Doxin</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45565790</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45565790</guid></item><item><title>New comment by azianmike in "Ask HN: What are you working on? (October 2025)"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;A couple of months ago, I saw a tweet from @awilkinson: “I just found out how much we pay for DocuSign and my jaw dropped. What's the best alternative?”&lt;p&gt;Me being naive, I thought “how hard could would it actually be to build a free e-sign tool?”&lt;p&gt;Turns out not that hard.&lt;p&gt;In about a weekend, I built a UETA and ESIGN compliant tool. And it was free. And it cost me less than $50. Unlimited free e-sign. &lt;a href="https://useinkless.com/" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://useinkless.com/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 13 Oct 2025 03:51:57 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45564517</link><dc:creator>azianmike</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45564517</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45564517</guid></item></channel></rss>