<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>Hacker News: Best Comments</title><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/bestcomments</link><description>Hacker News RSS</description><docs>https://hnrss.org/</docs><generator>hnrss v2.1.1</generator><lastBuildDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 23:59:50 +0000</lastBuildDate><ns0:link href="https://hnrss.org/bestcomments" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item><title>New comment by _fat_santa in "Nvidia Stock Crash Prediction"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;This article goes more into the technical analysis of the stock rather than the underlying business fundamentals that would lead to a stock dump.&lt;p&gt;My 30k ft view is that the stock will inevitably slide as AI datacenter spending goes down. Right now Nvidia is flying high because datacenters are breaking ground everywhere but eventually that will come to an end as the supply of compute goes up.&lt;p&gt;The counterargument to this is that the "economic lifespan" of an Nvidia GPU is 1-3 years depending on where it's used so there's a case to be made that Nvidia will always have customers coming back for the latest and greatest chips. The problem I have with this argument is that it's simply unsustainable to be spending that much every 2-3 years and we're already seeing this as Google and others are extending their depreciation of GPU's to something like 5-7 years.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 16:41:19 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46693996</link><dc:creator>_fat_santa</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46693996</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46693996</guid></item><item><title>New comment by touwer in "De-dollarization: Is the US dollar losing its dominance? (2025)"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;The US century is already over. It's just that a lot of US citizens don't see that. De-dollarization will happen when one is a traitor to it's allies&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 16:34:43 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46693885</link><dc:creator>touwer</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46693885</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46693885</guid></item><item><title>New comment by snovymgodym in "De-dollarization: Is the US dollar losing its dominance? (2025)"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;The international value of the dollar as a reserve and trade currency is inherently tied to the behavior of the US Government and the Federal Reserve.&lt;p&gt;The behavior of the US Government has been very unusual lately, and the independence of the Federal Reserve is actively being challenged.&lt;p&gt;So draw from that whatever conclusions you wish.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 16:21:50 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46693662</link><dc:creator>snovymgodym</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46693662</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46693662</guid></item><item><title>New comment by jacquesm in "De-dollarization: Is the US dollar losing its dominance? (2025)"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;It's not losing it so much as that it is being destroyed on purpose.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 16:20:22 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46693638</link><dc:creator>jacquesm</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46693638</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46693638</guid></item><item><title>New comment by azinman2 in "Danish pension fund divesting US Treasuries"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;You’re assuming the people in charge are sane, rationale, and value past decisions that have worked out. It’s quite clear with the now likely permanent damage to NATO this isn’t the case.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 16:11:25 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46693478</link><dc:creator>azinman2</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46693478</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46693478</guid></item><item><title>New comment by alphazard in "Danish pension fund divesting US Treasuries"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&gt; It's symbolism.&lt;p&gt;It's not.  This is where the financial rubber meets the road, actions have consequences, and the rest of the world is looking at the US as increasingly unlikely to pay above inflation on its debts.&lt;p&gt;The people managing the pension funds (if they are acting in good faith) really want to generate yield, and really want to preserve capital for the Danish people.
They don't want to symbolically do those things, they want to actually do them.
If treasuries were still part of what they believe to be the best strategy, they would still be holding them.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 16:02:11 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46693319</link><dc:creator>alphazard</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46693319</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46693319</guid></item><item><title>New comment by afavour in "Danish pension fund divesting US Treasuries"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;It's symbolism. But it's important symbolism. Far more notable, I think, is Macron saying this morning that Europe needs more investment from China. Canada signing a deal with China to allow their cars to be sold in the country.&lt;p&gt;It's all a sliding slope until it reaches a breaking point and falls off like a cliff.&lt;p&gt;EDIT: to quote the Canadian PN earlier today:&lt;p&gt;“American hegemony in particular helped provide public goods, a stable financial system... this bargain no longer works. Let me be direct. We are in the midst of a rupture, not a transition... recently, great powers have begun using economic integration as a weapon. Tariffs as leverage ..."&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 15:49:44 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46693087</link><dc:creator>afavour</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46693087</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46693087</guid></item><item><title>New comment by n4r9 in "I'm addicted to being useful"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I frame it not as turning a dial down, but as switching channel from practical problem-solver to emotional problem-solver.&lt;p&gt;Often when someone wants to talk about a situation involving difficult feelings, they're actually trying to process those feelings: to understand where the feelings are coming from, to be validated, and to be able to take a broader perspective.&lt;p&gt;You can help by being curious about what they're saying, reflecting it back to them in your own terms, explaining how what they're feeling is understandable, and offering context or alternative viewpoints. These are actually complex problem-solving skills, although they can all fall under the umbrella of what people mean when they say "to be heard".&lt;p&gt;As a man, I've realised that once my emotions feel validated and accepted, I relax and the practical solutions just pop into my mind.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 13:08:33 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46691435</link><dc:creator>n4r9</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46691435</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46691435</guid></item><item><title>New comment by tclancy in "I'm addicted to being useful"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&gt;  I don’t mind the ways in which my job is dysfunctional, because it matches the ways in which I myself am dysfunctional&lt;p&gt;As a fellow traveller, I offer one caution: learn to turn this down in personal relationships as it can be counterproductive. It took decades for my wife to finally get through and explain not every problem she voices is something that needs a solution. Some times people just want to be heard. It bugs the hell out of me because I tend to need to solve All The Problems before I can do any self-care, but rather than seem heroic, I think this attitude can seem transactional or uncaring as though everyone is just a screw that needed a bit of tightening, etc.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 12:39:18 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46691196</link><dc:creator>tclancy</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46691196</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46691196</guid></item><item><title>New comment by knallfrosch in "Giving university exams in the age of chatbots"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I don't understand.&lt;p&gt;10 years ago, we wrote exams by hand with whatever we understood (in our heads.)&lt;p&gt;No colleagues, no laptops, no internet, no LLMs.&lt;p&gt;This approach still works, why do something else? Unless you're specifically testing a student's ability to Google, they don't need access to it.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 09:39:11 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46689873</link><dc:creator>knallfrosch</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46689873</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46689873</guid></item><item><title>New comment by thecupisblue in "Prediction markets are ushering in a world in which news becomes about gambling"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Not just America, everything is.
With stock market, at least we can somehow stop the bad actors, insider traders, corporate manipulation, pumps and dumps - with prediction markets, there is no way.&lt;p&gt;With prediction markets? Next to impossible. The markets being tied to crypto makes it even worse - things get harder to track, jurisdictions get blurry, proving becomes a ping pong between bureaucracy. And proving something becomes moreso a question of free will - if I decided to do X and then someone bets millon dollars on me doing X when odds are low, how do you prove I haven't decided to do X before? Will you prevent me from exercising my free will because of suspect insider trading? What if I am a president/senator?&lt;p&gt;Years ago, I was a kid who discovered online betting - often it was the only time I could place bets on MMA events, especially because it wasn't as popular as it is now. Even then, the gambling sites had "Other" options where you could bet on presidents, popes, landing on mars etc. The new markets aren't that much different, but are just using a nicer way to talk about it.&lt;p&gt;It isn't gambling, it's prediction.&lt;p&gt;You aren't a gambler, you're a "hyperinformed high iq individual predicting the geopolitical moves". Just like crypto gave people the identity crutch of a "tech investor", this gives them the identity crutch of a "geopolitical strategist".&lt;p&gt;But in the end, it is still just gambling - wrapped in a nice ego stroking suit, but gambling none the less.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 09:09:47 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46689641</link><dc:creator>thecupisblue</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46689641</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46689641</guid></item><item><title>New comment by melenaboija in "Porsche sold more electrified cars in Europe in 2025 than pure gas-powered cars"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&gt; Then I think you see an early indication not just of electric car dominance, but of the (very potential) rise of China as the premier automotive super power.&lt;p&gt;It’s done man. Americans are stuck in ICE engines because they’ve been told they’re “car enthusiasts” while the Chinese have been developing EV technology for years. Meanwhile, European makers are stuck not knowing what to do, make Americans happy or compete with the Chinese. The result: nothing has been done properly. And let’s be real, “car enthusiasts” are going to disappear in one or two generations. Practicality beats enthusiasm for 95% of car use.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 03:55:38 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46687749</link><dc:creator>melenaboija</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46687749</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46687749</guid></item><item><title>New comment by cweagans in "Fix macOS 26 (Tahoe) exaggerated rounded corners"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Your GitHub repo and the associated medium article do a great job of describing the problem and the solution that you settled on. I don’t understand why you didn’t include a screenshot of what this looks like though. The suitability of your tool depends on what it looks like.&lt;p&gt;Please, always include screenshots in open source projects that are aesthetic in nature.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 20:35:19 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46684148</link><dc:creator>cweagans</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46684148</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46684148</guid></item><item><title>New comment by WmWsjA6B29B4nfk in "Fix your robots.txt or your site disappears from Google"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Google docs are pretty clear (&lt;a href="https://developers.google.com/crawling/docs/robots-txt/robots-txt-spec" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://developers.google.com/crawling/docs/robots-txt/robot...&lt;/a&gt;):&lt;p&gt;&gt; Google's crawlers treat all 4xx errors, except 429, as if a valid robots.txt file didn't exist. This means that Google assumes that there are no crawl restrictions.&lt;p&gt;This is a better source than a random SEO dude with a channel full of AI-generated videos.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 19:52:23 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46683634</link><dc:creator>WmWsjA6B29B4nfk</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46683634</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46683634</guid></item><item><title>New comment by qntty in "Letter from a Birmingham Jail (1963)"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&gt; Sometimes a law is just on its face and unjust in its application. For instance, I have been arrested on a charge of parading without a permit. Now, there is nothing wrong in having an ordinance which requires a permit for a parade. But such an ordinance becomes unjust when it is used to maintain segregation and to deny citizens the First-Amendment privilege of peaceful assembly and protest.&lt;p&gt;&gt; I hope you are able to see the distinction I am trying to point out. In no sense do I advocate evading or defying the law, as would the rabid segregationist. That would lead to anarchy. One who breaks an unjust law must do so openly, lovingly, and with a willingness to accept the penalty. I submit that an individual who breaks a law that conscience tells him is unjust, and who willingly accepts the penalty of imprisonment in order to arouse the conscience of the community over its injustice, is in reality expressing the highest respect for law.&lt;p&gt;I always have to go back to read this part again because I feel like it's so unexpected. You don't really hear anyone saying quite the same thing today.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 19:32:50 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46683399</link><dc:creator>qntty</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46683399</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46683399</guid></item><item><title>New comment by steve1977 in "What came first: the CNAME or the A record?"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I don't find the wording in the RFC to be that ambiguous actually.&lt;p&gt;&gt; The answer to the query, possibly preface by one or more CNAME RRs that specify aliases encountered on the way to an answer.&lt;p&gt;The "possibly preface" (sic!) to me is obviously to be understood as "if there are any CNAME RRs, the answer to the query is to be prefaced by those CNAME RRs" and not "you can preface the query with the CNAME RRs or you can place them wherever you want".&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 18:46:28 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46682857</link><dc:creator>steve1977</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46682857</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46682857</guid></item><item><title>New comment by mdasen in "Apple testing new App Store design that blurs the line between ads and results"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;This is what basically everyone else has done over the past decade. Google used to put a different background behind ads in its search (&lt;a href="https://www.fsedigital.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/11/Google-results-page-in-2013.png" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://www.fsedigital.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/11/Google...&lt;/a&gt;). It made it really easy to tell what was an ad and skip over it quickly. Now it's a lot harder to quickly notice what's an ad and what isn't.&lt;p&gt;Sites used to have banner ads. Now they show posts that look exactly like the organic posts in your feed, just with a small "sponsored", "promoted", or "ad" mark somewhere. Half the time the post is large enough that it takes up my entire screen and the "sponsored" mark is below and off-screen.&lt;p&gt;If you go on Amazon, the "sponsored" text is much smaller and light gray rgb(87,89,89) while the product text is near-black rgb(15,17,17). They want to make the sponsored text less visible. Sometimes it's even unclear if the sponsored tag applies to a single product or a group of products.&lt;p&gt;It's shocking that Apple hasn't done this trick yet when everyone else started doing it years ago.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 17:27:00 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46681806</link><dc:creator>mdasen</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46681806</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46681806</guid></item><item><title>New comment by yomismoaqui in "Apple testing new App Store design that blurs the line between ads and results"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Can we use "ensheetification" to describe this phenomeon? (sure I'm not the first to use this word)&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 17:10:01 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46681537</link><dc:creator>yomismoaqui</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46681537</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46681537</guid></item><item><title>New comment by atonse in "Apple testing new App Store design that blurs the line between ads and results"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;More and more evidence that the a-holes with spreadsheets are taking over at Apple and they’re completely devoid of any ideas on the software side.&lt;p&gt;I heard someone randomly say that they should replace Tim Cook with Scott Forstall. I chuckled at the idea but this might be a great idea.&lt;p&gt;Apple is having its Ballmer moment. Google did too before AI lit the fire under their feet.&lt;p&gt;Who is going to be Apple’s next Nadella? Steve Jobs was the original.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 17:00:52 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46681411</link><dc:creator>atonse</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46681411</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46681411</guid></item><item><title>New comment by bartread in "American importers and consumers bear the cost of 2025 tariffs: analysis"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I'm glad they've done the work here and put a figure on it - the impact absolutely needed to be quantified - but I also have to say... to the surprise of absolutely no-one with even the most basic grasp of how economies function.&lt;p&gt;People, lots of people, lots of people who have a really deep understanding of national and global economics (unlike me), have been warning about this since talk of tariffs became common currency a year ago.&lt;p&gt;I wouldn't like to comment on HN's political leanings in the round and, obviously, there are a large portion of non-US readers/commenters on the site (including me), but will say this: there are a portion of you who voted for this. Exactly this.&lt;p&gt;What were you thinking? What was going through your heads? I'm genuinely curious.&lt;p&gt;EDIT: Wow... well, having asked the question, it looks like I now have a &lt;i&gt;lot&lt;/i&gt; of answers and perspectives to read. Thank you all for taking the time to comment.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 16:12:22 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46680616</link><dc:creator>bartread</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46680616</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46680616</guid></item><item><title>New comment by modeless in "A decentralized peer-to-peer messaging application that operates over Bluetooth"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;It's criminal that cell phones are bristling with incredibly advanced radio technology and yet they are by law not allowed to communicate directly with each other over a distance of more than a couple hundred meters without assistance from a licensed and centrally controlled base station. Meanwhile a $10 walkie talkie using primitive stone-age radio technology can go many miles with zero infrastructure, but by law is not allowed to be used for data transmission. This is a choice our governments have made, not something inherent to the technology.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 15:38:49 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46680154</link><dc:creator>modeless</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46680154</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46680154</guid></item><item><title>New comment by al_borland in "Amazon is ending all inventory commingling as of March 31, 2026"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;It’s about time. I’ve been going out of my way to not buy from Amazon, especially on items that are often counterfeit, or where a counterfeit item would cause real issues.&lt;p&gt;Just a couple days ago I was planning to buy some supplements, which Amazon had. I went to the actual website of the company and bought from them, because the idea of getting a knock off was a bit scary. To my dismay, I received an Amazon shipping notice after making the purchase outside of Amazon. This brought back my skepticism. I’m still waiting for the package to arrive and will end up inspecting it closely.&lt;p&gt;A few months ago I bought some headphones from Amazon, because the official site was out of stock on the color I wanted. I ended up going on YouTube and finding a video on how to spot authentic pairs vs counterfeit ones to make sure I got the real thing.&lt;p&gt;This all stemmed from when I bought a water bottle, and the reviews mentioned this commingling issue and how to spot authentic real one vs a fake. I double checked that I was buying from the company’s listing and not one of the other sellers on the item. I received a counterfeit one. Thankfully this review tipped me off. I lost a significant amount of trust in Amazon that day. A random bottle isn’t something I even thought I needed to worry about counterfeit version for.&lt;p&gt;Amazon has a long way to go to rebuild trust with me. This is a step in the right direction. The fact that it took this long is pretty sad. Amazon is the only mainstream store where I’ve ever had to question if I was buying legitimate goods or not.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 13:20:03 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46678672</link><dc:creator>al_borland</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46678672</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46678672</guid></item><item><title>New comment by ThisNameIsTaken in "Radboud University selects Fairphone as standard smartphone for employees"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;As Fairphone owner I have become somewhat sceptical of their repairability claim.&lt;p&gt;Mine fell on its side on some pebble stones. The power-button, unprotected by the case, got scratched. The button doubles as a fingerprint reader, which ceased working due to the scratch. At first, I thought "no worries, this phone is friendly to those who want to repair it."&lt;p&gt;It turns out, this part is not available for replacement. I think this is an oversight; just like the screen, it is an outward facing part, hence, bound to be damaged for some.&lt;p&gt;Then, I brought it to my local repair shop. The owner had to tell me that they cannot repair Fairphone's, and that, for him, it is one of the worst companies to deal with. They try to centralise all repairs in their own repair center. Which means sending the phone -- which I need -- away for 2 weeks; paying a fee for diagnosis, an unknown cost for repair, and the hassle of a flashed phone. I already know what's broken, I just want the part.&lt;p&gt;I feel this is a real shame, as I am fully supportive of the stated aims of the company, and I want the product to be good.&lt;p&gt;[Aside: suggestions on how to deal with a scratched fingerprint reader are most welcome. E.g. can the scatch be re-painted? The phone thinks the reader is there, but it doesn't register any touch. ]&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 13:11:53 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46678606</link><dc:creator>ThisNameIsTaken</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46678606</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46678606</guid></item><item><title>New comment by amiga386 in "Radboud University selects Fairphone as standard smartphone for employees"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I bought a Fairphone 3, released in 2019.&lt;p&gt;The charging port wore out. I bought another one in 2023. They still sell that part today. &lt;a href="https://shop.fairphone.com/shop/fairphone-3-bottom-module-37" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://shop.fairphone.com/shop/fairphone-3-bottom-module-37&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;In fact, I see they still sell parts (the screen, at least) for the Fairphone 2, released in 2015. First-party parts 10 years later, what a concept! &lt;a href="https://shop.fairphone.com/spare-parts" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://shop.fairphone.com/spare-parts&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;I don't know your friend's scenario, but this was mine.&lt;p&gt;It's not an either-or, like "either buy first-party parts for a Fairphone OR buy a second-hand Samsung". You can buy a second-hand Fairphone too. It would be nice if you got first-party parts for Samsungs, years after they're released.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 10:57:15 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46677522</link><dc:creator>amiga386</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46677522</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46677522</guid></item><item><title>New comment by Antibabelic in "Wikipedia: WikiProject AI Cleanup"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I found the page Wikipedia:Signs of AI Writing[1] very interesting and informative. It goes into a lot more detail than the typical "em-dashes" heuristic.&lt;p&gt;[1]: &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Wikipedia:Signs_of_AI_writing" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Wikipedia:Signs_of_AI_writing&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 10:46:11 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46677431</link><dc:creator>Antibabelic</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46677431</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46677431</guid></item><item><title>New comment by nicois in "A decentralized peer-to-peer messaging application that operates over Bluetooth"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;One missing feature: deferred message propagation. As far as I understand, while messages will be rebroadcast until a TTL is exhausted, there is no mechanism to retain in-transit messages and retransmit them to future peers. While this adds overheads, it's table stakes for real-life usage.&lt;p&gt;You should be able to write a message and not rely on the recipient being available when you press send. You should also be able to run nodes to cache messages for longer, and opt in to holding messages for a greater time period. This would among other things allow couriers between disjoint groups of users.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 08:48:05 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46676451</link><dc:creator>nicois</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46676451</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46676451</guid></item><item><title>New comment by vim-guru in "Show HN: I quit coding years ago. AI brought me back"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I'm at the opposite end. I feel AI is sucking all the joy out of the profession. Might pivot away and perhaps live a simpler life. Only problem is that I really need the paycheck :(&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 08:38:39 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46676382</link><dc:creator>vim-guru</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46676382</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46676382</guid></item><item><title>New comment by j1436go in "Show HN: I quit coding years ago. AI brought me back"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Happy for everyone who enjoys it. For me it's the opposite: AI everywhere sucks the joy out of it and I'm seriously starting to consider a career shift after roughly 10 years of writing code for a living.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 08:00:22 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46676106</link><dc:creator>j1436go</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46676106</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46676106</guid></item><item><title>New comment by seiferteric in "Dead Internet Theory"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;My parents were tricked the other day by a fake youtube video of "racist cop" doing something bad and getting outraged by it. I watch part of the video and even though it felt off I couldn't immediately tell for sure if it was fake or not. Nevertheless I googled the names and details and found nothing but repostings of the video. Then I looked at the youtube channel info and there it said it uses AI for "some" of the videos to recreate "real" events. I really doubt that.. it all looks fake. I am just worried about how much divisiveness this kind of stuff will create all so someone can profit off of youtube ads.. it's sad.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 02:40:26 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46674496</link><dc:creator>seiferteric</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46674496</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46674496</guid></item><item><title>New comment by gpm in "Prediction markets are ushering in a world in which news becomes about gambling"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;If the prediction market is for a non-trivial amount, it's likely &lt;i&gt;someone is going to kill you in exchange for the money the prediction market offered them&lt;/i&gt;. The prediction market isn't acting as a prophet here, it's acting as a plausibly deniable murder for hire service and you are its victim.&lt;p&gt;The people "betting against" you dying just paid to have you killed.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 00:15:01 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46673577</link><dc:creator>gpm</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46673577</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46673577</guid></item></channel></rss>