<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>Hacker News: Best Comments</title><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/bestcomments</link><description>Hacker News RSS</description><docs>https://hnrss.org/</docs><generator>hnrss v2.1.1</generator><lastBuildDate>Fri, 24 Oct 2025 00:09:19 +0000</lastBuildDate><ns0:link href="https://hnrss.org/bestcomments" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item><title>New comment by Alifatisk in "Trump pardons convicted Binance founder"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I cannot comprehend how half of Americans are fine with this corrupt leader? He even does this bizarre maffia like deals out in the open for his own interest, that's how confident he is no one will say anything&lt;p&gt;The message is clear from his circus administration, you can do anything as long as you bribe them&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2025 20:46:33 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45686881</link><dc:creator>Alifatisk</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45686881</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45686881</guid></item><item><title>New comment by neilv in "Armed police swarm student after AI mistakes bag of Doritos for a weapon"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&gt; &lt;i&gt;Omnilert later admitted the incident was a “false positive” but claimed the system “functioned as intended,” saying its purpose is to “prioritize safety and awareness through rapid human verification.”&lt;/i&gt;&lt;p&gt;It just &lt;i&gt;created&lt;/i&gt; a situation in which a bunch of people with guns were told that some teen had a gun.  That's a very unsafe situation that the system created, out of nothing.&lt;p&gt;And some teen may be traumatized.  Again, unsafe.&lt;p&gt;Incidentally, the article's quotes make this teen sound more adult than anyone who sold or purchased this technology product.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2025 19:16:46 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45685696</link><dc:creator>neilv</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45685696</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45685696</guid></item><item><title>New comment by Havoc in "Trump pardons convicted Binance founder"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Coffeezilla video about this is up already&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=JMEJTORMVN4" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=JMEJTORMVN4&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2025 18:44:26 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45685302</link><dc:creator>Havoc</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45685302</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45685302</guid></item><item><title>New comment by cainxinth in "Claude Memory"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I don't use any of these type of LLM tools which basically amount to just a prompt you leave in place. They make it harder to refine my prompts and keep track of what is causing what in the outputs. I write very precise prompts every time.&lt;p&gt;Also, I try not work out a problem over the course of several prompts back and forth. The first response is always the best and I try to one shot it every time. If I don't get what I want, I adjust the prompt and try again.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2025 17:50:45 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45684719</link><dc:creator>cainxinth</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45684719</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45684719</guid></item><item><title>New comment by mikeyouse in "US axes website for reporting human rights abuses by US-armed foreign forces"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&gt; Tim Rieser, former senior aide to Senator Leahy who wrote the 2011 amendment mandating information gathering, told the BBC the gateway's removal meant the State Department was "clearly ignoring the law".&lt;p&gt;We're in a really bad place... with a servile congress, it turns out there aren't really any laws constraining the executive branch. When everything relies on "independent IGs" for law enforcement inside executive branch departments, and the President can fire them all without consequence or oversight, then it turns out there is no law.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2025 14:35:43 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45682307</link><dc:creator>mikeyouse</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45682307</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45682307</guid></item><item><title>New comment by nucleative in "Google flags Immich sites as dangerous"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;We really need an internet Bill of Rights. Google has too much power to delete your company from existence with no due process or recourse.&lt;p&gt;If any company controls some (high) percentage of a particular market, say web browsers, search, or e-commerce, or social media, the public's equal access should start to look more like a right and less like an at-will contract.&lt;p&gt;30 years ago, if a shop had a falling out with the landlord, it could move to the next building over and resume business. Now if you annoy eBay, Amazon or Walmart, you're locked out nationwide. If you're an Uber, Lyft, or Doordash (etc) gig worker and their bots decide they don't like you anymore, then sayonara sucker! Your account has been disabled, have a nice day and don't reapply.&lt;p&gt;Our regulatory structure and economies of scale encourage consolidation and scale and grant access to this market to these businesses, but we aren't protecting the now powerless individuals and small businesses who are randomly and needlessly tossed out with nobody to answer their pleas of desperation, no explanation of rules broken, and no opportunity to appeal with transparency.&lt;p&gt;It's a sorry state of affairs at the moment.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2025 13:05:57 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45681348</link><dc:creator>nucleative</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45681348</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45681348</guid></item><item><title>New comment by perihelions in "SpaceX disables 2,500 Starlink terminals allegedly used by Asian scam centers"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;The title is underselling the nuance—there's the entire Myanmar civil war hiding behind the word "allegedly". The group in power claims a group trying to overthrow them is operating scam centers (they deny it); this SpaceX intervention cuts off communications on a large scale, presumably aiding one side or the other in some unclear way.&lt;p&gt;&gt; &lt;i&gt;"“Maj. Gen. Zaw Min Tun, the spokesperson for the military government, charged in a statement Monday night that the top leaders of the Karen National Union, an armed ethnic organization opposed to army rule, were involved in the scam projects at KK Park,” the AP wrote. The Karen National Union is “part of the larger armed resistance movement in Myanmar’s civil war” and “deny any involvement in the scams.”"&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2025 11:37:53 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45680687</link><dc:creator>perihelions</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45680687</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45680687</guid></item><item><title>New comment by dmoreno in "Google flags Immich sites as dangerous"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Happened to me last week. One morning we wake up and the whole company website does not work.&lt;p&gt;Not advice with some time to fix any possible problem, just blocked.&lt;p&gt;We gave very bad image to our clients and users, and had to give  explanations of a false positive from google detection.&lt;p&gt;The culprit, according to google search console, was a double redirect on our web email domain (/ -&gt; inbox -&gt; login).&lt;p&gt;After just moving the webmail to another domain, removing one of the redirections just in case, and asking politely 4 times to be unblocked.. took about 12 hours. And no real recourse, feedback or anything about when its gonna be solved. And no responsibility.&lt;p&gt;The worse is the feeling of not in control of your own business, and depending on a third party which is not related at all with us, which made a huge mistake, to let out clients use our platform.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2025 08:34:39 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45679583</link><dc:creator>dmoreno</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45679583</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45679583</guid></item><item><title>New comment by bayindirh in "VST3 audio plugin format is now MIT"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Yamaha is an &lt;i&gt;old&lt;/i&gt; company found on very different ethos compared to others. Their history is interesting, too: &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=y6t5F3cb810" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=y6t5F3cb810&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;It's worth a watch.&lt;p&gt;On another note, it's very telling that companies that protect their "hey! we do this interesting thing, gonna buy?" character survives for much longer compared to companies which say "we can earn a ton of money if we do this".&lt;p&gt;The companies in the second lot does a lot of harm to their ecosystems to be able to continue existing.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2025 08:04:55 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45679405</link><dc:creator>bayindirh</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45679405</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45679405</guid></item><item><title>New comment by mastazi in "VST3 audio plugin format is now MIT"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I'm going to file this under "examples of Yamaha doing the right thing" (Steinberg is owned by Yamaha)&lt;p&gt;previous examples:&lt;p&gt;* Yamaha saved Korg by buying it when it was in financial trouble and giving it a cash injection, only to then sell it back to its previous owners once they had enough cash[1].&lt;p&gt;* Yamaha in the 80's had acquired Sequential (for those not familiar: Sequential Circuits is one of the most admired synthesizer makers). Many years later, Sequential's founder Dave Smith established a new company under a different name and in 2015 Yamaha decided to return the rights to use the Sequential brand to Smith, as a gesture of goodwill, on Sequential's 40th anniversary (this was also thanks to Roland's founder Ikutaro Kakehashi who convinced Yamaha that it would be the right thing to do) [1][2][3]&lt;p&gt;[1] &lt;a href="https://www.soundonsound.com/music-business/history-korg-part-2" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://www.soundonsound.com/music-business/history-korg-par...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;[2] &lt;a href="https://www.gearnews.com/american-giants-the-history-of-sequential/" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://www.gearnews.com/american-giants-the-history-of-sequ...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;[3] &lt;a href="https://ra.co/news/42428" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://ra.co/news/42428&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2025 06:51:54 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45678956</link><dc:creator>mastazi</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45678956</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45678956</guid></item><item><title>New comment by Jackson__ in "Google flags Immich sites as dangerous"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;If there are any googlers here, I'd like to report an even more dangerous website. As much as 30-50% of the traffic to it relates to malware or scams, and it has gone unpunished for a very long time.&lt;p&gt;The address appears to be adsense.google.com.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2025 05:30:10 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45678446</link><dc:creator>Jackson__</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45678446</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45678446</guid></item><item><title>New comment by hu3 in "Google flags Immich sites as dangerous"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;This is the first time I hear about &lt;a href="https://publicsuffix.org" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://publicsuffix.org&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2025 01:11:40 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45677097</link><dc:creator>hu3</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45677097</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45677097</guid></item><item><title>New comment by arccy in "Google flags Immich sites as dangerous"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;If you're going to host user content on subdomains, then you should probably have your site on the Public Suffix List &lt;a href="https://publicsuffix.org/list/" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://publicsuffix.org/list/&lt;/a&gt; .
That should eventually make its way into various services so they know that a tainted subdomain doesn't taint the entire site....&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2025 23:30:24 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45676475</link><dc:creator>arccy</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45676475</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45676475</guid></item><item><title>New comment by NelsonMinar in "Google flags Immich sites as dangerous"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Be sure to see the team's whole list of Cursed Knowledge. &lt;a href="https://immich.app/cursed-knowledge" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://immich.app/cursed-knowledge&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2025 23:29:19 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45676467</link><dc:creator>NelsonMinar</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45676467</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45676467</guid></item><item><title>New comment by jacquesm in "Accessing Max Verstappen's passport and PII through FIA bugs"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;That's not just one vulnerability, that's a whole slew of failures. For instance there is absolutely no need to keep those documents on the live server for applicants once they have been used for their intended purpose. Blast radius reduction and all that.&lt;p&gt;I hope you got at least free tickets for life out of this.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2025 20:48:15 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45674947</link><dc:creator>jacquesm</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45674947</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45674947</guid></item><item><title>New comment by tester457 in "Scripts I wrote that I use all the time"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I am not the author, but my bet is that he didn't know of its existence.&lt;p&gt;The best part about sharing your config or knowledge is that someone will always light up your blind spots.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2025 20:28:42 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45674740</link><dc:creator>tester457</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45674740</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45674740</guid></item><item><title>New comment by softwaredoug in "Criticisms of “The Body Keeps the Score”"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;This article (and author) seems to be something of a trauma-skeptic, which doesn't seem to agree with mainstream science (setting aside Body Keeps the Score)&lt;p&gt;&gt; That is, trauma doesn’t lead to dysfunction or abnormal brain function, physiology or hormonal regulation. Rather, an unhealthy person may be more susceptible to trauma.&lt;p&gt;What has been documented about Adverse Childhood Experiences doesn’t agree with this. There is copious evidence that the presence of ACEs, independent of other factors, leads to poor health outcomes [1]&lt;p&gt;It's also well known that past trauma predisposes you to future trauma [2]&lt;p&gt;There's also data indicating CPTSD, PTSD, and Borderline are distinct disorders [3]&lt;p&gt;1 - &lt;a href="https://pmc.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/articles/PMC8882933/" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://pmc.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/articles/PMC8882933/&lt;/a&gt;  &lt;a href="https://bmcpublichealth.biomedcentral.com/articles/10.1186/s12889-025-22785-2" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://bmcpublichealth.biomedcentral.com/articles/10.1186/s...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;2 - &lt;a href="https://pmc.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/articles/PMC5858954/" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://pmc.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/articles/PMC5858954/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;3 - &lt;a href="https://www.psychiatrypodcast.com/psychiatry-psychotherapy-podcast/episode-215-understanding-complex-ptsd-and-borderline-personality-disorder" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://www.psychiatrypodcast.com/psychiatry-psychotherapy-p...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2025 20:13:46 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45674571</link><dc:creator>softwaredoug</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45674571</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45674571</guid></item><item><title>New comment by scrollop in "Meta is axing 600 roles across its AI division"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Why are you asking questions about their PR department coordinated "Company missions"?&lt;p&gt;Let me summarise their real missions:&lt;p&gt;1. Power and money&lt;p&gt;2. Power and money&lt;p&gt;3. Power and money&lt;p&gt;How does AI help them make money and gain more power?&lt;p&gt;I can give you a few ways...&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2025 18:59:43 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45673603</link><dc:creator>scrollop</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45673603</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45673603</guid></item><item><title>New comment by ceejayoz in "Meta is axing 600 roles across its AI division"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Because the AI works so well, or because it doesn't?&lt;p&gt;&gt; ”By reducing the size of our team, fewer conversations will be required to make a decision, and each person will be more load-bearing and have more scope and impact,” Wang writes in a memo seen by Axios.&lt;p&gt;That's kinda wild. I'm kinda shocked they put it in writing.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2025 17:14:57 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45672187</link><dc:creator>ceejayoz</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45672187</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45672187</guid></item><item><title>New comment by scarmig in "AI assistants misrepresent news content 45% of the time"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;If you dig into the actual report (I know, I know, how passe), you see how they get the numbers. Most of the errors are "sourcing issues": the AI assistant doesn't cite a claim, or it (shocking) cites Wikipedia instead of the BBC.&lt;p&gt;Other issues: the report doesn't even say which particular models it's querying [ETA: discovered they do list this in an appendix], aside from saying it's the consumer tier. And it leaves off Anthropic (in my experience, by far the best at this type of task), favoring Perplexity and (perplexingly) Copilot. The article also intermingles claims from the recent report and the one on research conducted a year ago, leaving out critical context that... things have changed.&lt;p&gt;This article contains significant issues.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2025 14:46:06 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45669929</link><dc:creator>scarmig</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45669929</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45669929</guid></item><item><title>New comment by michaelmauderer in "Internet's biggest annoyance: Cookie laws should target browsers, not websites"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;But the courts are saying: the law does NOT allow this.&lt;p&gt;So maybe “malicious compliance” is a misnomer. We should just call it "illegal dark pattern".&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2025 13:02:16 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45668443</link><dc:creator>michaelmauderer</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45668443</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45668443</guid></item><item><title>New comment by crazygringo in "Internet's biggest annoyance: Cookie laws should target browsers, not websites"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;No, the problem &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; 100% the law, because it was written in a way that &lt;i&gt;allows&lt;/i&gt; this type of malicious compliance.&lt;p&gt;Laws need to be written well to achieve good outcomes. If the law allows for malicious compliance, it is a badly written law.&lt;p&gt;The sites are just trying to maximize profit, as anyone could predict. So write better laws.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2025 12:52:44 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45668318</link><dc:creator>crazygringo</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45668318</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45668318</guid></item><item><title>New comment by michaelmauderer in "Internet's biggest annoyance: Cookie laws should target browsers, not websites"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;The problem here is not the law, but malicious compliance by websites that don't want to give up tracking.&lt;p&gt;"Spend Five Minutes in a Menu of Legalese" is not the intended alternative to "Accept All". "Decline All" is! And this is starting to be enforced through the courts, so you're increasingly seeing the "Decline All" option right away. As it should be.
&lt;a href="https://www.techspot.com/news/108043-german-court-takes-stand-against-manipulative-cookie-banners.html" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://www.techspot.com/news/108043-german-court-takes-stan...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;Of course, also respecting a Do-Not-Track header and avoiding the cookie banner entirely while not tracking the user, would be even better.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2025 12:36:03 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45668112</link><dc:creator>michaelmauderer</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45668112</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45668112</guid></item><item><title>New comment by rustc in "Internet's biggest annoyance: Cookie laws should target browsers, not websites"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Or just ban this kind of data collection. Is there any reason anyone would willingly click "Accept" when a website asks to share your data with 500+ partner sites?&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2025 12:29:15 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45668037</link><dc:creator>rustc</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45668037</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45668037</guid></item><item><title>New comment by mattbee in "MinIO stops distributing free Docker images"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;They abandoned documentation (edit: for the open source codebase) a couple of weeks ago - that seems more significant.&lt;p&gt;From their Slack on Oct 10:&lt;p&gt;"The documentation sites at docs.min.io/community have been pulled of this morning and will redirect to the equivalent AIStor documentation &lt;i&gt;where possible&lt;/i&gt;". [emphasis mine]&lt;p&gt;The minio/docs repository hasn't been updated in 2 weeks now, and the implication is that isn't going to be.&lt;p&gt;Even when I set up a minio cluster this February, it was both impressively easy and hard in a few small aspects.  The most crucial installation tips - around 100Gb networking, Linux kernel tunables and fault-finding - were hung off comments on their github, talking about files that were deleted from the repository years ago.&lt;p&gt;I've built a cluster for a client that's being expanded to ≈100PB this year.  The price of support comes in at at slightly less than the equivalent amount of S3 storage (not including the actual hosting costs!).  The value of it just isn't that high to my client - so I guess we're just coasting on what we can get now, and will have to see what real community might form around the source.&lt;p&gt;I'm not a free software die-hard so I'm grateful for the work minio have put into the world, and the business it's enabling. But it seems super-clear they're stopping those contributions, and I'd bet the final open source release will happen in the next year.&lt;p&gt;If anyone else is hosting with minio &amp; can't afford the support either :) please drop me a line and maybe we can get something going.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2025 10:53:12 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45667259</link><dc:creator>mattbee</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45667259</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45667259</guid></item><item><title>New comment by greatgib in "French ex-president Sarkozy begins jail sentence"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Something really scary in France right now is that you can see really clearly how most mainstream media are used for propaganda.&lt;p&gt;Since a few days, there is an abundance of cover and articles in most major newspaper here with propaganda and repeated lies supporting him. 
It's hard to imagine but non stop.
You have everyday interviews of his family saying that it is an injustice, that he did nothing, that the judgement was rigged, that he was a great men that served France and so should not be treated like everyone else. Article about how sad the poor family is. Number of articles repeating friends of him verbatim s that the judgement was fake.&lt;p&gt;Almost none speaking about the facts, the grounds for his sentence, the big number of other trials against him that are running. And also the other definitive convictions he got. Like for attempting to bribe a head prosecutor to get insider info about his case. Using a prepaid line opened with a fake name...&lt;p&gt;But what you see in the end is that 90% of medias in France belongs to a few wealthy families that are friends with him.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2025 10:01:54 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45666908</link><dc:creator>greatgib</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45666908</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45666908</guid></item><item><title>New comment by weli in "MinIO stops distributing free Docker images"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;When you always published and built Docker images for the public you are creating an expectation, people will rely on that and will chose your software based on that expectation.&lt;p&gt;You suddenly deciding that you won't be offering updated Docker images &lt;i&gt;especially&lt;/i&gt; after a CVE and with no prior notice (except a hidden commit 4 days ago that updated the README) is approaching malicious-level actions.&lt;p&gt;If they truly cared about their community and still wanted to go through the decision of not offering public docker builds the responsible thing to do is offer a warning period, start adding notices in the repo (gh and docker) and create an easy migration path, even endorse or help some community members who would be fine with taking care of the public builds of the image.&lt;p&gt;But no, they introduced the change, made no public statement about it, waited for someone to notice this, offered no explanation and went silent. After a huge CVE. Irresponsible.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2025 09:42:34 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45666766</link><dc:creator>weli</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45666766</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45666766</guid></item><item><title>New comment by MuteXR in "MinIO stops distributing free Docker images"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Keep in mind this is the same project that removed all useful functionality from the included web UI in the community edition with the excuse that it was too much effort to maintain.&lt;p&gt;This is another case of VC-funded companies pulling up the ladder behind themselves.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2025 09:05:56 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45666513</link><dc:creator>MuteXR</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45666513</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45666513</guid></item><item><title>New comment by sehansen in "Greenland’s national telco, Tusass, signs new agreement with Eutelsat"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;That's a pretty damn editorialized title[0] given that Tusass signed an extended deal with their original provider. To me the chosen title implies that Tusass had chosen Starlink and then decided to stop using them. Starlink did submit a tender offer, but losing to an established competitor isn't super newsworthy.&lt;p&gt;0: No shade thrown at the submitter, as this is the title used by the site.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2025 07:27:58 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45665875</link><dc:creator>sehansen</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45665875</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45665875</guid></item><item><title>New comment by rayiner in "NASA chief suggests SpaceX may be booted from moon mission"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;My first job out of law school was at a 176 year old law firm. New lawyers were socialized to identify with the past achievements of the firm, like helping J.P. Morgan build the railroads. There was a good reason for that: it socializes people to adhere to a culture and practices that have proven to be effective.&lt;p&gt;You’re right that, if overdone, it can lead to complacency. But if you treat every generation as a blank slate, you abandon the valuable capital of experience.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2025 00:09:39 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45663420</link><dc:creator>rayiner</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45663420</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45663420</guid></item></channel></rss>