<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>Hacker News: Best Comments</title><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/bestcomments</link><description>Hacker News RSS</description><docs>https://hnrss.org/</docs><generator>hnrss v2.1.1</generator><lastBuildDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 23:50:21 +0000</lastBuildDate><ns0:link href="https://hnrss.org/bestcomments" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item><title>New comment by sedatk in "Microsoft forced me to switch to Linux"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;My story is simpler. Microsoft dropped the support for Windows 10 and gave me no upgrade path to Windows 11 because my CPU was 5 years too old apparently.&lt;p&gt;So I installed Fedora on that machine, I learned the process, I went through the hurdles. It wasn’t seamless. But, Fedora never said “I can’t”. When it was over, it was fine.&lt;p&gt;Only if Microsoft had just let me install Windows 11 and suffer whatever the perf problem my CPU would bring. Then I could consider a hardware upgrade then, maybe.&lt;p&gt;But, “you can’t install unless you upgrade your CPU” forced me to adopt Linux. More importantly, it gave me a story to tell.&lt;p&gt;There is a marketing lesson there somewhere, like Torvalds’ famous “you don’t break userspace”, something along the lines of “you don’t break the upgrade path”.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 17:11:22 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46798223</link><dc:creator>sedatk</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46798223</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46798223</guid></item><item><title>New comment by ryukoposting in "Microsoft forced me to switch to Linux"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I just started a new job where I'm subjected to Windows 11. They gave me a behemoth of a laptop. 64GB of RAM, absolute screamer of a CPU, big GPU, the whole deal.&lt;p&gt;Windows 11's file browser lags when opening directories with more than 100-ish files. Windows 11's file browser takes a few seconds to open at all.&lt;p&gt;Context menus take a noticeable amount of time to appear.&lt;p&gt;I'm getting used to a new keyboard, so I keep hitting Print Screen by accident. Half the time I can smack Esc and Snipping Tool will go away. The other half of the time, I have to mouse over and click the X to close it. There is no pattern to when Esc does/doesn't work.&lt;p&gt;If my computer goes to sleep, WSL becomes unresponsive. I have to save all my stuff and reboot to continue working.&lt;p&gt;If Windows 11 struggles &lt;i&gt;this&lt;/i&gt; badly on a brand new laptop that I'm certain would retail for $4000+, I can only imagine how miserable it is for everyone else. All my colleagues who have been here for a bit longer got last-generation laptops. &lt;i&gt;oof.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;p&gt;Edit... and besides, what does Windows 11 even &lt;i&gt;do&lt;/i&gt; that KDE Plasma 5 wasn't doing a decade ago? How did it take &lt;i&gt;this&lt;/i&gt; long to get a tabbed file browser?&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 16:24:09 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46797454</link><dc:creator>ryukoposting</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46797454</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46797454</guid></item><item><title>New comment by focusgroup0 in "Amazon cuts 16k jobs"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&gt;Amazon axes 16,000 American jobs as it ... relocates to a larger campus in India&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://techcrunch.com/2025/12/10/amazon-to-invest-additional-35b-in-india-by-2030-taking-total-planned-spending-to-75b/" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://techcrunch.com/2025/12/10/amazon-to-invest-additiona...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 16:19:56 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46797370</link><dc:creator>focusgroup0</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46797370</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46797370</guid></item><item><title>New comment by paxys in "Amazon cuts 16k jobs"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Every large company is updating its standard layoffs announcement press release from "economic headwinds" to "AI".&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 16:00:47 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46797061</link><dc:creator>paxys</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46797061</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46797061</guid></item><item><title>New comment by Zambyte in "Microsoft forced me to switch to Linux"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&gt; if you don't sell your games on Steam or in a way I can run them on Linux I am not buying or playing them.&lt;p&gt;So much this. People like to moan about "oh game XYZ doesn't run so it's not reasonable for gaming". More games run on GNU / Linux than any gaming console. There are simply too many games that do run to give a second thought about the ones that don't, and it's been that way for years.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 15:28:39 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46796585</link><dc:creator>Zambyte</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46796585</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46796585</guid></item><item><title>New comment by giancarlostoro in "Microsoft forced me to switch to Linux"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;This was me in 2022 or 2023. I have posted on HN about my shift a few times. I gave up with Windows 10 because you needed Windows Pro in order to make an "offline" account, I spent $2000+ for a gaming rig, and I couldn't add new users, one program told me to use the other program which brought me back to the original program... I had to go out of my way, buy a license just to make it work. I just went and installed Linux finally. I was on POP_OS! for a good year, but been on Arch Linux for one year plus now.&lt;p&gt;I know its a "meme" to talk about how great Arch is, but when you want the latest of something, Arch has it. I use EndeavourOS since it had a nicer simpler installer (idk why Arch doesn't invest in whats standard in every other major distro) and if you just use "yay" you don't run into Pacman woes.&lt;p&gt;Alternatively, I'm only buying Macs as well, but for my gaming rigs, straight to Arch.  Steam and Proton work perfectly, if you don't sell your games on Steam or in a way I can run them on Linux I am not buying or playing them.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 15:21:11 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46796497</link><dc:creator>giancarlostoro</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46796497</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46796497</guid></item><item><title>New comment by petterroea in "ICE and Palantir: US agents using health data to hunt illegal immigrants"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Private surveillance is so much more scary than regular government surveillance because they have every incentive to invent new ways of surveilling you that they then try to sell to governments, or private actors who want to influence the world. It's like classic government surveillance but every company you interacted with and every app you use may at some point turn on you and use your data against you, just because someone realized "hey, I bet we can sell this data"&lt;p&gt;We are really seeing the fears of data collection from the 2000s and 2010s come to fruition as privatized surveillance now. Cambridge analytica should have been the warning shot but it wasn't enough.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 12:51:15 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46794654</link><dc:creator>petterroea</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46794654</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46794654</guid></item><item><title>New comment by skrebbel in "ASML staffing changes could result in a net reduction of around 1700 positions"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;The press release (&lt;a href="https://www.asml.com/en/news/press-releases/2026/strengthening-focus-on-engineering-and-innovation" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://www.asml.com/en/news/press-releases/2026/strengtheni...&lt;/a&gt;) seems remarkably to the point, for CEO press release standards.&lt;p&gt;I'm impressed by their ambition to fire &lt;i&gt;1700 managers&lt;/i&gt;(!) That's a lot of managers! I interviewed with ASML a decade and a half ago and while there was plenty to complain about (eg their tens of millions of lines of absolutely unmaintainable C code), I didn't feel at the time feel like it was a very top-heavy organization. It was &lt;i&gt;very&lt;/i&gt; engineer-y, and I loved that about them. This press release (when taken at face value) suggests that this has changed a lot over time and they're now trying to correct it.&lt;p&gt;I gotta say, if true and not code for general "cheese slicer" cost cutting, I think that this is rather ballsy. Philips (which ASML spun out of) famously never did anything of the sort and gradually cramped into an extremely management-heavy organization where most people just write reports for other people with scary few people actually moving the needle. I think it's cool that ASML has identified that they're risking becoming like Philips and trying to do something about it, even if the method seems rather crude. I think the risk is real. ASML's fast-moving culture formed in a mad multi-decade survival-crunch, but they've been a near-monopolist for a while now and that means those pressures are long gone.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 08:45:04 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46792672</link><dc:creator>skrebbel</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46792672</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46792672</guid></item><item><title>New comment by Perseids in "Prism"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I'm dumbfounded they chose the name of the infamous NSA mass surveillance program revealed by Snowden in 2013. And even more so that there is just one other comment among 320 pointing this out [1]. Has the technical and scientific community in the US already forgotten this huge breach of trust? This is especially jarring at a time where the US is burning its political good-will at unprecedented rate (at least unprecedented during the life-times of most of us) and talking about digital sovereignty has become mainstream in Europe. As a company trying to promote a product, I would stay as far away from that memory as possible, at least if you care about international markets.&lt;p&gt;[1] &lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46787165"&gt;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46787165&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 07:12:21 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46792035</link><dc:creator>Perseids</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46792035</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46792035</guid></item><item><title>New comment by mw888 in "FBI is investigating Minnesota Signal chats tracking ICE"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;There seems to be wild speculation about freedom of speech rights or hacking Signal.&lt;p&gt;The FBI simply joined groupchats and read them. This is trivial stuff.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 02:15:38 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46790186</link><dc:creator>mw888</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46790186</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46790186</guid></item><item><title>New comment by SchemaLoad in "Prism"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;GenAI largely seems like a DDoS on free resources. The effort to review this stuff is now massively more than the effort to "create" it, so really what is the point of even submitting it, the reviewer could have generated it themself. Seeing it in software development where coworkers are submitting massive PRs they generated but hardly read or tested. Shifting the real work to the PR review.&lt;p&gt;I'm not sure what the final state would be here but it seems we are going to find it increasingly difficult to find any real factual information on the internet going forward. Particularly as AI starts ingesting it's own generated fake content.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2026 22:26:00 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46787976</link><dc:creator>SchemaLoad</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46787976</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46787976</guid></item><item><title>New comment by epistasis in "FBI is investigating Minnesota Signal chats tracking ICE"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;And importantly the DoJ attorneys who would be responsible for investigating g the murders &lt;i&gt;resigned&lt;/i&gt; because they were prevented from performing the standard procedure investigation that happens after every single shooting. They were instead directed to investigate the family of the person who was shot:&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://kstp.com/kstp-news/top-news/nyt-6-federal-prosecutors-resign-over-pressure-to-investigate-renee-goods-widow/" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://kstp.com/kstp-news/top-news/nyt-6-federal-prosecutor...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;We are through the looking glass, folks. This will be dropped and ignored like so many other outrages unless we demand answers from Congress, and hold SCOTUS responsible for partisan abdication of their constitutional duties.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2026 21:29:02 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46787140</link><dc:creator>epistasis</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46787140</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46787140</guid></item><item><title>New comment by chinathrow in "FBI is investigating Minnesota Signal chats tracking ICE"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;The FBI should investigate the murders done by ICE and until done with that, remain silent.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2026 21:11:38 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46786814</link><dc:creator>chinathrow</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46786814</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46786814</guid></item><item><title>New comment by hedayet in "FBI is investigating Minnesota Signal chats tracking ICE"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;With all the predatory tech Palantir has produced, it won't take more than a few minutes for FBI to start taking actions, &lt;i&gt;IF&lt;/i&gt; they had anything tangible.&lt;p&gt;This is just an intimidation tactic to stop people talking (chatting)&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2026 20:26:47 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46786044</link><dc:creator>hedayet</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46786044</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46786044</guid></item><item><title>New comment by JBorrow in "Prism"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;From my perspective as a journal editor and a reviewer these kinds of tools cause many more problems than they actually solve. They make the 'barrier to entry' for submitting vibed semi-plausible journal articles much lower, which I understand some may see as a benefit. The drawback is that scientific editors and reviewers provide those services for free, as a community benefit. One example was a submission their undergraduate affiliation (in accounting) to submit a paper on cosmology, entirely vibe-coded and vibe-written. This just wastes our (already stretched) time. A significant fraction of submissions are now vibe-written and come from folks who are looking to 'boost' their CV (even having a 'submitted' publication is seen as a benefit), which is really not the point of these journals at all.&lt;p&gt;I'm not sure I'm convinced of the benefit of lowering the barrier to entry to scientific publishing. The hard part always has been, and always will be, understanding the research context (what's been published before) and producing novel and interesting work (the underlying research). Connecting this together in a paper is indeed a challenge, and a skill that must be developed, but is really a minimal part of the process.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2026 20:09:44 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46785750</link><dc:creator>JBorrow</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46785750</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46785750</guid></item><item><title>New comment by titzer in "U.S. government has lost more than 10k STEM PhDs since Trump took office"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;It's harder to recruit PhD students and it's harder to fund them. NSF budget was cut 55% in the first year. The administration is doing everything possible to make it clear that no foreigners are welcome here. America is stabbing itself directly in the brain.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2026 19:46:50 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46785403</link><dc:creator>titzer</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46785403</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46785403</guid></item><item><title>New comment by daxfohl in "A few random notes from Claude coding quite a bit last few weeks"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I worry about the "brain atrophy" part, as I've felt this too. And not just atrophy, but even moreso I think it's evolving into "complacency".&lt;p&gt;Like there have been multiple times now where I wanted the code to look a certain way, but it kept pulling back to the way it wanted to do things. Like if I had stated certain design goals recently it would adhere to them, but after a few iterations it would forget again and go back to its original approach, or mix the two, or whatever. Eventually it was easier just to quit fighting it and let it do things the way it wanted.&lt;p&gt;What I've seen is that after the initial dopamine rush of being able to do things that would have taken much longer manually, a few iterations of this kind of interaction has slowly led to a disillusionment of the whole project, as AI keeps pushing it in a direction I didn't want.&lt;p&gt;I think this is especially true if you're trying to experiment with new approaches to things. LLMs are, by definition, biased by what was in their training data. You can shock them out of it momentarily, whish is awesome for a few rounds, but over time the gravitational pull of what's already in their latent space becomes inescapable. (I picture it as working like a giant Sierpinski triangle).&lt;p&gt;I want to say the end result is very akin to doom scrolling. Doom tabbing? It's like, yeah I could be more creative with just a tad more effort, but the AI is already running and the bar to seeing what the AI will do next is so low, so....&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2026 18:59:08 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46784594</link><dc:creator>daxfohl</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46784594</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46784594</guid></item><item><title>New comment by einrealist in "A few random notes from Claude coding quite a bit last few weeks"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&gt; It's so interesting to watch an agent relentlessly work at something. They never get tired, they never get demoralized, they just keep going and trying things where a person would have given up long ago to fight another day. It's a "feel the AGI" moment to watch it struggle with something for a long time just to come out victorious 30 minutes later.&lt;p&gt;Somewhere, there are GPUs/NPUs running hot. You send all the necessary data, including information that you would never otherwise share. And you most likely do not pay the actual costs. It might become cheaper or it might not, because reasoning is a sticking plaster on the accuracy problem. You and your business become dependent on this major gatekeeper. It may seem like a good trade-off today. However, the personal, professional, political and societal issues will become increasingly difficult to overlook.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2026 18:44:42 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46784407</link><dc:creator>einrealist</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46784407</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46784407</guid></item><item><title>New comment by Bluecobra in "Amazon closing its Fresh and Go stores"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Doesn’t surprise me.  I frequently shop at Amazon Fresh in store and it’s a mediocre experience. It’s a poorly run store with no visible manager making sure things are in order. You constantly have to work around employees fulfilling online orders and they aren’t helpful.  I always find expired groceries/produce on the shelf so I have to spend a lot of extra time inspecting each item.  The only reason I put up with their nonsense is that some of their prices are insane and they have easy returns, for example $0.85 for a box of Barilla pasta. They actually don’t accept returns in store and just refund you automatically in the app (Returnless returns).  It’s pretty silly and rife for abuse.&lt;p&gt;I also found a loophole with the Amazon.com return grocery credit.  The systems are separate for the $10 off $40 coupon and you just scan a QR code in the store to get it. It  turns out you can just take a photo of their QR code and reuse it over and over again.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2026 16:51:58 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46782592</link><dc:creator>Bluecobra</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46782592</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46782592</guid></item><item><title>New comment by throwup238 in "430k-year-old well-preserved wooden tools are the oldest ever found"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Tools predate homo sapiens (which emerged about 300 kYA) by millions of years. The first stone industry - Oldowan - is at least two million years old and might be as old as three million. They predate what we call “archaic humans” by a long time.&lt;p&gt;Even this evidence of woodworking is largely unremarkable. We’ve got phytolith [1] and microwear [2] studies showing unambiguous evidence of woodworking going back at least 1.5 million years. Wood tools just don’t survive very long, so this find is most notable for its preservation.&lt;p&gt;[1] &lt;a href="https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/abs/pii/S0047248400904664" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/abs/pii/S00472...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;[2] &lt;a href="https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/abs/pii/S0047248415001906" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/abs/pii/S00472...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2026 16:19:05 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46782017</link><dc:creator>throwup238</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46782017</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46782017</guid></item><item><title>New comment by js8 in "TikTok users can't upload anti-ICE videos. The company blames tech issues"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;When I was 11, on 17th Nov 1989, in Czechoslovakia, my father was watching the evening news on our (black and white) TV, as usual.&lt;p&gt;There was a protest and the state media was reporting on it. When the reporter said, "our camera broke down and we can only show black and white pictures", my father IMMEDIATELY jumped up and angrily said, "that's bs, you don't want to show how they [the protesting students] got beaten up [by the police]!"&lt;p&gt;This was an interesting life lesson. So yeah, sure, technical difficulties..&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2026 14:58:55 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46780843</link><dc:creator>js8</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46780843</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46780843</guid></item><item><title>New comment by iugtmkbdfil834 in "TikTok users can't upload anti-ICE videos. The company blames tech issues"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Allow me to offer some words of wisdom. If you help building weapons to be used against $currently_designated_bad_people, you can rest assured that given enough time, those weapons will be used against you. I am watching all this with a mild sense of bemusement.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2026 14:55:40 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46780791</link><dc:creator>iugtmkbdfil834</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46780791</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46780791</guid></item><item><title>New comment by mark_l_watson in "TikTok users can't upload anti-ICE videos. The company blames tech issues"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;The forced US hosted tik-tok sale is all about hiding information from the US public that most people in the rest of the world have easy access to.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2026 14:02:11 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46780016</link><dc:creator>mark_l_watson</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46780016</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46780016</guid></item><item><title>New comment by hosteur in "Heathrow scraps liquid container limit"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I have a rock that keeps tigers away. For 30 years I have not encountered any tigers. That’s a pretty good record.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2026 05:57:55 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46776050</link><dc:creator>hosteur</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46776050</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46776050</guid></item><item><title>New comment by edm0nd in "Heathrow scraps liquid container limit"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Correct. In the US, the TSA is just a government jobs program for the lowly skilled or unskilled. It's all security theater.&lt;p&gt;TSA Chief Out After Agents Fail 95 Percent of Airport Breach Tests&lt;p&gt;"In one case, an alarm sounded, but even during a pat-down, the screening officer failed to detect a fake plastic explosive taped to an undercover agent's back. In all, so-called "Red Teams" of Homeland Security agents posing as passengers were able get weapons past TSA agents in 67 out of 70 tests — a 95 percent failure rate, according to agency officials."&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.nbcnews.com/news/us-news/investigation-breaches-us-airports-allowed-weapons-through-n367851" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://www.nbcnews.com/news/us-news/investigation-breaches-...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2026 05:19:32 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46775836</link><dc:creator>edm0nd</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46775836</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46775836</guid></item><item><title>New comment by bleepblap in "Heathrow scraps liquid container limit"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;there is actually a science change that happened, and it's not (entirely) just politicians changing their mind.&lt;p&gt;The big thing going from X-ray (2d) to CT (spin an X-ray machine around and take a ton of pictures to recreate a 3d image) did a lot to let security people see inside of a bag, but the hitch is that if you see a blob of gray is that water, shampoo or something else?&lt;p&gt;The recent advance that is letting this happen is machines who will send multiple wavelengths of X-ray through the material: since different materials absorb light differently, your machine can distinguish between materials, which lets you be more sure that that 2litre is (mostly) water, and then they can discriminate&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2026 05:16:28 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46775816</link><dc:creator>bleepblap</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46775816</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46775816</guid></item><item><title>New comment by jandrewrogers in "Heathrow scraps liquid container limit"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;This just adds confusion as to the purpose of all this.&lt;p&gt;The motivation behind the liquid limits is that there are extremely powerful explosives that are stable water-like liquids. Average people have never heard of them because they aren’t in popular lore. There has never been an industrial or military use, solids are simpler. Nonetheless, these explosives are easily accessible to a knowledgeable chemist like me.&lt;p&gt;These explosives can be detected via infrared spectroscopy but that isn’t going to be happening to liquids in your bag. This reminds me of the chemical swipes done on your bags to detect explosives. Those swipes can only detect a narrow set of explosive chemistries and everyone knows it. Some explosives notoriously popular with terror organizations can’t be detected. Everyone, including the bad guys, knows all of this.&lt;p&gt;It would be great if governments were more explicit about precisely what all of this theater is intended to prevent.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2026 04:58:34 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46775722</link><dc:creator>jandrewrogers</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46775722</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46775722</guid></item><item><title>New comment by atonse in "A few random notes from Claude coding quite a bit last few weeks"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&gt; LLM coding will split up engineers based on those who primarily liked coding and those who primarily liked building.&lt;p&gt;I’ve always said I’m a builder even though I’ve also enjoyed programming (but for an outcome, never for the sake of the code)&lt;p&gt;This perfectly sums up what I’ve been observing between people like me (builders) who are ecstatic about this new world and programmers who talk about the craft of programming, sometimes butting heads.&lt;p&gt;One viewpoint isn’t necessarily more valid, just a difference of wiring.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2026 02:43:21 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46774862</link><dc:creator>atonse</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46774862</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46774862</guid></item><item><title>New comment by trollbridge in "Apple introduces new AirTag with longer range and improved findability"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I need to applaud the efficiency and moxie of the Zurich / Swiss police service.&lt;p&gt;In America, the UK, Canada, etc they'd tell you to fill out a report that nobody would ever read, and also advise you it's probably unsafe to go pick it up yourself.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2026 01:10:40 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46774156</link><dc:creator>trollbridge</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46774156</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46774156</guid></item><item><title>New comment by chrisfosterelli in "I let ChatGPT analyze a decade of my Apple Watch data, then I called my doctor"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Health metrics are absolutely tarnished by a lack of proper context. Unsurprisingly, it turns out that you can't reliably take a concept as broad as health and reduce it to a number. We see the same arguments over and over with body fat percentages, vo2 max estimates, BMI, lactate thresholds, resting heart rate, HRV, and more. These are all useful metrics, but it's important to consider them in the proper context that each of them deserve.&lt;p&gt;This article gave an LLM a bunch of health metrics and then asked it to reduce it to a single score, didn't tell us any of the actual metric values, and then compared that to a doctor's opinion. Why anyone would expect these to align is beyond my understanding.&lt;p&gt;The most obvious thing that jumps out to me is that I've noticed doctors generally, for better or worse, consider "health" much differently than the fitness community does. It's different toolsets and different goals. If this person's VO2 max estimate was under 30, that's objectively a poor VO2 max by most standards, and an LLM trained on the internet's entire repository of fitness discussion is likely going to give this person a bad score in terms of cardio fitness. But a doctor who sees a person come in who isn't complaining about anything in particular, moves around fine, doesn't have risk factors like age or family history, and has good metrics on a blood test is probably going to say they're in fine cardio health regardless of what their wearable says.&lt;p&gt;I'd go so far to say this is probably the case for most people. Your average person is in really poor fitness-shape but just fine health-shape.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2026 00:45:22 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46773944</link><dc:creator>chrisfosterelli</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46773944</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46773944</guid></item></channel></rss>