<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>Hacker News: Best Comments</title><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/bestcomments</link><description>Hacker News RSS</description><docs>https://hnrss.org/</docs><generator>hnrss v2.1.1</generator><lastBuildDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2025 23:49:53 +0000</lastBuildDate><ns0:link href="https://hnrss.org/bestcomments" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item><title>New comment by marcprux in "What we talk about when we talk about sideloading"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Author here. I admit I am rather startled by the tone of many comments here and the accusations of disingenuity. Splitting hairs about the origin of the term "sideload" does not change the fact that those who promote the term tend to do so in order to make it feel deviant and hacker-ish. You don't "sideload" software on your Linux, Windows, or macOS computer: you install it.&lt;p&gt;You have the right to install whatever you want on your computer, regardless of whether that computer is on your desk or in your pocket. That's a hill I'll die on. I'm dismayed to see that this sentiment is not more widespread in this of all communities.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2025 19:56:47 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45738237</link><dc:creator>marcprux</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45738237</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45738237</guid></item><item><title>New comment by kstrauser in "Samsung makes ads on smart fridges official with upcoming software update"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;This guarantees I'll never buy a Samsung appliance. If they're this willing to screw with their customers today, they'll do it again tomorrow.&lt;p&gt;Sadly, I'm including their TVs in this. I have one today, displaying the output of an Apple TV and not directly connected to the Internet because hah, no way, but I'll be shopping around when it comes time to replace it.&lt;p&gt;Pity. They make nice stuff. Not nice enough that I'm willing to tolerate their anti-customer shenanigans, but otherwise decent quality.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2025 19:26:30 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45737719</link><dc:creator>kstrauser</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45737719</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45737719</guid></item><item><title>New comment by egorfine in "Using AI to negotiate a $195k hospital bill down to $33k"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Non-US person here.&lt;p&gt;Happy for your happy-end to that story!&lt;p&gt;Though why do you Americans put up with all this? I have heard the US is a democracy. So then insurance-based healthcare is what American people truly want?&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2025 18:42:06 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45736987</link><dc:creator>egorfine</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45736987</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45736987</guid></item><item><title>New comment by chrisgeleven in "Using AI to negotiate a $195k hospital bill down to $33k"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I fought insurance over this past summer after they declined covering a life saving surgery for my 6-year-old child at the last minute. We were in despair that my child's life was at risk each day we waited because of insurance incompetence.&lt;p&gt;ChatGPT literally guided me through the whole external appeal process, who to contact outside of normal channels to ask for help / apply pressure, researched questions I had, helped with wording on the appeals, and yes, helped keep me pushing forward at some of the darkest moments when I was grasping for anything, however small, to help keep the pressure up on the insurance company.&lt;p&gt;I didn't follow everything it suggested blindly. Definitely decided a few times to make decisions that differed from its advice partially or completely, and I sometimes ran suggested next steps by several close friends/family to make sure I wasn't missing something obvious. But the ideas/path ChatGPT suggested, the chasing down different scenarios to rule in/out them, and coaching me through this is what ultimately got movement on our case.&lt;p&gt;10 days post denial, I was able to get the procedure approved from these efforts.&lt;p&gt;21 days post denial and 7 days after the decision was reversed, we lucked into a surgery slot that opened up and my child got their life saving surgery. They have recovered and is in the best health of the past 18 months.&lt;p&gt;This maybe isn't leveling the playing field, at least not entirely. But it gave us a fighting chance on a short timeline and know where to best use our pressure. The hopeful part of me is that many others can use similar techniques to win.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2025 18:39:04 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45736945</link><dc:creator>chrisgeleven</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45736945</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45736945</guid></item><item><title>New comment by ecosystem in "Using AI to negotiate a $195k hospital bill down to $33k"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;The American Medical Association owns copyright to all the codes and their descriptions. They have an extremely restrictive and expensive licensing options and they strictly forbid training models with the codes.&lt;p&gt;This month, the practice was called out (&lt;a href="https://www.help.senate.gov/rep/newsroom/press/chair-cassidy-rebukes-ama-for-abusing-cpt-system-raising-health-care-costs-on-american-families" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://www.help.senate.gov/rep/newsroom/press/chair-cassidy...&lt;/a&gt;) so the Overton window may be opening.&lt;p&gt;The AMA (a nonprofit!) clears ~$300M/year revenue from the codes, which is the direct cost passed through to consumers, but the indirect costs are the byzantine nightmare of OP.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2025 16:55:21 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45735410</link><dc:creator>ecosystem</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45735410</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45735410</guid></item><item><title>New comment by ibash in "Using AI to negotiate a $195k hospital bill down to $33k"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;The thing is the prices are all made up anyway. The hospital hallucinates prices, so they don’t blink an eye when an llm does the same.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2025 16:24:17 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45734931</link><dc:creator>ibash</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45734931</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45734931</guid></item><item><title>New comment by no_wizard in "The next chapter of the Microsoft–OpenAI partnership"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;They’ll devalue the term into something that makes it so. The common conception of it however, no I don’t believe we are anywhere close to it.&lt;p&gt;It’s no different than how they moved the goalpost on the definition of AI at the start of this boom cycle&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2025 14:11:56 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45733156</link><dc:creator>no_wizard</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45733156</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45733156</guid></item><item><title>New comment by philipwhiuk in "The next chapter of the Microsoft–OpenAI partnership"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&gt; Once AGI is declared by OpenAI, that declaration will now be verified by an independent expert panel.&lt;p&gt;&gt; Microsoft’s IP rights for both models and products are extended through 2032 and now includes models post-AGI, with appropriate safety guardrails.&lt;p&gt;Does anyone really think we are close to AGI? I mean honestly?&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2025 14:01:00 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45733027</link><dc:creator>philipwhiuk</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45733027</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45733027</guid></item><item><title>New comment by phoe-krk in "Amazon confirms 14,000 job losses in corporate division"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;These aren't "job losses", these are "firings". They aren't unfortunate accidents of external origin that happened to them, they are conscious internal decisions to let people go.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2025 12:01:20 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45731677</link><dc:creator>phoe-krk</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45731677</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45731677</guid></item><item><title>New comment by simonw in "10M people watched a YouTuber shim a lock; the lock company sued him – bad idea"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;This reminded me of Matt Blaze's work on physical lock security back in 2003. He found a method of deriving the "master key" for a building (one key that opens all locks) from a single example: &lt;a href="https://www.mattblaze.org/masterkey.html" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://www.mattblaze.org/masterkey.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;When he published about this he was bombarded with messages from locksmiths complaining that they all knew about this and kept it secret for a reason! &lt;a href="https://www.mattblaze.org/papers/kiss.html" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://www.mattblaze.org/papers/kiss.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;It was a fascinating clash between computer security principles - disclose vulnerabilities - and physical locksmith culture, which was all about trade secrets.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2025 09:32:06 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45730792</link><dc:creator>simonw</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45730792</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45730792</guid></item><item><title>New comment by tgsovlerkhgsel in "PSF has withdrawn $1.5M proposal to US Government grant program"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;This is how DEI &lt;i&gt;should&lt;/i&gt; work, and probably does in some, or maybe many, cases.&lt;p&gt;In other cases, it boiled down to "this quarter, we only have headcount for 'diverse' candidates", metrics for DEI hiring that turn into goals, and e-mails stating "only accept new L3 candidates that are from historically underrepresented groups".&lt;p&gt;I expect that I'll get accused of making this up, which is why the latter is an exact quote shown on page 28 in this court case: &lt;a href="https://www.scribd.com/document/372802863/18-CIV-00442-ARNE-WILBERG-vs-GOOGLE-INC-et-al" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://www.scribd.com/document/372802863/18-CIV-00442-ARNE-...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2025 23:59:33 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45727817</link><dc:creator>tgsovlerkhgsel</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45727817</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45727817</guid></item><item><title>New comment by dekhn in "10M people watched a YouTuber shim a lock; the lock company sued him – bad idea"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I once worked for a company that kept its passwords locked in a safe.  One day, all other copies of the password were lost, and they needed it, but the safe's key could not be found.&lt;p&gt;They expensed a sledgehammer and obtained the password through physical modification of the safe using a careful application of force.  Some employees complained that meant the safe wasn't... well, safe.&lt;p&gt;The security team replied "Working as Intended" - no safe is truly safe, it's just designed to slow down an attacker.  At that moment, I was enlightened.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2025 23:34:21 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45727604</link><dc:creator>dekhn</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45727604</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45727604</guid></item><item><title>New comment by th in "PSF has withdrawn $1.5M proposal to US Government grant program"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;It seems like a number of the "DEI is anti-merit discrimination" messages in this thread are overlooking how DEI work usually works.&lt;p&gt;A relevant tweet from 2016 (&lt;a href="https://x.com/jessicamckellar/status/737299461563502595" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://x.com/jessicamckellar/status/737299461563502595&lt;/a&gt;):&lt;p&gt;&gt; Hello from your @PyCon Diversity Chair. % PyCon talks by women: (2011: 1%), (2012: 7%), (2013: 15%), (2014/15: 33%), (2016: 40%). #pycon2016&lt;p&gt;Increased diversity in communities usually comes from active outreach work. PyCon's talk selection process starts blinded.&lt;p&gt;If 300 people submit talks and 294 are men, then 98% of talks will likely be from men.&lt;p&gt;If 500 people submit talks and 394 are men, then ~79% will likely be by men.&lt;p&gt;Outreach to encourage folks to apply/join/run/etc. can make a big difference in the makeup of applicants and the makeup of the end results. Bucking the trend even during just one year can start a snowball effect that moves the needle further in future years.&lt;p&gt;The world doesn't run on merit. Who you know, whether you've been invited in to the club, and whether you feel you belong all affect where you end up. So unusually homogenous communities (which feel hard for outsiders to break into) can arise even without deliberate discrimination.&lt;p&gt;Organizations like the PSF could choose to say "let's avoid outreach work and simply accept the status quo forever", but I would much rather see the Python community become more diverse and welcoming over time.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2025 22:15:41 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45726973</link><dc:creator>th</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45726973</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45726973</guid></item><item><title>New comment by jkelleyrtp in "PSF has withdrawn $1.5M proposal to US Government grant program"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;In high school, I ran a robotics team that did lots of STEM outreach. We went to community centers, after school programs, and worked with other similar orgs like "girls who code."&lt;p&gt;I think we played an important role in the community. In our mission we stated we wanted to help bring "equity to STEM education."&lt;p&gt;In 2025, according to the current admin's stance on "DEI," my robotics team would not be able to receive grants without risk of being sued. It's plainly obvious the line is not drawn at restraining "overly progressive policies" - it's just arbitrarily placed so the govt can pick and choose the winners based on allegiance.&lt;p&gt;It's a shame that folks with a strong moral fiber are now punished for wanting to help their communities.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2025 21:58:30 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45726825</link><dc:creator>jkelleyrtp</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45726825</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45726825</guid></item><item><title>New comment by elicash in "PSF has withdrawn $1.5M proposal to US Government grant program"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;On the one hand, the plain text of the language is not against DEI practices in general -- only DEI practices that are "in violation of Federal anti-discrimination laws."&lt;p&gt;On the other hand, the federal government has gone after law firms that are not actually in violation of law and forced settlements due to their DEI programs, so you can't actually trust that you won't be hassled. Additionally, that you won't at minimum have the money clawed back, even if the claims are meritless, as the administration has done on Congressionally appropriated funds repeatedly as part of DOGE efforts.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2025 21:22:08 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45726457</link><dc:creator>elicash</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45726457</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45726457</guid></item><item><title>New comment by crazygringo in "Study finds growing social circles may fuel polarization"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&gt; &lt;i&gt;"Despite minor differences between individual surveys, the data consistently show that the average number of close friendships rose from 2.2 in 2000 to 4.1 in 2024," says Hofer.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;p&gt;If true, this is an astonishing social transformation, because it goes against everything we here about the loneliness epidemic getting &lt;i&gt;worse&lt;/i&gt;.&lt;p&gt;Or have people redefined what they consider to be "close friends"? Or are people actually genuinely maintaining more friendships because phones make it so much easier to message?&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2025 21:13:40 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45726363</link><dc:creator>crazygringo</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45726363</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45726363</guid></item><item><title>New comment by Scubabear68 in "Claude for Excel"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Having wrangled many spreadsheets personally, and worked with CFOs who use them to run small-ish businesses, and all the way up to one of top 3 brokerage houses world-wide using them to model complex fixed income instruments... this is a disaster waiting to happen.&lt;p&gt;Spreadsheet UI is already a nightmare. The formula editing and relationship visioning is not there at all. Mistakes are rampant in spreadsheets, even my own carefully curated ones.&lt;p&gt;Claude is not going to improve this. It is going to make it far, far worse with subtle and not so subtle hallucinations happening left and right.&lt;p&gt;The key is really this - all LLMs that I know of rely on entropy and randomness to emulate human creativity. This works pretty well for pretty pictures and creating fan fiction or emulating someone's voice.&lt;p&gt;It is not a basis for getting correct spreadsheets that show what you want to show. I don't want my spreadsheet correctness to start from a random seed. I want it to spring from first principles.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2025 20:33:37 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45725940</link><dc:creator>Scubabear68</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45725940</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45725940</guid></item><item><title>New comment by rdtsc in "10M people watched a YouTuber shim a lock; the lock company sued him – bad idea"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&gt; On July 7, the company dismissed the lawsuit against McNally instead.&lt;p&gt;&gt; Proven also made a highly unusual request: Would the judge please seal almost the entire court record—including the request to seal?&lt;p&gt;Tough at first then running away with the tail between their legs. Typical bullying behavior.&lt;p&gt;&gt; but Proven complained about a “pattern of intimidation and harassment by individuals influenced by Defendant McNally’s content.”&lt;p&gt;They have to know it's generated by their own lawsuit and how they approached it, right? They can't be that oblivious to turn around and say "Judge, look at all the craziness this generated, we just have to seal the records!". It's like an ice-cream cone that licks itself.&lt;p&gt;&gt; the case became a classic example of the Streisand Effect, in which the attempt to censor information can instead call attention to it.&lt;p&gt;A constant reminder to keep the people who don't know what they are doing (including the owners of the company!) from the social media.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2025 19:18:00 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45725152</link><dc:creator>rdtsc</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45725152</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45725152</guid></item><item><title>New comment by neilv in "JetKVM – Control any computer remotely"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Provenance and trust are relevant for a remote KVM.&lt;p&gt;But I can't find any information on their Web site about who runs the JetKVM company, not even a partial name or handle of anyone, nor even what country they are in.  Which seems odd for how much this product needs to be trusted.&lt;p&gt;Searching elsewhere, other than the company Web site... Crunchbase for JetKVM shows 2 people, who it says are based in Berlin, and who also share a principal company, BuildJet, which Crunchbase says is based in Estonia.  The product reportedly ships from Shenzhen.  BuildJet apparently is a YC company, but BuildJet's Web site has very similar lack of info identifying anyone or their location, again despite the high level of trust required for this product.&lt;p&gt;Are corporate customers who are putting these products into positions of serious trust -- into their CI, and remote access to inside their infrastructure -- doing any kind of vetting?  When the official Web sites have zero information about who this is, are the customers getting the information some other way, before purchasing and deploying?&lt;p&gt;If these people are still running the companies, why aren't they or anyone else mentioned on the company Web sites?  That would be helpful first step for trust for corporate use.  So its absence is odd.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2025 18:59:42 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45724932</link><dc:creator>neilv</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45724932</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45724932</guid></item><item><title>New comment by jimbokun in "10M people watched a YouTuber shim a lock; the lock company sued him – bad idea"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&gt; Under questioning, however, one of Proven’s employees admitted that he had been able to duplicate McNally’s technique, leading to the question from McNally’s lawyer: “When you did it yourself, did it occur to you for one moment that maybe the best thing to do, instead of file a lawsuit, was to fix [the lock]?”&lt;p&gt;Sometimes a single question tells you how the entire case is going to go.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2025 18:58:18 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45724914</link><dc:creator>jimbokun</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45724914</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45724914</guid></item><item><title>New comment by OkayPhysicist in "10M people watched a YouTuber shim a lock; the lock company sued him – bad idea"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;LPL owns Covert Instruments, who employs McNally, the YouTuber who got sued in this case. Probably not a coincidence that Covert Instruments &lt;i&gt;wasn't&lt;/i&gt; named in the lawsuit.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2025 18:41:56 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45724734</link><dc:creator>OkayPhysicist</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45724734</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45724734</guid></item><item><title>New comment by jwr in "10M people watched a YouTuber shim a lock; the lock company sued him – bad idea"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;If you don't know him already, I highly recommend videos by LockPickingLawyer — he routinely destroys bogus claims of various companies within seconds. It's quite entertaining to see how little security you actually get from most locks.&lt;p&gt;I wonder if anybody tried suing him…&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2025 18:15:40 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45724434</link><dc:creator>jwr</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45724434</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45724434</guid></item><item><title>New comment by jedberg in "Avoid 2:00 and 3:00 am cron jobs (2013)"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I've told this story before, but it's super relevant here.  When I set up all the servers for reddit, I set them all to Arizona time.  Arizona does not have DST, and is only one hour off of California (where we all were) for five months, and the same as here the rest of the year.&lt;p&gt;I didn't use UTC because subtracting eight when reading raw logs is a lot harder than subtracting one.&lt;p&gt;They use UTC now, which makes sense since they have a global workforce and log reading interfaces that can automatically change timezones on display.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2025 17:44:17 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45724071</link><dc:creator>jedberg</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45724071</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45724071</guid></item><item><title>New comment by extr in "Claude for Excel"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;What is with the negativity in these comments? This is a huge, huge surface area that touches a large percentage of white collar work. Even just basic automation/scaffolding of spreadsheets would be a big productivity boost for many employees.&lt;p&gt;My wife works in insurance operations - everyone she manages from the top down lives in Excel. For line employees a large percentage of their job is something like "Look at this internal system, export the data to excel, combine it with some other internal system, do some basic interpretation, verify it, make a recommendation". Computer Use + Excel Use isn't there yet...but these jobs are going to be the first on the chopping block as these integrations mature. No offense to these people but Sonnet 4.5 is already at the level where it would be able to replicate or beat the level of analysis they typically provide.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2025 16:45:12 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45723179</link><dc:creator>extr</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45723179</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45723179</guid></item><item><title>New comment by jihadjihad in "It's insulting to read AI-generated blog posts"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;It's similarly insulting to read your AI-generated pull request. If I see another "dart-on-target" emoji...&lt;p&gt;You're telling me I need to use 100% of my brain, reasoning power, and time to go over your code, but you didn't feel the need to hold yourself to the same standard?&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2025 16:38:07 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45723057</link><dc:creator>jihadjihad</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45723057</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45723057</guid></item><item><title>New comment by aspir in "PSF has withdrawn $1.5M proposal to US Government grant program"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;This isn't good for the PSF, but if these "poison pill" terms are a pattern that applies to all NSF and (presumably) other government research funding, the entire state of modern scientific research is at risk.&lt;p&gt;Regardless of how you, as an individual, might feel about "DEI," imposing onerous political terms on scientific grants harms everyone in the long term.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2025 15:50:59 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45722391</link><dc:creator>aspir</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45722391</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45722391</guid></item><item><title>New comment by ProllyInfamous in "10M people watched a YouTuber shim a lock; the lock company sued him – bad idea"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Back in 2007, I published the first YouTube bypass of the Master Lock #175 (very common 4-digit code lock), using a paperclip.&lt;p&gt;After the video reached 1.5M views (over a couple years), the video was eventually demonetized (no official reason given). I suspect there was a similarly-frivolous DMCA / claim, but at that point in my life I didn't have any money (was worth &lt;i&gt;negative&lt;/i&gt;) so I just accepted YouTube's ruling.&lt;p&gt;Eventually shut down the account, not wanting to help thieves bypass one of the most-common utility locks around — but definitely am in a position now where I understand that videos like mine and McNally's force manufacturers to actually improve their locks' securities/mechanisms.&lt;p&gt;It is lovely now to see that the tolerances on the #175 have been tightened enough that a paperclip no longer defeats the lock (at least non-destructively); but thin high-tensile picks still do the trick (of bypassing the lock) via the exact same mechanism.&lt;p&gt;Locks keep honest people honest, but to claim Master's products &lt;i&gt;high security&lt;/i&gt; is inherently dishonest (e.g. in their advertising). Thievery is about ease of opportunity; if I were stealing from a jobsite with multiple lockboxes, the ones with Master locks would be attacked first (particularly wafer cylinders).&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2025 15:30:19 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45722107</link><dc:creator>ProllyInfamous</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45722107</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45722107</guid></item><item><title>New comment by everdrive in "What happened to running what you wanted on your own machine?"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;It's important to understand that we could genuinely lose general purpose computing. I don't think it's in serious danger at the moment, but we've been in the midst of a slide in that direction for the last 10-15 years. Part of it is mobile phones, part of it is TPM, part of it is market forces. The latest turn is strictly political. We've really foolishly built the technology necessary for authoritarianism just a few years head of a general global trend towards authoritarianism. At the moment, anyone can use Linux; it's better and easier than ever. Will the laws of your country make it harder or more difficult to avoid? Will major vendors lock you out of basic functions? Will age verification require an agent run on your Windows or macOS computer? (or worse, require the use of a smart phone just to use the internet?)&lt;p&gt;We're not anywhere there yet, but we're closer than we've ever been, and things keep moving in the wrong direction.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2025 13:15:25 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45720707</link><dc:creator>everdrive</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45720707</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45720707</guid></item><item><title>New comment by bre1010 in "You are how you act"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;[flagged]&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2025 12:10:54 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45720066</link><dc:creator>bre1010</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45720066</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45720066</guid></item><item><title>New comment by varenc in "We saved $500k per year by rolling our own "S3""</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;In HN style, I'm going to diverge from the content and rant about the company:&lt;p&gt;Nanit needs this storage because they run cloud based baby cameras.  Every Nanit user is uploading video and audio of their home/baby
live to Nanit without any E2EE. It's a hot mic sending anything you say near it to the cloud.&lt;p&gt;Their hardware essentially requires a subscription to use, even though it costs $200/camera. You must spend an additional $200 on a Nanit floor stand if you want sleep tracking. This is purely a software limitation since there's plenty of other ways to get an overhead camera mount. (I'm curious how they even detect if you're using the stand since it's just a USB-C cable. Maybe etags?)&lt;p&gt;Of course Nanit is a popular and successful product that many parents swear by. It just pains me to see cloud based in-home audio/video storage being so normalized. Self-hosted video isn't that hard but no one makes a baby-monitor centric solution. I'm sure the cloud based video storage model will continue to be popular because it's easy, but also because it helps justifies a recurring subscription.&lt;p&gt;edit: just noticed an irony in my comment. I'm ranting about Nanit locking users into their 3rd party cloud video storage, and the article is about Nanit's engineering team moving off a 3rd party (S3) and self-hosting their own storage.  Props to them for getting off S3.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2025 04:22:35 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45717363</link><dc:creator>varenc</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45717363</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45717363</guid></item></channel></rss>