<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>Hacker News: Best Comments</title><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/bestcomments</link><description>Hacker News RSS</description><docs>https://hnrss.org/</docs><generator>hnrss v2.1.1</generator><lastBuildDate>Sat, 17 Jan 2026 00:07:07 +0000</lastBuildDate><ns0:link href="https://hnrss.org/bestcomments" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item><title>New comment by pavlov in "Cursor's latest “browser experiment” implied success without evidence"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;The comment that points out that this week-long experiment produced nothing more than a non-functional wrapper for Servo (an existing Rust browser) should be at the top:&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46649046"&gt;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46649046&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 19:45:33 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46651198</link><dc:creator>pavlov</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46651198</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46651198</guid></item><item><title>New comment by athenot in "STFU"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;This is a fun app.&lt;p&gt;One way I deal with people talking on speakerphone, is inviting myself into their conversation and making comments as if I were an active participant. That usually earns me a weird look, and then they go off speaker so I can't hear what's been said. Success.&lt;p&gt;Similar with folks watching reels on speaker, I fake a laugh or make comments about the content. It's awkward enough that they usually stop because they want a moment alone, not an interactive session with a stranger. Which ironically is the same thing I want too.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 19:16:26 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46650791</link><dc:creator>athenot</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46650791</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46650791</guid></item><item><title>New comment by wrs in "Our approach to advertising"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;This sounds exactly like what Google used to say about search results. Just a few ads, clearly separated from organic results, never detracting from the core mission of providing the most effective access to all the world’s information. (And certainly not driven by a secret profile of you based on pervasive surveillance of your internet activity.)&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 19:14:06 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46650756</link><dc:creator>wrs</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46650756</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46650756</guid></item><item><title>New comment by throw0101d in "Canada slashes 100% tariffs on Chinese EVs to 6%"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;A Canadian satire site has the headline "Canada chooses lawful evil over chaotic evil":&lt;p&gt;* &lt;a href="https://thebeaverton.com/2026/01/canada-chooses-lawful-evil-over-chaotic-evil/" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://thebeaverton.com/2026/01/canada-chooses-lawful-evil-...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;* &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Alignment_(Dungeons_%26_Dragons)" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Alignment_(Dungeons_%26_Dragon...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;Edit: A comment in /r/canada:&lt;p&gt;&gt; &lt;i&gt;TBF I would much rather work for Lex Luthor than The Joker if I had to choose one.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 18:05:30 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46649624</link><dc:creator>throw0101d</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46649624</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46649624</guid></item><item><title>New comment by cush in "Lock-Picking Robot"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;The number of comments in here slandering the developer’s morality for picking locks is actually pretty surprising for a site literally called Hacker News. Every day there’s a story on the front page of some grey/white-hat showing off an exploit they found to infiltrate a site we all use. It’s an odd double standard.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 16:24:25 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46648198</link><dc:creator>cush</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46648198</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46648198</guid></item><item><title>New comment by OptionOfT in "Dev-owned testing: Why it fails in practice and succeeds in theory"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;The conversation is usually: devs can write their own tests. We don't need QA.&lt;p&gt;And the first part is true. We can. But that's not why we have (had) QA.&lt;p&gt;First: it's not the best use of our time. I believe dev and QA are separate skillset. Of course there is overlap.&lt;p&gt;Second, and most important: it's a separate person, an additional person who can question the ticket, and who can question my translation of the ticket into software.&lt;p&gt;And lastly: they don't suffer from the curse of knowledge on how I implemented the ticket.&lt;p&gt;I miss my QA colleagues. When I joined my current employer there were 8 or so. Initially I was afraid to give them my work, afraid of bad feedback.&lt;p&gt;Never have I met such graceful people who took the time in understanding something, and talking to me to figure out where there was a mismatch.&lt;p&gt;And then they were deemed not needed.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 15:01:48 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46647035</link><dc:creator>OptionOfT</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46647035</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46647035</guid></item><item><title>New comment by agnishom in "Briar keeps Iran connected via Bluetooth and Wi-Fi when the internet goes dark"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;This should be a lesson for all of us. We should start building and maintaining lightweight mesh networks, just in case. We shouldn't take the world of cooperating ISPs and Meta and Cloudflare and Google and AWS for granted.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 09:08:05 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46644551</link><dc:creator>agnishom</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46644551</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46644551</guid></item><item><title>New comment by sailfast in "Ask HN: How can we solve the loneliness epidemic?"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;In my experience, the problem is not a low success rate, but the burnout from being the only person that invites people to do things. At a certain point you want to see some reciprocation to create community. It can definitely happen, but a lot of folks still fall back on the habits. You have to invite and then also start asking people who's gonna host the next one and get them on the hook, and then not burnout from being a constant organizer :)&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 23:21:22 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46640869</link><dc:creator>sailfast</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46640869</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46640869</guid></item><item><title>New comment by eagsalazar2 in "Ask HN: How can we solve the loneliness epidemic?"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I love this but I think you'll be surprised at your success rate.  &lt;i&gt;Everyone&lt;/i&gt; is struggling with this, not just you.  Right on the heels of covid we were debating whether to have a NYE party or just go to a friend's house for a low key thing.  We were paralyzed a bit feeling like, why we weren't invited to other parties ourselves?  Won't everyone already be busy doing other stuff?  In the end my wife took the leap and invited a ton of neighbors and friends.  Guess what??  Almost everyone showed up!  Which means all those people were going to be sitting at home feeling bad and wondering the same thing.  You just need to believe and get over it, people want to hang out.  We've all just gotten out of the habit.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 23:01:10 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46640660</link><dc:creator>eagsalazar2</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46640660</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46640660</guid></item><item><title>New comment by neilk in "Ask HN: How can we solve the loneliness epidemic?"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;You have to be the one who creates things to do.&lt;p&gt;Really, that’s it.&lt;p&gt;You want to play D&amp;D together, you host and DM.&lt;p&gt;You want to just hang out, you reach out and propose what you’re doing.&lt;p&gt;You want more purposeful and meaningful time, join a volunteer group you vibe with.&lt;p&gt;Even if it’s meeting for coffee. You have to be the one who reaches out. You have to do it on a regular cadence. If, like me, you don’t have little alarms in your head that go off when you haven’t seen someone in a while, you can use automated reminders.&lt;p&gt;I have observed my spouse (who is not on social media) do this and she maintains friendships for decades this way. Nowadays she has regular zoom check ins, book clubs, and more, even with people who moved to the other coast. You do now have the tools for this. I have adopted it into my own life with good results.&lt;p&gt;Note: you are going to get well under a 50% success rate here. Accept that most people flake. It may always feel painful (and nerds like us often are rejection-sensitive). You have to feel your feelings, accept it, and move on.&lt;p&gt;You are struggling against many aspects of the way we in the developed world/nerd world live. We have a wealth of passive entertainment, often we have all consuming jobs or have more time-consuming relationship with our families than our parents ever did. We move to different cities for jobs, and even as suburban sprawl has grown, you’re on average probably further away from people who even live in the same city! You get from place to place in a private box on wheels, or alternatively in a really big box on wheels with a random assortment of people. You don’t see people at church, or market day, or whatever other rituals our ancestors had. On the positive side, you have more tools and leisure than ever before to arrange more voluntary meetings.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 22:30:58 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46640332</link><dc:creator>neilk</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46640332</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46640332</guid></item><item><title>New comment by disconcision in "Claude is good at assembling blocks, but still falls apart at creating them"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I've yet to be convinced by any article, including this one, that attempts to draw boxes around what coding agents are and aren't good at in a way that is robust on a 6 to 12 month horizon.&lt;p&gt;I agree that the examples listed here are relatable, and I've seen similar in my uses of various coding harnesses, including, to some degree, ones driven by opus 4.5. But my general experience with using LLMs for development over the last few years has been that:&lt;p&gt;1. Initially models could at best assemble a simple procedural or compositional sequences of commands or functions to accomplish a basic goal, perhaps meeting tests or type checking, but with no overall coherence,&lt;p&gt;2. To being able to structure small functions reasonably,&lt;p&gt;3. To being able to structure large functions reasonably,&lt;p&gt;4. To being able to structure medium-sized files reasonably,&lt;p&gt;5. To being able to structure large files, and small multi-file subsystems, somewhat reasonably.&lt;p&gt;So the idea that they are now falling down on the multi-module or multi-file or multi-microservice level is both not particularly surprising to me and also both not particularly indicative of future performance. There is a hierarchy of scales at which abstraction can be applied, and it seems plausible to me that the march of capability improvement is a continuous push upwards in the scale at which agents can reasonably abstract code.&lt;p&gt;Alternatively, there could be that there is a legitimate discontinuity here, at which anything resembling current approaches will max out, but I don't see strong evidence for it here.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 22:09:24 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46640068</link><dc:creator>disconcision</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46640068</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46640068</guid></item><item><title>New comment by asdfman123 in "Ask HN: How can we solve the loneliness epidemic?"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I think the trick is getting off social media.&lt;p&gt;When I was a computer nerd in the 2000s, I noticed people used to like to hang around and chat, but I mostly didn't.&lt;p&gt;Now, everyone is an internet addict, and I was just ahead of the curve. No one hangs around and chats anymore.&lt;p&gt;When you get off social media, real life becomes far more interesting. The problem with addiction is that it's so stimulating that everything else is boring. You have to let your mind reset.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 19:22:23 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46637748</link><dc:creator>asdfman123</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46637748</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46637748</guid></item><item><title>New comment by pixelready in "‘ELITE’: The Palantir app ICE uses to find neighborhoods to raid"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I’ve never worked at Palantir, but once you get past the noisy leadership’s villain virtue signaling, every report I’ve read about the platform itself gives me strong “typical enterprise vendor” vibes. A lackluster software offering that is overhyped to institutional purchasers, then shoved down frontline employees’ throats because the vendor is good at navigating the sales and compliance labyrinth to secure deals.&lt;p&gt;The goals and motivation for using these tools, and their broad allowance of access to what should be highly controlled data (or in some cases even not collected at all) is the problem. Don’t give Palantir the bad-boy street cred they crave, focus on the policy decisions that are leading to agencies wanting tools like this in the first place.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 19:16:58 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46637660</link><dc:creator>pixelready</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46637660</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46637660</guid></item><item><title>New comment by ecshafer in "Ask HN: How can we solve the loneliness epidemic?"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;People need to purposefully and intentionally do things. Sitting home on an app, watching TV is easy. There is no fear or rejection, there is no work to get out of the house, there is no risk. But there is also no reward.&lt;p&gt;My thoughts on this are you need to have multiple roots into your community. This is something that you go to often and talk to people, become a regular, say hi. Think back to how your parents or grandparents did it: They went to church/temple/synagogue, they went to PTA meetings, they talked to their neighbors, they were in clubs, they went to the same bar.&lt;p&gt;So I think doing things that get you out of the house, consistently the most important part:&lt;p&gt;1. People need to make a point to talk to their neighbors, invite them over for dinner or bbqs, make small talk. How towns are constructed now is a hindrance to this (unwalkable towns where all of the houses are big garages in the front and no porches).&lt;p&gt;2. Join a religious organization. Go to church, but also join the mens/womens group, join a bible studies class. Attend every week.&lt;p&gt;3. Join social clubs / ethnic organization. The polish or ukrainian clubs, knights of columbus, elks, freemasons. Go every week.&lt;p&gt;4. Join a club / league. Chess club, bowling league, softball league, golf league. Tech meetups, DnD Night etc. But you have to talk with people and try to elevate things to friendships.&lt;p&gt;5. Have lunch, happy hour, etc with coworkers.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 18:50:41 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46637259</link><dc:creator>ecshafer</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46637259</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46637259</guid></item><item><title>New comment by asa400 in "The Palantir app helping ICE raids in Minneapolis"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;First, all of what you say is true. I'm going to try to add a little context as someone who is here on the ground, in the city in question.&lt;p&gt;There is the imminent threat of mass death, and no one here is under any illusions about it.&lt;p&gt;Every ICE agent is armed, and most have ready access to automatic weapons. These are not well-trained members of an elite organization with a storied, patriotic culture. ICE is a personalist paramilitary organization, and the president has indicated that these ICE agents are immune from consequences, even if they kill people. These are people who volunteered knowing they were going to go into American cities and do violence to people they perceive as their political enemies.&lt;p&gt;Most of these agents are inexperienced, jittery, poorly trained new recruits away from home. They aren't locals. Their nexus of power and governance isn't local. These are not our community members, they aren't from here, they don't know us or care about us, so they do not empathize with us.&lt;p&gt;In addition to this, the American citizenry is shockingly well armed. Because everyone involved is so well armed, everybody is slightly touchy about this descending into rioting, because there is a very short path from light rioting to what would essentially amount to civil war. The costs of such any such violence will overwhelmingly be borne by the innocent people who live here, and we know it.&lt;p&gt;So, people are trying to strike a balance of making sure these people know they aren't welcome here while trying to prevent the situation from spiraling into one in which some terrified agent mag-dumps a crowd of protestors and causes a chain reaction that results in truly catastrophic mass death.&lt;p&gt;Wish us luck, we're trying.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 17:49:18 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46636371</link><dc:creator>asa400</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46636371</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46636371</guid></item><item><title>New comment by bakje in "GitHub Incident"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Perhaps the gemini-cli bot arguing with itself is taking its toll&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/google-gemini/gemini-cli/issues/16750" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://github.com/google-gemini/gemini-cli/issues/16750&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 17:44:07 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46636291</link><dc:creator>bakje</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46636291</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46636291</guid></item><item><title>New comment by thunderbong in "25 Years of Wikipedia"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;In the 2000s, in the tech world, the open source successes that were being talked about was always Apache and Linux.&lt;p&gt;When Wikipedia started gaining a bit of traction, everyone made fun of it. It was the butt of jokes in all the prime time comedy shows. And I always felt like telling the critics - "Don't you see what is happening? People all over the world are adding their own bits of knowledge and creating this huge thing way beyond what we've seen till now. It's cooperation on an international scale! By regular people! This is what the internet is all about. People, by the thousands, are contributing without asking for anything else in return. This is incredible! "&lt;p&gt;A few years later, Encyclopedia Britannica, stopped their print edition. A few years after that I read that Wikipedia had surpassed even that.&lt;p&gt;The amount of value Wikipedia brings to the world is incalculable.&lt;p&gt;And I'm very fortunate to be alive at a time where I can witness something at this scale. Something that transcends borders and boundaries. Something that goes beyond our daily vices of politics and religion. Something that tries to bring a lot of balance and objectivity in today's polarized world.&lt;p&gt;Thank you, Wikipedia.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 17:25:07 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46635979</link><dc:creator>thunderbong</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46635979</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46635979</guid></item><item><title>New comment by publicdebates in "Ask HN: How can we solve the loneliness epidemic?"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I'm also in this group, so I have a few theories as to what causes it and how to fix it.&lt;p&gt;For one thing, I was severely traumatized as a kid, which delayed a lot of my social skills. I'm catching up but not all the way there yet. When my social battery is full, I can do pretty well, but if I'm even a little down, it's basically impossible to act normally.&lt;p&gt;I also had it hammered into me as a kid that nobody wants me around, nobody could ever love me, I'm a failure, a burden, a creep, a weirdo, and nothing but a bothersome nuisance that nobody would ever want to spend 30 seconds alone with. I'm trying to reject these thoughts, but it's difficult when you have nobody to talk to. It's like pulling yourself up by your bootstraps. I wonder how many people have the same issue. I've made a few friends in person, but I rarely get to see them.&lt;p&gt;Well I've started doing public surveys in my nearby big city, and documenting the results. I just hold out a posterboard that says "how alone do you feel"[1] or "have you ever been in love" etc, and hold out a marker, and people come up and take the survey. At first I did this out of sheer loneliness and boredom. But I have done it for enough months that some people have come up to me and told me that I've helped them, or that they look forward to my signs.&lt;p&gt;I'm trying to reach those people who feel the way I feel have no way of connecting with anyone, or at least feel that they don't. Do you have any new ideas of how to achieve this?&lt;p&gt;[1] &lt;a href="https://chicagosignguy.com/blog/how-alone-do-you-feel.html" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://chicagosignguy.com/blog/how-alone-do-you-feel.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 16:57:19 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46635483</link><dc:creator>publicdebates</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46635483</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46635483</guid></item><item><title>New comment by anoojb in "Apple is fighting for TSMC capacity as Nvidia takes center stage"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;So let's say TMSC reciprocated Apple's consistency as a customer by giving them preferential treatment for capacity. It's good business after all.&lt;p&gt;However, everyone knows that good faith reciprocity at that scale is not rewarded. Apple is ruthless. There are probably thousands of untold stories of how hard Apple has hammered it's suppliers over the years.&lt;p&gt;While Apple has good consumer brand loyalty, they arguably treat their suppliers relatively poorly compared to the Gold standard like Costco.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 16:43:55 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46635261</link><dc:creator>anoojb</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46635261</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46635261</guid></item><item><title>New comment by embedding-shape in "The Palantir app helping ICE raids in Minneapolis"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;If all those things happened in Spain where I live, I'm 99% we'd have actual riots on the streets, together with a lot of other unpleasant-but-needed civilian action, until things got better, like we've done in the past (sometimes maybe went slightly overboard with it, but better than nothing).&lt;p&gt;Why are Americans so passive? You're literally transitioning into straight up authoritarianism, yet where are the riots? How are you not fighting back with more than whistles and blocking them in cars? Is there more stuff actually happening on the ground, but there simply isn't any videos of it, or are people really this passive in the land of the free?&lt;p&gt;Are people inside the country not getting the same news we're getting on the outside? Are you not witnessing your government carrying out extra-judicial murders and then being protected by that same government? I'm really lost trying to understand how the average person (like you reading this) isn't out on the streets trying to defend what I thought your country was all about.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 16:41:01 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46635212</link><dc:creator>embedding-shape</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46635212</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46635212</guid></item><item><title>New comment by chinathrow in "The Palantir app helping ICE raids in Minneapolis"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;If you work for Palantir and if you work on these systems: You have blood on your hands. You know that it's not right what is happening on the ground right now. Do something.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 15:38:09 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46634046</link><dc:creator>chinathrow</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46634046</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46634046</guid></item><item><title>New comment by andrewvc in "The Palantir app helping ICE raids in Minneapolis"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;For an idea as to how this gets translated into the reality on the ground here in Minneapolis this is an article on what’s going on from the main newspaper in the state.&lt;p&gt;&gt; In the past week alone, ICE boxed in a Woodbury real estate agent recording their movements from his car, slammed him to the ground and detained him at the Whipple Federal Building near Fort Snelling for 10 hours. A 51-year-old teacher patrolling the Nokomis East community told the Star Tribune she was run off the road into a snowbank by ICE for laying on her horn. Officers shattered the car window of a woman attempting to drive past a raid in south Minneapolis to get to a doctor’s appointment nearby, then carried her through the street. Feds pushed an unidentified motorist through a red light into a busy intersection, reportedly fired projectiles at a pedestrian walking “too slowly” in a crosswalk and shoved Minneapolis City Council President Elliott Payne while he was observing their actions from a public sidewalk.&lt;p&gt;You can read the full thing here: &lt;a href="https://www.startribune.com/have-yall-not-learned-federal-agents-target-legal-observers-in-the-aftermath-of-good-shooting/601562804" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://www.startribune.com/have-yall-not-learned-federal-ag...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 15:27:10 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46633847</link><dc:creator>andrewvc</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46633847</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46633847</guid></item><item><title>New comment by Fiveplus in "Apple is fighting for TSMC capacity as Nvidia takes center stage"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Calling Nvidia niche feels a bit wild given their status-quo right now, but from a foundry perspective, it seems true. Apple is the anchor tenant that keeps the lights on across 12 different mature and leading-edge fabs.&lt;p&gt;Nvidia is the high-frequency trader hammering the newest node until the arb closes. Stability usually trades at a discount during a boom, but Wei knows the smartphone replacement cycle is the only predictable cash flow. Apple is smart. If the AI capex cycle flattens in late '27 as models hit diminishing returns, does Apple regain pricing power simply by being the only customer that can guarantee wafer commits five years out?&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 15:20:39 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46633724</link><dc:creator>Fiveplus</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46633724</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46633724</guid></item><item><title>New comment by zipy124 in "Photos capture the breathtaking scale of China's wind and solar buildout"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;It is incredible to see just how many big-oil talking points there are in this thread. From renewable energies resource costs, to their land use impact. I didn't realise just how effective their propaganda was in the tech space till reading this thread. That is not to say that these projects should be free of criticism, but anyone who believes these negatives are remotely close to the damage that fossil fuels are doing needs to re-evaluate their world view.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 12:45:34 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46631654</link><dc:creator>zipy124</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46631654</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46631654</guid></item><item><title>New comment by appointment in "Photos capture the breathtaking scale of China's wind and solar buildout"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&gt; That’s not to exclude the harsh reality of mining for the minerals required to build these, nor the land use concerns.&lt;p&gt;This is Big Oil propaganda. The impact from this is massively less than the horrific damage caused by every part of the fossil fuel industry.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 11:48:33 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46631174</link><dc:creator>appointment</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46631174</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46631174</guid></item><item><title>New comment by roxolotl in "Photos capture the breathtaking scale of China's wind and solar buildout"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;It genuinely makes me so sad to see the US not doing the same. Having grown up to the constant beat of “energy independence” as the core goal of a party it seemed obvious that the nearly limitless energy that rains down from the sky would be the answer. But instead we’ve kept choosing the option which requires devastating our, and other’s around the world, community. That’s not to exclude the harsh reality of mining for the minerals required to build these, nor the land use concerns. But it’s difficult to compare localized damage to war and globalized damage.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 11:20:07 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46630953</link><dc:creator>roxolotl</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46630953</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46630953</guid></item><item><title>New comment by nicbou in "To those who fired or didn't hire tech writers because of AI"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I write documentation for a living. Although my &lt;i&gt;output&lt;/i&gt; is writing, my &lt;i&gt;job&lt;/i&gt; is observing, listening and understanding. I can only write well because I have an intimate understanding of my readers' problems, anxieties and confusion. This decides what I write about, and how to write about it. This sort of curation can only come from a thinking, feeling human being.&lt;p&gt;I revise my local public transit guide every time I experience a foreign public transit system. I improve my writing by walking in my readers' shoes and experiencing their confusion. Empathy is the engine that powers my work.&lt;p&gt;Most of my information is carefully collected from a network of people I have a good relationship with, and from a large and trusting audience. It took me years to build the infrastructure to surface useful information. AI can only report what someone was bothered to write down, but I actually go out in the real world and ask questions.&lt;p&gt;I have built tools to collect people's experience at the immigration office. I have had many conversations with lawyers and other experts. I have interviewed hundreds of my readers. I have put a lot of information on the internet for the first time. AI writing is only as good as the data it feeds on. I hunt for my own data.&lt;p&gt;People who think that AI can do this and the other things have an almost insulting understanding of the jobs they are trying to replace.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 11:19:33 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46630948</link><dc:creator>nicbou</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46630948</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46630948</guid></item><item><title>New comment by postalcoder in "The URL shortener that makes your links look as suspicious as possible"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;There may actually be some utility here. LLM agents refuse to traverse the links. Tested with gemini-3-pro, gpt-5.2, and opus 4.5.&lt;p&gt;edit: gpt-oss 20B &amp; 120B both eagerly visit it.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 05:05:04 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46628273</link><dc:creator>postalcoder</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46628273</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46628273</guid></item><item><title>New comment by lanyard-textile in "Ask HN: What did you find out or explore today?"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I found out my crimson-bellied conure is laying an egg today! She's nesting in some towels now, chirping away while she works on laying it.&lt;p&gt;Having an egg is relatively hard on parrots. I've given her lots of food and warmth to prepare. She is comically hungry -- she's usually not such a big eater, but she's happy today to be scarfing down her apple slices, fruit pellets, and safflower seeds.&lt;p&gt;She usually sleeps at the bottom of her cage, beneath a towel I put down for her. It's already unusual for parrots! But tonight she has made quite a nest with her towel: It's folded in half like usual, but she has nuzzled her way between the fold, so she has the towel underneath and on top of her. It's super cute.&lt;p&gt;I'm treating her with delicacy but she is determined to be a wild child of a bird. She's still flying around during the day and moving around plenty. I don't think I would be so confident if I had an egg like that inside me.&lt;p&gt;She has a stone perch that she likes to nibble on when she's working on an egg. I've wondered if it is some innate need to nourish herself with calcium, or if it's stress relief :)&lt;p&gt;So that's my night. Sitting outside of the metaphorical delivery ward with a metaphorical cigar, making sure she lays this egg that isn't even fertile to begin with! Birds :)&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 04:53:41 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46628204</link><dc:creator>lanyard-textile</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46628204</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46628204</guid></item><item><title>New comment by raincole in "Claude Cowork exfiltrates files"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&gt; because a .md file feel less suspicious than a .docx&lt;p&gt;For a programmer?&lt;p&gt;I bet 99.9% people won't consider opening a .docx or .pdf 'unsafe.' Actually, an average white-collar workers will find .md much more suspicious because they don't know what it is while they work with .docx files every day.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 03:57:16 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46627831</link><dc:creator>raincole</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46627831</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46627831</guid></item></channel></rss>