<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>Hacker News: Best Comments</title><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/bestcomments</link><description>Hacker News RSS</description><docs>https://hnrss.org/</docs><generator>hnrss v2.1.1</generator><lastBuildDate>Sun, 21 Dec 2025 23:58:04 +0000</lastBuildDate><ns0:link href="https://hnrss.org/bestcomments" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item><title>New comment by unstyledcontent in "You’re not burnt out, you’re existentially starving"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I'm burned out because I have to raise two young children, work a full time job in a demanding career, and then in the hour or two a day of time that isn't accounted for in those two tasks, I need to maintain a household and try to care for myself. I feel a strong sense of purpose caring for my family, but don't have enough time to meet life's demands. Maybe other people relate more to this post because they more money and no kids.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 21 Dec 2025 19:31:08 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46347543</link><dc:creator>unstyledcontent</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46347543</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46347543</guid></item><item><title>New comment by Aurornis in "Reasons not to become famous (2020)"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;If you’re not familiar with Tim Ferriss, you should know that there is always more to the story than the narrative he shares. He’s one of the most charismatic and charming writers and podcasters out there and has a strong ability to build trust through his writing. However, he also has a long history of stretching the truth and spinning history in his favor, often by omitting important facts.&lt;p&gt;One example: His 4 Hour Work Week book really was on the New York Times Best Seller list for a long time like he brags about in this post, but he has also bragged in other contexts about all of the manipulation and engineering (including mass purchasing books to artificially inflate sales numbers) that goes into gaming the New York Times Best Seller List.&lt;p&gt;On the topic of being famous, he’s not typically famous like a celebrity. He built his career around being a self-help guru who will bring you the secrets to success in business, life, relationships, and even cooking. He’s talked about how he selects his writing topics based on how to present solutions for people’s inner desires, like financial freedom or impressing people for dating success. He puts himself at the center of these writings, presenting himself as the conduit for these revelations. He was even early in social media and blogging and experimented with social media engagements and paid events where you get to come hang out with Tim Ferriss and learn his secrets, encouraging his fans to idolize him and his wisdom dispensing abilities.&lt;p&gt;So his relationship with his fans isn’t typical fame in the style of a celebrity or actor. He’s more of an early self-help guru who embraced social media and blogging early on. His experience with uncomfortable fan obsessions is therefore probably on the next level, but not exactly typical fame.&lt;p&gt;EDIT to add why I know this: Tim Ferriss literally wrote the book on how to abuse remote work. His Four Hour Work Week book encourages readers to talk their boss into working remote then to outsource their work to low paid overseas assistants so they have more time to travel the world. It encourages things like setting up an e-mail auto responder and only responding to your coworkers once a week whine you’re “working remote” and setting up your own side job while traveling the world. If you’ve ever had a remote work job get ruined by people abusing it, chances are good that those people had read a Tim Ferriss book somewhere along the way.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 21 Dec 2025 17:02:16 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46346238</link><dc:creator>Aurornis</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46346238</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46346238</guid></item><item><title>New comment by kshahkshah in "Ruby website redesigned"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I used cursor over the past three weeks to update a 12 year-old Ruby on rails project. While it has been slightly updated throughout the years, this was my first proper modernization of the code base.&lt;p&gt;It’s been a real pleasure getting back into Ruby after so many years in typescript, python, and rust.&lt;p&gt;Happy to see the update. Real shame about the haters here, the Ruby community is a supportive and positive bunch that has shipped real products while others seem to worship at the altar of computer science alone… that’s about as counter snarky as I want to be here&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 21 Dec 2025 14:09:18 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46344963</link><dc:creator>kshahkshah</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46344963</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46344963</guid></item><item><title>New comment by thiht in "Clair Obscur having its Indie Game Game Of The Year award stripped due to AI use"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;That’s incredibly harsh. A blanket ban on AI generated assets is dumb as hell. Generating placeholder assets is completely acceptable.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 21 Dec 2025 09:52:08 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46343613</link><dc:creator>thiht</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46343613</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46343613</guid></item><item><title>New comment by skibidithink in "Clair Obscur having its Indie Game Game Of The Year award stripped due to AI use"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;The AI witch hunt claims its first victim, apparently over some placeholder textures.&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://english.elpais.com/culture/2025-07-19/the-low-cost-creative-revolution-how-technology-is-making-art-accessible-to-everyone.html" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://english.elpais.com/culture/2025-07-19/the-low-cost-c...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;&gt; Sandfall Interactive further clarifies that there are no generative AI-created assets in the game. When the first AI tools became available in 2022, some members of the team briefly experimented with them to generate temporary placeholder textures. Upon release, instances of a placeholder texture were removed within 5 days to be replaced with the correct textures that had always been intended for release, but were missed during the Quality Assurance process.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 21 Dec 2025 09:02:47 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46343336</link><dc:creator>skibidithink</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46343336</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46343336</guid></item><item><title>New comment by yellow_lead in "Claude in Chrome"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;So Claude seems to have access to a tool to evaluate JS on the webpage, using the Chrome debugger.&lt;p&gt;However, don't worry about the security of this! There is a comprehensive set of regexes to prevent secrets from being exfiltrated.&lt;p&gt;const r = [/password/i, /token/i, /secret/i, /api[_-]?key/i, /auth/i, /credential/i, /private[_-]?key/i, /access[_-]?key/i, /bearer/i, /oauth/i, /session/i];&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 21 Dec 2025 04:26:00 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46342247</link><dc:creator>yellow_lead</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46342247</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46342247</guid></item><item><title>New comment by ethmarks in "Show HN: HN Wrapped 2025 - an LLM reviews your year on HN"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://hn-wrapped.kadoa.com/ethmarks" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://hn-wrapped.kadoa.com/ethmarks&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;Mine seems to think that I'm some kind of detail-obsessed super-pedant. Personally, I think this is ridiculous. "super" is a Latin stem meaning "beyond", which implies that I've transcended the qualities of pedantry. A better term would be 'pluri-pedant', which denotes someone who is exceptionally punctilious while still remaining within the bounds of being pedantic.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 21 Dec 2025 03:13:32 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46341900</link><dc:creator>ethmarks</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46341900</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46341900</guid></item><item><title>New comment by greyface- in "Flock and Cyble Inc. weaponize “cybercrime” takedowns to silence critics"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;If Flock truly believed that the domain name infringes on their trademark, they would file an ICANN UDRP complaint instead of Cloudflare and Hetzner abuse reports.&lt;p&gt;But they don't, because the former would require them to perjure themselves, and the latter just requires them to lie to a hosting company.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 21 Dec 2025 02:53:02 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46341793</link><dc:creator>greyface-</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46341793</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46341793</guid></item><item><title>New comment by CAP_NET_ADMIN in "Claude in Chrome"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Let's spend years plugging holes in V8, splitting browser components to separate processes and improving sandboxing and then just plug in LLM with debugging enabled into Chrome. Great idea. Last time we had such a great idea it was lead in gasoline.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 20 Dec 2025 23:47:56 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46340821</link><dc:creator>CAP_NET_ADMIN</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46340821</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46340821</guid></item><item><title>New comment by muzani in "Show HN: Jmail – Google Suite for Epstein files"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I'm impressed. You guys cloned a whole suite of products in a short period of time that cost millions of dollars. Even the little bits of humor look costly.&lt;p&gt;On the other hand, it's way more information than I expected. I can see why someone would hesitate to release them - there's a lot to sift through and it's likely even the government couldn't sift through all of them to make sure their friends weren't mentioned somewhere.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 20 Dec 2025 23:36:25 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46340750</link><dc:creator>muzani</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46340750</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46340750</guid></item><item><title>New comment by jsheard in "Backing up Spotify"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&gt; The Anna’s archive group is ideologically motivated. They’re definitely not doing this for AI companies.&lt;p&gt;They have a page directly addressed to AI companies, offering them "enterprise-level" access to their complete archives in exchange for tens of thousands of dollars. AI may not be their original/primary motivation but they are evidently on board with facilitating AI labs piracy-maxxing.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 20 Dec 2025 21:13:57 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46339690</link><dc:creator>jsheard</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46339690</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46339690</guid></item><item><title>New comment by flxy in "Backing up Spotify"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I think what earned what.cd that title wasn't necessarily just the amount but the quality, as you mentioned, as well as the obscurity of a lot of the offered material. I remember finding an early EP of an unknown local band on there, and I live in the middle of nowhere in Europe. There were also quite a few really old and niche records on there which possibly couldn't be put on streaming services due to the ownership of rights being unknown. It was the equivalent of vinyl crate digging without physical restrictions.&lt;p&gt;Additionally there was a lot of discourse about music and a lot of curated discovery mechanisms I sorely miss to this day. An algorithm is no replacement for the amount of time and care people put into the web of similar artists, playlists of recommendations and reviews. Despite it being piracy, music consumption through it felt more purposeful. It's introduced me to some of my all time favourite artists, which I've seen live and own records and merchandise of.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 20 Dec 2025 21:10:07 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46339663</link><dc:creator>flxy</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46339663</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46339663</guid></item><item><title>New comment by Etheryte in "Backing up Spotify"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;To put this into perspective, What.CD [0] was widely considered to be the music library of Alexandria, unparalleled in both its high quality standard and it's depth. What had in the ballpark of a few million torrents when it got raided and shut down. Anna's rip of Spotify includes roughly 186 million unique records. Granted, the tail end is a mixed bag of bot music and whatnot, but the scale is staggering.&lt;p&gt;[0] &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/What.CD" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/What.CD&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 20 Dec 2025 20:08:33 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46339136</link><dc:creator>Etheryte</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46339136</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46339136</guid></item><item><title>New comment by Aurornis in "Backing up Spotify"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&gt; The thing is, this doesn't even seem particularly useful for average consumers/listeners, since Spotify itself is so convenient, and trying to locate individual tracks in massive torrent files of presumably 10,000's of tracks each sounds horrible.&lt;p&gt;I wouldn’t be so sure. There are already tools to automatically locate and stream pirated TV and movie content automatic and on demand. They’re so common that I had non-technical family members bragging at Thanksgiving about how they bought at box at their local Best Buy that has an app which plays any movie or TV show they want on demand without paying anything. They didn’t understand what was happening, but they said it worked great.&lt;p&gt;&gt; Definitely wondering if this was in response to desire from AI researchers/companies who wanted this stuff.&lt;p&gt;The Anna’s archive group is ideologically motivated. They’re definitely not doing this for AI companies.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 20 Dec 2025 19:55:21 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46339019</link><dc:creator>Aurornis</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46339019</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46339019</guid></item><item><title>New comment by crazygringo in "Backing up Spotify"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;This is insane.&lt;p&gt;I definitely was not aware Spotify DRM had been cracked to enable downloading at scale like this.&lt;p&gt;The thing is, this doesn't even seem particularly useful for average consumers/listeners, since Spotify itself is so convenient, and trying to locate individual tracks in massive torrent files of presumably 10,000's of tracks each sounds horrible.&lt;p&gt;But this &lt;i&gt;does&lt;/i&gt; seem like it will be a godsend for researchers working on things like music classification and generation. The only thing is, you can't really publicly admit exactly what dataset you trained/tested on...?&lt;p&gt;Definitely wondering if this was in response to desire from AI researchers/companies who wanted this stuff. Or if the major record labels already license their entire catalogs for training purposes cheaply enough, so this really is just solely intended as a preservation effort?&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 20 Dec 2025 19:50:17 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46338973</link><dc:creator>crazygringo</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46338973</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46338973</guid></item><item><title>New comment by Too in "Log level 'error' should mean that something needs to be fixed"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;This is why it’s almost always wrong for library functions to log anything, even on ”errors”. Pass the status up through return values or exceptions. As a library author you have no clue as how an application might use it. Multi threading, retry loops and expected failures will turn what’s a significant event in one context into what’s not even worthy of a debug log in another. No rule without exceptions of course, one valid case could be for example truly slow operations where progress reports are expected. Modern tracing telemetry with sampling can be another solution for the paranoid.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 20 Dec 2025 18:44:47 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46338463</link><dc:creator>Too</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46338463</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46338463</guid></item><item><title>New comment by layer8 in "Log level 'error' should mean that something needs to be fixed"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&gt; When implementing logging, it's important to distinguish between an error from the perspective of an individual operation and an error from the perspective of the overall program or system. Individual operations may well experience errors that are not error level log events for the overall program. You could say that an operation error is anything that prevents an operation from completing successfully, while a program level error is something that prevents the program as a whole from working right.&lt;p&gt;This is a nontrivial problem when using properly modularized code and libraries that perform logging. They can’t tell whether their operational error is also a program-level error, which can depend on usage context, but they still want to log the operational error themselves, in order to provide the details that aren’t accessible to higher-level code. This lower-level logging has to choose &lt;i&gt;some&lt;/i&gt; status.&lt;p&gt;Should only “top-level” code ever log an error?  That can make it difficult to identify the low-level root causes of a top-level failure. It also can hamper modularization, because it means you can’t repackage one program’s high-level code as a library for use by other programs, without somehow factoring out the logging code again.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 20 Dec 2025 18:28:07 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46338335</link><dc:creator>layer8</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46338335</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46338335</guid></item><item><title>New comment by Youden in "Over 40% of deceased drivers in vehicle crashes test positive for THC: Study"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;There was a larger discussion in a previous thread on this topic: &lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45494730"&gt;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45494730&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;Since then, [0] has been published and I think it's worth at least a skim. Since it's quite recent the introduction summarizes some of the most recent research.&lt;p&gt;The things that jump out at me are:&lt;p&gt;- [0]: Habitual users with baseline concentrations above legal limits perform just as well as habitual users with baseline concentrations below the legal limit, indicating that for habitual users, the legal limit doesn't have any relation to impairement.&lt;p&gt;- [1]: A study in Canada analyzed crash reports and blood tests to look at the state of drivers responsible for accidents. While alcohol had a very clear and statistically-significant influence on the risk of a driver causing an accident, THC did not.&lt;p&gt;To steelman the idea that THC causes accidents, [0] only looks at habitual users with baseline levels of THC and [1] only looks at non-fatal injuries.&lt;p&gt;My conclusion right now is that the number of drivers in accidents with THC in their blood is going up because the number of people with THC in their blood is going up, not because drivers who use THC cause accidents.&lt;p&gt;The law's assumption that this level of THC is evidence of impairment seems to be invalid.&lt;p&gt;The law would be better off measuring impairment in some way and perhaps intensifying penalties when an impairment test fails &lt;i&gt;and&lt;/i&gt; the user has THC concentration above some threshold.&lt;p&gt;[0]: &lt;a href="https://academic.oup.com/clinchem/article/71/12/1225/8299832?login=false" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://academic.oup.com/clinchem/article/71/12/1225/8299832...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;[1]: &lt;a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/31106494/" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/31106494/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 20 Dec 2025 18:26:27 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46338322</link><dc:creator>Youden</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46338322</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46338322</guid></item><item><title>New comment by mittermayr in "Go ahead, self-host Postgres"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Self-hosting is more a question of responsibility I'd say. I am running a couple of SaaS products and self-host at much better performance at a fraction of the cost of running this on AWS. It's amazing and it works perfectly fine.&lt;p&gt;For client projects, however, I always try and sell them on paying the AWS fees, simply because it shifts the responsibility of the hardware being "up" to someone else. It does not inherently solve the downtime problem, but it allows me to say, "we'll have to wait until they've sorted this out, Ikea and Disney are down, too."&lt;p&gt;Doesn't always work like that and isn't always a tried-and-true excuse, but generally lets me sleep much better at night.&lt;p&gt;With limited budgets, however, it's hard to accept the cost of RDS (and we're talking with at least one staging environment) when comparing it to a very tight 3-node Galera cluster running on Hetzner at barely a couple of bucks a month.&lt;p&gt;Or Cloudflare, titan at the front, being down again today and the past two days (intermittently) after also being down a few weeks ago and earlier this year as well. Also had SQS queues time out several times this week, they picked up again shortly, but it's not like those things ...never happen on managed environments. They happen quite a bit.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 20 Dec 2025 17:30:30 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46337844</link><dc:creator>mittermayr</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46337844</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46337844</guid></item><item><title>New comment by tokai in "Over 40% of deceased drivers in vehicle crashes test positive for THC: Study"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;An issue with having the legal limit at ~2-5ng/ml is that it makes habitual users be over the limit if they have smoked recently or not.[0] Making the prohibition seem unserious to some, not about safety but about punitive control, and in turn making it matter less if you smoke and drive as you are taking the risk of getting into trouble in any case.&lt;p&gt;The impairments of driving under the influence of alcohol have been extensively studied, but unless I have overlooked the literature it seems that the same investigations have not been carried out with THC.&lt;p&gt;[0] «Blood THC &gt;2 ng/mL, and possibly even THC &gt;5 ng/mL, does not necessarily represent recent use of cannabis in frequent cannabis users.»; &lt;a href="https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/abs/pii/S0376871620303422" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/abs/pii/S03768...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 20 Dec 2025 17:30:30 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46337843</link><dc:creator>tokai</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46337843</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46337843</guid></item><item><title>New comment by etra0 in "Reflections on AI at the End of 2025"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;LLMs have certainly become extremely useful for Software Engineers, they're very convincing (and pleasers, too) and I'm still unsure about the future of our day-to-day job.&lt;p&gt;But one thing that has scared me the most, is the trust of LLMs output to the general society. I believe that for software engineers it's really easy to see if it's being useful or not -- We can just run the code and see if the output is what we expected, if not, iterate it, and continue. There's still a professional looking to what it produces.&lt;p&gt;On the contrary, for more day-to-day usage of the general pubic, is getting really scary. I've had multiple members of my family using AI to ask for medical advice, life advice, and stuff were I still see hallucinations daily, but at the same time they're so convincing that it's hard for them not to trust them.&lt;p&gt;I still have seen fake quotes, fake investigations, fake news being spreaded by LLMs that have affected decisions (maybe, not as crucials yet but time will tell) and that's a danger that most software engineers just gross over.&lt;p&gt;Accountability is a big asterisk that everyone seems to ignore&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 20 Dec 2025 15:52:49 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46337014</link><dc:creator>etra0</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46337014</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46337014</guid></item><item><title>New comment by cornholio in "NTP at NIST Boulder Has Lost Power"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;The disater plan is to have a few dozens stratum 1 servers spread around the world, each connected to a distinct primary atomic clock, so that a catastrophic disaster needs to take down the global internet itself for all servers to become unreachable.&lt;p&gt;The failure of a single such server is far from a disaster.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 20 Dec 2025 13:45:47 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46336153</link><dc:creator>cornholio</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46336153</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46336153</guid></item><item><title>New comment by jimnotgym in "Airbus to migrate critical apps to a sovereign Euro cloud"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Freeloading?&lt;p&gt;My country spends less on defence as a percentage of GDP than the US. But it spends much of that with US companies.  This is not Freeloading. It was a deal. Cancel TSR-2, and buy American and we will lend you some money. Cancel your nuclear program and buy US submarine launched missiles and we will help you look after yourself.  Now let Visa and Mastercard skim off all your transactions and we will keep you secure to keep the money flowing. Sweetheart tax deals for US companies to operate,  and we will keep you safe to keep the money flowing. It is not Freeloading, it is colonialism&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 20 Dec 2025 10:46:41 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46335170</link><dc:creator>jimnotgym</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46335170</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46335170</guid></item><item><title>New comment by arn3n in "NTP at NIST Boulder Has Lost Power"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Wind gusts were reaching 125 MPH in Boulder county, if anyone’s curious. A lot of power was shut off preemptively to prevent downed power lines from starting wildfires. Energy providers gave warning to locals in advance. Shame that NIST’s backup generator failed, though.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 20 Dec 2025 09:48:31 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46334864</link><dc:creator>arn3n</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46334864</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46334864</guid></item><item><title>New comment by breve in "Airbus to migrate critical apps to a sovereign Euro cloud"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;A necessary step to reduce risk to infrastructure given that the US government has become erratic and has decided it is now anti-Europe.&lt;p&gt;The US means to undermine the EU: &lt;a href="https://www.dw.com/en/will-trump-pull-italy-austria-poland-hungary-from-eu/a-75134777" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://www.dw.com/en/will-trump-pull-italy-austria-poland-h...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;The US means to annex European territory: &lt;a href="https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/c0j9l08902eo" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/c0j9l08902eo&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;It's the same reason you don't want Chinese equipment in your telecommunications infrastructure. You can't trust what the Chinese government will do to it or with it.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 20 Dec 2025 09:42:30 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46334831</link><dc:creator>breve</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46334831</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46334831</guid></item><item><title>New comment by autarch in "NTP at NIST Boulder Has Lost Power"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Time travel is extremely dangerous right now. I highly recommend deferring time travel plans except for extreme temporal emergencies.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 20 Dec 2025 09:42:08 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46334829</link><dc:creator>autarch</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46334829</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46334829</guid></item><item><title>New comment by flumpcakes in "Airbus to migrate critical apps to a sovereign Euro cloud"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Some people in the US deride it's close allies as "freeloaders" because they choose to use and buy US tech, reinforcing the US's position as a global powerhouse. (Meanwhile US tech is built on the shoulders of their allies.) Now we see these same allies are starting to look inward and invest in technology they own completely because the US is acting decisively not like an ally. Something unthinkable since WW2.&lt;p&gt;I don't see this news as anything but a good thing. For every technology out there, the EU needs a native alternative. It's clear the current US administration wants to make the EU worse based on a politics of grievance.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 20 Dec 2025 09:32:32 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46334787</link><dc:creator>flumpcakes</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46334787</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46334787</guid></item><item><title>New comment by mk89 in "Privacy doesn't mean anything anymore, anonymity does"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;At first I thought it was a blog. No, this is a company. So, their privacy page (&lt;a href="https://servury.com/privacy/" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://servury.com/privacy/&lt;/a&gt;):&lt;p&gt;&gt; Server Logs
&gt; Like all web services, our servers may log:
&gt;    IP addresses of visitors
&gt;    Request timestamps
&gt;    User agent strings
&gt; These logs are used for security and debugging purposes and are not linked to your account.&lt;p&gt;That's already a huge breach in comparison to mullvad privacy page. (&lt;a href="https://mullvad.net/en/help/no-logging-data-policy" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://mullvad.net/en/help/no-logging-data-policy&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 20 Dec 2025 08:46:58 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46334575</link><dc:creator>mk89</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46334575</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46334575</guid></item><item><title>New comment by hirsin in "Android introduces $2-4 install fee and 10–20% cut for US external content links"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;The apparent information gathering and brutal review process is unbelievable here. If I'm understanding this correctly, the requirement is that eg Epic Game Store must register and upload every single APK for every app they offer, and cannot offer it in their store until Google approves it, which may take a week or more - including every time the app updates.&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile they get full competitive insight into which apps are being added to Epics store, their download rates apparently, and they even get the APKs to boot, potentially making it easier for those app devs to onboard if they like, and can pressure them to do so by dragging their feet on that review process.&lt;p&gt;&gt; Provide direct, publicly accessible customer support to end users through readily accessible communication channels.&lt;p&gt;This is an interesting requirement. I want to see someone provide the same level of support that Google does to see if it draws a ban.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 20 Dec 2025 06:43:19 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46334110</link><dc:creator>hirsin</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46334110</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46334110</guid></item><item><title>New comment by culi in "CSS Grid Lanes"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Props to the Safari team. They surprised us all when they suddenly shot to the top of interop-2025 this October&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://wpt.fyi/interop-2025" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://wpt.fyi/interop-2025&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Dec 2025 23:38:53 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46332259</link><dc:creator>culi</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46332259</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46332259</guid></item></channel></rss>