<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>Hacker News: Best Comments</title><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/bestcomments</link><description>Hacker News RSS</description><docs>https://hnrss.org/</docs><generator>hnrss v2.1.1</generator><lastBuildDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 00:00:02 +0000</lastBuildDate><ns0:link href="https://hnrss.org/bestcomments" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item><title>New comment by cronos in "Tailscale state file encryption no longer enabled by default"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I'm one of the Tailscale engineers who built node state encryption initially (@awly on Github), and who made the call to turn it off by default in 1.92.5.&lt;p&gt;Another comment in this thread guessed right - this feature is too support intensive.
Our original thinking was that a TPM being reset or replaced is always sign of tampering and should result in the client refusing to start or connect. But turns out there are many situations where TPMs are not reliable for non-malicious reasons. Some examples:
* &lt;a href="https://github.com/tailscale/tailscale/issues/17654" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://github.com/tailscale/tailscale/issues/17654&lt;/a&gt;
* &lt;a href="https://github.com/tailscale/tailscale/issues/18288" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://github.com/tailscale/tailscale/issues/18288&lt;/a&gt;
* &lt;a href="https://github.com/tailscale/tailscale/issues/18302" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://github.com/tailscale/tailscale/issues/18302&lt;/a&gt;
* plus a number of support tickets&lt;p&gt;TPMs are a great tool for organizations that have good control of their devices. But the very heterogeneous fleet of devices that Tailscale users have is very difficult to support out of the box. So for now we leave it to security-conscious users and admins to enable, while avoiding unexpected breakage for the broader user base.&lt;p&gt;We should've provided more of this context in the changelog, apologies!&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 20:51:33 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46532492</link><dc:creator>cronos</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46532492</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46532492</guid></item><item><title>New comment by woodruffw in "Eat Real Food"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Of note: the US's per capita consumption of meat has increased by more than 100 pounds over the last century[1]. We now consume an immense amount of meat per person in this country. That increase is disproportionately in poultry, but we also consume more beef[2].&lt;p&gt;A demand for the average American to eat &lt;i&gt;more&lt;/i&gt; meat would have to explain, as a baseline, why our &lt;i&gt;already&lt;/i&gt; positive trend in meat consumption isn't yielding positive outcomes. There are potential explanations (you could argue increased processing offsets the purported benefits, for example), but those are left unstated by the website.&lt;p&gt;[1]: &lt;a href="https://www.agweb.com/opinion/drivers-u-s-capita-meat-consumption-over-last-century" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://www.agweb.com/opinion/drivers-u-s-capita-meat-consum...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;[2]: &lt;a href="https://ers.usda.gov/data-products/chart-gallery/chart-detail?chartId=59426" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://ers.usda.gov/data-products/chart-gallery/chart-detai...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 20:41:44 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46532352</link><dc:creator>woodruffw</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46532352</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46532352</guid></item><item><title>New comment by roadside_picnic in "US will ban Wall Street investors from buying single-family homes"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;The key word here is "Wall Street". And this statement is playing off a popular misconception around corporate investors buying up American houses.&lt;p&gt;There has been a bit of a panic around "Investors buying up all the property!!!" With people often citing Black Rock and Blackstone as the main culprits. But most of the "investors" buying up property are &lt;i&gt;individuals&lt;/i&gt; purchasing investment properties.&lt;p&gt;Here's an article on the topic from 2023[0], a bit old but my understanding is large institutional investment in residential real estate was already starting to cool down.&lt;p&gt;Black rock isn't buying up all the housing, your neighbors are.&lt;p&gt;I suspect this statement, and even if it becomes an actual ban, is largely to gain wider popular support around a largely imaginary concern people have.&lt;p&gt;0. &lt;a href="https://www.housingwire.com/articles/no-wall-street-investors-havent-bought-44-of-homes-this-year/" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://www.housingwire.com/articles/no-wall-street-investor...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 19:46:57 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46531528</link><dc:creator>roadside_picnic</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46531528</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46531528</guid></item><item><title>New comment by FfejL in "Dell's CES 2026 chat was the most pleasingly un-AI briefing I've had in 5 years"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&gt; It's not that Dell doesn't care about AI or AI PCs anymore, it's just that over the past year or so it's come to realise that the consumer doesn't.&lt;p&gt;I wish every consumer product leader would figure this out.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 17:02:54 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46528946</link><dc:creator>FfejL</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46528946</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46528946</guid></item><item><title>New comment by srameshc in "Creators of Tailwind laid off 75% of their engineering team"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&gt; But the reality is that 75% of the people on our engineering team lost their jobs here yesterday because of the brutal impact AI has had on our business.&lt;p&gt;Adam is simply trying to navigate this new reality, and he's being honest, so there's no need to criticize him.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 16:28:15 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46528354</link><dc:creator>srameshc</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46528354</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46528354</guid></item><item><title>New comment by freedomben in "Creators of Tailwind laid off 75% of their engineering team"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Very sad to hear, I bought Tailwind UI years ago and although it was a lot more expensive than I wanted, I've appreciated the care and precision and highly recommend buying it (It's now called Tailwind Plus) even still (maybe even especially now).&lt;p&gt;Mad props to Adam for his honesty and transparency.  Adam if you're reading, just know that the voices criticizing you are not the only voices out there.  Thanks for all you've done to improve web development and I sincerely hope you can figure out a way to navigate the AI world, and all the best wishes.&lt;p&gt;Btw the Tailwind newsletter/email that goes out is genuinely useful as well, so I recommend signing up for that if you use Tailwind CSS at all.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 16:27:09 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46528327</link><dc:creator>freedomben</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46528327</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46528327</guid></item><item><title>New comment by mbgerring in "US Job Openings Decline to Lowest Level in More Than a Year"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;It makes sense that you wouldn't hire in such an uncertain environment. We have a President using emergency powers to affect sweeping, unpredictable, consequential changes to the economy that can dramatically alter unit economics overnight and completely tank a previously viable business. Within this calendar year, the President's ability to do this may be upended by pending court cases, an election, or both. Following those potential changes, the breach of trust created by the previous chaos may mean that trade never returns to normal. I don't envy anyone trying to make long-term business decisions, like hiring, in such an environment.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 16:01:34 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46527938</link><dc:creator>mbgerring</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46527938</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46527938</guid></item><item><title>New comment by Fiveplus in "A4 Paper Stories"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Nice! The author touches on the area properties and here's the most practical life hack derived from the standard I personally use. It uses the relationship between size and mass.&lt;p&gt;Because A0 is defined as having an area of exactly 1 square meter, the paper density (GSM or grams per square meter) maps directly to the weight of the sheet.&lt;p&gt;&gt;A0 = 1 meter square.&lt;p&gt;&gt;Standard office paper = 80 gsm&lt;p&gt;&gt;Therefore, one sheet of A0 = 80 grams.&lt;p&gt;&gt;Since A4 is 1/16th of an A0, a single sheet of standard A4 paper weighs 5 grams.&lt;p&gt;I rarely need to use a scale for postage. If I have a standard envelope (~5g) and 3 sheets of paper (15g), I know I'm at 20g total. It turns physical shipping logistics into simple integer arithmetic. The elegance of the metric system is that it makes the properties of materials discoverable through their definitions.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 13:45:38 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46526297</link><dc:creator>Fiveplus</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46526297</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46526297</guid></item><item><title>New comment by hollowturtle in "Opus 4.5 is not the normal AI agent experience that I have had thus far"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I'm tired of constantly debating the same thing again and again. Where are the products? Where is some great performing software all LLM/agent crafted? All I see is software bloatness and decline. Where is Discord that uses just a bunch of hundreds megs of ram? Where is unbloated faster Slack? Where is the Excel killer? Fast mobile apps? Browsers and the web platform improved? Why Cursor team don't use Cursor to get rid of vscode base and code its super duper code editor? I see tons of talking and almost zero products.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 11:12:19 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46525021</link><dc:creator>hollowturtle</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46525021</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46525021</guid></item><item><title>New comment by mattlondon in "Sergey Brin's Unretirement"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I too would very happily do just the bits of my job that I like, when and how I want, and have any requests or comments or complaints I make get immediate attention and responses.&lt;p&gt;All in the knowledge that no one is going to be time-tracking me or doing performance reviews, and I can just &lt;i&gt;not&lt;/i&gt; do work at any moment I don't feel like it or have something better to do that day, like go to my private island or take my private jet to burning man etc (or as it turns out do a talk at Stanford). All while you have so much money that the price of anything from clothes to cars to houses is just some arbitrary number that has no meaning to you it is so absolutely tiny number... not that you actually buy anything &lt;i&gt;yourself&lt;/i&gt; any more, mainly your team of personal staff deal with that grubby reality.&lt;p&gt;As for the rest of us, well we need to pay the bills while playing "the game" and politics and cowtowing to keep the money coming.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 07:33:56 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46523615</link><dc:creator>mattlondon</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46523615</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46523615</guid></item><item><title>New comment by tmerr in "The creator of Claude Code's Claude setup"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;This is interesting to hear, but I don't understand how this workflow actually works.&lt;p&gt;I don't need 10 parallel agents making 50-100 PRs a week, I need 1 agent that successfully solves the most important problem.&lt;p&gt;I don't understand how you can generate requirements quicky enough to have 10 parallel agents chewing away at meaningful work. I don't understand how you can have any meaningful supervising role over 10 things at once given the limits of human working memory.&lt;p&gt;It's like someone is claiming they unlocked ultimate productivity by washing dishes, in parallel with doing laundry, and cleaning their house.&lt;p&gt;Likely I am missing something. This is just my gut reaction as someone who has definitely not mastered using agents. Would love to hear from anyone that has a similar workflow where there is high parallelism.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 06:42:02 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46523312</link><dc:creator>tmerr</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46523312</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46523312</guid></item><item><title>New comment by multisport in "Opus 4.5 is not the normal AI agent experience that I have had thus far"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;What bothers me about posts like this is: mid-level engineers are not tasked with atomic, greenfield projects. If all an engineer did all day was build apps from scratch, with no expectation that others may come along and extend, build on top of, or depend on, then sure, Opus 4.5 could replace them. The hard thing about engineering is not "building a thing that works", its building it the right way, in an easily understood way, in a way that's easily extensible.&lt;p&gt;No doubt I could give Opus 4.5 "build be a XYZ app" and it will do well. But day to day, when I ask it "build me this feature" it uses strange abstractions, and often requires several attempts on my part to do it in the way I consider "right". Any non-technical person might read that and go "if it works it works" but any reasonable engineer will know that thats not enough.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 00:33:02 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46520951</link><dc:creator>multisport</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46520951</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46520951</guid></item><item><title>New comment by OldGreenYodaGPT in "Opus 4.5 is not the normal AI agent experience that I have had thus far"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Most software engineers are seriously sleeping on how good LLM agents are right now, especially something like Claude Code.&lt;p&gt;Once you’ve got Claude Code set up, you can point it at your codebase, have it learn your conventions, pull in best practices, and refine everything until it’s basically operating like a super-powered teammate. The real unlock is building a solid set of reusable “skills” plus a few agents for the stuff you do all the time.&lt;p&gt;For example, we have a custom UI library, and Claude Code has a skill that explains exactly how to use it. Same for how we write Storybooks, how we structure APIs, and basically how we want everything done in our repo. So when it generates code, it already matches our patterns and standards out of the box.&lt;p&gt;We also had Claude Code create a bunch of ESLint automation, including custom ESLint rules and lint checks that catch and auto-handle a lot of stuff before it even hits review.&lt;p&gt;Then we take it further: we have a deep code review agent Claude Code runs after changes are made. And when a PR goes up, we have another Claude Code agent that does a full PR review, following a detailed markdown checklist we’ve written for it.&lt;p&gt;On top of that, we’ve got like five other Claude Code GitHub workflow agents that run on a schedule. One of them reads all commits from the last month and makes sure docs are still aligned. Another checks for gaps in end-to-end coverage. Stuff like that. A ton of maintenance and quality work is just… automated. It runs ridiculously smoothly.&lt;p&gt;We even use Claude Code for ticket triage. It reads the ticket, digs into the codebase, and leaves a comment with what it thinks should be done. So when an engineer picks it up, they’re basically starting halfway through already.&lt;p&gt;There is so much low-hanging fruit here that it honestly blows my mind people aren’t all over it. 2026 is going to be a wake-up call.&lt;p&gt;(used voice to text then had claude reword, I am lazy and not gonna hand write it all for yall sorry!)&lt;p&gt;Edit: made an example repo for ya&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/ChrisWiles/claude-code-showcase" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://github.com/ChrisWiles/claude-code-showcase&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2026 18:13:15 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46516157</link><dc:creator>OldGreenYodaGPT</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46516157</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46516157</guid></item><item><title>New comment by xoxxala in "Vietnam bans unskippable ads"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Mr. Beast on youtube is guilty of that. Matt Parker of Standup Maths fame did an in-depth look at how that works. Whoever came up with that type of progress bar must hate people in general.&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=uc0OU1yJD-c" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=uc0OU1yJD-c&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2026 17:25:03 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46515374</link><dc:creator>xoxxala</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46515374</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46515374</guid></item><item><title>New comment by DrewADesign in "Vietnam bans unskippable ads"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;My favorite most annoying ad tactic is the trick slowing down progress bar. It starts off fast making it seem like it’s going to be, say, a ten-second ad so you decide to suffer through it… but progressively slows so you notice at like the 20 second mark you’re only 2/3 of the way through the progress bar, so probably less than halfway done. Murderous rage.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2026 17:18:56 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46515263</link><dc:creator>DrewADesign</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46515263</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46515263</guid></item><item><title>New comment by jason_s in "Vietnam bans unskippable ads"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I just uninstalled a game from my mobile phone this morning that had heavy ad usage. It was interesting to note the different ad display strategies. From least to most annoying:&lt;p&gt;- display a static ad, have the "x" to close appear soon (3-10 seconds)&lt;p&gt;- display an animated ad, have the "x" to close appear soon (3-10 seconds)&lt;p&gt;- display a static ad, have the "x" to close appear after 20-30 seconds&lt;p&gt;- display an animated ad, have the "x" to close appear after 20-30 seconds&lt;p&gt;- display several ads in succession, each short, but it automatically proceeds to the next; the net time after which the "x" to close appears after 20-30 seconds&lt;p&gt;- display several ads in succession, each lasts for 3-10 seconds but you have to click on an "x" to close each one before the next one appears&lt;p&gt;I live in the USA. The well-established consumer product brands (Clorox, McDonalds, etc.) almost all had short ads that were done in 3-5 seconds. The longest ads were for obscure games or websites, or for Temu, and they appeared over and over again, making me hate them with a flaming passion. The several-ads-in-succession were usually British newspaper websites (WHY???? I don't live there) or celebrity-interest websites (I have no interest in these).&lt;p&gt;It seems like the monkey's-paw curse for this kind of legislation is to show several ads in a row, each allowing you to skip them after 5 seconds.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2026 17:12:15 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46515127</link><dc:creator>jason_s</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46515127</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46515127</guid></item><item><title>New comment by HPsquared in "Why is the Gmail app 700 MB?"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;The article doesn't answer the question. The content can be summarised as "The Gmail app is 700 MB!"&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2026 17:04:41 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46514992</link><dc:creator>HPsquared</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46514992</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46514992</guid></item><item><title>New comment by _jab in "Vietnam bans unskippable ads"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I've often wondered whether the world would be better without ads. The incentive to create services (especially in social media) that strive to addict their users feels toxic to society. Often, it feels uncertain whether these services are providing actual value, and I suspect that whether a user would pay for a service in lieu of watching ads is incidentally a good barometer for whether real value is present.&lt;p&gt;Don't get me wrong, I'm well aware this is impractical. But it's fun to think about sometimes.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2026 17:00:25 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46514926</link><dc:creator>_jab</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46514926</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46514926</guid></item><item><title>New comment by cheschire in "State of the Fin 2026-01-06"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I have to thank Plex for changing their cost model. It motivated me to setup Jellyfin, something that took slightly more effort than Plex. And by getting that inertia going, I then followed up with Navidrome, a local OSM service with routing, and finally my own mediawiki copy that has a starting point from the pre-AI days as well as an annual content refresh so my "compare" history is short and simple on all articles.&lt;p&gt;That inspired me to build a homelab finally, which then became a NAS, which then became an OCIS server to replace my commercial cloud storage.&lt;p&gt;I finally got proxmox setup, OPNsense, with Caddy for reverse proxying the externally facing services and tailscale for access to those services I want to keep only for me and not others in my family.&lt;p&gt;So yeah, all of this big massive avalanche of work started with the little tiny snowball of Plex deciding they wanted to charge me to use my own media while away from my house.&lt;p&gt;Thanks Plex!&lt;p&gt;And thanks Jellyfin for being a fantastic alternative for video.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2026 16:42:47 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46514643</link><dc:creator>cheschire</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46514643</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46514643</guid></item><item><title>New comment by ryukoposting in "65% of Hacker News posts have negative sentiment, and they outperform"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;OP's classifiers make two assumptions that I'd bet strongly influence the result:&lt;p&gt;1. Binning skepticism with negativity.&lt;p&gt;2. Not allowing for a "neutral" category.&lt;p&gt;The comment I'm writing right now is critical, but is it "negative?" I certainly don't mean it that way.&lt;p&gt;It's cool that OP made this thing. The data is nicely presented, and the conclusion is articulated cleanly, and that's precisely why I'm able to build a criticism of it!&lt;p&gt;And I'm now realizing that I don't normally feel the need to disclaim my criticism by complimenting the OP's quality work. Maybe I should do that more. Or, maybe my engagement with the material implies that I found it engaging. Hmm.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2026 16:18:33 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46514302</link><dc:creator>ryukoposting</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46514302</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46514302</guid></item><item><title>New comment by california-og in "65% of Hacker News posts have negative sentiment, and they outperform"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Back when Reddit allowed API access, I used a reader (rif) which allowed blocking subreddits. I did an experiment where I would browse /r/all and  block any subreddit that had a toxic, gruesome, nsfw, or other content playing on negative emotions (like a pseudo feel-good post based on an otherwise negative phenomena). After a few years, and hundreds of banned subreddits, my /r/all was very wholesome, but contained only animal or niche hobby related subreddits. It was quite eye-opening on how negative reddit is, and also revealed how boring it is without the kind of algorithmic reaction seeking content.&lt;p&gt;In other words, if 35% of hn content is positive (or neutral?), compared to reddit and most mainstream social media, it's actually very positive!&lt;p&gt;Edit: I found the list of blocked subreddits if anyone is curious to see:&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://hlnet.neocities.org/RIF_filters_categorized.txt" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://hlnet.neocities.org/RIF_filters_categorized.txt&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;Note that it also includes stuff I wasn't interested in at the time, like anime, and only has subreddits up until I quit, around the API ban.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2026 15:25:07 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46513431</link><dc:creator>california-og</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46513431</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46513431</guid></item><item><title>New comment by misnome in "C Is Best (2025)"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&gt; strangely and disproportionately pushed on Hacker News&lt;p&gt;There is literally nothing strange or disproportionate. It's incredibly obvious that new languages, that were designed by people who found older languages lacking, are of interest to groups of people interested in new applications of technology and who want to use their new languages.&lt;p&gt;&gt; then those from outside the project shouldn't really have any say on it. It's their project.&lt;p&gt;People outside the project are allowed to say whatever the hell they want, the project doesn't have to listen.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2026 13:56:54 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46512281</link><dc:creator>misnome</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46512281</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46512281</guid></item><item><title>New comment by baranul in "C Is Best (2025)"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Every project and programmer shouldn't feel they have to justify their choice not to use Rust (or Zig), who seem to be strangely and disproportionately pushed on Hacker News and specific other social media platforms. This includes the pressure, though a bit less in recent years, to use OOP.&lt;p&gt;If they are getting good results with C and without OOP, and people like the product, then those from outside the project shouldn't really have any say on it. It's their project.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2026 13:46:48 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46512163</link><dc:creator>baranul</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46512163</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46512163</guid></item><item><title>New comment by adonovan in "enclose.horse"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I think you should change the cherries to a battery and call the game Correct Horse Battery Stable.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2026 13:27:27 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46511950</link><dc:creator>adonovan</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46511950</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46511950</guid></item><item><title>New comment by muvlon in "AWS raises GPU prices 15% on a Saturday, hopes you weren't paying attention"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I don't know how everyone arrives at that conclusion when the cost of the subscription services is also going up (as evidenced by the very article we're talking about). People who are renting are feeling this immediately, whereas people who bought their computers can wait the price hikes out for a couple years before they &lt;i&gt;really&lt;/i&gt; need an upgrade.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2026 12:58:19 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46511672</link><dc:creator>muvlon</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46511672</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46511672</guid></item><item><title>New comment by xvxvx in "AWS raises GPU prices 15% on a Saturday, hopes you weren't paying attention"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;- GPU prices rising&lt;p&gt;- RAM prices rising&lt;p&gt;- hard drive prices rising&lt;p&gt;Are we looking at a future where home computers are replaced by thin clients and all the power lies in subscription services?&lt;p&gt;‘You don't need storage space, use our cloud subscription’&lt;p&gt;‘You don’t need processing power, stream your games through our subscription service.’&lt;p&gt;Game publishers have already publicly floated the idea of not selling their games but charging per hour. Imagine how that impact Call of Duty or GTA.&lt;p&gt;Physical media could easily be killed off. Does my iPhone need 1TB of storage or will they shrink that and force everything through iCloud?&lt;p&gt;How long before car ownership is replaced with autonomous vehicle car pools? Grocery stores closed to visitors, all shopping done online and delivered to your door by drone.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2026 12:35:03 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46511477</link><dc:creator>xvxvx</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46511477</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46511477</guid></item><item><title>New comment by ManlyBread in "Try to take my position: The best promotion advice I ever got"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Ah, the classic "work even harder and do things you're not paid for with zero guarantee that someone will appreciate what you're doing while the company reaps the benefits". What a novel thought, I am so glad I clicked the article, especially since the author isn't even speaking from experience so he has nothing to back up his blogpost with.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2026 10:43:10 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46510805</link><dc:creator>ManlyBread</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46510805</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46510805</guid></item><item><title>New comment by gorgoiler in "enclose.horse"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Great game, I love it!  I hope the author is collecting juicy analytics.  They would be useful if they ever want to bundle 100 levels in order of difficulty and release this as a Steam game (which I would absolutely buy!)&lt;p&gt;I don’t think the gates should animate up into the air.  It breaks the visual logic of 2D for no benefit.  It’s subconsciously confusing to see a gate I place in one cell move to occupy pixels in the cell “above” it.&lt;p&gt;I look forward to future days introducing new mechanics as well.  Can I suggest a few, based on dynamics?&lt;p&gt;- Food!  The horse moves on every turn towards an attractor.  Have a hay bale / giant sugar cube in one corner fall off the back of a truck / helicopter :)  Horses start out dumb and move directly towards the goal before backtracking.  Smarter horses path find the shortest route to the goal.&lt;p&gt;- Goals!  Now that the horse is moving, get the horse into a static horse box / cattle pen cell by strategically placing fences so that the path it takes towards the food involves walking onto the goal square.&lt;p&gt;- Floods!  Water encroaches from the edges on a turn by turn basis.  Not only do you have to contain the horse, you also have to hold back the flood.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2026 09:11:41 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46510219</link><dc:creator>gorgoiler</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46510219</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46510219</guid></item><item><title>New comment by Quothling in "The Post-American Internet"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I've spent a couple of decades in the Danish public sector of digitalisation and in the private sector for global green energy. 10 years ago people would've laughed if you talked about leaving Microsoft and iOS in enterprise. Now we all have contingency plans for just that, and a lot of organisations are already actually doing it. So I would argue that there is more of a crack, but I'm not sure the post-american internet is going to be all that great. Because unlike the open source and decentralised platforms which are taking the place of US tech, the EU is going to regulate the internet. There is a saying about how us citizens trust companies but not their government, and how Europeans trust their governments but not their companies. Which obviously doesn't apply to everyone, but it's how you can view the EU. With one hand they do so much to protect consumer rights for us citizens, but with the other hand they build a survailance state.&lt;p&gt;Of course that is how democracy works. You'll have multiple factions working toward their own goals with very different ideologies, and the EU has a lot of that. For the most part what comes out is great, because compromise is how you get things done when there aren't just two sides. For survailance, however, there are really just two sides and the wrong one of them is winning.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2026 07:11:18 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46509554</link><dc:creator>Quothling</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46509554</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46509554</guid></item><item><title>New comment by Aloisius in "There were BGP anomalies during the Venezuela blackout"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;&gt; When BGP traffic is being sent from point A to point B, it can be rerouted through a point C. If you control point C, even for a few hours, you can theoretically collect vast amounts of intelligence that would be very useful for government entities. The CANTV AS8048 being prepended to the AS path 10 times means there the traffic would not prioritize this route through AS8048, perhaps that was the goal?&lt;/i&gt;&lt;p&gt;AS prepending is a relatively common method of traffic engineering to reduce traffic from a peer/provider. Looking at CANTV's (AS8048) announcements from outside that period shows they do this a lot.&lt;p&gt;Since this was detected as a BGP route leak, it looks like CANTV (AS8048) propagated routes from Telecom Italia Sparkle (AS6762) to GlobeNet Cabos Sumarinos Columbia (AS52320). This could have simply been a misconfiguration.&lt;p&gt;Nothing nefarious immediately jumps out to me here. I don't see any obvious attempts to hijack routes to Dayco Telecom (AS21980), which was the actual destination. The prepending would have made traffic less likely to transit over CANTV assuming there was any other route available.&lt;p&gt;The prepending done by CANTV does make it slightly easier to hijack traffic destined to it (though not really to Dayco), but that just appears to be something they just normally do.&lt;p&gt;This could be CANTV trying to force some users of GlobeNet to transit over them to Dayco I suppose, but leaving the prepending in would be an odd way of going about it. I suppose if you &lt;i&gt;absolutely&lt;/i&gt; knew you were the shortest path length, there's no reason to remove the prepending, but a misconfiguration is usually the cause of these things.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2026 23:03:30 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46506387</link><dc:creator>Aloisius</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46506387</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46506387</guid></item></channel></rss>