<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>Hacker News: Best Comments</title><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/bestcomments</link><description>Hacker News RSS</description><docs>https://hnrss.org/</docs><generator>hnrss v2.1.1</generator><lastBuildDate>Tue, 11 Nov 2025 00:31:46 +0000</lastBuildDate><ns0:link href="https://hnrss.org/bestcomments" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item><title>New comment by HiPhish in "Reminder to passengers ahead of move to 100% digital boarding passes"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&gt; but will instead need to use the digital boarding pass generated in their “myRyanair” app during check-in to board their Ryanair flight.&lt;p&gt;And of course it's only possible using a specific proprietary app. You'd think a penny-pinching company would want to use open standard to save money instead of develop a custom app, right? I'm 100% sure this is done intentionally to scoop up as much personal data from their customers.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2025 18:43:31 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45879273</link><dc:creator>HiPhish</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45879273</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45879273</guid></item><item><title>New comment by codexb in "Time to start de-Appling"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Sounds more like people need to de-UK. It's going to be a problem with any company or technology.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2025 16:44:28 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45877765</link><dc:creator>codexb</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45877765</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45877765</guid></item><item><title>New comment by Thev00d00 in "Beets: The music geek’s media organizer"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;A few people commenting that some of their collection "doesn't exist in any DB", the best way to fix it is to add it to Musicbrainz[0] yourself!&lt;p&gt;I have found that adding things to Musicbrainz is actually pretty easy (and if you are so inclined like me, pretty rewarding and fun).&lt;p&gt;Streaming releases (and Bandcamp) you simply drop the release URL into Harmony[1] and it does most of the work for you.&lt;p&gt;Musicbrainz can represent nearly everything musically related and its all freely licensed, a very cool thing to exist.&lt;p&gt;Most (non-destructive) edits are auto-applied, whilst the rest go through a 7 day voting period (they are still applied by default unless someone votes against). The barrier to entry is very low.&lt;p&gt;0. &lt;a href="https://musicbrainz.org/" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://musicbrainz.org/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;1. &lt;a href="https://harmony.pulsewidth.org.uk/" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://harmony.pulsewidth.org.uk/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2025 11:15:30 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45874814</link><dc:creator>Thev00d00</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45874814</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45874814</guid></item><item><title>New comment by konimex in "XSLT RIP"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&gt; &lt;a href="https://dbushell.com" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://dbushell.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;Heh, I honestly thought the domain name stood for "D-Bus Hell" and not their own name.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2025 08:32:59 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45873792</link><dc:creator>konimex</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45873792</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45873792</guid></item><item><title>New comment by koito17 in "XSLT RIP"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I was hoping the site itself would be an XML document. Thankfully, it &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; an XML document.&lt;p&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;  % curl https://xslt.rip/
  &lt;?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?&gt;
  &lt;?xml-stylesheet href="/index.xsl" type="text/xsl"?&gt;
  &lt;html&gt;
    &lt;head&gt;
      &lt;title&gt;XSLT.RIP&lt;/title&gt;
    &lt;/head&gt;
    &lt;body&gt;
      &lt;h1&gt;If you're reading this, XSLT was killed by Google.&lt;/h1&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Thoughts and prayers.&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Rest in peace.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/body&gt;
  &lt;/html&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2025 07:46:51 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45873491</link><dc:creator>koito17</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45873491</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45873491</guid></item><item><title>New comment by urlahmed in "Work after work: Notes from an unemployed new grad watching the job market break"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Hey all, OP here (author of the blog post, someone else submitted it ).&lt;p&gt;I wrote this a few days ago mostly out of frustration and honestly did not expect it to go anywhere. It is pretty surreal to wake up and see it on HN with so much discussion.&lt;p&gt;Thank you for reading and for all the comments, messages, and thoughtful critiques.&lt;p&gt;I am currently looking for roles that sit at the intersection of ML, product, and research. I like open ended work where you figure out what to build as much as how to build it. I am a builder, and I also enjoy PM type work and being close to users and the product. If you are working on something in that space and think I might be a fit, I would love to chat.&lt;p&gt;Also, thank you to Daniel Han for sending me the link and bringing this to my attention.&lt;p&gt;In any case, thanks again for reading and for the conversation.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2025 03:58:39 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45872267</link><dc:creator>urlahmed</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45872267</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45872267</guid></item><item><title>New comment by SoftTalker in "LLM policy?"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I think everything has a growing problem with LLM/AI generated content. Emails, blog posts, news articles, research papers, grant applications, business proposals, music, art, pretty much everything you can think of.&lt;p&gt;There’s already more human produced content in the world than anyone could ever hope to consume, we don’t need more from AI.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2025 03:34:48 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45872106</link><dc:creator>SoftTalker</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45872106</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45872106</guid></item><item><title>New comment by windowshopping in "Work after work: Notes from an unemployed new grad watching the job market break"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Two initial thoughts:&lt;p&gt;1. This author's writing is extremely, uncommonly good. Good enough to write a book and have it sell. "Competing with the past of the economy," "residual behaviour of a world that treated labour as sacred," "immigration without immigrants" -- there are many elegant turns of phrase here. This is a very skilled writer.&lt;p&gt;2. His resume is designed poorly. Have a look. I'm not surprised his job search has been unsuccessful when his resume looks like an essay. OP, you gotta cut that text down by like 70% and put more highlights. This is the world of tiktok and instagram reels.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2025 01:46:56 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45871320</link><dc:creator>windowshopping</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45871320</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45871320</guid></item><item><title>New comment by paulhebert in "Ask HN: What Are You Working On? (Nov 2025)"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I recently launched a daily word puzzle!&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://tiledwords.com" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://tiledwords.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;It’s inspired by tile placement board games like Patchwork and crosswords. You rotate and move tiles to rebuild a broken crossword.&lt;p&gt;It’s free, web based, and responsive.&lt;p&gt;I currently have several hundred daily players and growing. My wife and I create the puzzles and I’m continuing to fix bugs and add new features.&lt;p&gt;I just launched a ”community puzzle” feature to let players help build new puzzles.&lt;p&gt;I’d love to know what you think!&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 09 Nov 2025 23:41:15 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45870446</link><dc:creator>paulhebert</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45870446</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45870446</guid></item><item><title>New comment by blitzar in "Drilling down on Uncle Sam's proposed TP-Link ban"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;The real lesson here: don't forget to bribe the president of the US.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 09 Nov 2025 21:48:08 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45869523</link><dc:creator>blitzar</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45869523</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45869523</guid></item><item><title>New comment by crmd in "Building a 2.5kWh battery from disposable vapes to power my workshop [video]"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;After all networked smartphones and computers were placed under control of the regime, resistance hackers relied on microcontrollers harvested from ordinary household devices like smart lamps and vape pens to slowly rebuild the covert but resilient mesh internetwork that became known as FreeNet.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 09 Nov 2025 21:45:37 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45869500</link><dc:creator>crmd</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45869500</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45869500</guid></item><item><title>New comment by WillMorr in "Marble Fountain"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;It's actually much weirder than that: banking changes the axis of rotation and thus kills the rotational inertia. The tracks bank super aggressively in order to prevent the ball from accelerating too much and hopping the track. This is part of why the descent is so smooth and all the balls move at more or less the same speed.&lt;p&gt;Also to be fair the final system does lose a ball every 30ish minutes. The tuning was largely me staring at the run or taking a video trying to catch where they get lost. Instead of hand tuning I would just update the generator and print another one. I'm considering closing the loop with a camera but that would be a whole new project.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 09 Nov 2025 21:02:51 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45869151</link><dc:creator>WillMorr</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45869151</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45869151</guid></item><item><title>New comment by yason in "Montana becomes first state to enshrine 'right to compute' into law"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;If that's the gist of it, then:&lt;p&gt;&gt; Government actions that restrict the ability to privately...&lt;p&gt;This seems weirdly backwards. The main problem is not generally what government can and wishes to restrict, it's all the proprietary/private restrictions such as not being able to run whatever code you want on hardware you own. The bill does nothing to address the actual &lt;i&gt;rights&lt;/i&gt; of citizens, it just limits some ways government can't further restrict the citizens' right. The government should be protecting the citizens' digital rights from anyone trying to clamp them down.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 09 Nov 2025 18:52:51 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45868050</link><dc:creator>yason</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45868050</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45868050</guid></item><item><title>New comment by dehrmann in "AI isn't replacing jobs. AI spending is"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Hacker News doesn't like to hear it, but remote work is a big part of this. All that effort convincing management you're just as effective working remotely was also a collective sales pitch to outsource your role.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 09 Nov 2025 17:55:30 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45867504</link><dc:creator>dehrmann</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45867504</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45867504</guid></item><item><title>New comment by arjie in "Startups are pushing the boundaries of reproductive genetics"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;My wife and I have a whole-genome sequenced embryo that we selected based on Orchid’s results. In our case, we were trying to avoid a specific kind of hearing loss caused by a mutation in GJB2.&lt;p&gt;People often try to bill these technologies as “trying to control everything” or “trying to make the perfect child” or all this business about “tech people think they deserve what they have due to their genetics” (paraphrasing Sasha Gusev) etc. but I don’t think that’s the driving impulse for most parents.&lt;p&gt;The reality is so much more complex than the headlines people chase. One couple who I spoke to who were considering this were afraid of the opposite of the intelligence chase. The mother was concerned that she’d pass on her Asperger’s Syndrome. Another friend of mine doesn’t want to have kids because her brothers (and other male relatives) have schizophrenia.&lt;p&gt;In my family’s case, we will not have boys (coincidence: all our female embryos are the ones unaffected) but that’s fine. Our baby girl is a beautiful happy child and even if she weren’t, she’d be mine and I’d love her as much. But being able to increase the chance she has the full sensory experience available to mankind brings me a bit of content.&lt;p&gt;I hope all of these people I have met who fear genetic disease will be able to mitigate the risks as well as we have. Ours is monogenic, but as polygenic prediction improves their chances will improve too.&lt;p&gt;People on the happy path don’t often realize what it’s like for those not on that path. In our family, a cousin had her child via her last embryo. That also happened to a friend. Imagine if the last one had a debilitating condition that could be edited out. Most parents would choose not to have that child and then they would simply be childless.&lt;p&gt;In some future world, those people could have the condition edited and they could have the child.&lt;p&gt;Finally, here are the notes I made throughout the process:&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://wiki.roshangeorge.dev/w/IVF" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://wiki.roshangeorge.dev/w/IVF&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;And a view into my genome&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://viz.roshangeorge.dev/roshan-genvue/" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://viz.roshangeorge.dev/roshan-genvue/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;And a link to my comment on an HN article on something similar: the potential for removing trisomy-21 (Down’s) from an embryo &lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44677834"&gt;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44677834&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 09 Nov 2025 17:13:08 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45867125</link><dc:creator>arjie</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45867125</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45867125</guid></item><item><title>New comment by Glyptodon in "AI isn't replacing jobs. AI spending is"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;As a recently laid of senior engineer, to the extent that my job was replaced, it was replaced with offshore junior devs who'd already been working with the company for over  year with a pretty rough level of productivity by man-hour, though maybe taking 3x the time to get things done is worth it if they're cheap enough. Which is to say I see my layoff as as cost cutting backed by a premise that there is no value in retaining senior level talent, to try and keep operating in the black, not because AI was materially producing a lot of benefits. (Because to the extent it was, I was the one reaping them compared to the offshore folks and less experienced onshore ones.)&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 09 Nov 2025 16:51:24 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45866918</link><dc:creator>Glyptodon</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45866918</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45866918</guid></item><item><title>New comment by ksajadi in "Samsung Family Hub for 2025 Update Elevates the Smart Home Ecosystem"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;My Samsung TV keeps blocking around 20% of the display at random times to tell me their terms and conditions have changed. Of course I have the option of checking it by reading the whole thing on my TV and then running a diff to see what’s changed but I don’t have an option to opt out of the terms.&lt;p&gt;It’s way too frequent and runs at random times in the middle of a movie so I always choose Accept.&lt;p&gt;Give me a dumb TV any time of the day now&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 09 Nov 2025 16:20:27 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45866654</link><dc:creator>ksajadi</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45866654</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45866654</guid></item><item><title>New comment by robin_reala in "Samsung Family Hub for 2025 Update Elevates the Smart Home Ecosystem"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;It’s really quite impressive how much this press release turns me off from every buying any white goods from Samsung at any point in the future. It’s a vortex of “no”.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 09 Nov 2025 15:47:45 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45866377</link><dc:creator>robin_reala</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45866377</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45866377</guid></item><item><title>New comment by dynm in "Montana becomes first state to enshrine 'right to compute' into law"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I &lt;i&gt;think&lt;/i&gt; this is the main content of the law. (Everything below is quoted.)&lt;p&gt;---&lt;p&gt;Section 3. Right to compute&lt;p&gt;Government actions that restrict the ability to privately own or make use of computational resources for lawful purposes, which infringes on citizens' fundamental rights to property and free expression, must be limited to those demonstrably necessary and narrowly tailored to fulfill a compelling government interest in public health or safety.&lt;p&gt;---&lt;p&gt;Section 4. Infrastructure controlled by artificial intelligence system -- shutdown.&lt;p&gt;(1) When critical infrastructure facilities are controlled in whole or in part by an artificial intelligence system, the deployer shall ensure the capability to disable the artificial intelligence system's control over the infrastructure and revert to human control within a reasonable amount of time.&lt;p&gt;(2) When enacting a full shutdown, the deployer shall consider, as appropriate, disruptions to critical infrastructure that may result from a shutdown.&lt;p&gt;(3) Deployers shall implement, annually review, and test a risk management policy that includes a fallback mechanism and a redundancy and mitigation plan to ensure the deployer can continue operations and maintain control of the critical infrastructure facility without the use of the artificial intelligence system.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 09 Nov 2025 15:09:28 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45866083</link><dc:creator>dynm</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45866083</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45866083</guid></item><item><title>New comment by talkingtab in "Alive internet theory"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Somehow, reading the comments made something CLICK for me about how passive and reactive we have all become in this culture.&lt;p&gt;1. The issue is real. Not sure it is articulated but I related to live vs dead internet.&lt;p&gt;2. The comments (only 10 as of now) are mostly critiques. (no javascript, call to action, style, theory is wrong)&lt;p&gt;The CLICK: "Critiques kill". You want a live internet? Don't critique. If you want a no javascript version make one. If you have a better solution do it. If you have insight into the problem share it.&lt;p&gt;The "follower" internet has somehow instilled the notion that making a comment is the same as "doing something". It is not.&lt;p&gt;Someone has done something here. If you want to comment, try to develop the thought, not critique. Help build something.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 09 Nov 2025 13:36:24 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45865520</link><dc:creator>talkingtab</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45865520</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45865520</guid></item><item><title>New comment by microtonal in "Ask HN: How would you set up a child’s first Linux computer?"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;My kids loved the power, freedom and later unexpected community this bought them.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;p&gt;I think it is also important to realize/point out that we do a lot of projecting and our child may have very different interests. Not saying that applies to you &lt;i&gt;evolve2k&lt;/i&gt;, just wanted to make the general point.&lt;p&gt;I set up a Linux machine with our daughter and while it was initially ok, she did not have much interest in the power/freedom and it only became a nuisance for her. Her school/friends use PowerPoint - there is a lot of friction trying work with them in LibreOffice. She wanted to do DTP-like things several times and the Linux options are not exactly... user-friendly. Etc.&lt;p&gt;In the end we got her a Mac Mini. She can still open a terminal, use Homebrew, etc. if she ever develops an interest. Heck, she can use most free software. However, she can also do the stuff she is currently interested in much more easily. E.g., she uses Swift Publisher, which is a very simple/user-friendly DTP program, can collaborate on PowerPoint presentations when needed, etc.&lt;p&gt;First and foremost listen to what &lt;i&gt;your child&lt;/i&gt; is interested in.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 09 Nov 2025 12:30:55 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45865082</link><dc:creator>microtonal</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45865082</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45865082</guid></item><item><title>New comment by kace91 in "I Am Mark Zuckerberg"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;My name isn’t super known, but it happened to be the same as that of a very big fish in the financial institution I worked for.&lt;p&gt;Thankfully these people were working mostly through physical meetings and calls, so no sensitive info was leaked, but I did get calendar invites to discuss the future of entire countries as an engineering intern.&lt;p&gt;I used the name a couple times to set up our internal meetings  in the fancier upper floors, so we could have whiteboard discussions over a fancy hardwoods table. No one questioned the name appearing in the entrance display as the current user.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 09 Nov 2025 12:29:03 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45865073</link><dc:creator>kace91</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45865073</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45865073</guid></item><item><title>New comment by bertil in "I Am Mark Zuckerberg"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;A friend of mine has a relatively common first name and last name, and she regularly gets mail that is clearly not meant for her. She started a Facebook group for homonyms to help her route mail, and it now have a hundred members and have helped people get important documents.&lt;p&gt;At some point, they even organized an impersonation because someone needed to retrieve an official document and couldn’t be there in person. Another member nearby offered to go and get it. “Won’t you need my ID for that? — Oh, I have one with just the right name…”&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 09 Nov 2025 10:43:28 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45864600</link><dc:creator>bertil</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45864600</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45864600</guid></item><item><title>New comment by mjd in "I Am Mark Zuckerberg"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Dennis Ritchie (co-inventor of the C programming language) had a page on his personal web site called “My other lives” with a list of other Dennis Ritchies.&lt;p&gt;“Outside of my main professional career, I have accumulated other WWW-recorded accomplishments and have other interests. Generally I pursue these interests using separate mail addresses, SS#, and DNA.”&lt;p&gt;It's preserved here:&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.nokia.com/bell-labs/about/dennis-m-ritchie/otherlives.html" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://www.nokia.com/bell-labs/about/dennis-m-ritchie/other...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 09 Nov 2025 09:05:27 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45864116</link><dc:creator>mjd</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45864116</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45864116</guid></item><item><title>New comment by piker in "I Am Mark Zuckerberg"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Interesting look into what Zuck and other mega celebrities experience day to day. I'm sure Zuck and others of a certain stature have many protection layers, but surely some things slip through and it's interesting to consider those just a tier lower that can't afford all of the security, etc.&lt;p&gt;Reminds me of the Bill Murray quote: "I always want to say to people who want to be rich and famous: 'try being rich first'. See if that doesn't cover most of it."&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 09 Nov 2025 09:03:20 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45864103</link><dc:creator>piker</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45864103</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45864103</guid></item><item><title>New comment by jowea in "I Am Mark Zuckerberg"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;This is why we should replace names with uuids.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 09 Nov 2025 08:36:07 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45863939</link><dc:creator>jowea</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45863939</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45863939</guid></item><item><title>New comment by thesumofall in "How Airbus took off"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I worked for Airbus a long time ago, and obviously I have some rose-tinted glasses, but what stands out in my memories:&lt;p&gt;- While the French and Germans love to hate each other, they culturally complement each other very well. I don’t think Airbus could have happened as a purely French or German project (and yes, the UK and Spain are also part of Airbus but are much less visible)&lt;p&gt;- Despite being a highly political entity, you wouldn’t feel any of that day to day. Even up to the highest management levels, it felt like an engineering company focused on incredibly hard engineering challenges. Every once in a while, there was fighting over which country would get which work share for a new project, but it felt more like internal teams pushing their pet peeves rather than external political influence&lt;p&gt;- It was a truly international company. My first team had eight colleagues based in four countries. To make it all work, they had some very early video conferencing systems where the equipment would take up entire side rooms.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 09 Nov 2025 07:22:24 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45863606</link><dc:creator>thesumofall</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45863606</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45863606</guid></item><item><title>New comment by bawolff in "Boring Company fined nearly $500K after it dumped drilling fluids into manholes"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;How is that only a $500,000 fine???&lt;p&gt;Stopping when inspectors are there only to restart once they leave is willful enough that you wonder why this doesn't go into criminal liability?&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 09 Nov 2025 04:35:29 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45862928</link><dc:creator>bawolff</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45862928</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45862928</guid></item><item><title>New comment by nullhole in "Largest cargo sailboat completes first Atlantic crossing"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;They have a passenger service too!&lt;p&gt;€3200 for France &lt;-&gt; Baltimore, 13 day trip. But with that you get three meals a day, a decent looking cabin, private bathroom, private balcony, and internet service (though how solid the connection is / what surcharges there may be is a question).&lt;p&gt;~€250/d doesn't sound too bad, and you could get work done along the way. Kind of sounds nice...&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.voilasailcoop.fr/transatlantic/" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://www.voilasailcoop.fr/transatlantic/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.voilasailcoop.fr/transatlantic/transatlantic-a-bord/" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://www.voilasailcoop.fr/transatlantic/transatlantic-a-b...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 09 Nov 2025 03:08:30 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45862554</link><dc:creator>nullhole</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45862554</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45862554</guid></item><item><title>New comment by Arrath in "Judge denies request to exempt Flock footage from Public Records Act"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Good, such records shouldn't be exempt. So what if they were gathered by a third party, it was a service carried out under request of the local government/law enforcement, and paid for by public money.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 09 Nov 2025 01:47:32 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45862150</link><dc:creator>Arrath</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45862150</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45862150</guid></item></channel></rss>