<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>Hacker News: Best Comments</title><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/bestcomments</link><description>Hacker News RSS</description><docs>https://hnrss.org/</docs><generator>hnrss v2.1.1</generator><lastBuildDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 02:35:45 +0000</lastBuildDate><ns0:link href="https://hnrss.org/bestcomments" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item><title>New comment by cbsks in "LinkedIn checks for 2953 browser extensions"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Looks like Firefox is immune.&lt;p&gt;This works by looking for web accessible resources that are provided by the extensions. For Chrome, these are are available in a webpage via the URL chrome-extension://[PACKAGE ID]/[PATH] &lt;a href="https://developer.chrome.com/docs/extensions/reference/manifest/web-accessible-resources" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://developer.chrome.com/docs/extensions/reference/manif...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;On Firefox, web accessible resources are available at "moz-extension://&lt;extension-UUID&gt;/myfile.png" &lt;extension-UUID&gt; is not your extension's ID. This ID is randomly generated for every browser instance. This prevents websites from fingerprinting a browser by examining the extensions it has installed. &lt;a href="https://developer.mozilla.org/en-US/docs/Mozilla/Add-ons/WebExtensions/manifest.json/web_accessible_resources" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://developer.mozilla.org/en-US/docs/Mozilla/Add-ons/Web...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 20:58:05 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46905200</link><dc:creator>cbsks</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46905200</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46905200</guid></item><item><title>New comment by toomanyrichies in "Flock CEO calls Deflock a “terrorist organization” (2025) [video]"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;"Thankfully, we live in a beautifully democratic and capitalistic society where we can fight in court."&lt;p&gt;Of course he's "thankful" for that, since in our "beautifully democratic and capitalistic" society, Flock can use their $658 million of VC funding [1] to wage lawfare against the have-nots with their armies of lobbyists and lawyers. [2]&lt;p&gt;1. &lt;a href="https://websets.exa.ai/websets/directory/flock-safety-funding"&gt;https://websets.exa.ai/websets/directory/flock-safety-fundin...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;2. &lt;a href="https://www.opensecrets.org/federal-lobbying/clients/lobbyists?cycle=2025&amp;id=D000116304" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://www.opensecrets.org/federal-lobbying/clients/lobbyis...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 20:12:15 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46904525</link><dc:creator>toomanyrichies</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46904525</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46904525</guid></item><item><title>New comment by tylerchilds in "Flock CEO calls Deflock a “terrorist organization” (2025) [video]"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Pointing cameras at people? Law and order&lt;p&gt;Pointing cameras at cameras? Terrorist organization&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 19:43:44 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46904105</link><dc:creator>tylerchilds</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46904105</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46904105</guid></item><item><title>New comment by clintfred in "CIA suddenly stops publishing, removes archives of The World Factbook"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Facts are the enemy.&lt;p&gt;I remember reading books like 1984 and Fahrenheit 451 as a teen thinking, "Cool story, but the US will never look like that." Oof.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 18:31:09 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46903021</link><dc:creator>clintfred</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46903021</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46903021</guid></item><item><title>New comment by gizmodo59 in "Claude Opus 4.6"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;5.3 codex &lt;a href="https://openai.com/index/introducing-gpt-5-3-codex/" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://openai.com/index/introducing-gpt-5-3-codex/&lt;/a&gt; crushes with a 77.3% in Terminal Bench. The shortest lived lead in less than 35 minutes. What a time to be alive!&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 18:14:01 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46902729</link><dc:creator>gizmodo59</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46902729</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46902729</guid></item><item><title>New comment by granzymes in "GPT-5.3-Codex"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I think Anthropic rushed out the release before 10am this morning to avoid having to put in comparisons to GPT-5.3-codex!&lt;p&gt;The new Opus 4.6 scores 65.4 on Terminal-Bench 2.0, up from 64.7 from GPT-5.2-codex.&lt;p&gt;GPT-5.3-codex scores 77.3.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 18:12:39 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46902712</link><dc:creator>granzymes</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46902712</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46902712</guid></item><item><title>New comment by simonw in "Claude Opus 4.6"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;The bicycle frame is a bit wonky but the pelican itself is great: &lt;a href="https://gist.github.com/simonw/a6806ce41b4c721e240a4548ecdbe216?permalink_comment_id=5972110#gistcomment-5972110" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://gist.github.com/simonw/a6806ce41b4c721e240a4548ecdbe...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 17:58:52 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46902495</link><dc:creator>simonw</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46902495</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46902495</guid></item><item><title>New comment by rogerrogerr in "Claude Opus 4.6"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Amateur. Opus 4.6 this afternoon built me a startup that identifies developers who aren’t embracing AI fully, liquifies them and sells the produce for $5/gallon. Software Engineering is over!&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 17:53:38 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46902421</link><dc:creator>rogerrogerr</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46902421</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46902421</guid></item><item><title>New comment by GenerocUsername in "Claude Opus 4.6"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;This is huge. It only came out 8 minutes ago but I was already able to bootstrap a 12k per month revenue SaaS startup!&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 17:50:06 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46902369</link><dc:creator>GenerocUsername</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46902369</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46902369</guid></item><item><title>New comment by adamcharnock in "Don't rent the cloud, own instead"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;This is an industry we're[0] in. Owning is at one end of the spectrum, with cloud at the other, and a broadly couple of options in-between:&lt;p&gt;1 - Cloud – This is minimising cap-ex, hiring, and risk, while largely maximising operational costs (its expensive) and cost variability (usage based).&lt;p&gt;2 - Managed Private Cloud - What we do. Still minimal-to-no cap-ex, hiring, risk, and medium-sized operational cost (around 50% cheaper than AWS et al). We rent or colocate bare metal, manage it for you, handle software deployments, deploy only open-source, etc. Only really makes sense above €$5k/month spend.&lt;p&gt;3 - Rented Bare Metal – Let someone else handle the hardware financing for you. Still minimal cap-ex, but with greater hiring/skilling and risk. Around 90% cheaper than AWS et al (plus time).&lt;p&gt;4 - Buy and colocate the hardware yourself – Certainly the cheapest option if you have the skills, scale, cap-ex, and if you plan to run the servers for at least 3-5 years.&lt;p&gt;A good provider for option 3 is someone like Hetzner. Their internal ROI on server hardware seems to be around the 3 year mark. After which I assume it is either still running with a client, or goes into their server auction system.&lt;p&gt;Options 3 &amp; 4 generally become more appealing either at scale, or when infrastructure is part of the core business. Option 1 is great for startups who want to spend very little initially, but then grow very quickly. Option 2 is pretty good for SMEs with baseline load, regular-sized business growth, and maybe an overworked DevOps team!&lt;p&gt;[0] &lt;a href="https://lithus.eu" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://lithus.eu&lt;/a&gt;, adam@&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 08:57:13 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46897416</link><dc:creator>adamcharnock</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46897416</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46897416</guid></item><item><title>New comment by Stratoscope in "Why more companies are recognizing the benefits of keeping older employees"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Many years ago, I worked at a company with a product that ran on Mac and Windows. The Mac version was pretty solid, but the Windows version had some problems.&lt;p&gt;They had a talented team of developers who were mostly Mac experts and just starting to get a grip on Windows.&lt;p&gt;I was known at the time as a "Windows expert", so they hired me to help the team get the Windows version into shape.&lt;p&gt;My typical day started with "house calls". People would ping me with their Windows questions and I'd go door to door to help solve them - &lt;i&gt;and&lt;/i&gt; to make sure they understood how to do things on Windows.&lt;p&gt;In the afternoon, I would work on my own code, but I told everyone they could always call on me for help with a Windows problem, any time of day.&lt;p&gt;One colleague asked me: "Mike, how can you afford to be so generous with your time?"&lt;p&gt;Then in a performance review, I got this feedback:&lt;p&gt;"Mike, we're worried. Your productivity has been OK lately, but not great. And it's surprising, because the productivity of the rest of the team has improved a &lt;i&gt;lot&lt;/i&gt; during this time."&lt;p&gt;I bit my tongue, but in retrospect I should have said:&lt;p&gt;"Isn't that what you hired me for?"&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 05:51:21 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46896158</link><dc:creator>Stratoscope</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46896158</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46896158</guid></item><item><title>New comment by doctoboggan in "ICE seeks industry input on ad tech location data for investigative use"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Hopefully this is a wakeup call to the software engineers and other employees at those companies - it's no longer a hypothetical future where the tools you are building might be abused, it's today.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 05:33:23 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46896048</link><dc:creator>doctoboggan</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46896048</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46896048</guid></item><item><title>New comment by FeteCommuniste in "Child prodigies rarely become elite performers"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&gt; Around 90% of superstar adults had not been superstars as children, while only 10% of top-level kids had gone on to become exceptional adults (see chart 1). It is not just that exceptional performance in childhood did not predict exceptional performance as an adult. The two were actually negatively correlated, says Dr Güllich.&lt;p&gt;Even if "only" 10% of elite kids go on to become elite adults, 10% is orders of magnitude larger than the base percentage of adults who are elite athletes, musicians, etc. This doesn't sound "uncorrelated" to me so much as "not as strongly correlated as one might expect."&lt;p&gt;And describing something that happens 10% of the time as "rare" sounds a bit weird, like referring to left-handedness (also about 1 in 10) as rare.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 04:04:10 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46895551</link><dc:creator>FeteCommuniste</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46895551</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46895551</guid></item><item><title>New comment by rr808 in "Why more companies are recognizing the benefits of keeping older employees"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I'm now in my 50s. I tried management but prefer working as an IC. I think I'm good but I know most companies would never hire me. One thing I do now is try to look after all the youngest grads and new joiners. Its so cutthroat now it seems no one has time to help anyone else, so I like helping people get up and running and encouraging them to enjoy their work while being productive and getting their skills up. No one else seems to care.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 04:04:06 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46895550</link><dc:creator>rr808</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46895550</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46895550</guid></item><item><title>New comment by kstrauser in "AI is killing B2B SaaS"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;OTOH, I was hired by an enterprise that was many months into a giant backend rewrite. After wrapping my head around the many plans, I realized they were rewriting Django, badly. One weekend I prototyped the whole thing… in Django. It worked. It met the specs. It was a CRUD app with a REST API.&lt;p&gt;I came in to work Monday morning, showed it off, and inadvertently triggered a firestorm. Later my boss told me not to do that again because it caused havoc with schedules and such.&lt;p&gt;So I quit and found a better job. Sometimes the new guy can make a better version themselves over the weekend, not because they’re a supergenius, but because they’re not hampered by 47 teams all trying to get their stamp on the project.&lt;p&gt;(In before “prime example of overconfidence!”: feel free to doubt. It was a CRUD app with a handful of models on a PostgreSQL backend. They were writing a new Python web framework to serve it, complete with their own ORM and forms library and validation library. Not because the existing ones wouldn’t work, mind you, but more out of not realizing that all these problems were already sufficiently solved for their requirements.)&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 02:33:55 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46894917</link><dc:creator>kstrauser</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46894917</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46894917</guid></item><item><title>New comment by huwsername in "OpenClaw is what Apple intelligence should have been"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I don’t believe this was ever confirmed by Apple, but there was widespread speculation at the time[1] that the delay was due to the very prompt injection attacks OpenClaw users are now discovering. It would be genuinely catastrophic to ship an insecure system with this kind of data access, even with an ‘unsafe mode’.&lt;p&gt;These kinds of risks can only be _consented to_ by technical people who correctly understand them, let alone borne by them, but if this shipped there would be thousands of Facebook videos explaining to the elderly how to disable the safety features and open themselves up to identity theft.&lt;p&gt;The article also confuses me because Apple _are_ shipping this, it’s pretty much exactly the demo they gave at WWDC24, it’s just delayed while they iron this out (if that is at all possible). By all accounts it might ship as early as next week in the iOS 26.4 beta.&lt;p&gt;[1]: &lt;a href="https://simonwillison.net/2025/Mar/8/delaying-personalized-siri/" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://simonwillison.net/2025/Mar/8/delaying-personalized-s...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 01:52:10 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46894613</link><dc:creator>huwsername</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46894613</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46894613</guid></item><item><title>New comment by crazygringo in "OpenClaw is what Apple intelligence should have been"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&gt; &lt;i&gt;This is exactly what Apple Intelligence should have been... They could have shipped an agentic AI that actually automated your computer instead of summarizing your notifications. Imagine if Siri could genuinely file your taxes, respond to emails, or manage your calendar by actually using your apps, not through some brittle API layer that breaks every update.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;p&gt;And this is probably coming, a few years from now. Because remember, Apple doesn't usually invent new products. It takes proven ones and then makes its own much nicer version.&lt;p&gt;Let other companies figure out the model. Let the industry figure out how to make it secure. &lt;i&gt;Then&lt;/i&gt; Apple can integrate it with hardware and software in a way no other company can.&lt;p&gt;Right now we are still in very, very, very early days.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 01:11:45 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46894312</link><dc:creator>crazygringo</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46894312</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46894312</guid></item><item><title>New comment by ChuckMcM in "Microsoft's Copilot chatbot is running into problems"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I expect this is the crux of the problem.&lt;p&gt;There &lt;i&gt;aren't&lt;/i&gt; any "AI" products that have enough value.&lt;p&gt;Compare to their Office suite, which had 100 - 150 engineers working on it, every business paid big $$ for every employee using it, and once they shipped install media their ongoing costs were the employees. With a 1,000,000:1 ratio of users to developers and an operating expense (OpEx) of engineers/offices/management. That works as a business.&lt;p&gt;But with "AI", not only is it not a product in itself, it's a &lt;i&gt;feature&lt;/i&gt; to a product, but it has OpEx and CapEx costs that dominate the balance sheet based on their public disclosures. Worse, as a feature, it demonstrably &lt;i&gt;harms&lt;/i&gt; business with its hallucinations.&lt;p&gt;In a normal world, at this point companies would say, "hmm, well we thought it could be amazing but it just doesn't work as a product or a feature of a product because we can't sell it for enough money to both cover its operation, &lt;i&gt;and&lt;/i&gt; its development, &lt;i&gt;and&lt;/i&gt; the capital expenditures we need to make every time someone signs up. So a normal C staff would make some post about "too early" or whatever and shelve it. But we don't live in a normal world, so companies are literally burning the cash they need to survive the future in a vain hope that somehow, somewhere, a real product will emerge.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 23:12:17 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46893258</link><dc:creator>ChuckMcM</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46893258</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46893258</guid></item><item><title>New comment by bandrami in "AI is killing B2B SaaS"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;It's a tale as old as time that developers, particularly junior developers, are convinced they could "slap together something in one weekend" that would replace expensive SAAS software and "just do the parts of it we actually use". Unfortunately, the same arguments against those devs regular-coding a bespoke replacement apply to them vibe-coding a bespoke replacement: management simply &lt;i&gt;doesn't want to be responsible for it&lt;/i&gt;. I didn't understand it before I was in management either, but now that I'm in management I 100% get it.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 21:50:32 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46892313</link><dc:creator>bandrami</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46892313</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46892313</guid></item><item><title>New comment by kriro in "AI is killing B2B SaaS"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I'd actually say the opposite is the case. B2B (even SaaS) is probably the most robust when it comes to AI resistance. The described "in house vibe coded SaaS replacement" does not mirror my experience in B2B at all. The B2B software mindset I've encountered the most is "We'll pay you so we don't have to wrestle with this and can focus on what we do. We'll pay you even more if we worry even less." which is basically the opposite of...let's have someone inhouse vibe code and push to production. B2B is usually fairly conservative.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 20:34:34 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46891299</link><dc:creator>kriro</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46891299</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46891299</guid></item><item><title>New comment by falloutx in "Claude Code for Infrastructure"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;All these tools to build something, but nothing to build. I feel like I am part of a Pyramid Scheme where every product is about building something else, but nothing reaches the end user.&lt;p&gt;Note: nothing against fluid.sh, I am struggling to figure out something to build.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 20:04:39 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46890881</link><dc:creator>falloutx</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46890881</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46890881</guid></item><item><title>New comment by _fat_santa in "Microsoft's Copilot chatbot is running into problems"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;The biggest issue I see is Microsoft's entire mentality around AI adoption that focuses more on "getting the numbers up" then actually delivering a product people want to use.&lt;p&gt;Most of the announcements I hear about Copilot, it's always how they've integrated it into some other piece of software or cut a deal with yet another vendor to add it to that vendors product offering. On the surface there's nothing wrong with doing that but that just seems to be the ONLY thing Microsoft is focused on.&lt;p&gt;Worse yet, most of these integrations seem like a exercise in ticking boxes rather than actually thinking through how integrating Copilot into a product will actually improve user experience. A great example was someone mentioned that Copilot was now integrated into the terminal app but beyond an icon + a chat window, there is zero integration.&lt;p&gt;Overall, MS just reeks of an organization that is cares more about numbers on a dashboard and pretty reports than they are on what users are actually experiencing.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 17:40:23 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46888871</link><dc:creator>_fat_santa</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46888871</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46888871</guid></item><item><title>New comment by simonw in "Voxtral Transcribe 2"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;This demo is &lt;i&gt;really&lt;/i&gt; impressive: &lt;a href="https://huggingface.co/spaces/mistralai/Voxtral-Mini-Realtime" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://huggingface.co/spaces/mistralai/Voxtral-Mini-Realtim...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;Don't be confused if it says "no microphone", the moment you click the record button it will request browser permission and then start working.&lt;p&gt;I spoke fast and dropped in some jargon and it got it all right - I said this and it transcribed it exactly right, WebAssembly spelling included:&lt;p&gt;&gt; Can you tell me about RSS and Atom and the role of CSP headers in browser security, especially if you're using WebAssembly?&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 16:21:17 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46887747</link><dc:creator>simonw</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46887747</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46887747</guid></item><item><title>New comment by fallous in "I miss thinking hard"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;You just described the burden of outsourcing programming.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 05:51:31 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46881955</link><dc:creator>fallous</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46881955</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46881955</guid></item><item><title>New comment by utopiah in "X offices raided in France as UK opens fresh investigation into Grok"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;To people claiming a physical raid is pointless from the point of gathering data :&lt;p&gt;- you are thinking about a company doing good things the right way. You are thinking about a company abiding by the law, storing data on its own server, having good practices, etc.&lt;p&gt;The moment a company starts to do dubious stuff then good practices start to go out the window. People write email with cryptic analogies, people start deleting emails, ... then as the circumvention become more numerous and complex, there needs to still be a trail in order to remain understandable. That trail will be in written form somehow and that must be hidden. It might be paper, it might be shadow IT but the point is that if you are not just forgetting to keep track of coffee pods at the social corner, you will leave traces.&lt;p&gt;So yes, raids do make sense BECAUSE it's about recurring complex activities that are just too hard to keep in the mind of one single individual over long periods of time.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 05:44:35 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46881916</link><dc:creator>utopiah</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46881916</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46881916</guid></item><item><title>New comment by helloplanets in "I miss thinking hard"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;And when programming with agentic tools, you need to actively push for the idea to not regress to the most obvious/average version. The amount of effort you need to expend on pushing the idea that deviates from the 'norm' (because it's novel), is actually comparable to the effort it takes to type something out by hand. Just two completely different types of effort.&lt;p&gt;There's an upside to this sort of effort too, though. You actually need to make it crystal clear what your idea is and what it is not, because of the continuous pushback from the agentic programming tool. The moment you stop pushing back, is the moment the LLM rolls over your project and more than likely destroys what was unique about your thing in the first place.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 05:08:36 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46881725</link><dc:creator>helloplanets</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46881725</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46881725</guid></item><item><title>New comment by keyle in "I miss thinking hard"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I don't get it.&lt;p&gt;I think just as hard, I type less. I specify precisely and I review.&lt;p&gt;If anything, all we've changed is working at a higher level. The product is the same.&lt;p&gt;But these people just keep mixing things up like "wow I got a ferrari now, watch it fly off the road!"&lt;p&gt;Yeah so you got a tools upgrade; it's faster, it's more powerful. Keep it on the road or give up driving!&lt;p&gt;We went from auto completing keywords, to auto completing symbols, to auto completing statements, to auto completing paragraphs, to auto completing entire features.&lt;p&gt;Because it happened so fast, people feel the need to rename programming every week. We either vibe coders now, or agentic coders or ... or just programmers hey. You know why? I write in C, I get machine code, I didn't write the machine code! It was all an abstraction!&lt;p&gt;Oh but it's not the same you say, it changes every time you ask. Yes, for now, it's still wonky and janky in places. It's just a stepping stone.&lt;p&gt;Just chill, it's programming. The tools just got even better.&lt;p&gt;You can still jump on a camel and cross the desert in 3 days. Have at it, you risk dying, but enjoy. Or you can just rent a helicopter and fly over the damn thing in a few hours. Your choice. Don't let people tell you it isn't travelling.&lt;p&gt;We're all Linus Torvalds now. We review, we merge, we send back. And if you had no idea what you were doing before, you'll still have no idea what you're doing today. You just fat-finger less typos today than ever before.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 05:07:50 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46881716</link><dc:creator>keyle</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46881716</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46881716</guid></item><item><title>New comment by gyomu in "I miss thinking hard"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;This March 2025 post from Aral Balkan stuck with me:&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://mastodon.ar.al/@aral/114160190826192080" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://mastodon.ar.al/@aral/114160190826192080&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;"Coding is like taking a lump of clay and slowly working it into the thing you want it to become. It is this process, and your intimacy with the medium and the materials you’re shaping, that teaches you about what you’re making – its qualities, tolerances, and limits – even as you make it. You know the least about what you’re making the moment before you actually start making it. That’s when you think you know what you want to make. The process, which is an iterative one, is what leads you towards understanding what you actually want to make, whether you were aware of it or not at the beginning. Design is not merely about solving problems; it’s about discovering what the right problem to solve is and then solving it. Too often we fail not because we didn’t solve a problem well but because we solved the wrong problem.&lt;p&gt;When you skip the process of creation you trade the thing you could have learned to make for the simulacrum of the thing you thought you wanted to make. Being handed a baked and glazed artefact that approximates what you thought you wanted to make removes the very human element of discovery and learning that’s at the heart of any authentic practice of creation. Where you know everything about the thing you shaped into being from when it was just a lump of clay, you know nothing about the image of the thing you received for your penny from the vending machine."&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 04:42:51 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46881543</link><dc:creator>gyomu</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46881543</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46881543</guid></item><item><title>New comment by elamje in "Data centers in space makes no sense"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I was talking to someone about this the other day. I was part of a team at NASA that developed a cooling system for the ISS and this whole premise makes no sense to me.&lt;p&gt;1. Getting things to space is incredibly expensive&lt;p&gt;2. Ingress/egress are almost always a major bottleneck - how is bandwidth cheaper in space?&lt;p&gt;3. Chips must be “Rad-hard” - that is do more error correcting from ionizing radiation - there were entire teams at NASA dedicated to special hardware for this.&lt;p&gt;4. Gravity and atmospheric pressure actually do wonders for easy cooling. Heat is not dissipated in space like we are all used to and you must burn additional energy trying to move the heat generated away from source.&lt;p&gt;5. Energy production will be cheaper from earth due to mass manufacturing of necessary components in energy systems - space energy systems need novel technology where economies of scale are lost.&lt;p&gt;Would love for someone to make the case for why it actually makes total sense, because it’s really hard to see for me!&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 02:16:32 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46880580</link><dc:creator>elamje</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46880580</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46880580</guid></item><item><title>New comment by hirsin in "Data centers in space makes no sense"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Simply put no, 50MW is not the typical hyperscaler cloud size. It's not even the typical single datacenter size.&lt;p&gt;A single AI rack consumes 60kW, and there is apparently a single DC that alone consumes 650MW.&lt;p&gt;When Microsoft puts in a DC, the machines are done in units of a "stamp", ie a couple racks together. These aren't scaled by dollar or sqft, but by the MW.&lt;p&gt;And on top of that... That's a bunch of satellites not even trying to crunch data at top speed. No where near the right order of magnitude.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 01:43:28 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46880296</link><dc:creator>hirsin</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46880296</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46880296</guid></item></channel></rss>