<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>Hacker News: Best Comments</title><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/bestcomments</link><description>Hacker News RSS</description><docs>https://hnrss.org/</docs><generator>hnrss v2.1.1</generator><lastBuildDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 00:08:34 +0000</lastBuildDate><ns0:link href="https://hnrss.org/bestcomments" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item><title>New comment by hardwaregeek in "Uv is the best thing to happen to the Python ecosystem in a decade"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I gotta say, I feel pretty vindicated after hearing for years how Python’s tooling was just fine and you should just use virtualenv with pip and how JS must be worse, that when Python devs finally get a taste of npm/cargo/bundler in their ecosystem, they freaking love it. Because yes, npm has its issues but lock files and consistent installs are amazing&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 20:01:34 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45752272</link><dc:creator>hardwaregeek</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45752272</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45752272</guid></item><item><title>New comment by NelsonMinar in "Minecraft removing obfuscation in Java Edition"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;It's extraordinary to me that Minecraft is both the game that has the most robust mod community out there and that the modders were working from obfuscated, decompiled Java binaries. With elaborate tooling to deobfuscate and then reobfuscate using the same mangled names. For over a decade! What dedication.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 18:28:48 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45751039</link><dc:creator>NelsonMinar</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45751039</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45751039</guid></item><item><title>New comment by AdmiralAsshat in "Tell HN: Azure outage"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Some exec at Microsoft told the Azure guys to ape everything Amazon does and they took it literally.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 17:06:10 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45749790</link><dc:creator>AdmiralAsshat</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45749790</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45749790</guid></item><item><title>New comment by Brett_Riverboat in "YouTube is taking down videos on performing nonstandard Windows 11 installs"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;For those who care at the first setup screen instead of answering any of the questions press Shift + F10&lt;p&gt;CMD will open&lt;p&gt;Type (no quotes) “net user Prefferedusername /add” (replacing Prefferedusername with the user name you wish to use) and press enter.&lt;p&gt;Next type “net localgroup administrators Prefferedusername /add” and press enter.&lt;p&gt;Next type “net user Prefferedusername /active:yes” and press enter.&lt;p&gt;Next type “net user Prefferedusername /expires:never” and press enter.&lt;p&gt;Next type “net user administrator /active:no” and press enter.&lt;p&gt;Next type “net user defaultUser0 /delete” (this is case sensitive make sure the "U" is capitalized) and press enter.&lt;p&gt;Next type "regedit" and press enter.&lt;p&gt;This opens registry editor, navigate to "HKEY_LOCAL_MACHINE\SOFTWARE\Microsoft\Windows\CurrentVersion\OOBE"&lt;p&gt;Delete "DefaultAccountAction", "DefaultAccountSAMName", and "DefaultAccountSID"&lt;p&gt;Right click on "LaunchUserOOBE" and rename it to "SkipMachineOOBE" and make sure the value is set to "1".&lt;p&gt;Close registry editor and type "shutdown /r /t 0"&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 12:44:52 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45746112</link><dc:creator>Brett_Riverboat</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45746112</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45746112</guid></item><item><title>New comment by TeMPOraL in "Keep Android Open"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Answer: bank/financial apps, enterprise apps, government apps and copyrighted media (music, video, games, books, ...).&lt;p&gt;Those are the players that &lt;i&gt;demand&lt;/i&gt; excessive control over end-user devices, and thus the ultimate driver behind the problem we're discussing.&lt;p&gt;It's not that &lt;i&gt;a&lt;/i&gt; new mobile platform couldn't possibly succeed. It's an &lt;i&gt;open&lt;/i&gt; platform that cannot, because aforementioned players don't want it, and without them, mobile devices lose 90%+ of their usefulness, dooming them to become mere gadgets instead of (crappy, toylike) tools for everyday use.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 12:17:42 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45745827</link><dc:creator>TeMPOraL</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45745827</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45745827</guid></item><item><title>New comment by bilekas in "AWS to bare metal two years later: Answering your questions about leaving AWS"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I'm so surprised there is so much pushback against this.. AWS is extremely expensive. The use cases for setting up your system or service entirely in AWS are more rare than people seem to realise. Maybe I'm just the old man screaming at cloud (no pun intended) but when did people forget how to run a baremetal server ?&lt;p&gt;&gt; We have 730+ days with 99.993% measured availability and we also escaped AWS region wide downtime that happened a week ago.&lt;p&gt;This is a very nice brag. Given they are using their ddos protection ingress via CloudFlare there is that dependancy, but in that case I can 100% agree than DNS and ingress can absolutely be a full time job. Running some microservices and a database absolutely is not. If your teams are constantly monitoring and adjusting them such as scaling, then the problem is the design. Not the hosting.&lt;p&gt;Unless you're a small company serving up billions of heavy requests an hour, I would put money on the bet AWS is overcharging you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 11:50:58 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45745567</link><dc:creator>bilekas</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45745567</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45745567</guid></item><item><title>New comment by liendolucas in "Keep Android Open"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I'm going to say something that probably will get me down votes:&lt;p&gt;Why do we have to beg Google to keep Android open? Seriously. So many open source projects have risen out of real and concrete needs and successfully made their way into our every day lives.&lt;p&gt;A new platform needs to rise that breaks out completely from Google. I've given PostmarketOS a go (with a PinePhone) and while today I can't say it isn't a daily driver for everyone it is certainly the route that needs to be taken.&lt;p&gt;I'm still unable to use it because is not easy to break away from Android, but is a platform that I think about almost every day, because I do not want to use Android anymore and I'm willing to sacrifice certain aspects to have an open and friendly platform on my hands. And if it is not PostmarketOS then let it be another project.&lt;p&gt;We need these kind of projects, not kneeling down to a company like Google and begging for Android to be open. Effort needs to be put elsewhere. That's how major projects like Linux, BSDs and open source projects have flourished and taken the world.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 11:17:22 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45745309</link><dc:creator>liendolucas</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45745309</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45745309</guid></item><item><title>New comment by breve in "YouTube is taking down videos on performing nonstandard Windows 11 installs"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;The solution is to run Linux. KDE is a good desktop environment: &lt;a href="https://kde.org/" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://kde.org/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;90% of Windows games run on Linux: &lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45736925"&gt;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45736925&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;LibreOffice is an okay office suite (good enough for my purposes): &lt;a href="https://www.libreoffice.org/" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://www.libreoffice.org/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;GIMP is a good image editor: &lt;a href="https://www.gimp.org/" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://www.gimp.org/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;VLC is a good media player: &lt;a href="https://www.videolan.org/vlc/" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://www.videolan.org/vlc/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 09:43:48 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45744605</link><dc:creator>breve</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45744605</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45744605</guid></item><item><title>New comment by jeena in "Keep Android Open"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Back in the 2007 or when it came out in Sweden I bought the iPhone and started developing for it. This was cool, new and exciting and it was fine as long as my company was paying the $100 fee every year. But then I switched jobs and worked at a company which produced mostly open source code. Suddenly I would have to pay $100 every year just to be able to put my own software on the phone ...&lt;p&gt;This is why I switched to Android, just for Google now to pull the rug from under my feet again ...&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 07:01:35 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45743519</link><dc:creator>jeena</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45743519</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45743519</guid></item><item><title>New comment by snorbleck in "ChatGPT's Atlas: The Browser That's Anti-Web"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;This is amazing. My entire web browser session state for every private and personal website I sign onto every day will be used for training data. It's great! I love this. This is exactly the direction humans should be going in to not self-destruct. The future is looking bright, while the light in our brains dims to eventual darkness. Slowly. Tragically. And for what purpose exactly. So cool.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 04:31:02 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45742646</link><dc:creator>snorbleck</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45742646</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45742646</guid></item><item><title>New comment by mtud in "Keeping the Internet fast and secure: introducing Merkle Tree Certificates"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&gt; During the TLS handshake, the client tells the server which treeheads it has.&lt;p&gt;I don’t love the idea of giving every server I connect to via TLS the ability to fingerprint me by how recently (or not) I’ve fetched MTC treeheads. Even worse if this is in client hello, where anyone on the network path can view it either per connection or for my DoH requests to bootstrap encrypted client hello.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 03:33:25 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45742317</link><dc:creator>mtud</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45742317</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45742317</guid></item><item><title>New comment by nrmitchi in "Nvidia takes $1B stake in Nokia"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Nvidia seems to be operating more like a sovereign wealth fund than a traditional business. They have a very-in-demand product, that is not likely to last forever, and is getting their fingers in as many pies as possible with the money and influence while they have it.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 02:13:28 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45741836</link><dc:creator>nrmitchi</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45741836</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45741836</guid></item><item><title>New comment by stavros in "Tinkering is a way to acquire good taste"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Decades ago, an old friend told me "I became a coffee expert, I learned everything there is to learn about beans, the ways to prepare them, the chemistry that goes into it, and now I can only enjoy a cup of coffee prepared by the most expensive machines from the most expensive beans. The shit part is that I enjoy it just as much as I enjoyed my shitty supermarket coffee back when I didn't know anything about coffee."&lt;p&gt;That advice has stuck with me, and I try to have the least taste I can. I use $20 headphones and a $200 TV because I can't tell what "good" is, and I enjoy music and movies as much as my friends with $600 headphones and $3k TVs do.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 00:46:46 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45741266</link><dc:creator>stavros</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45741266</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45741266</guid></item><item><title>New comment by Grom_PE in "Nearly 90% of Windows Games Now Run on Linux"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I've gone over to Linux after using Windows for 25 years.&lt;p&gt;As someone who enjoys older games, I am pleasantly surprised that Wine (with dxvk and cnc-ddraw) lets me run more games in a better way than I was able to on Windows.&lt;p&gt;I can run some 16-bit games on a 64-bit OS!&lt;p&gt;Games that rudely switch to fullscreen, I can run in Wine Virtual Desktop. Previously on Windows, I had to configure hacks like DxWnd and it didn't always work.&lt;p&gt;I only wish Wine also allowed me to zoom 2x or 3x, but this is where Gamescope comes in:&lt;p&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;    gamescope -S integer -F nearest --borderless wine game.exe
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
Also there is a potential to use a different Wine configuration (prefix) for every game specifically. So far I haven't had to resort to this.&lt;p&gt;I noticed some Unity games waste disk space with gigabytes of zeroes, Linux lets me run them from inside a compressed SquashFS image, this even makes the game load faster:&lt;p&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;    mkdir ./game
    squashfuse ./game.squashfs ./game
    pushd ./game
    wine game.exe
    popd
    sleep 1
    umount ./game
    rmdir ./game
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
I encountered a game that crashes due to multiprocessor system, the fix is simple, restricting it to one CPU:&lt;p&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;    taskset --cpu-list 1 wine game.exe&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2025 23:09:34 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45740506</link><dc:creator>Grom_PE</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45740506</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45740506</guid></item><item><title>New comment by al_borland in "Boring is what we wanted"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I always get a little bothered when I see negative reviews from a CPU update in Apple laptops. While a new CPU alone isn’t a thrilling update, it’s important that they do these regularly so consumers looking to buy aren’t forced to buy a 3 year old product with no idea when a refresh will come. I’ve been in this situation many times with Apple and it has been very frustrating. I’m glad they are back on a yearly refresh schedule.&lt;p&gt;I think the issue stems from too many people making their living off reviews that require something exciting to get views. When updates are more evolution than revolution, it makes for a more boring article/video. I always worry that these types of responses will lead Apple to do silly things, like leaving old chips out there too long, or adding pointless features just so there is something new to talk about.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2025 21:58:41 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45739781</link><dc:creator>al_borland</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45739781</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45739781</guid></item><item><title>New comment by marcprux in "What we talk about when we talk about sideloading"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Author here. I admit I am rather startled by the tone of many comments here and the accusations of disingenuity. Splitting hairs about the origin of the term "sideload" does not change the fact that those who promote the term tend to do so in order to make it feel deviant and hacker-ish. You don't "sideload" software on your Linux, Windows, or macOS computer: you install it.&lt;p&gt;You have the right to install whatever you want on your computer, regardless of whether that computer is on your desk or in your pocket. That's a hill I'll die on. I'm dismayed to see that this sentiment is not more widespread in this of all communities.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2025 19:56:47 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45738237</link><dc:creator>marcprux</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45738237</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45738237</guid></item><item><title>New comment by BrenBarn in "What we talk about when we talk about sideloading"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I think we could set the bar substantially higher.  Don't even bother with discussion of sideloading.  Talk about bounded transactions and device control.&lt;p&gt;What is needed is: Once I have purchased a device, the transaction is over.  I then have 100% control over that device and the hardware maker, the retailer, and the OS maker have a combined 0% control.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2025 19:50:47 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45738134</link><dc:creator>BrenBarn</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45738134</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45738134</guid></item><item><title>New comment by kstrauser in "Samsung makes ads on smart fridges official with upcoming software update"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;This guarantees I'll never buy a Samsung appliance. If they're this willing to screw with their customers today, they'll do it again tomorrow.&lt;p&gt;Sadly, I'm including their TVs in this. I have one today, displaying the output of an Apple TV and not directly connected to the Internet because hah, no way, but I'll be shopping around when it comes time to replace it.&lt;p&gt;Pity. They make nice stuff. Not nice enough that I'm willing to tolerate their anti-customer shenanigans, but otherwise decent quality.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2025 19:26:30 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45737719</link><dc:creator>kstrauser</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45737719</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45737719</guid></item><item><title>New comment by egorfine in "Using AI to negotiate a $195k hospital bill down to $33k"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;[flagged]&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2025 18:42:06 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45736987</link><dc:creator>egorfine</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45736987</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45736987</guid></item><item><title>New comment by chrisgeleven in "Using AI to negotiate a $195k hospital bill down to $33k"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I fought insurance over this past summer after they declined covering a life saving surgery for my 6-year-old child at the last minute. We were in despair that my child's life was at risk each day we waited because of insurance incompetence.&lt;p&gt;ChatGPT literally guided me through the whole external appeal process, who to contact outside of normal channels to ask for help / apply pressure, researched questions I had, helped with wording on the appeals, and yes, helped keep me pushing forward at some of the darkest moments when I was grasping for anything, however small, to help keep the pressure up on the insurance company.&lt;p&gt;I didn't follow everything it suggested blindly. Definitely decided a few times to make decisions that differed from its advice partially or completely, and I sometimes ran suggested next steps by several close friends/family to make sure I wasn't missing something obvious. But the ideas/path ChatGPT suggested, the chasing down different scenarios to rule in/out them, and coaching me through this is what ultimately got movement on our case.&lt;p&gt;10 days post denial, I was able to get the procedure approved from these efforts.&lt;p&gt;21 days post denial and 7 days after the decision was reversed, we lucked into a surgery slot that opened up and my child got their life saving surgery. They have recovered and is in the best health of the past 18 months.&lt;p&gt;This maybe isn't leveling the playing field, at least not entirely. But it gave us a fighting chance on a short timeline and know where to best use our pressure. The hopeful part of me is that many others can use similar techniques to win.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2025 18:39:04 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45736945</link><dc:creator>chrisgeleven</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45736945</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45736945</guid></item><item><title>New comment by ecosystem in "Using AI to negotiate a $195k hospital bill down to $33k"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;The American Medical Association owns copyright to all the codes and their descriptions. They have an extremely restrictive and expensive licensing options and they strictly forbid training models with the codes.&lt;p&gt;This month, the practice was called out (&lt;a href="https://www.help.senate.gov/rep/newsroom/press/chair-cassidy-rebukes-ama-for-abusing-cpt-system-raising-health-care-costs-on-american-families" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://www.help.senate.gov/rep/newsroom/press/chair-cassidy...&lt;/a&gt;) so the Overton window may be opening.&lt;p&gt;The AMA (a nonprofit!) clears ~$300M/year revenue from the codes, which is the direct cost passed through to consumers, but the indirect costs are the byzantine nightmare of OP.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2025 16:55:21 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45735410</link><dc:creator>ecosystem</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45735410</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45735410</guid></item><item><title>New comment by sidewndr46 in "Using AI to negotiate a $195k hospital bill down to $33k"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;having hired an expert in this field, I can tell you they aren't really that sophisticated. I found myself with an absolute mountain of cash after an accident as part of a settlement. My medical insurance won't pay claims until I've exhausted that cash. The claims I had were much higher than even the mountain of cash. The lawyer I hired use a pretty effective strategy: he contacted all of the claims against me and told them we could engage in N-way negotiations amongst all the parties until we came to a settlement so everyone got their nibble of the pie. Or they could get X today, where X was some amount that was a bit less than the rate the industry actually gets paid for those services. They all accepted.&lt;p&gt;The discounts he negotiated left me with tons of cash &amp; were in excess of the fee he charged me.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2025 16:48:19 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45735292</link><dc:creator>sidewndr46</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45735292</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45735292</guid></item><item><title>New comment by ibash in "Using AI to negotiate a $195k hospital bill down to $33k"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;The thing is the prices are all made up anyway. The hospital hallucinates prices, so they don’t blink an eye when an llm does the same.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2025 16:24:17 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45734931</link><dc:creator>ibash</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45734931</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45734931</guid></item><item><title>New comment by adzm in "EuroLLM: LLM made in Europe built to support all 24 official EU languages"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;For those curious, the 24 official languages are Bulgarian, Croatian, Czech, Danish, Dutch, English, Estonian, Finnish, French, German, Greek, Hungarian, Irish, Italian, Latvian, Lithuanian, Maltese, Polish, Portuguese, Romanian, Slovak, Slovenian, Spanish, and Swedish.&lt;p&gt;Maltese, interestingly, is the only Afro-Asiatic derived language.&lt;p&gt;Hungarian, Finnish, and Estonian are the three Uralic languages.&lt;p&gt;All the others are Indo-European, Greek being the only Hellenic one, Irish the only Celtic, the rest are Baltic, Slavic, Italic, or Germanic.&lt;p&gt;(I originally used the term Balto-Slavic, though I was unaware of some of the connotations of that term until just now. Baltic and Slavic do share a common origin, but that was a very very long time ago)&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2025 15:07:45 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45733828</link><dc:creator>adzm</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45733828</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45733828</guid></item><item><title>New comment by no_wizard in "The next chapter of the Microsoft–OpenAI partnership"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;They’ll devalue the term into something that makes it so. The common conception of it however, no I don’t believe we are anywhere close to it.&lt;p&gt;It’s no different than how they moved the goalpost on the definition of AI at the start of this boom cycle&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2025 14:11:56 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45733156</link><dc:creator>no_wizard</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45733156</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45733156</guid></item><item><title>New comment by philipwhiuk in "The next chapter of the Microsoft–OpenAI partnership"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&gt; Once AGI is declared by OpenAI, that declaration will now be verified by an independent expert panel.&lt;p&gt;&gt; Microsoft’s IP rights for both models and products are extended through 2032 and now includes models post-AGI, with appropriate safety guardrails.&lt;p&gt;Does anyone really think we are close to AGI? I mean honestly?&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2025 14:01:00 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45733027</link><dc:creator>philipwhiuk</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45733027</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45733027</guid></item><item><title>New comment by phoe-krk in "Amazon confirms 14,000 job losses in corporate division"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;These aren't "job losses", these are "firings". They aren't unfortunate accidents of external origin that happened to them, they are conscious internal decisions to let people go.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2025 12:01:20 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45731677</link><dc:creator>phoe-krk</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45731677</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45731677</guid></item><item><title>New comment by simonw in "10M people watched a YouTuber shim a lock; the lock company sued him – bad idea"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;This reminded me of Matt Blaze's work on physical lock security back in 2003. He found a method of deriving the "master key" for a building (one key that opens all locks) from a single example: &lt;a href="https://www.mattblaze.org/masterkey.html" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://www.mattblaze.org/masterkey.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;When he published about this he was bombarded with messages from locksmiths complaining that they all knew about this and kept it secret for a reason! &lt;a href="https://www.mattblaze.org/papers/kiss.html" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://www.mattblaze.org/papers/kiss.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;It was a fascinating clash between computer security principles - disclose vulnerabilities - and physical locksmith culture, which was all about trade secrets.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2025 09:32:06 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45730792</link><dc:creator>simonw</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45730792</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45730792</guid></item><item><title>New comment by tgsovlerkhgsel in "PSF has withdrawn $1.5M proposal to US Government grant program"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;This is how DEI &lt;i&gt;should&lt;/i&gt; work, and probably does in some, or maybe many, cases.&lt;p&gt;In other cases, it boiled down to "this quarter, we only have headcount for 'diverse' candidates", metrics for DEI hiring that turn into goals, and e-mails stating "only accept new L3 candidates that are from historically underrepresented groups".&lt;p&gt;I expect that I'll get accused of making this up, which is why the latter is an exact quote shown on page 28 in this court case: &lt;a href="https://www.scribd.com/document/372802863/18-CIV-00442-ARNE-WILBERG-vs-GOOGLE-INC-et-al" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://www.scribd.com/document/372802863/18-CIV-00442-ARNE-...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2025 23:59:33 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45727817</link><dc:creator>tgsovlerkhgsel</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45727817</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45727817</guid></item><item><title>New comment by dekhn in "10M people watched a YouTuber shim a lock; the lock company sued him – bad idea"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I once worked for a company that kept its passwords locked in a safe.  One day, all other copies of the password were lost, and they needed it, but the safe's key could not be found.&lt;p&gt;They expensed a sledgehammer and obtained the password through physical modification of the safe using a careful application of force.  Some employees complained that meant the safe wasn't... well, safe.&lt;p&gt;The security team replied "Working as Intended" - no safe is truly safe, it's just designed to slow down an attacker.  At that moment, I was enlightened.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2025 23:34:21 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45727604</link><dc:creator>dekhn</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45727604</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45727604</guid></item></channel></rss>