<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>Hacker News: Best Comments</title><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/bestcomments</link><description>Hacker News RSS</description><docs>https://hnrss.org/</docs><generator>hnrss v2.1.1</generator><lastBuildDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 02:07:03 +0000</lastBuildDate><ns0:link href="https://hnrss.org/bestcomments" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item><title>New comment by bandrami in "AI is killing B2B SaaS"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;It's a tale as old as time that developers, particularly junior developers, are convinced they could "slap together something in one weekend" that would replace expensive SAAS software and "just do the parts of it we actually use". Unfortunately, the same arguments against those devs regular-coding a bespoke replacement apply to them vibe-coding a bespoke replacement: management simply &lt;i&gt;doesn't want to be responsible for it&lt;/i&gt;. I didn't understand it before I was in management either, but now that I'm in management I 100% get it.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 21:50:32 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46892313</link><dc:creator>bandrami</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46892313</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46892313</guid></item><item><title>New comment by kriro in "AI is killing B2B SaaS"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I'd actually say the opposite is the case. B2B (even SaaS) is probably the most robust when it comes to AI resistance. The described "in house vibe coded SaaS replacement" does not mirror my experience in B2B at all. The B2B software mindset I've encountered the most is "We'll pay you so we don't have to wrestle with this and can focus on what we do. We'll pay you even more if we worry even less." which is basically the opposite of...let's have someone inhouse vibe code and push to production. B2B is usually fairly conservative.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 20:34:34 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46891299</link><dc:creator>kriro</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46891299</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46891299</guid></item><item><title>New comment by falloutx in "Claude Code for Infrastructure"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;All these tools to build something, but nothing to build. I feel like I am part of a Pyramid Scheme where every product is about building something else, but nothing reaches the end user.&lt;p&gt;Note: nothing against fluid.sh, I am struggling to figure out something to build.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 20:04:39 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46890881</link><dc:creator>falloutx</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46890881</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46890881</guid></item><item><title>New comment by simonw in "Voxtral Transcribe 2"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;This demo is &lt;i&gt;really&lt;/i&gt; impressive: &lt;a href="https://huggingface.co/spaces/mistralai/Voxtral-Mini-Realtime" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://huggingface.co/spaces/mistralai/Voxtral-Mini-Realtim...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;Don't be confused if it says "no microphone", the moment you click the record button it will request browser permission and then start working.&lt;p&gt;I spoke fast and dropped in some jargon and it got it all right - I said this and it transcribed it exactly right, WebAssembly spelling included:&lt;p&gt;&gt; Can you tell me about RSS and Atom and the role of CSP headers in browser security, especially if you're using WebAssembly?&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 16:21:17 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46887747</link><dc:creator>simonw</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46887747</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46887747</guid></item><item><title>New comment by fallous in "I miss thinking hard"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;You just described the burden of outsourcing programming.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 05:51:31 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46881955</link><dc:creator>fallous</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46881955</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46881955</guid></item><item><title>New comment by utopiah in "X offices raided in France as UK opens fresh investigation into Grok"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;To people claiming a physical raid is pointless from the point of gathering data :&lt;p&gt;- you are thinking about a company doing good things the right way. You are thinking about a company abiding by the law, storing data on its own server, having good practices, etc.&lt;p&gt;The moment a company starts to do dubious stuff then good practices start to go out the window. People write email with cryptic analogies, people start deleting emails, ... then as the circumvention become more numerous and complex, there needs to still be a trail in order to remain understandable. That trail will be in written form somehow and that must be hidden. It might be paper, it might be shadow IT but the point is that if you are not just forgetting to keep track of coffee pods at the social corner, you will leave traces.&lt;p&gt;So yes, raids do make sense BECAUSE it's about recurring complex activities that are just too hard to keep in the mind of one single individual over long periods of time.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 05:44:35 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46881916</link><dc:creator>utopiah</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46881916</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46881916</guid></item><item><title>New comment by helloplanets in "I miss thinking hard"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;And when programming with agentic tools, you need to actively push for the idea to not regress to the most obvious/average version. The amount of effort you need to expend on pushing the idea that deviates from the 'norm' (because it's novel), is actually comparable to the effort it takes to type something out by hand. Just two completely different types of effort.&lt;p&gt;There's an upside to this sort of effort too, though. You actually need to make it crystal clear what your idea is and what it is not, because of the continuous pushback from the agentic programming tool. The moment you stop pushing back, is the moment the LLM rolls over your project and more than likely destroys what was unique about your thing in the first place.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 05:08:36 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46881725</link><dc:creator>helloplanets</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46881725</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46881725</guid></item><item><title>New comment by keyle in "I miss thinking hard"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I don't get it.&lt;p&gt;I think just as hard, I type less. I specify precisely and I review.&lt;p&gt;If anything, all we've changed is working at a higher level. The product is the same.&lt;p&gt;But these people just keep mixing things up like "wow I got a ferrari now, watch it fly off the road!"&lt;p&gt;Yeah so you got a tools upgrade; it's faster, it's more powerful. Keep it on the road or give up driving!&lt;p&gt;We went from auto completing keywords, to auto completing symbols, to auto completing statements, to auto completing paragraphs, to auto completing entire features.&lt;p&gt;Because it happened so fast, people feel the need to rename programming every week. We either vibe coders now, or agentic coders or ... or just programmers hey. You know why? I write in C, I get machine code, I didn't write the machine code! It was all an abstraction!&lt;p&gt;Oh but it's not the same you say, it changes every time you ask. Yes, for now, it's still wonky and janky in places. It's just a stepping stone.&lt;p&gt;Just chill, it's programming. The tools just got even better.&lt;p&gt;You can still jump on a camel and cross the desert in 3 days. Have at it, you risk dying, but enjoy. Or you can just rent a helicopter and fly over the damn thing in a few hours. Your choice. Don't let people tell you it isn't travelling.&lt;p&gt;We're all Linus Torvalds now. We review, we merge, we send back. And if you had no idea what you were doing before, you'll still have no idea what you're doing today. You just fat-finger less typos today than ever before.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 05:07:50 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46881716</link><dc:creator>keyle</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46881716</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46881716</guid></item><item><title>New comment by gyomu in "I miss thinking hard"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;This March 2025 post from Aral Balkan stuck with me:&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://mastodon.ar.al/@aral/114160190826192080" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://mastodon.ar.al/@aral/114160190826192080&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;"Coding is like taking a lump of clay and slowly working it into the thing you want it to become. It is this process, and your intimacy with the medium and the materials you’re shaping, that teaches you about what you’re making – its qualities, tolerances, and limits – even as you make it. You know the least about what you’re making the moment before you actually start making it. That’s when you think you know what you want to make. The process, which is an iterative one, is what leads you towards understanding what you actually want to make, whether you were aware of it or not at the beginning. Design is not merely about solving problems; it’s about discovering what the right problem to solve is and then solving it. Too often we fail not because we didn’t solve a problem well but because we solved the wrong problem.&lt;p&gt;When you skip the process of creation you trade the thing you could have learned to make for the simulacrum of the thing you thought you wanted to make. Being handed a baked and glazed artefact that approximates what you thought you wanted to make removes the very human element of discovery and learning that’s at the heart of any authentic practice of creation. Where you know everything about the thing you shaped into being from when it was just a lump of clay, you know nothing about the image of the thing you received for your penny from the vending machine."&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 04:42:51 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46881543</link><dc:creator>gyomu</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46881543</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46881543</guid></item><item><title>New comment by elamje in "Data centers in space makes no sense"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I was talking to someone about this the other day. I was part of a team at NASA that developed a cooling system for the ISS and this whole premise makes no sense to me.&lt;p&gt;1. Getting things to space is incredibly expensive&lt;p&gt;2. Ingress/egress are almost always a major bottleneck - how is bandwidth cheaper in space?&lt;p&gt;3. Chips must be “Rad-hard” - that is do more error correcting from ionizing radiation - there were entire teams at NASA dedicated to special hardware for this.&lt;p&gt;4. Gravity and atmospheric pressure actually do wonders for easy cooling. Heat is not dissipated in space like we are all used to and you must burn additional energy trying to move the heat generated away from source.&lt;p&gt;5. Energy production will be cheaper from earth due to mass manufacturing of necessary components in energy systems - space energy systems need novel technology where economies of scale are lost.&lt;p&gt;Would love for someone to make the case for why it actually makes total sense, because it’s really hard to see for me!&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 02:16:32 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46880580</link><dc:creator>elamje</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46880580</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46880580</guid></item><item><title>New comment by hirsin in "Data centers in space makes no sense"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Simply put no, 50MW is not the typical hyperscaler cloud size. It's not even the typical single datacenter size.&lt;p&gt;A single AI rack consumes 60kW, and there is apparently a single DC that alone consumes 650MW.&lt;p&gt;When Microsoft puts in a DC, the machines are done in units of a "stamp", ie a couple racks together. These aren't scaled by dollar or sqft, but by the MW.&lt;p&gt;And on top of that... That's a bunch of satellites not even trying to crunch data at top speed. No where near the right order of magnitude.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 01:43:28 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46880296</link><dc:creator>hirsin</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46880296</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46880296</guid></item><item><title>New comment by ggm in "Lessons learned shipping 500 units of my first hardware product"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;This is the second article about hardware supply from China I've read and it reads very much the same, albiet in a different niche (the other one was about SBC construction) -Anything you don't specify will be done least cost, and there is no amount of "least" which cannot be chased in manufacture.&lt;p&gt;The other one noted if you don't specify the density of plastic for bags, or paper for bags and packing, you get clingfilm thinner than you thought existed, and paper which is almost tissue in its weakness. You don't even get boxes to put the boxes in, if you don't specify boxes to be delivered in boxes. So now wrapping a pallet becomes a nightmare if they don't stack. And if you don't specify how many to stack, and how to pad the stack, they won't do unit height stacking if it costs labour time. Your risk.&lt;p&gt;Some of this like the casting mistake, or the knob thing, could happen anywhere and you have to be close to final manufacture spec to find out e.g. the metal coating impinges on the knob at the free space you specified, because your test rig didn't have powder coating. Or, that a design feature you need like the light entry holes, is used by the casting engineer as pour points because it looked like you'd specified mould pour points not functional holes.&lt;p&gt;But other things like "yea, you didn't spec how long to make the tails so we cut the tails as close as we could" is just the cheapening above: if you don't SAY its a 10cm tail for the connector, it will be 2cm, if saving 8cm of cable saves money for them.&lt;p&gt;I've read some stuff which says the cost of 5 SBC boards with pre-applied SMD is now so low, you might as well order 5 so you get at least 1 which works. That means they will wind up working out your tolerance for failure, and produce goods to meet that: if 1 in 5 is viable, thats what they'll target.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 01:01:41 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46879928</link><dc:creator>ggm</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46879928</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46879928</guid></item><item><title>New comment by lancewiggs in "Data centers in space makes no sense"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;It's exiting the 5th best social network and the 10th (or worse) best AI company and selling them to a decent company.&lt;p&gt;It probably increases Elon's share of the combined entity.&lt;p&gt;It delivers on a promise to investors that he will make money for them, even as the underlying businesses are lousy.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 00:21:10 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46879507</link><dc:creator>lancewiggs</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46879507</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46879507</guid></item><item><title>New comment by robflynn in "New York’s budget bill would require “blocking technology” on all 3D printers"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;My main concern is, how long is it before you can't print a replacement part for something you bought because it looks too similar to an OEM part and the manufacturer doesn't think you should be able to do that so they throw a little money to the right politician.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 00:20:10 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46879497</link><dc:creator>robflynn</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46879497</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46879497</guid></item><item><title>New comment by beloch in "Data centers in space makes no sense"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I would &lt;i&gt;not&lt;/i&gt; assume cooling has been worked out.&lt;p&gt;Space is a vacuum.  i.e. The lack-of-a-thing that makes a thermos great at keeping your drink hot.  A satellite is, if nothing else, a &lt;i&gt;fantastic&lt;/i&gt; thermos.  A data center in space would necessarily rely &lt;i&gt;completely&lt;/i&gt; on cooling by radiation, unlike a terrestrial data center that can make use of convection and conduction. You can't just pipe heat out into the atmosphere or build a heat exchanger. You can't exchange heat with vacuum.  You can only radiate heat into it.&lt;p&gt;Heat is going to limit the compute that can be done in a satellite data centre and radiative cooling solutions are going to massively increase weight. It makes far more sense to build data centers in the arctic.&lt;p&gt;Musk is up to something here.  This could be another hyperloop (i.e. A distracting promise meant to sabotage competition).  It could be a legal dodge.  It could be a power grab.  What it will &lt;i&gt;not&lt;/i&gt; be is a useful source of computing power.  Anyone who takes this venture seriously is probably going to be burned.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2026 23:33:46 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46878977</link><dc:creator>beloch</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46878977</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46878977</guid></item><item><title>New comment by cwal37 in "Lessons learned shipping 500 units of my first hardware product"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&gt; As someone who generally stays out of politics, I didn’t know much about the incoming administration’s stance towards tariffs, though I don’t think anyone could have predicted such drastic hikes.&lt;p&gt;I have an appreciation for very bright lamps, and the project is neat, but that stuck out to me.&lt;p&gt;I'm always fascinated by people who both feel comfortable ignoring maybe the single most impactful society-determining apparatus but will also say "no one could have seen that coming", where that is whatever they were unaware of because they chose to check out. I find the stance so fascinating because for myself, it would be impossible to not try and understand why the world is the way it is.&lt;p&gt;Everything is downstream of politics whether people want to recognize that or not, and choosing to ignore it is, in fact, a political choice.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2026 23:18:51 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46878821</link><dc:creator>cwal37</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46878821</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46878821</guid></item><item><title>New comment by paulfitz in "France dumps Zoom and Teams as Europe seeks digital autonomy from the US"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I work at Grist, the "tableur collaboratif" (collaborative spreadsheet) listed on the La Suite homepage. We're in the interesting situation of being both a NYC-based company, and open source software the French gov has adopted and is helping to develop. Grist is mostly a node backend. So it is a complicated story. The key is having code the gov can review and trust and run it on sovereign infrastructure.&lt;p&gt;Grist &lt;a href="https://www.getgrist.com/" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://www.getgrist.com/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;A write-up of how the French gov uses it &lt;a href="https://interoperable-europe.ec.europa.eu/collection/open-source-observatory-osor/news/grist-joins-suite-numerique-public-administration" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://interoperable-europe.ec.europa.eu/collection/open-so...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2026 19:51:56 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46876302</link><dc:creator>paulfitz</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46876302</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46876302</guid></item><item><title>New comment by input_sh in "France dumps Zoom and Teams as Europe seeks digital autonomy from the US"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Worth pointing out: France is not &lt;i&gt;adopting&lt;/i&gt; existing open source software, they're building their own software and releasing it under the MIT licence. Most of it (or all of it?) is Django backend + React frontend (using a custom-built UI kit).&lt;p&gt;Home page for the entire suite (in French) with some screenshots: &lt;a href="https://lasuite.numerique.gouv.fr/" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://lasuite.numerique.gouv.fr/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;Code bases are on GitHub and they use English there: &lt;a href="https://github.com/suitenumerique/" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://github.com/suitenumerique/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dev handbook (in English): &lt;a href="https://suitenumerique.gitbook.io/handbook" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://suitenumerique.gitbook.io/handbook&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;Not French and I can't say I personally tried deploying any of them, but I've been admiring their efforts from afar for a while now.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2026 19:18:53 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46875837</link><dc:creator>input_sh</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46875837</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46875837</guid></item><item><title>New comment by flohofwoe in "Xcode 26.3 – Developers can leverage coding agents directly in Xcode"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Building castles in the sky while the foundation is rotting away :/ Xcode really needs a couple of years of pure bugfix and optimization releases instead of hype-chasing.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2026 18:24:34 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46874953</link><dc:creator>flohofwoe</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46874953</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46874953</guid></item><item><title>New comment by pelagicAustral in "France dumps Zoom and Teams as Europe seeks digital autonomy from the US"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Refreshing. No more Teams? Sounds like a dream... Of all the crapware I am forced to work with, Teams really pushes the envelope in every single negative way conceivable. I think I have more love for SharePoint than Teams, and that is a massive concession.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2026 17:29:51 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46874040</link><dc:creator>pelagicAustral</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46874040</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46874040</guid></item><item><title>New comment by cedws in "Qwen3-Coder-Next"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I kind of lost interest in local models. Then Anthropic started saying I’m not allowed to use my Claude Code subscription with my preferred tools and it reminded me why we need to support open tools and models. I’ve cancelled my CC subscription, I’m not paying to support anticompetitive behaviour.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2026 17:05:08 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46873708</link><dc:creator>cedws</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46873708</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46873708</guid></item><item><title>New comment by cschmatzler in "Bunny Database"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;fwiw, Bunny are the people that announced S3 compatibility for their object storage in Q2 2022 [1]&lt;p&gt;&gt;  We can’t wait to have this available as a preview later in Q2 and truly make global storage a breeze, so keep an eye out!&lt;p&gt;then apologised for missing that in September 2023 [2]&lt;p&gt;&gt; We initially announced that we were working on S3 support for Bunny Storage all the way back in 2022. Today, as 2023 is slowly coming to an end, many of our customers continue to follow our blog, hoping for good news about the release.&lt;p&gt;changing the roadmap to early 2024 [2]&lt;p&gt;&gt; But we are working aggressively toward shipping S3 compatibility in early 2024.&lt;p&gt;That same post also has the beautiful "At bunny.net, we value transparency." quote.
It's early 2026, and they're literally ignoring my support requests asking about what the roadmap is looking like for this now.&lt;p&gt;So, do not trust their product or leadership at all.&lt;p&gt;[1] &lt;a href="https://bunny.net/blog/introducing-edge-storage-sftp-support-s3-next/" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://bunny.net/blog/introducing-edge-storage-sftp-support...&lt;/a&gt;
[2] &lt;a href="https://bunny.net/blog/whats-happening-with-s3-compatibility/" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://bunny.net/blog/whats-happening-with-s3-compatibility...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2026 16:56:55 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46873586</link><dc:creator>cschmatzler</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46873586</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46873586</guid></item><item><title>New comment by pjc50 in "New York’s budget bill would require “blocking technology” on all 3D printers"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;This is insanely stupid stuff. Even the UK with our weird panic over Incredibly Specific Knives hasn't tried to do this kind of technical restriction to prevent people printing guns. Why not? Because nobody is printing guns! It's an infeasible solution to a non-problem!&lt;p&gt;Someone should dig into who this is coming from and why. The answers are usually either (a) they got paid to do it by a company selling the tech, which appears not to be the case here, or (b) they went insane on social media.&lt;p&gt;(can't confirm this personally, but it seems from other comments that it's perfectly feasible to just drive out of New York State and buy a gun somewhere else in the gun-owning US? And this is quite likely where all the guns used in existing NY crime come from?)&lt;p&gt;I would also note that the Shinzo Abe doohickey wasn't 3D-printed.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2026 16:35:13 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46873220</link><dc:creator>pjc50</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46873220</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46873220</guid></item><item><title>New comment by breakyerself in "Banning lead in gas worked. The proof is in our hair"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Almost every environmental regulation has come after it was already shown that there was some harm that needed to be mitigated.&lt;p&gt;The worst environmental crisis in human history is going largely unchecked. I find it hard to take seriously any argument that environmental regulation has gone too far as opposed to not nearly far enough.&lt;p&gt;If there's a specific regulation that can be shown to be doing more harm than good I'm cool with revisiting anything, but the common sense wisdom around environmental regulation has been corrupted by corporate public relations campaigns.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2026 15:48:39 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46872493</link><dc:creator>breakyerself</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46872493</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46872493</guid></item><item><title>New comment by iainmerrick in "Agent Skills"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;This stuff smells like maybe the bitter lesson isn't fully appreciated.&lt;p&gt;You might as well just write instructions in English in any old format, as long as it's comprehensible. Exactly as you'd do for human readers! Nothing has really changed about what constitutes good documentation. &lt;i&gt;(Edit to add: my parochialism is showing there, it doesn't have to be English)&lt;/i&gt;&lt;p&gt;Is any of this standardization really needed? Who does it benefit, except the people who enjoy writing specs and establishing standards like this? If it really is a productivity win, it ought to be possible to run a comparison study and prove it. Even then, it might not be worthwhile in the longer run.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2026 15:09:04 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46871907</link><dc:creator>iainmerrick</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46871907</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46871907</guid></item><item><title>New comment by cfiggers in "Banning lead in gas worked. The proof is in our hair"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;In my opinion it is obvious and should be uncontroversial that &lt;i&gt;some&lt;/i&gt; environmental regulations work and are great and should if anything be reinforced, while &lt;i&gt;other&lt;/i&gt; environmental regulations do more harm than good and need to be reigned in or eliminated.&lt;p&gt;Turning "environmental regulation" into a unified bloc that must be either supported or opposed in totality is a manipulative political maneuver and it should be forcefully rejected.&lt;p&gt;Regulations are not people, and they don't have rights. It is fair and reasonable to demand that environmental regulation justify its existence with hard, scientifically verifiable data or else get chopped. Clearly, banning leaded gasoline has that kind of justification, and therefore I'm strongly in favor of maintaining that ban and extending it wherever it isn't in place yet. The same reasonable standard should be applied to other regulations across the board.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2026 14:31:10 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46871420</link><dc:creator>cfiggers</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46871420</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46871420</guid></item><item><title>New comment by ruhith in "What's up with all those equals signs anyway?"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;The real punchline is that this is a perfect example of "just enough knowledge to be dangerous." Whoever processed these emails knew enough to know emails aren't plain text, but not enough to know that quoted-printable decoding isn't something you hand-roll with find-and-replace. It's the same class of bug as manually parsing HTML with regex, it works right up until it doesn't, and then you get congressional evidence full of mystery equals signs.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2026 11:56:40 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46869870</link><dc:creator>ruhith</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46869870</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46869870</guid></item><item><title>New comment by bgnn in "xAI joins SpaceX"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;The real reason is, Elon has SpaceX and xAI. He can create an illusion of synergy and orders of magnitude advancements to boost the market cap and pocket all the money. He realized long time ago you don't need to deliver to play the market cap game, in fact it's better if you are selling a story far in the future rather than a something you can deliver now.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2026 07:54:14 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46867905</link><dc:creator>bgnn</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46867905</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46867905</guid></item><item><title>New comment by igorramazanov in "Court orders restart of all US offshore wind power construction"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;If a country changes course every four years, how can the success of a long-term project be ensured?&lt;p&gt;And what of its negotiating credibility? How can the other side trust that an agreement will hold in the future?&lt;p&gt;This is not a critique, but a genuine curiosity, because there's an obvious drawback with a system with opposing world views.&lt;p&gt;Unless, of course, something still unites them in the first place, with acceptable disparity on each side turning it into an advantage of flexibility and adaptability while keeping the focus on long-term ideas and plans.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2026 03:37:02 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46866145</link><dc:creator>igorramazanov</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46866145</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46866145</guid></item><item><title>New comment by caseysoftware in "The TSA's New $45 Fee to Fly Without ID Is Illegal"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&gt; &lt;i&gt;So it was never about security at all then, was it?&lt;/i&gt;&lt;p&gt;Never was.&lt;p&gt;I flew every other week prior to covid and haven't once been through the scanners. For the first ~6 years, I opted out and got pat down over and over again.&lt;p&gt;Then I realized I could even skip that.&lt;p&gt;Now at the checkpoint, I stand at the metal detector. When they wave me to the scanner, I say "I can't raise my arms over my head." They wave me through the metal detector, swab my hands, and I'm done. I usually make it through before my bags.&lt;p&gt;Sometimes, a TSA moron asks "why not?" and I simply say "are you asking me to share my personal healthcare information out loud in front of a bunch of strangers? Are you a medical professional?" and they back down.&lt;p&gt;Other times, they've asked "can you raise them at least this high?" and kind of motion. I ask "are you asking me to potentially injure myself for your curiosity? are you going to pay for any injuries or pain I suffer?"&lt;p&gt;The TSA was NEVER about security. It was designed as a jobs program and make it look like we were doing something for security.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2026 01:16:05 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46864953</link><dc:creator>caseysoftware</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46864953</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46864953</guid></item></channel></rss>