<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>Hacker News: Best Comments</title><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/bestcomments</link><description>Hacker News RSS</description><docs>https://hnrss.org/</docs><generator>hnrss v2.1.1</generator><lastBuildDate>Mon, 04 Aug 2025 00:09:38 +0000</lastBuildDate><ns0:link href="https://hnrss.org/bestcomments" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item><title>New comment by dabedee in "Lina Khan points to Figma IPO as vindication of M&amp;A scrutiny"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I think the Figma IPO proves Khan was right. $60B market cap today vs the $20B Adobe offered in 2023.
There was some criticism about regulatory overreach when the deal got blocked. Now Figma employees are rich, the design tools market stays competitive, and we have another major independent tech company instead of just another Adobe product line.
This is exactly why we need regulators willing to tell Big Tech "no" sometimes. Competition creates more value than consolidation.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 03 Aug 2025 09:20:29 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44775279</link><dc:creator>dabedee</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44775279</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44775279</guid></item><item><title>New comment by PaulRobinson in "Helsinki records zero traffic deaths for full year"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I was in Helsinki for work a couple of years ago, walking back to my hotel with some colleagues after a few hours drinking (incredibly expensive, but quite nice), beer.&lt;p&gt;It was around midnight and we happened to come across a very large mobile crane on the pavement blocking our way. As we stepped out (carefully), into the road to go around it, one of my Finnish colleagues started bemoaning that no cones or barriers had been put out to safely shepherd pedestrians around it. I was very much "yeah, they're probably only here for a quick job, probably didn't have time for that", because I'm a Londoner and, well, that's what we do in London.&lt;p&gt;My colleague is like "No, that's not acceptable", and he literally pulls out his phone and calls the police. As we carry on on our way, a police car comes up the road and pulls over to have a word with the contractors.&lt;p&gt;They take the basics safely over there in a way I've not seen anywhere else. When you do that, you get the benefits.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 02 Aug 2025 20:49:39 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44771331</link><dc:creator>PaulRobinson</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44771331</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44771331</guid></item><item><title>New comment by dv_dt in "We may not like what we become if A.I. solves loneliness"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Though it's popularized to blame social media and phones, economics should not be overlooked. Pay for young generations is lagging and restaurants and bar prices are super high. Public spaces for informal gatherings has shrunk - eg fewer malls&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 02 Aug 2025 16:12:53 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44768795</link><dc:creator>dv_dt</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44768795</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44768795</guid></item><item><title>New comment by stdvit in "We may not like what we become if A.I. solves loneliness"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&gt; Even in a world brimming with easy distractions—TikTok, Pornhub, Candy Crush, Sudoku—people still manage to meet for drinks, work out at the gym, go on dates, muddle through real life.&lt;p&gt;They actually don't. Everything from dating and fitness to manufacturing and politics is in decline in activities, and more so in effect and understanding. You can't convince (enough) people anymore that it is even important as many don't have capacity to do it. And it isn't even something new at this point.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 02 Aug 2025 14:11:16 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44767790</link><dc:creator>stdvit</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44767790</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44767790</guid></item><item><title>New comment by andrewstuart2 in "Atlassian terminates 150 staff"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;It's a pretty impersonal way to announce layoffs but I think they all tend to be impersonal. I do think the 6 months of pay says a lot more than the fact that they used a video.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2025 19:42:03 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44761465</link><dc:creator>andrewstuart2</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44761465</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44761465</guid></item><item><title>New comment by legitster in "Corporation for Public Broadcasting ceasing operations"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Contrary to the conservative spin over the years, I have found public broadcasting to be one of the least biased sources of headline news and information available. (For their national broadcasts at least - local ... can be hit or miss).&lt;p&gt;In particular, their kids programming is the absolute best. Nothing flashy or exciting, but it's laser focused on education and has zero agenda. And the PBS kids apps are one of the few things I can hand to my kid worry-free. And the fact that it's money-free and ad-free to access in this modern age is a miracle.&lt;p&gt;The only people who could support this are not just wrong, they are people out of touch with reality. These are people who think public parks are a waste of space. Or that having nice things to share is elitist.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2025 17:43:48 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44759929</link><dc:creator>legitster</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44759929</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44759929</guid></item><item><title>New comment by lapcat in "Live coding interviews measure stress, not coding skills"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I won't attempt to generalize from my case, but let me offer a personal anecdote.&lt;p&gt;I'm now a successful, self-employed indie developer. One of the main reasons I stuck with indie development through the hard times—the maxim that it takes 5 years to become an overnight success was true for me—was that I became practically unhireable. There are multiple strikes against me: I'm middle age in an industry rife with age discrimination, I don't have a computer science degree, and I experience brain freeze during live coding interviews.&lt;p&gt;I would note that not all stress is the same. Firefighters rush into burning buildings for a living, and what could be more stressful, yet many of them would panic at the idea of giving a speech to a non-burning roomful of strangers. I have no problem with stress on the job, and I've successfully navigated many work emergencies during my career, but something about strangers standing over my shoulder judging me, determining my financial future by providing or withholding a job, like the sword of Damocles, turns my stomach inside out. And like the article author, I can revisit the coding problems and solve them afterward, as soon as the interview is over. Interviewers must think I'm a fraud who can't code, yet all evidence from my career, now almost 2 decades long, suggests otherwise.&lt;p&gt;A lot of commenters causally speak of "false negatives" as if they were random, but some people, myself included, are &lt;i&gt;always&lt;/i&gt; the false negative. I am consistently filtered out by audition-style interviews. I'm not a stage performer.&lt;p&gt;[Edit:] I didn't expect my comment to rise to the top of an already crowded discussion. I feel a little self-conscious about it. ;-)&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2025 14:20:05 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44757214</link><dc:creator>lapcat</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44757214</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44757214</guid></item><item><title>New comment by a2128 in "Our Farewell from Google Play"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;From a cursory glance, their apps seem to be of the kind that don't need continuous updates and can be considered complete. Self-contained, offline software that serves a specific purpose: &lt;a href="https://search.f-droid.org/?q=SECUSO&amp;lang=en" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://search.f-droid.org/?q=SECUSO&amp;lang=en&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, Google no longer recognizes this as a valid development strategy. If you want to publish on Google Play, you need to continuously release updates targeting an SDK released within the past year[0]. If you don't, they will send you constant warnings about how your app is violating their policies, they might derank your app, and eventually they'll stop making your app available to new users.&lt;p&gt;Updating the SDK is not that simple and it often introduces new bugs if you don't read through the full changelog and test thoroughly. I have 3 apps and it already feels like I spend too much time each year updating SDK, I can't imagine updating 30.&lt;p&gt;They talk about how this somehow improves security and enhances user experience, meanwhile this policy worsens user experience by pushing people towards ad-filled apps that have the resources and courage to release needless updates, and they still publish spyware on their store.&lt;p&gt;[0] &lt;a href="https://developer.android.com/google/play/requirements/target-sdk" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://developer.android.com/google/play/requirements/targe...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2025 12:43:49 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44755954</link><dc:creator>a2128</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44755954</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44755954</guid></item><item><title>New comment by tptacek in "The anti-abundance critique on housing is wrong"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;So much of the journalism we read is heavily processed and barely-reported and it's startling to see how much of a superpower simple shoe-leather reporting actually is. Derek Thompson's an incredibly sharp writer, but not really a subject matter expert on housing economics; all he did here was read papers and call up the authorities they cited, and the narrative behind those papers collapsed.&lt;p&gt;We're often so down on journalism on HN, and I believe a big part of that is we tend to read so much opinion and analysis and so little basic reporting.&lt;p&gt;I've been loving Thompson's substack (which is mostly not about housing policy so far).&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 31 Jul 2025 22:30:59 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44750898</link><dc:creator>tptacek</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44750898</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44750898</guid></item><item><title>New comment by lubujackson in "Slow"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I'm reminded of the famous story of (I think) the central beam in a building at Oxford. The story goes something like:&lt;p&gt;The central beam was beginning to fail and the Oxford administration knew they needed to replace it. When they went around for quotes, no one could replace the beam because it was 100 ft in length and sourced from an old growth tree. Such logs were simply unavailable to buy. To solve the issue, the staff begin to look at major renovations to the building's architecture.&lt;p&gt;Until the Oxford groundskeeper heard about the problem. "We have a replacement beam," he said.&lt;p&gt;The groundskeeper took the curious admins to the edge of the grounds. There stood two old growth trees, over 150 feet tall.&lt;p&gt;"But these must be over 200 years old! When were they planted?" the admins asked.&lt;p&gt;"The day they replaced the previous beam."&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 31 Jul 2025 19:58:27 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44749473</link><dc:creator>lubujackson</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44749473</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44749473</guid></item><item><title>New comment by nicoburns in "I tried Servo"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&gt; The current roadmap lists Shadow DOM and CSS Grid as priorities&lt;p&gt;I've been working on the CSS Grid support. About to land "named grid lines and areas" support which should make a bunch more websites layout correctly.&lt;p&gt;I'm biased because it's my project, but IMO the approach Servo is using for CSS Grid is pretty cool in that the actual implementation is in an external library (Taffy [0]) that can be used standalone and is widely used accross the Rust UI ecosystem, including in the Blitz [1] web engine (which also uses Taffy for Flexbox and Block layout), the Zed [2] text editor, and the Bevy [3] game engine.&lt;p&gt;I'm hopeful that this approach of breaking down a web engine into independently usable modules with public APIs (which builds upon Servo's earlier work on modular libraries such as Stylo and html5ever) will make it easier for people to get involved in web engine development (as they can understand each piece in isolation), and make it easier for people to create new web engines in future (as they won't have to start completely from scratch).&lt;p&gt;[0]: &lt;a href="https://github.com/DioxusLabs/taffy"&gt;https://github.com/DioxusLabs/taffy&lt;/a&gt;
[1]: &lt;a href="https://github.com/DioxusLabs/blitz"&gt;https://github.com/DioxusLabs/blitz&lt;/a&gt;
[2]: &lt;a href="https://zed.dev" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://zed.dev&lt;/a&gt;
[3]: &lt;a href="https://bevy.org/" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://bevy.org/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 31 Jul 2025 12:11:48 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44744821</link><dc:creator>nicoburns</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44744821</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44744821</guid></item><item><title>New comment by WD-42 in "Vibe code is legacy code"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I would not default to assuming it was his competitors, that sounds like scapegoating to deflect responsibility. What most likely happened is his site was scanned by one of the increasingly sophisticated exploit crawlers (anyone who runs an internet facing site and can view traffic knows what I'm talking about). His site got flagged as vulnerable, the hacker found out it was built like swiss cheese and had fun with it.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 30 Jul 2025 23:02:52 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44740554</link><dc:creator>WD-42</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44740554</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44740554</guid></item><item><title>New comment by hn_throwaway_99 in "Fast"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Just want to say how much I thank YCom for not f'ing up the HN interface, and keeping it fast.&lt;p&gt;I distinctly remember when Slashdot committed suicide. They had an interface that was very easy for me to scan and find high value comments, and in the name of "modern UI" or some other nonsense needed to keep a few designers employed, completely revamped it so that it had a ton of whitespace and made it basically impossible for me to skim the comments.&lt;p&gt;I think I tried it for about 3 days before I gave up, and I was a daily Slashdot reader before then.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 30 Jul 2025 20:37:03 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44739199</link><dc:creator>hn_throwaway_99</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44739199</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44739199</guid></item><item><title>New comment by kbrkbr in "Sleep all comes down to the mitochondria"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&gt; So the ancient mystery of why we need sleep might have just been answered.&lt;p&gt;I would be very surprised if sleep would serve only one purpose. In complex interconnected systems you usually don't get far with monocausal explanations.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 30 Jul 2025 10:13:25 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44732539</link><dc:creator>kbrkbr</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44732539</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44732539</guid></item><item><title>New comment by jacobedawson in "Study mode"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;An underrated quality of LLMs as study partner is that you can ask "stupid" questions without fear of embarrassment. Adding in a mode that doesn't just dump an answer but works to take you through the material step-by-step is magical. A tireless, capable, well-versed assistant on call 24/7 is an autodidact's dream.&lt;p&gt;I'm puzzled (but not surprised) by the standard HN resistance &amp; skepticism. Learning something online 5 years ago often involved trawling incorrect, outdated or hostile content and attempting to piece together mental models without the chance to receive immediate feedback on intuition or ask follow up questions. This is leaps and bounds ahead of that experience.&lt;p&gt;Should we trust the information at face value without verifying from other sources? Of course not, that's part of the learning process. Will some (most?) people rely on it lazily without using it effectively? Certainly, and this technology won't help or hinder them any more than a good old fashioned textbook.&lt;p&gt;Personally I'm over the moon to be living at a time where we have access to incredible tools like this, and I'm impressed with the speed at which they're improving.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 29 Jul 2025 22:34:39 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44729042</link><dc:creator>jacobedawson</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44729042</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44729042</guid></item><item><title>New comment by czhu12 in "Study mode"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I'll personally attest: LLM's have been absolutely incredible to self learn new things post graduation. It used to be that if you got stuck on a concept, you're basically screwed. Unless it was common enough to show up in a well formed question on stack exchange, it was pretty much impossible, and the only thing you can really do is keep paving forward and hope at some point, it'll make sense to you.&lt;p&gt;Now, everyone basically has a personal TA, ready to go at all hours of the day.&lt;p&gt;I get the commentary that it makes learning too easy or shallow, but I doubt anyone would think that college students would learn better if we got rid of TA's.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 29 Jul 2025 17:27:28 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44726074</link><dc:creator>czhu12</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44726074</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44726074</guid></item><item><title>New comment by zetazzed in "‘I witnessed war crimes’ in Gaza – former worker at GHF aid site [video]"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I see an increasing number of politicians taking the position:
 "I supported Israel's government's actions when they first attacked, given the goals of destroying Hamas' leadership and freeing hostages, but now that it has turned into a brutal siege with mass civilian casualties on a horrific scale, I'm strongly against their actions." E.g. Macron, Angus King, and many people I know personally.
 And I think we need to say "Great!" The dumbest reaction is "screw you, you were for Israel's invasion and you're an asshole." Movements that want to grow should accept people who change their minds when the situation changes, they get new data, or they learn a new perspective.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 28 Jul 2025 22:59:36 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44716791</link><dc:creator>zetazzed</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44716791</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44716791</guid></item><item><title>New comment by churchill in "‘I witnessed war crimes’ in Gaza – former worker at GHF aid site [video]"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Does anyone still need testimonies like these to be convinced that Israel is systematically exterminating the Palestinians using kinetic force and starvation? We're past that point now. Making Gaza unlivable by carpet-bombing the strip, telegraphing mass murder in unambiguous statements at the highest levels of government, dehumanizing the Palestinians and silencing anyone who dares to speak up?&lt;p&gt;I, for one, am thankful this hasn't been taken down like any article remotely critical of Israel.&lt;p&gt;And this has eliminated the whole Western bullshit about human rights maximalism - it's just the same damn thing every time. Like the atrocities in the Congo free State, the Scramble for Africa, etc. the West will sponsor unspeakable atrocities overseas and then act shocked when they actually happen.&lt;p&gt;Many people in the West don't realize it, but Palestine will wreck severe damage on the West. Just like Gorbachev visiting a random store in the US and seeing insane abundance in a shop in the middle of nowhere while Soviet citizens starved, what killed the Soviet Union was disillusion; people at all levels realized that a system that couldn't provide its people the basics didn't deserve to exist.&lt;p&gt;That's what happening in the West: American GWOT veterans are still feeling disillusioned about what they went to do in Iraq &amp; Afg. (and Vietnam, before it), and now their kids are seriously asking, "Are we the baddies?"&lt;p&gt;What's the point of this industrial capacity and wealth if all we do with it is bomb kids? No political system can survive disillusion, that is, the point where people across the spectrum start seeing their nation as hypocritical.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 28 Jul 2025 20:24:24 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44715162</link><dc:creator>churchill</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44715162</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44715162</guid></item><item><title>New comment by Wowfunhappy in "Claude Code weekly rate limits"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I'm probably not going to hit the weekly limit, but it makes me nervous that the limit is weekly as opposed to every 36 hours or something. If I &lt;i&gt;do&lt;/i&gt; hit the limit, that's it for the &lt;i&gt;entire week&lt;/i&gt;—a long time to be without a tool I've grown accustomed to!&lt;p&gt;I feel like someone is going to reply that I'm too reliant on Claude or something. Maybe that's true, but I'd feel the same about the prospect of loosing ripgrep for a week, or whatever. Loosing it for a couple of days is more palatable.&lt;p&gt;Also, I find it notable they said this will affect "less than 5% of users". I'm used to these types of announcements claiming they'll affect less than 1%. Anthropic is saying that one out of every 20 users will hit the new limit.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 28 Jul 2025 19:25:32 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44714494</link><dc:creator>Wowfunhappy</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44714494</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44714494</guid></item><item><title>New comment by Kapura in "Visa and Mastercard are getting overwhelmed by gamer fury over censorship"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;It's crazy that we live in a world where maybe a few dozen people's weird ideas about what shouldn't be allowed can cause payment processors to pressure the storefronts to delist the titles. It is censorship of something they personally find distasteful. guess what: nobody is forcing you to play weird art games about trauma.&lt;p&gt;obviously we must keep the pressure up on payment processors to reverse course, but we also need to push back against people in society who think they can decide what other adults are allowed to do on their own time. If folks IRL have weird ideas pushed back on IRL we wouldn't get to crisis points like this.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 28 Jul 2025 18:43:29 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44713909</link><dc:creator>Kapura</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44713909</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44713909</guid></item><item><title>New comment by skibz in "Copyparty – Turn almost any device into a file server"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;The author of this tool uploaded a YouTube video demonstrating it a few days ago: &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=15_-hgsX2V0" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=15_-hgsX2V0&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;At one point in his demo, he uploads a file but terminates the upload more or less halfway. Then he begins downloading the file - which only progresses to the point it had been uploaded, and subsequently stalls indefinitely. And, finally, he finishes uploading the file (which gracefully resumes) and the file download (which is still running) seamlessly completes.&lt;p&gt;I found that particularly impressive.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 28 Jul 2025 15:14:17 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44711691</link><dc:creator>skibz</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44711691</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44711691</guid></item><item><title>New comment by zaik in "Debian switches to 64-bit time for everything"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Celebrate 100 years since complete ipv6 adoption.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 28 Jul 2025 11:46:03 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44709887</link><dc:creator>zaik</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44709887</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44709887</guid></item><item><title>New comment by cs02rm0 in "VPN use surges in UK as new online safety rules kick in"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;The UK is becoming increasingly authoritarian in ways that feel increasingly antagonistic to the majority of the population, regardless of political party. Taxes are rising (with tax take falling), crimes are going unchecked, just mentioning increased immigration gets a lot of people's backs up, but as GDP per capita continues to stall and even fall, the pressure it puts on services is a factor for many. And we're seeing those with a few quid to rub together leave, but as long as those people leaving are straight, white males, or their families, they're being told "good riddance" regardless of the brain drain and loss of tax income.&lt;p&gt;On the NHS, I tried for years to push for improvements to switch to digital cancer screening invitations after they missed my mother (offering to build the software for free), which is now happening, but suggesting the NHS isn't perfect is against the religion here. My sister who works in NHS DEI hasn't spoken to me since publishing a book on it.&lt;p&gt;Every time someone with the finances, vision and ability leaves I think the situation gets a little bit worse, it increases the proportion of people remaining willing to put up with all of it. Anecdotally, many of my friends have already left, some of the older generation want to leave but feel tied in. My flight out is in 6 weeks. Good riddance, no doubt.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 28 Jul 2025 07:05:59 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44708055</link><dc:creator>cs02rm0</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44708055</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44708055</guid></item><item><title>New comment by zaptheimpaler in "VPN use surges in UK as new online safety rules kick in"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Basically every new law, piece of news or media I see coming from the UK paints a picture of a beat-down, cynical &amp; scared society that's complacent to or in support of increasing surveillance and control by the government. Like maybe Adolescence or basically any mention of the NHS. The crimes they cite like child grooming or terrorism/hate being incited sound pretty terrible too, but I wonder why the UK specifically is taking action - is the issue bigger there, or are they just more aware of and willing to act on it.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 28 Jul 2025 05:54:54 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44707618</link><dc:creator>zaptheimpaler</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44707618</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44707618</guid></item><item><title>New comment by userbinator in "EU age verification app to ban any Android system not licensed by Google"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;"Device security checks" is the most horrifying aspect as it basically means "officially sanctioned hardware and software", and leads straight into the dystopia that Stallman warned us about in &lt;i&gt;Right to Read&lt;/i&gt;.&lt;p&gt;There is some amusing irony in the EU relying on the US for furthering its own authoritarianism. It's unfortunate that freedom (in the classic rebellious, American sense) never became that popular in the EU, or for that matter, the UK.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 28 Jul 2025 00:45:05 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44706081</link><dc:creator>userbinator</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44706081</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44706081</guid></item><item><title>New comment by WarOnPrivacy in "EU age verification app to ban any Android system not licensed by Google"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;In the case of Android, genuine means:&lt;/i&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;    The operating system was licensed by Google
    The app was downloaded from the Play Store (thus requiring a Google account)
    Device security checks have passed
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;i&gt;While there is value to verify device security,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;this strongly ties the app to many Google properties and services,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;because those checks won't pass on an aftermarket Android OS&lt;/i&gt;&lt;p&gt;The issue is being raised here: &lt;a href="https://github.com/eu-digital-identity-wallet/av-app-android-wallet-ui/issues/10"&gt;https://github.com/eu-digital-identity-wallet/av-app-android...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;    I would like to strongly urge to abandon this plan. 
    Requiring a dependency on American tech giants for age verification
    further deepens the EU's dependency on America and the USA's
    control over the internet. 
    Especially in the current political climate I hope I do not have
    to explain how undesirable and dangerous that is.
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
As a resident of the aforementioned political climate, I find their concerns to be reasonable.&lt;p&gt;There are a number of comments in that same thread that indicate a mandate to utilize Google services may run afoul of EU member nations' integrity and privacy laws.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 27 Jul 2025 23:03:47 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44705507</link><dc:creator>WarOnPrivacy</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44705507</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44705507</guid></item><item><title>New comment by alextousss in "Ask HN: What are you working on? (July 2025)"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;My roommate and I are still working on Tornyol, our mosquito killing drone! It uses ultrasonic sonar to detect mosquitoes, and missile control theory to ram into mosquitoes and grind them in its propellers.&lt;p&gt;Our target platform is a 40 grams tinywhoop so it’s safe to fly everywhere and makes almost no noise :). A Roomba for mosquitoes!&lt;p&gt;The main plus compared to traditional systems is that a drone can cover an enormous surface in a short time compared to static systems or man-portable insecticide spraying. Our goal is to be competitive with ITNs against Malaria.&lt;p&gt;Some links :&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://hackaday.com/2025/03/25/supercon-2024-killing-mosquitoes-with-freaking-drones-and-sonar/" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://hackaday.com/2025/03/25/supercon-2024-killing-mosqui...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://manifund.org/projects/build-anti-mosqu" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://manifund.org/projects/build-anti-mosqu&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 27 Jul 2025 18:45:36 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44703517</link><dc:creator>alextousss</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44703517</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44703517</guid></item><item><title>New comment by samrus in "4k NASA employees opt to leave agency through deferred resignation program"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I understand wanting to make the organization more efficient, but i don't think this is what's happening here. I think this is the classic republican strat of gutting federal agencies, pointing to the inefficiencies caused by the loss of institutional knowledge, and using that as an excuse to privatize to their friends.&lt;p&gt;The fact that Elon's DOGE suggested these cuts lines up&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 27 Jul 2025 14:33:10 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44701607</link><dc:creator>samrus</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44701607</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44701607</guid></item><item><title>New comment by mkw5053 in "Return of wolves to Yellowstone has led to a surge in aspen trees"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;It's amazing the impact that the reintroduction has had. On a recent winter trip there I also learned that the reintroduction literally moved rivers [1]:&lt;p&gt;- Elk quit loitering along streams, so willow and cottonwood shot up, anchoring soil and narrowing channels.&lt;p&gt;- The new woody growth gave beavers lumber; their colonies jumped from one in 1996 to a dozen within fifteen years, raising water tables and rebuilding wetlands.&lt;p&gt;- With healthier riparian zones came deeper pools, colder water, and a surge in native trout and song-bird nests.&lt;p&gt;[1] &lt;a href="https://phys.org/news/2025-02-predators-ecosystems-yellowstone-wolves-carnivores.html" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://phys.org/news/2025-02-predators-ecosystems-yellowsto...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 27 Jul 2025 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44701025</link><dc:creator>mkw5053</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44701025</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44701025</guid></item><item><title>New comment by thunderbong in "What went wrong for Yahoo"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&gt; In 1998, Yahoo turned down the opportunity to acquire Google for $1 million. Yahoo made six acquisitions that year, spending $107.3 million.&lt;p&gt;&gt; In 2002, Google offered to sell again for $1 billion. Yahoo hesitated and Google raised its price to $3 billion. Yahoo declined at the higher price. Google went on to become a trillion dollar company.&lt;p&gt;&gt; Yahoo attempted to acquire Facebook for $1 billion in 2006, but Mark Zuckerberg turned down the offer. Had Yahoo increased its offer by just $100 million, Facebook’s board would have forced Zuckerberg to take it. Facebook also became a trillion dollar company.&lt;p&gt;In inclined to believe that neither would have become trillion dollar companies if they had been acquired by Yahoo.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 26 Jul 2025 18:50:54 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44696197</link><dc:creator>thunderbong</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44696197</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44696197</guid></item></channel></rss>