<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>Hacker News: Best Comments</title><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/bestcomments</link><description>Hacker News RSS</description><docs>https://hnrss.org/</docs><generator>hnrss v2.1.1</generator><lastBuildDate>Sun, 23 Nov 2025 00:34:05 +0000</lastBuildDate><ns0:link href="https://hnrss.org/bestcomments" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item><title>New comment by yndoendo in "In a U.S. First, New Mexico Opens Doors to Free Child Care for All"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;US actually provided child care to mothers employed during WWII. [0]&lt;p&gt;Richard Nixon vetoed the bill that would have expanded it out to all families. [1]&lt;p&gt;Funny how we keep forgetting the past and reject what benefited us as a whole with a moved to pure individualism built around selfishness. AKA The rich keep getting richer.&lt;p&gt;[0] &lt;a href="https://www.wwiimemorialfriends.org/blog/the-lanham-act-and-universal-childcare-during-world-war-ii" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://www.wwiimemorialfriends.org/blog/the-lanham-act-and-...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;[1] &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Comprehensive_Child_Development_Act" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Comprehensive_Child_Developmen...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 22 Nov 2025 16:55:15 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46016130</link><dc:creator>yndoendo</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46016130</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46016130</guid></item><item><title>New comment by jandrewrogers in "Kodak ran a nuclear device in its basement for decades"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;When I studied chemistry at university, only a handful of select students were introduced to the nuclear science lab in the basement. It had a lot of spicy isotopes, neutron sources, etc. Even as a chemistry student with free run of the place for years I had no idea it was in the building until the department head pulled a few of us aside.&lt;p&gt;The reason for the informal secrecy, as it was explained to me, is that every so often someone would find out there was plutonium etc in the basement and have a public freak out, including on occasion other (non-STEM) professors at the same university. These people would try to organize crusades to get it shut down because evil. Intentionally obscuring its existence greatly mitigated this drama. They appreciated us continuing the tradition of keeping it out of sight and out of mind from the general public.&lt;p&gt;The publicity around this Kodak case was an example of why no one talks about nuclear labs. The public cannot be trusted to engage in a discussion about anything “nuclear” in good faith. There are quite a few areas of science like this.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 22 Nov 2025 13:27:41 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46014624</link><dc:creator>jandrewrogers</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46014624</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46014624</guid></item><item><title>New comment by sebmellen in "Original Superman comic becomes the highest-priced comic book ever sold"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;He added: “This isn’t simply a blurb of words and phrases. This is not just a stock statement from an LLM.&lt;p&gt;This is a testament to outsourcing, laziness and the unexpected ways technology finds ways to change every press release.”&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 22 Nov 2025 06:07:54 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46012518</link><dc:creator>sebmellen</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46012518</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46012518</guid></item><item><title>New comment by dbacar in "Original Superman comic becomes the highest-priced comic book ever sold"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;"He added: "This isn't simply a story about old paper and ink. This was never just about a collectible.&lt;p&gt;"This is a testament to memory, family and the unexpected ways the past finds its way back to us."
"""
Men going extreme in sentimental when they just sold a $9M collectible :).&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 22 Nov 2025 05:49:37 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46012442</link><dc:creator>dbacar</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46012442</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46012442</guid></item><item><title>New comment by simonw in "Personal blogs are back, should niche blogs be next?"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Here are some reasons to start a personal blog:&lt;p&gt;1. It's a great way to learn. Teaching something to someone else has always been the best learning tool, and writing about something with an audience in mind is an effective way to capture some of that value.&lt;p&gt;2. It can be a big boost in job hunting. As a hiring manager two of the most important questions I have about a potential candidate are: Can they code? Can they communicate well? If a candidate has a blog with just two articles on it that hasn't been updated in five years that's &lt;i&gt;still&lt;/i&gt; a big boost over candidates with nothing like that at all. In a competitive market that could be the boost you need to make it from the resume review to the first round.&lt;p&gt;3. If you blog more frequently than that it can be a really valuable resource for your future self. I love being able to look back on what I was thinking and writing about ten years ago. Having a good tagging system helps with this too - I can review my tag of "scaling" or "postgresql" and see a timeline of how my understanding developed.&lt;p&gt;4. It's a great way to help establish credibility. If someone asks you about X and you have a blog entry about X from five years ago you can point them to that.&lt;p&gt;5. Building a blog is really fun! It used to be one of the classic starter projects for new web developers, I think that needs to come back. It's a fun project and one that's great to keep on hacking on long into the future.&lt;p&gt;Notably none of the above reasons require your blog to attract readers! There's a ton of value to be had even if nobody actually reads the thing.&lt;p&gt;As a general rule, assume nobody will read your blog unless you actively encourage them to. That's fine. What matters isn't the quantity of readers, it's their quality. I'd rather have a piece read by just a single person that leads to a new opportunity for me than 1,000 people who read it and never interact with me ever again.&lt;p&gt;If you DO start to get readers things get even more valuable. I've been blogging since 2002 and most of the opportunities in my career came from people I met via blogging. Today I get invited to all sorts of interesting events because I have a prominent blog covering stuff relating to AI and LLMs.&lt;p&gt;But I do honestly think that a blog is a powerful professional tool even if nobody else is reading it at all.&lt;p&gt;If you want to give it a go I've written a few things that might be useful:&lt;p&gt;- What to blog about: &lt;a href="https://simonwillison.net/2022/Nov/6/what-to-blog-about/" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://simonwillison.net/2022/Nov/6/what-to-blog-about/&lt;/a&gt; - Today I learned and write about your projects&lt;p&gt;- My approach to running a link blog - &lt;a href="https://simonwillison.net/2024/Dec/22/link-blog/" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://simonwillison.net/2024/Dec/22/link-blog/&lt;/a&gt; - aka write about stuff you've found&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 22 Nov 2025 03:38:48 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46011877</link><dc:creator>simonw</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46011877</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46011877</guid></item><item><title>New comment by ajb in "Samsung's 60% DRAM price hike signals a new phase of global memory tightening"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Dram alternates between feast and famine; it's the nature of a business when the granularity of investment is so huge (you have a fab or you don't, and they cost billions -maybe trillions by now). So, it will swing back. Unfortunately it looks like maybe 3-5 years on average, from some analysis here: 
&lt;a href="https://storagesearch.com/memory-boom-bust-cycles.html" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://storagesearch.com/memory-boom-bust-cycles.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;(That's just me eyeballing it, feel free to do the math)&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 22 Nov 2025 02:07:09 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46011404</link><dc:creator>ajb</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46011404</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46011404</guid></item><item><title>New comment by willio58 in "California DMV approves map increase in Waymo driverless operations"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I didn’t think I’d be so pro Waymo but anecdotally I had a fantastic experience with one recently.&lt;p&gt;I was at a music show very late ~1-2am in SF and walked out to grab an uber to the airbnb I was staying at. I kept getting assigned an uber, then I’d wait 10 minutes, then they’d cancel. Rinse and repeat for 30 minutes, mind you I even resorted to calling Lyfts at the same time and nothing bit. Then I say screw it and download Waymo. 1 minute and it’s accepted my ride, and I know it’s not going to cancel because it’s a robot. 3 minutes and it picks me up. The car is clean, quiet, I can play my own music in it via Spotify, and it’s driving honestly more safely than some uber drivers I’ve had in SF. It’s one of the few things where the end result actually lives up to the promise from a tech company.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 22 Nov 2025 00:14:50 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46010696</link><dc:creator>willio58</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46010696</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46010696</guid></item><item><title>New comment by atomicnumber3 in "Helping Valve to power up Steam devices"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;This is what I say a lot. Valve isn't even remotely close to having clean hands here. They invented loot crates. Hats. Etc.&lt;p&gt;It's just that the bar is so INSANELY low - it's probably somewhere deep in the earth's core at this point - that valve looks like a fucking angel by being only VAGUELY greedy on occasion.&lt;p&gt;When your competition is EA... it's not hard.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 22:56:00 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46010040</link><dc:creator>atomicnumber3</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46010040</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46010040</guid></item><item><title>New comment by BadBadJellyBean in "LAPD helicopter tracker with real-time operating costs"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I find it interesting that the question is "why don't they use drones". My question is: why so much air surveillance? I live in Germany. The only times I hear a helicopter is if someone is being rescued or if someones missing. I rarely see them at all.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 22:48:26 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46009959</link><dc:creator>BadBadJellyBean</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46009959</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46009959</guid></item><item><title>New comment by zamalek in "Helping Valve to power up Steam devices"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&gt; Much credit to Valve for pushing that out as FOSS.&lt;p&gt;Cynical: Valve doesn't sell hardware or operating systems, they sell games. These devices are merely another storefront.&lt;p&gt;Optimistic: Valve has also figured out how to turn good will into a commodity. Blowing cash on Steam sales is a bit of a cultural centerpiece of the PC gaming community.&lt;p&gt;Gabe has proven that you can make stupid amounts of money by [mostly] doing right by the consumer. I'm not sure if there's more to the secret source, her sauce, because we've yet to see another CEO pull their head out of their arse far enough to see how lucrative this approach can be: consumerism is fickle, fanaticism is loyal.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 22:39:04 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46009871</link><dc:creator>zamalek</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46009871</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46009871</guid></item><item><title>New comment by epistasis in "Samsung's 60% DRAM price hike signals a new phase of global memory tightening"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;It is a weird form of centralized planning. Except there's no election to get on to the central committee, it's like in the Soviet era where you had to run in the right circles and have sway in them.&lt;p&gt;There's too much group-think in the executive class. Too much forced adoption of AI, too much bandwagon hopping.&lt;p&gt;The return-to-office fad is similar, a bunch of executives following the mandates of their board, all because there's a few CEOs who were &lt;i&gt;REALLY&lt;/i&gt; worked up about it and there was a decision that workers had it too easy. Watching the executive class sacrifice profits for power is pretty fascinating.&lt;p&gt;Edit: A good way to decentralize the power and have better decision making would be to have less centralized rewards in the capital markets. Right now are living through a new gilded age with a few barons running things, because we have made the rewards too extreme and too narrowly distributed. Most market economics assumes that there's somewhat equal decision making power amongst the econs. We are quickly trending away from that.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 21:43:20 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46009325</link><dc:creator>epistasis</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46009325</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46009325</guid></item><item><title>New comment by sbarre in "Samsung's 60% DRAM price hike signals a new phase of global memory tightening"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I'm so mad about this, I need DDR5 for a new mini-PC I bought and prices have literally gone up by 2.5x..&lt;p&gt;128GB used to be 400$ in June, and now it's over $1,000 for the same 2x64GB set..&lt;p&gt;I have no idea if/when prices will come back down but it sucks.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 21:40:12 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46009300</link><dc:creator>sbarre</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46009300</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46009300</guid></item><item><title>New comment by mrsilencedogood in "Samsung's 60% DRAM price hike signals a new phase of global memory tightening"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;All I can say is,&lt;p&gt;- the insane frothing hype behind AI is showing me a new kind of market failure - where resources can be massively misallocated just because some small class of individuals THINK or HOPE it will result in massive returns. Even if it squeezes out every single other sector that happens to want to use SDRAM to do things OTHER than buffer memory before it's fed into a PCIE lane for a GPU.&lt;p&gt;- I'm really REALLY glad i decided to buy brand new gaming laptops for my wife and I just a couple months ago, after not having upgraded our gaming laptops for 7 and 9 years respectively. It seems like gamers are going to have this the worst - GPUs have been f'd for a long time due to crypto and AI, and now even DRAM isn't safe. Plus SSD prices are going up too. And unlike many other DRAM users where it's a business thing and they can to some degree just hike prices to cover - gamers are obviously not running businesses. It's just making the hobby more expensive.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 21:22:43 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46009135</link><dc:creator>mrsilencedogood</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46009135</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46009135</guid></item><item><title>New comment by rpmisms in "Helping Valve to power up Steam devices"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;It's incredibly obvious that they're trying to make Steam Deck 2 ARM-based. That's the generational change Valve is waiting for.&lt;p&gt;This is gonna be fantastic.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 21:09:53 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46009022</link><dc:creator>rpmisms</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46009022</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46009022</guid></item><item><title>New comment by sejje in "Homeschooling hits record numbers"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I used to work at a YMCA, and the local homeschool group asked us to do a PE class, which I taught.&lt;p&gt;I had the kids doing swimming, rock climbing, and all kinds of traditional PE games.&lt;p&gt;I worked with "normal" kids most of the time, and I will say the homeschool kids stuck out. They're more awkward around kids their age, but far less awkward around adults. They know how to speak and act, in large part. And they were disproportionately ahead of their peers academically--though I think that's probably a selection bias for the parents seeking out homeschool PE classes.&lt;p&gt;This was in the early 2000s, before Facebook. I'm sure the avenues to connect have only grown with social media.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 20:55:24 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46008885</link><dc:creator>sejje</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46008885</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46008885</guid></item><item><title>New comment by tikhonj in "Make product worse, get money"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;All of the pizza examples are about &lt;i&gt;reducing cost&lt;/i&gt;. The argument about dating apps is about &lt;i&gt;increasing retention&lt;/i&gt;. The dynamics are qualitatively different.&lt;p&gt;The argument with pizza is more like "people like salty, fatty food, so pizza places are incentivized to make their pizza less healthy so that people come back more often"... which is exactly what happens!&lt;p&gt;So why doesn't a legitimately healthy restaurant come along and take the whole market? It's partly because restaurants aren't just in the business of selling (healthy) food: it's also about convenience and satisfaction and experience. More importantly, that just doesn't fit with how people largely make day-to-day decisions.&lt;p&gt;The same thing happens with dating apps. People get drawn in for all sorts of reasons that don't necessarily map to getting married, even if finding a long-term relationship is explicitly their goal. Tinder competes with Tiktok more than it competes with other dating apps.&lt;p&gt;The other problem is that making a really effective dating app is just &lt;i&gt;hard&lt;/i&gt;. It's fundamentally difficult to help people find compatible partners, especially without in-person contact. That's compounded by cultural and demographic issues. It doesn't matter how well your app is designed when there's a massive imbalance in genders!&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 19:33:09 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46008040</link><dc:creator>tikhonj</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46008040</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46008040</guid></item><item><title>New comment by kylehotchkiss in "Homeschooling hits record numbers"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I can't say my public school experience was great, I was bullied and didn't really click with the popular kids, but being around a cross section of actual American kids in my age group (my school district mixed middle class with lower class neighborhoods) helped me shape my worldview and learn to deal with people who didn't look or talk like me. I frequently saw fights, so I learned that you just stay away and watch your mouth around specific people. I learned that the BS American value of "popularity" doesn't translate into successful futures.&lt;p&gt;I worry this move to homeschooling and micromanaging children's social lives just creates bubbles and makes children incapable of interacting with those outside of them.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 19:26:48 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46007963</link><dc:creator>kylehotchkiss</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46007963</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46007963</guid></item><item><title>New comment by fidotron in "Helping Valve to power up Steam devices"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&gt; This is a very difficult combination to achieve, and yet that’s exactly what we’ve done for Valve with Mesa3D Turnip, a FOSS Vulkan driver for Qualcomm Adreno GPUs.&lt;p&gt;Look at that. Something Qualcomm should have been doing.&lt;p&gt;Much credit to Valve for pushing that out as FOSS.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 19:13:03 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46007799</link><dc:creator>fidotron</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46007799</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46007799</guid></item><item><title>New comment by dap in "We should all be using dependency cooldowns"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;At my last job, we only updated dependencies when there was a compelling reason.  It was awful.&lt;p&gt;What would happen from time to time was that an important reason &lt;i&gt;did&lt;/i&gt; come up, but the team was now many releases behind.  Whoever was unlucky enough to sign up for the project that needed the updated dependency now had to do all those updates of the dependency, including figuring out how they affected a bunch of software that they weren't otherwise going to work on.  (e.g., for one code path, I need a bugfix that was shipped three years ago, but pulling that into my component affects many other code paths.)  They now had to go figure out what would break, figure out how to test it, etc.  Besides being awful for them, it creates bad incentives (don't sign up for those projects; put in hacks to avoid having to do the update), and it's also just plain bad for the business because it means almost any project, however simple it seems, might wind up running into this pit.&lt;p&gt;I now think of it this way: either you're on the dependency's release train or you jump off.  If you're on the train, you may as well stay pretty up to date.  It doesn't need to be every release the minute it comes out, but nor should it be "I'll skip months of work and several major releases until something important comes out".  So if you decline to update to a particular release, you've got to ask: am I jumping off forever, or am I just deferring work?  If you think you're just deferring the &lt;i&gt;decision&lt;/i&gt; until you know if there's a release worth updating to, you're really rolling the dice.&lt;p&gt;(edit: The above experience was in Node.js.  Every change in a dynamically typed language introduces a lot of risk.  I'm now on a team that uses Rust, where knowing that the program compiles and passes all tests gives us a lot of confidence in the update.  So although there's a lot of noise with regular dependency updates, it's not actually that much work.)&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 18:40:49 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46007447</link><dc:creator>dap</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46007447</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46007447</guid></item><item><title>New comment by layer8 in "We should all be using dependency cooldowns"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;People in this thread are worried that they are significantly vulnerable if they don't update right away. However, this is mostly not an issue in practice. A lot of software doesn't have continuous deployment, but instead has customer-side deployment of new releases, which follow a slower rhythm of several weeks or months, barring emergencies. They are fine. Most vulnerabilities that &lt;i&gt;aren't&lt;/i&gt; supply-chain attacks are only exploitable under special circumstances anyway. The thing to do is to &lt;i&gt;monitor&lt;/i&gt; your dependencies and their published vulnerabilities, and for critical vulnerabilities to assess whether your product is affect by it. Only then do you need to update that specific dependency right away.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 17:07:51 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46006342</link><dc:creator>layer8</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46006342</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46006342</guid></item><item><title>New comment by KeplerBoy in "XBMC 4.0 for the Original Xbox"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;XBMC on the original Xbox was so unbelievably far ahead of it's time, it's crazy and that's not just nostalgia talking.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 16:46:46 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46006118</link><dc:creator>KeplerBoy</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46006118</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46006118</guid></item><item><title>New comment by malfist in "HP and Dell disable HEVC support built into their laptops' CPUs"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Note that it's not a $0.24 increase Dell and HP are upset over, its an increase of $0.04. The price they were paying was $0.20.&lt;p&gt;So if you have a Dell or HP laptop, your hardware acceleration is broken because your experience with the hardware isn't worth $0.04 to the OEM.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 13:09:54 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46004166</link><dc:creator>malfist</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46004166</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46004166</guid></item><item><title>New comment by wongarsu in "HP and Dell disable HEVC support built into their laptops' CPUs"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&gt; For example, no background blurring in conference programs, significantly degraded system performance&lt;p&gt;So HP and Dell, two companies well knows for business laptops, sell some laptops with degraded video conferencing, all to save $0.24 per laptop? And Dell doesn't even mention this in the spec sheet or give you a straight list which models are affected?&lt;p&gt;I can't help but think that the reputational damage from "my new Dell laptop sucks with Teams, the previous one with worse specs was fine" is going to be a lot more expensive long-term than those $0.24&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 10:56:22 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46003285</link><dc:creator>wongarsu</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46003285</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46003285</guid></item><item><title>New comment by ErroneousBosh in "It's hard to build an oscillator"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&gt; There’s an old electronics joke that if you want to build an oscillator, you should try building an amplifier&lt;p&gt;It's funny, I was just thinking this morning about an old article in (I think) Television magazine that I read in the 80s when I was getting into electronics. The author was talking about some service notes he'd received for a particular model of Philips radio, which had just come out, and it was when shops tended to have their own service department that would repair things right there in the shop - and also, apply any "factory fixes".&lt;p&gt;One such fix was described as "Fix VIUPS", and involved changing a couple of resistors and adding a couple of capacitors. Not really any difference, but the author did think it seemed to make the amp a bit more stable and less inclined to make squealy ploppy noises at high volume when the battery was low. But, curiosity got the better of him, so he rang the Philips rep - what's this "VIUPS"?&lt;p&gt;No idea. But I'll get hold of someone at head office you can ring. Okay, what's this "VIUPS" thing? No idea, said the head office guy, but I can put you in touch with one of the factory engineers in Eindhoven.&lt;p&gt;So, a call came in, an international call! Quite a big deal in the 80s. "What's this VIUPS Fix thing in the service notes?" he asked the guy.&lt;p&gt;"Aha yes", he said in a heavy Dutch accent, "the VIUPS is the noise the set makes when the fault is present."&lt;p&gt;VIUPS VIUPS VIUPS. Yup.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 10:37:14 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46003184</link><dc:creator>ErroneousBosh</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46003184</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46003184</guid></item><item><title>New comment by sitkack in "Scientists now know that bees can process time, a first in insects"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;We are learning so many wonderful things about Bees!&lt;p&gt;They can count &lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=21222227"&gt;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=21222227&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;Bees play &lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=33369572"&gt;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=33369572&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.science.org/content/article/are-these-bumble-bees-playing-toys" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://www.science.org/content/article/are-these-bumble-bee...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;All of this reinforces my belief that nearly everything is conscious and aware, we differ in a capabilities and resolution but we are all more similar than we are different.&lt;p&gt;Spider Cognition: How Tiny Brains Do Mighty Things  &lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46003146"&gt;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46003146&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 10:17:56 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46003076</link><dc:creator>sitkack</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46003076</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46003076</guid></item><item><title>New comment by maccard in "Over-regulation is doubling the cost"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;It’s not over regulation, it’s bad regulation.&lt;p&gt;Not all regulation is bad, and some of it is wildly effective at not just achieving the letter of the law but actually solving the problem it was defined for. Good regulation IMO looks bad because you never hear of anyone being punished for breaking it because it is complied with.&lt;p&gt;The EU banned roaming charges in 2017. Most networks by then had already abolished them, &lt;i&gt;but only because this change was coming&lt;/i&gt;. The UK then decided it was going to leave the EU, and pretty much overnight the major mobile providers reintroduced the roaming charges.&lt;p&gt;EU flight compensation rules are another great example - they don’t pay out often because what’s happened is the airlines don’t get delayed to that point as often as they used to.&lt;p&gt;Scotland has a “right to roam”, which can be summarised as “don’t be a dick and you can go anywhere you want outdoors”. So you can walk, camp etc pretty much anywhere (it’s a bit more complex). In theory this means I can just open a gate to a farm, and walk across their fields. In practice, this means that most popular walking paths have access routes maintained by landowners that people use.&lt;p&gt;On the flip side, the cookie banners are a perfect example of bad regulation. They’re super easy to (allegedly) comply with and the result is just an annoyance for some 300 million people and absolutely no change to company behaviour whatsoever.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 08:34:31 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46002494</link><dc:creator>maccard</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46002494</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46002494</guid></item><item><title>New comment by goku12 in "Over-regulation is doubling the cost"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I can see two problems causing the pain described here, which I will discuss shortly. But the article seems to stretch that experience too much into the 'regulation is bad' territory. Regulations exist for a reason. They aren't created for the power trip of government officials. This is the same US where companies dump PFAS into drinking water sources with impunity, has some of the highest fees for the worst quality interest access, where insulin is unaffordable and corporate house renting is a thing. There are many such areas where regulation and oversight is woefully inadequate, much less any 'overregulation'. Regulations are practically the only thing standing between the rich and the powerful and their incessant attempt to drive even more wealth into their own pockets at the expense ordinary people's health, wealth, future, welfare, housing, etc.&lt;p&gt;Now let's look at the specific problems here with a much narrower scope than 'regulations'. The first problem is the type of regulations. Some regulations are too arcane and don't reflect the current state of technology. Others affect the unprivileged people disproportionately. The solution for that is to amend these regulations fast enough - not deregulation. It's also important to assess the negative impacts of loosening these regulations - something I don't see discussed in this article.&lt;p&gt;The other important requirement is to increase the staffing of the regulatory agencies so that their individual workload doesn't become a bottleneck in the entire process. There is a scientific method to assess the staffing requirements of public service institutions. According to that, a significant number of government departments all over the world are understaffed. Regulatory agencies and police departments top that list. Increased workload on their officials lead to poor experience for the citizens availing their services (this is very evident in policing). Yet those same experiences are misconstrued and misrepresented to call for deregulation and defunding of these institutions - the opposite of what's actually needed. (PDs need more staff and more training in empathy. Not defunding, nor militarization.) This is exactly what I see in this article. An attempt to target regulations as a whole using a sob anecdote.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 06:33:04 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46001803</link><dc:creator>goku12</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46001803</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46001803</guid></item><item><title>New comment by autoexec in "Why top firms fire good workers"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&gt; The firm starts to underpay those better workers who kept their jobs, akin to making them pay for being “chosen.” Consequently, profits do not decline and may even increase.&lt;p&gt;&gt; “Firms now essentially can threaten the remaining employees: ‘Look, I can let you go, and everybody’s going to think that you’re the worst in the pool. If you want me not to let you go, you need to accept below market wages,’”&lt;p&gt;This is exactly what unions are for. Any time there are enough skilled workers avilable that a company can let good employees go as a warning to others not to complain about substandard wages it's clear that the imbalance of power has resulted in exploitation. There is strength in numbers though which is why companies go to great lengths to convince people that you all alone negotiating with a huge corporation of people who have more money and resources than you'll ever see in your lifetime and who can replace you with someone else easily is somehow totally fair. No matter how special they might make you feel, you are almost always disposable to them and they will drop you at any time and for any reason, even if it's just to make an example out of you to keep your ex-coworkers in fear.&lt;p&gt;For the very few employees out there who actually are totally indispensable, any sane company would be looking for your replacement immediately because there's no telling what might happen to you or when. No company should fail because one employee dies in a car cash or gets a cancer diagnosis. Until you are also replaceable the company isn't safe. They'll pay you handsomely to keep you, right up until the moment they don't have to.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 05:11:00 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46001437</link><dc:creator>autoexec</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46001437</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46001437</guid></item><item><title>New comment by wackget in "Android and iPhone users can now share files, starting with the Pixel 10"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Incredible! In an astounding feat, it has only taken a mere two decades to enable the world's largest tech companies to provide the most basic levels of interopability.&lt;p&gt;At this breakneck speed of technological development, one can only imagine what wonderful boons await consumers in the next few decades.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 04:11:39 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46001148</link><dc:creator>wackget</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46001148</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46001148</guid></item><item><title>New comment by ukuina in "Nano Banana Pro"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Congrats on the move to Google!&lt;p&gt;Please allow me to rant to someone who can actually do something about this.&lt;p&gt;Vertex AI has been a nightmare to simply sign up, link a credit card, and start using Claude Sonnet (now available on Vertex AI).&lt;p&gt;The sheer number of steps required for this (failed) user journey is dizzying:&lt;p&gt;* AI Studio, get API key&lt;p&gt;* AI Studio, link payment method: Auto-creates GCP property, which is nice&lt;p&gt;* Punts to GCP to actually create the payment method and link to GCP property&lt;p&gt;* Try to use API key in Claude Code; need to find model name&lt;p&gt;* Look around to find actual model name, discover it is only deployed on some regions, thankfully, the property was created on the correct region&lt;p&gt;* Specify the new endpoint and API key, Claude Code throws API permissions errors&lt;p&gt;* Search around Vertex and find two different places where the model must be provisioned for the account&lt;p&gt;* Need to fill out a form to get approval to use Claude models on GCP&lt;p&gt;* Try Claude Code again, fails with API quota errors&lt;p&gt;* Check Vertex to find out the default quota for Sonnet 4.5 is 0 TPM (why is this a reasonable default?)&lt;p&gt;* Apply for quota increase to 10k tokens/minute (seemingly requires manual review)&lt;p&gt;* Get rejection email with no reasoning&lt;p&gt;* Apply for quota increase to 1 token/minute&lt;p&gt;* Get rejection email with no reasoning&lt;p&gt;* Give up&lt;p&gt;Then I went to Anthropic's own site, here's what that user journey looks like:&lt;p&gt;* console.anthropic.com, get API key&lt;p&gt;* Link credit card&lt;p&gt;* Launch Claude Code, specify API key&lt;p&gt;* Success&lt;p&gt;I don't think this is even a preferential thing with Claude Code, since the API key is working happily in OpenCode as well.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 01:40:40 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46000250</link><dc:creator>ukuina</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46000250</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46000250</guid></item></channel></rss>