<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>Hacker News: Best Comments</title><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/bestcomments</link><description>Hacker News RSS</description><docs>https://hnrss.org/</docs><generator>hnrss v2.1.1</generator><lastBuildDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 00:04:19 +0000</lastBuildDate><ns0:link href="https://hnrss.org/bestcomments" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item><title>New comment by SteveNuts in "Linux gamers on Steam cross over the 3% mark"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;The only thing windows has focused on has been dark patterns to force users towards cloud and figuring out more and more ways to collect data to sell ads.&lt;p&gt;I’m not naive, I know a ton of huge enterprises still run huge fleets of windows “servers” but I still find it hilarious that a supposedly serious server OS would default to showing you the weather and ads in the start menu.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 02 Nov 2025 20:18:31 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45793048</link><dc:creator>SteveNuts</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45793048</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45793048</guid></item><item><title>New comment by TACIXAT in "Linux gamers on Steam cross over the 3% mark"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I just made the switch. I had been developing on Windows for the last couple of years, mostly to get used to the ecosystem. I wanted to be able to write C and C++ like I do on Linux, without an IDE and with the native toolchain (i.e. no cygwin). On top of that, I play Overwatch every night.&lt;p&gt;Windows just seems to have zero focus on performance though. React based start menu with visible lag, file Explorer (buggily) parsing files to display metadata before listing them, mysterious memory leaks not reflected in task manager processes.&lt;p&gt;I installed Linux Mint. While it didn't just work (TM), and I had to go into recovery mode to install Nvidia drivers, it worked well enough. I can run Overwatch via Steam and pull comparable FPS to Windows (500 FPS on a 3090 with dips into the 400s). Memory usage is stable and at a very low baseline.&lt;p&gt;It is nice to come back to Linux, and with games I don't really have a need to run Windows anymore.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 02 Nov 2025 20:00:56 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45792940</link><dc:creator>TACIXAT</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45792940</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45792940</guid></item><item><title>New comment by jorl17 in "URLs are state containers"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;When I get my way reviewing a codebase, I make sure that as much state as possible is saved in a URL, sometimes (though rarely) down to the scroll position.&lt;p&gt;I genuinely don't understand why people don't get more upset over hitting refresh on a webpage and ending up in a significantly different place. It's mind-boggling and actually insulting as a user. Or grabbing a URL and sending to another person, only to find out it doesn't make sense.&lt;p&gt;Developing like this on small teams also tends, in my experience, to lead to better UX, because it makes you much more aware of how much state you're cramming into a view. I'll admit it makes development slower, but I'll take the hit most days.&lt;p&gt;I've seen some people in this thread comment on how having state in a URL is risky because it then becomes a sort of public API that limits you. While I agree this might be a problem in some scenarios, I think there are many others where that is not the case, as copied URLs tend to be short-lived (bookmarks and "browser history" are an exception), mostly used for refreshing a page (which will later be closed) or for sharing . In the remaining cases, you can always plug in some code to migrate from the old URL to the new URL when loading, which will actually solve the issue if you got there via browser history (won't fix for bookmarks though).&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 02 Nov 2025 13:49:29 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45790346</link><dc:creator>jorl17</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45790346</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45790346</guid></item><item><title>New comment by perlgeek in "We reduced a container image from 800GB to 2GB"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;The real lesson they should learn is to not rely on running images and then using "docker commit" to turn it into an image, but instead to use proper image building tools.&lt;p&gt;If you absolutely have to do it that way, be very deliberate about what you actually need. Don't run an SSH daemon, don't run cron, don't an SMTP daemon, don't run the suite of daemons that run on a typical Linux server. Only run precisely what you need to create the files that you need for a "docker commit".&lt;p&gt;Each service that you run can potentially generate log files, lock files, temp files, named pipes, unix sockets and other things you don't want in your image.&lt;p&gt;Taking a snapshot from a working, regular VM and using that as a docker image is one of the worst ways to built one.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 02 Nov 2025 12:02:51 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45789695</link><dc:creator>perlgeek</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45789695</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45789695</guid></item><item><title>New comment by visopsys in "Visopsys: OS maintained by a single developer since 1997"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I took an OS in college in 2006 and the big project that my prof required us to do was to make modification of visopsys. The software was primitive at that time but still had UI interface.&lt;p&gt;I emailed the author to ask some questions in my project. The author had connection with my prof and informed my prof about this. My prof told me that I was not allowed to ask the author regarding this project. So I had to figured out on my own.&lt;p&gt;It was fun to play around with and learnt how things work at deep OS level. It was a good memory for me :)&lt;p&gt;And you guys notice anything about my username? :)&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 02 Nov 2025 06:09:54 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45788159</link><dc:creator>visopsys</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45788159</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45788159</guid></item><item><title>New comment by simonw in "How I use every Claude Code feature"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&gt; Finally, we keep this file synced with an AGENTS.md file to maintain compatibility with other AI IDEs that our engineers might be using.&lt;p&gt;I researched this the other day, the recommended (by Anthropic) way to do this is to have a CLAUDE.md with a single line in it:&lt;p&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;  @AGENTS.md
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
Then keep your actual content in the other file: &lt;a href="https://docs.claude.com/en/docs/claude-code/claude-code-on-the-web#best-practices" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://docs.claude.com/en/docs/claude-code/claude-code-on-t...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 02 Nov 2025 02:27:09 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45787397</link><dc:creator>simonw</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45787397</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45787397</guid></item><item><title>New comment by roughly in "Why "everyone dies" gets AGI all wrong"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I’m more optimistic about the possibility of beneficial AGI in general than most folks, I think, but something that caught me in the article was the recourse to mammalian sociality to (effectively) advocate for compassion as an emergent quality of intelligence.&lt;p&gt;A known phenomenon among sociologists is that, while people may be compassionate, when you collect them into a superorganism like a corporation, army, or nation, they will by and large behave and make decisions according to the moral and ideological landscape that superorganism finds itself in. Nobody rational would kill another person for no reason, but a soldier will bomb a village for the sake of their nation’s geostrategic position. Nobody would throw someone out of their home or deny another person lifesaving medicine, but as a bank officer or an insurance agent, they make a living doing these things and sleep untroubled at night. A CEO will lay off 30,000 people - an entire small city cast off into an uncaring market - with all the introspection of a Mongol chieftain subjugating a city (and probably less emotion). Humans may be compassionate, but employees, soldiers, and politicians are not, even though at a glance they’re made of the same stuff.&lt;p&gt;That’s all to say that to just wave generally in the direction of mammalian compassion and say “of course a superintelligence will be compassionate” is to abdicate our responsibility for raising our cognitive children in an environment that rewards the morals we want them to have, which is emphatically not what we’re currently doing for the collective intelligences we’ve already created.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 02 Nov 2025 02:18:00 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45787356</link><dc:creator>roughly</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45787356</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45787356</guid></item><item><title>New comment by rtpg in "Claude Code can debug low-level cryptography"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I understand the pitch here ("it finds bugs! it's basically all upside because worst case there's no output anyways"), but I'm finding some of these agents to be ... uhhh... kind of agressive at trying to find the solution and end up missing the forest for the trees. And there's some "oh you should fix this" stuff which, while sometimes isn't _wrong_, is completely besides the point.&lt;p&gt;The end result being these robots doing bikeshedding. When paired with junior engineers looking at this output and deciding to act on it, it just generates busywork. Not helping that everyone and their dog wants to automatically run their agent against PRs now&lt;p&gt;I'm trying to use these to some extent when I find myself in a canonical situation that should work and am not getting the value everyone else seems to get in many cases. Very much "trying to explain a thing to a junior engineer taking more time than doing it myself" thing, except at least the junior is a person.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2025 23:07:59 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45786313</link><dc:creator>rtpg</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45786313</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45786313</guid></item><item><title>New comment by zug_zug in "Dating: A mysterious constellation of facts"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I think it's actually very simple... the paradox of choice.&lt;p&gt;You introduce somebody to your attractive single friend there's a real chance they hit it off and form a relationship. You introduce them to 100 attractive friends, one makes more money, one has a more stable job, one is flirtier, etc then it's both exhausting and none of them seem like a great opportunity.&lt;p&gt;I think there are certain basic psychological facts that are anti-standard-economics that nerds (and therefore tech companies) almost always tend to be completely blind to. This is one of them.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2025 21:16:21 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45785456</link><dc:creator>zug_zug</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45785456</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45785456</guid></item><item><title>New comment by simonw in "Claude Code can debug low-level cryptography"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Using coding agents to track down the root cause of bugs like this works really well:&lt;p&gt;&gt; Three out of three one-shot debugging hits with no help is extremely impressive. Importantly, there is no need to trust the LLM or review its output when its job is just saving me an hour or two by telling me where the bug is, for me to reason about it and fix it.&lt;p&gt;The approach described here could also be a good way for LLM-skeptics to start exploring how these tools can help them without feeling like they're cheating, ripping off the work of everyone who's code was used to train the model or taking away the most fun part of their job (writing code).&lt;p&gt;Have the coding agents do the work of digging around hunting down those frustratingly difficult bugs - don't have it write code on your behalf.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2025 21:01:18 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45785306</link><dc:creator>simonw</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45785306</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45785306</guid></item><item><title>New comment by 113 in "Show HN: Why write code if the LLM can just do the thing? (web app experiment)"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&gt; Because nobody actually wants a "web app". People want food, love, sex or: solutions.&lt;p&gt;Okay but when I start my car I want to drive it, not fuck it.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2025 19:33:07 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45784588</link><dc:creator>113</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45784588</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45784588</guid></item><item><title>New comment by iamnothere in "Chat Control proposal fails again after public opposition"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Great news. Now maybe we can go on the offense for once. Work to enable constitutional protections against this sort of thing, and develop systems that can work around it if and when this comes back again.&lt;p&gt;There are places in the world &lt;i&gt;today&lt;/i&gt; where only sneakernet communication has any semblance of privacy, so we need non-specialist tools that can provide privacy and secrecy regardless of local conditions. (I’d love to see more communication tools that don’t assume an always-on connection, or low latency, or other first world conditions.)&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2025 18:26:37 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45784029</link><dc:creator>iamnothere</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45784029</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45784029</guid></item><item><title>New comment by sunaurus in "Show HN: Why write code if the LLM can just do the thing? (web app experiment)"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;The question posed sounds like "why should we have deterministic behavior if we can have non-deterministic behavior instead?"&lt;p&gt;Am I wrong to think that the answer is obvious? I mean, who wants web apps to behave differently every time you interact with them?&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2025 18:25:20 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45784020</link><dc:creator>sunaurus</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45784020</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45784020</guid></item><item><title>New comment by efitz in "Updated practice for review articles and position papers in ArXiv CS category"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;There is a general problem with rewarding people for the volume of stuff they create, rather than the quality.&lt;p&gt;If you incentivize researchers to publish papers, individuals will find ways to game the system, meeting the minimum quality bar, while taking the least effort to create the most papers and thereby receive the greatest reward.&lt;p&gt;Similarly, if you reward content creators based on views, you will get view maximization behaviors.  If you reward ad placement based on impressions, you will see gaming for impressions.&lt;p&gt;Bad metrics or bad rewards cause bad behavior.&lt;p&gt;We see this over and over because the reward issuers are designing systems to optimize for their upstream metrics.&lt;p&gt;Put differently, the online world is optimized for algorithms, not humans.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2025 16:20:20 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45782897</link><dc:creator>efitz</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45782897</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45782897</guid></item><item><title>New comment by UniverseHacker in "You can't refuse to be scanned by ICE's facial recognition app, DHS document say"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Per thousands of videos on social media, it doesn’t matter what your rights are anymore, if you try to ask for them ICE will just become even more sadistic and violent, and the DOJ/government will refuse to cooperate in bringing them to justice for denying you your rights- you have no rights or recourse anymore even as a citizen. Moreover, the agents are masked and refuse to self identify as the law requires so you will never be able to say who violated your rights- they are hiding their identities because they are committing crimes. They are not police that follow laws, they are state sponsored white supremacist terrorists.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2025 15:43:25 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45782563</link><dc:creator>UniverseHacker</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45782563</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45782563</guid></item><item><title>New comment by jvanderbot in "Updated practice for review articles and position papers in ArXiv CS category"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;For &lt;i&gt;position&lt;/i&gt; (opinion) or &lt;i&gt;review&lt;/i&gt; (summarizing state of art and often laden with opinions on categories and future directions). LLMs would be happy to generate both these because they require zero technical contributions, working code, validated results, etc.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2025 15:26:39 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45782402</link><dc:creator>jvanderbot</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45782402</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45782402</guid></item><item><title>New comment by Sharlin in "Updated practice for review articles and position papers in ArXiv CS category"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;So what they no longer accept is preprints (or rejects…) It’s of course a pretty big deal given that arXiv &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; all about preprints. And an accepted journal paper presumably cannot be submitted  to arXiv anyway unless it’s an open journal.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2025 15:18:54 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45782329</link><dc:creator>Sharlin</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45782329</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45782329</guid></item><item><title>New comment by thomascountz in "Updated practice for review articles and position papers in ArXiv CS category"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;The HN submission title is incorrect.&lt;p&gt;&gt; Before being considered for submission to arXiv’s CS category, review articles and position papers must now be accepted at a journal or a conference and complete successful peer review.&lt;p&gt;Edit: original title was "arXiv No Longer Accepts Computer Science Position or Review Papers Due to LLMs"&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2025 15:11:50 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45782265</link><dc:creator>thomascountz</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45782265</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45782265</guid></item><item><title>New comment by GarnetFloride in "You can't refuse to be scanned by ICE's facial recognition app, DHS document say"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Just like IBM said, a computer can't be held responsible for its decisions. 
Management's been doing this for a long time to justify layoffs and such. This is just the next step.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2025 15:10:28 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45782252</link><dc:creator>GarnetFloride</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45782252</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45782252</guid></item><item><title>New comment by oddsockmachine in "You can't refuse to be scanned by ICE's facial recognition app, DHS document say"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Your point about orphaned records resonates with me, but for a much simpler (or stupider) "use case". I took a domestic flight earlier this year and foolishly showed my British passport as ID. I had returned to the country the day before, it just happened to be in my pocket. My green card was clipped to the front of it. After checking the identification page, the TSA agent flipped through the pages of entry stamps, visas, etc. There, they found all my old US work visas, which have long since expired. The agent was convinced that, since I have expired visas, I must be here illegally and would have to "come with [her]". I pointed out that I have a valid green card, so I'm here legally, and that of course every visa in the book has expired because - well that's what they do. It took 30 minutes, multiple staff being called over, supervisors, etc before I was allowed to continue. At every step, the presence of the expired visas was a mark against me. Never got an apology or recognition that they were wrong, just eventually told I could be on my way. I truly fear that overzealous thugs will use any "evidence" to prove their presuppositions, like your orphaned records. 
(I've naturalized since then, and carry my passport card around religiously, for all the good it may do...)&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2025 15:07:18 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45782215</link><dc:creator>oddsockmachine</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45782215</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45782215</guid></item><item><title>New comment by lambdaone in "Hard Rust requirements from May onward"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;It's about time. Critical infrastructure still written in C - particularly code that parses data from untrusted sources - is technical debt that is only going to get worse over time. It's not as if Rust is that much more difficult to write than C. Rust is explicitly designed to be what you'd get if you were to re-create C knowing what we know now about language design and code safety.&lt;p&gt;If 32-bit x86 support can be dropped for pragmatic reasons, so can these architectures. If people really, really want to preserve these architectures as ongoing platforms for the future, they need to step up and create a backend for the Rust toolchain that supports them.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2025 14:55:43 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45782109</link><dc:creator>lambdaone</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45782109</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45782109</guid></item><item><title>New comment by MSFT_Edging in "You can't refuse to be scanned by ICE's facial recognition app, DHS document say"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Someone I know is in a similar situation. She doesn't have the "naturalization documents". She has a passport, a ssn, and became a citizen before she turned 18.&lt;p&gt;Will ICE get it right? or will she be put into a prison for months with poor conditions, with an administration that does not want lawyers involved, with little ability to be found or call out for help?&lt;p&gt;This site likes to do the cowardly take of avoiding politics as long as it's advantageous. I'm going to look into these companies that produce this tech, and memorize the company names. If a resume ever passes my desk with a significant time at any of these companies, it's going to be a "no" from me. That's the small bit of power I hold.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2025 14:23:00 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45781864</link><dc:creator>MSFT_Edging</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45781864</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45781864</guid></item><item><title>New comment by rgsahTR in "You can't refuse to be scanned by ICE's facial recognition app, DHS document say"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&gt; They've just created an app to justify what they were already doing right?&lt;p&gt;This was also one of the more advanced theories about the people selection and targeting AI apps used in Gaza. I've only heard one journalist spell it out, because many journalists believe that AI works.&lt;p&gt;But the dissenter said that they know it does not work and just use it to blame the AI for mistakes.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2025 13:53:12 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45781662</link><dc:creator>rgsahTR</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45781662</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45781662</guid></item><item><title>New comment by asa400 in "SQLite concurrency and why you should care about it"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;In SQLite, transactions by default start in “deferred” mode. This means they do not take a write lock until they attempt to perform a write.&lt;p&gt;You get SQLITE_BUSY when transaction #1 starts in read mode, transaction #2 starts in write mode, and then transaction #1 attempts to upgrade from read to write mode while transaction #2 still holds the write lock.&lt;p&gt;The fix is to set a busy_timeout and to begin any transaction that does a write (any write, even if it is not the first operation in the transaction) in “immediate” mode rather than “deferred” mode.&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://zeroclarkthirty.com/2024-10-19-sqlite-database-is-locked" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://zeroclarkthirty.com/2024-10-19-sqlite-database-is-lo...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2025 13:32:31 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45781519</link><dc:creator>asa400</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45781519</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45781519</guid></item><item><title>New comment by hexbin010 in "You can't refuse to be scanned by ICE's facial recognition app, DHS document say"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&gt; “ICE officials have told us that an apparent biometric match by Mobile Fortify is a ‘definitive’ determination of a person’s status and that an ICE officer may ignore evidence of American citizenship—including a birth certificate—if the app says the person is an alien,”&lt;p&gt;This is "computer says no (not a citizen)". Which is horrifying&lt;p&gt;They've just created an app to justify what they were already doing right? And the argument will be "well it's a super complex app run by a very clever company so it can't be wrong"?&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2025 13:30:10 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45781498</link><dc:creator>hexbin010</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45781498</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45781498</guid></item><item><title>New comment by noodlesUK in "You can't refuse to be scanned by ICE's facial recognition app, DHS document say"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;This is going to be a huge pain. The US has a very fragmented identity system, and "move fast and break things" approaches like this to bring information from across government systems well outside the scope of what that information was collected for will result in real problems.&lt;p&gt;I worry what this app and systems like it might mean for me. I'm a US citizen, but I used to be an LPR. I never naturalized - I got my citizenship automatically by operation of law (INA 320, the child citizenship act). At some point I stopped being noodlesUK (LPR) and magically became noodlesUK (US Citizen), but not through the normal process. Presumably this means that there are entries in USCIS's systems that are orphaned, that likely indicate that I am an LPR who has abandoned their status, or at least been very bad about renewing their green card.&lt;p&gt;I fear that people in similar situations to my own might have a camera put in their face, some old database record that has no chance of being updated will be returned, and the obvious evidence in front of an officer's eyes, such as a US passport will be ignored. There are probably millions of people in similar situations to me, and millions more with even more complex statuses.&lt;p&gt;I know people who have multiple citizenships with multiple names, similar to this person: &lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45531721"&gt;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45531721&lt;/a&gt;. Will these hastily deployed systems be able to cope with the complex realities of real people?&lt;p&gt;EDIT: LPR is lawful permanent resident, i.e., green card holder&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2025 12:39:26 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45781183</link><dc:creator>noodlesUK</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45781183</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45781183</guid></item><item><title>New comment by baubino in "You can't refuse to be scanned by ICE's facial recognition app, DHS document say"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&gt;&gt;&gt; Photos captured by Mobile Fortify will be stored for 15 years, regardless of immigration or citizenship status, the document says.&lt;p&gt;The headline plus this quote reveals the real intentions — to create a comprehensive dataset that includes biometric data and can be used  however the government wishes, regardless of one’s citizenship. I have no doubt that this data will also be sold to other entities.&lt;p&gt;I remember reading years ago about how facial recognition was particularly bad at correctly identifying people with darker skin and was generally not great as the sole method of identification. The possibility of a mistaken identity being captured by this app would have life-altering implications with essentially no recourse. This is really disturbing.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2025 11:13:17 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45780791</link><dc:creator>baubino</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45780791</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45780791</guid></item><item><title>New comment by tranq_cassowary in "Leaker reveals which Pixels are vulnerable to Cellebrite phone hacking"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;GrapheneOS isn't made by volunteers. They have a team of around 10 paid developers. They are a nonprofit foundation that receives donations and uses those to pay developers, infrastructure etc.&lt;p&gt;Ars Technica has update its article to rectify that mistake. It doesn't mention that anymore.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2025 03:40:51 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45779079</link><dc:creator>tranq_cassowary</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45779079</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45779079</guid></item><item><title>New comment by shipman05 in "Addiction Markets"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;It feels like banning advertising for gambling would be a sweet spot between harm reduction and maintaining individual liberty.&lt;p&gt;Sports gambling ads have ruined sports media. State lottery ads are even worse. The government should not spend money to encourage its own citizens to partake in harmful activities.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2025 00:43:41 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45778266</link><dc:creator>shipman05</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45778266</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45778266</guid></item><item><title>New comment by Humorist2290 in "Addiction Markets"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;  But if you want to outlaw this harmful activity [licensed gambling], you have to find a way to replace 6.4% of Maryland’s budget, which is slightly less than the entire amount the state brings in from corporate taxes.
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
A fraction of the proceeds of losing bets from a fraction of Maryland's citizens contributes almost the same to state services -- EMS, education, road maintenance, etc -- than the total corporate taxes levied on all businesses.&lt;p&gt;Do I misunderstand, or is this just actually incredible?&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2025 23:50:46 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45777973</link><dc:creator>Humorist2290</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45777973</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45777973</guid></item></channel></rss>