<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>Hacker News: Best Comments</title><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/bestcomments</link><description>Hacker News RSS</description><docs>https://hnrss.org/</docs><generator>hnrss v2.1.1</generator><lastBuildDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 23:54:04 +0000</lastBuildDate><ns0:link href="https://hnrss.org/bestcomments" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item><title>New comment by gwd in "Apple is crossing a Steve Jobs red line"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&gt; From that point on, Steve would go on to spend lavishly on things that improved the experience, and he would reject—often brutally—any idea that diluted or harmed the experience. ...I’ll go out on a limb and say that uninvited advertising is not normally equated with a better customer experience.&lt;p&gt;YES!!!  SOO much of the Apple user experience has degraded due to this.  I can't listen to my own music that I bought on the Music app, without being interrupted asking if I want Apple Music.  I open up the Books app to read Winnie the Pooh to my son, and the opening screen has loads of random trashy romances to try to sell me.  I go to comfort read Ender's Game, which I did buy though the store a decade ago, and it helpfully "groups" it with the other four (!?) books in that series which I haven't bought, as if to say, "Don't you want to buy these too?"  NO!   If I want to buy them, I know where to find them!&lt;p&gt;It is SUCH an unpleasant experience.  EVERY time I open the App Store to update some apps, I'm angry that I have to wander past advertising assaults to do it.  EVERY time I open the music app to play an old favorite, I'm angry that I have to go past the advertising assault.  EVERY time I open up the book app, I'm angry that I have to go past the advertising assault.&lt;p&gt;I very much doubt the execs understand how much they're damaging the brand for that little bit of extra revenue.  The see the extra revenue, but they don't see the lost brand, or the people that switch away.  Is it really worth it?&lt;p&gt;ETA: I don't think it's an exaggeration to say:&lt;p&gt;Modern iPhones don't come with a music player.  They come with a music store, that you happen to be able to put your own music into.  But it's not structured to help you play your music, it's structured to sell you what they want to sell you.&lt;p&gt;Modern iPhones don't come with an e-book app.  They come with a book store that you happen to be able to upload some of your own books into.  But it's not structured to help you organize and read your books -- even the ones you've bought; it's structured to sell you more books.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 21:35:53 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45851385</link><dc:creator>gwd</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45851385</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45851385</guid></item><item><title>New comment by glerk in "Gmail AI gets more intrusive"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Google must have some awful PMs and designers. The worst UX decision I have seen recently is AI auto-dubbing all youtube videos by default with no way to disable this behavior globally. How could you miss that people can be fluent in multiple languages and if I click on a video in a foreign language, I most likely want the original soundtrack? Clearly, the intention was to boost some metric “X users are using this feature” with no regard for the actual user.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 19:39:00 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45850156</link><dc:creator>glerk</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45850156</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45850156</guid></item><item><title>New comment by trey-jones in "Denmark's government aims to ban access to social media for children under 15"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;As a parent who gave my oldest child a (very used) smartphone just before she turned 14, I would be in favor of making smartphones illegal under age 15 (or some other number, higher or lower I don't care).  I'm pretty sure they're worse than cigarettes for the future of humanity.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 18:38:28 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45849458</link><dc:creator>trey-jones</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45849458</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45849458</guid></item><item><title>New comment by cs702 in "Leaving Meta and PyTorch"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Many of the comments here are judging PyTorch &lt;i&gt;in hindsight&lt;/i&gt;, which is unfair.&lt;p&gt;When Soumith Chintala co-launched PyTorch, and for many years after, the alternatives for fast, interactive, convenient development were &lt;i&gt;much worse&lt;/i&gt;. There was no Jax.&lt;p&gt;Every single AI researcher I know, including me, who &lt;i&gt;tried&lt;/i&gt; PyTorch back then &lt;i&gt;immediately wanted to switch to it, because it was so much better&lt;/i&gt;. Andrej Karpathy described what PyTorch felt like back then when he tweeted, on May 2017, "I've been using PyTorch a few months now and I've never felt better. I have more energy. My skin is clearer. My eyesight has improved."[a]&lt;p&gt;THANK YOU SOUMITH for your hard work over all these years! Your hard work has made a difference for a huge number of people, including many of us here on HN.&lt;p&gt;We wish you success in your future endeavors, whatever they turn out to be!&lt;p&gt;Please ignore all the petty criticism.&lt;p&gt;---&lt;p&gt;[a] &lt;a href="https://x.com/karpathy/status/868178954032513024" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://x.com/karpathy/status/868178954032513024&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 15:41:42 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45847552</link><dc:creator>cs702</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45847552</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45847552</guid></item><item><title>New comment by macNchz in "Meta projected 10% of 2024 revenue came from scams"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Alongside a password manager and keeping things up to date, using an ad blocker is truly a foundational security practice these days. The big advertising players simply have all of the wrong incentives to control this problem. They &lt;i&gt;could&lt;/i&gt; massively reduce the volume of scams advertised on their networks, but it’d be worse for them on two fronts: they’d have to pay for more moderation, &lt;i&gt;and&lt;/i&gt; they’d lose billions in revenue in the process. Shoulder surfing while a non-savvy user browses Facebook or YouTube without an ad blocker and engages with obviously fraudulent ads is painful.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 13:47:04 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45846303</link><dc:creator>macNchz</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45846303</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45846303</guid></item><item><title>New comment by markphip in "A Fond Farewell"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;There is still the Old Farmer’s Almanac &lt;a href="https://www.almanac.com/old-farmers-almanac-233-years-and-still-going-strong" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://www.almanac.com/old-farmers-almanac-233-years-and-st...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 10:27:20 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45845131</link><dc:creator>markphip</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45845131</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45845131</guid></item><item><title>New comment by yanhangyhy in "Kimi K2 Thinking, a SOTA open-source trillion-parameter reasoning model"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;As a Chinese user, I can say that many people use Kimi, even though I personally don’t use it much. China’s open-source strategy has many significant effects—not only because it aligns with the spirit of open source. For domestic Chinese companies, it also prevents startups from making reckless investments to develop mediocre models. Instead, everyone is pushed to start from a relatively high baseline. Of course, many small companies in the U.S., Japan, and Europe are also building on Qwen. Kimi is similar: before DeepSeek and others emerged, their model quality was pretty bad. Once the open-source strategy was set, these companies had no choice but to adjust their product lines and development approaches to improve their models.&lt;p&gt;Moreover, the ultimate competition between models will eventually become a competition over energy. China’s open-source models have major advantages in energy consumption, and China itself has a huge advantage in energy resources. They may not necessarily outperform the U.S., but they probably won’t fall too far behind either.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 02:45:51 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45843056</link><dc:creator>yanhangyhy</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45843056</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45843056</guid></item><item><title>New comment by naet in "Two billion email addresses were exposed"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;There have been enough data breaches at this point that I'm sure all my info has been exposed multiple times (addresses, SSN, telephone number, email, etc).  My email is in over a dozen breaches listed on the been pwned site.  I've gotten legal letters about breaches from colleges I applied to, job boards I used, and other places that definitely have a good amount of my past personal information.  And that's not even counting the "legal" big data /analytics collected from past social media, Internet browsing, and whatever else.&lt;p&gt;I now use strong passwords stored in bitwarden to try to at least keep on top of that one piece. I'm sure there are unfortunately random old accounts on services I don't use anymore with compromised passwords out there.&lt;p&gt;Not really sure what if anything can be done at this point. I wish my info wasn't out there but it is.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2025 20:55:09 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45840304</link><dc:creator>naet</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45840304</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45840304</guid></item><item><title>New comment by klipklop in "FBI tries to unmask owner of archive.is"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;FBI wants to remind everyone that only US mega-cap companies can scrape the entire internet, not share the data, use it to train AI models and then charge people to use chatbots that use this 'laundered' data. Anybody else attempting to do this is a criminal in their eyes and must be punished.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2025 19:12:20 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45839058</link><dc:creator>klipklop</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45839058</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45839058</guid></item><item><title>New comment by vincvinc in "ICC ditches Microsoft 365 for openDesk"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Related:&lt;p&gt;"IMPOSING SANCTIONS ON THE INTERNATIONAL CRIMINAL COURT" (white house, feb 2025) &lt;a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/presidential-actions/2025/02/imposing-sanctions-on-the-international-criminal-court/?utm_source=chatgpt.com" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://www.whitehouse.gov/presidential-actions/2025/02/impo...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;Microsoft admits in French court it can't keep EU data safe from US authorities (jul 2025) &lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45822902"&gt;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45822902&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2025 18:23:36 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45838497</link><dc:creator>vincvinc</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45838497</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45838497</guid></item><item><title>New comment by joshmn in "FBI tries to unmask owner of archive.is"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;As someone who has been the target of an FBI investigation for what was effectively criminal copyright infringement (later arrested and did time in prison), my only takeaway is that this, if anything, should just be a civil suit just like so many other similar cases of copyright issues.&lt;p&gt;In my personal experience, the priorities of the FBI are typically highly politically motivated. The exceptions are if you’re doing something seriously icky, or doing fraud that deceives people.&lt;p&gt;For those interested in what’s reported and what actually happens, I’ve made some comments on my case and my experience here: &lt;a href="https://prison.josh.mn" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://prison.josh.mn&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2025 18:07:17 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45838283</link><dc:creator>joshmn</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45838283</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45838283</guid></item><item><title>New comment by BigTTYGothGF in "FBI tries to unmask owner of archive.is"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&gt; We can not allow the FBI to work for Evil here&lt;p&gt;Historically speaking I can't see this as even being in the top 100 evil things the FBI has done.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2025 17:52:53 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45838055</link><dc:creator>BigTTYGothGF</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45838055</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45838055</guid></item><item><title>New comment by perihelions in "FBI tries to unmask owner of archive.is"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;They pardoned the Silk Road drug lord to go after a copyright infringement-lord instead? It's not even in their effective jurisdiction, if this indeed is a Russian national. Don't they have more important Russian crimes to investigate?&lt;p&gt;I read there was a US government investigation tracking Ukranian children abducted by Russian forces, but supposedly there weren't enough resources [0] to sustain that.&lt;p&gt;[0] &lt;a href="https://www.npr.org/2025/03/19/nx-s1-5333328/trump-admin-cuts-funding-for-program-that-tracked-ukrainian-children-abducted-by-russia" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://www.npr.org/2025/03/19/nx-s1-5333328/trump-admin-cut...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2025 17:04:22 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45837420</link><dc:creator>perihelions</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45837420</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45837420</guid></item><item><title>New comment by teeray in "FBI tries to unmask owner of archive.is"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I pay subscriptions to some of these sites and still use archive.is on them because it is a more pleasant reading experience. No auth failures, no annoying popover windows begging me to subscribe to their dumb newsletter. Just the internet equivalent of a static piece of newsprint.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2025 16:51:27 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45837247</link><dc:creator>teeray</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45837247</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45837247</guid></item><item><title>New comment by shevy-java in "FBI tries to unmask owner of archive.is"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;We need to preserve data. The FBI is trying to kill data.&lt;p&gt;We can not allow the FBI to work for Evil here. I actually think there should be a human right to data. With that I mean, primarily, knowledge, not to data about a single human being as such (e. g. "doxxing" or any such crap - I mean knowledge).&lt;p&gt;Knowledge itself should become a human right. I understand that the current law is very favourable to mega-corporations milking mankind dry, but the law should also be changed. (I am not anti-business per se, mind you - I just think the law should not become a tool to contain human rights, including access to knowledge and information at all times.)&lt;p&gt;Wikipedia is somewhat ok, but it also misses a TON of stuff, and unfortunately it only has one primary view, whereas many things need some explanation before one can understand it. When I read up on a (to me) new topic, I try to focus on simple things and master these first. Some wikipedia articles are so complicated that even after staring at them for several minutes, and reading it, I still haven't the slightest clue what this is about. This is also a problem of wikipedia - as so many different people write things, it is sometimes super-hard to understand what wikipedia is trying to convey here.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2025 16:41:03 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45837144</link><dc:creator>shevy-java</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45837144</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45837144</guid></item><item><title>New comment by 55555 in "FBI tries to unmask owner of archive.is"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://archive.is/XdQRp" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://archive.is/XdQRp&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2025 16:29:51 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45836987</link><dc:creator>55555</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45836987</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45836987</guid></item><item><title>New comment by willvarfar in "Australia has so much solar that it's offering everyone free electricity"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Ignoring the politics, we have to say that China has done the world collectively as a whole a major service in strategically developing and mass producing super cheap solar panels.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2025 16:15:33 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45836788</link><dc:creator>willvarfar</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45836788</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45836788</guid></item><item><title>New comment by ACCount37 in "Cloudflare tells U.S. govt that foreign site blocking efforts are trade barriers"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I'm no fan of Cloudflare, but they're completely in the right on that. Infrastructure for blocking websites simply shouldn't exist.&lt;p&gt;Because if it's allowed to exist, it ends up subsumed by political and corporate interests, and becomes a tool of overreach and abuse. We've seen that happen over and over again.&lt;p&gt;If US Trade Office can be leveraged to destroy internet censorship efforts in other countries, then so be it.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2025 15:13:27 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45836147</link><dc:creator>ACCount37</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45836147</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45836147</guid></item><item><title>New comment by everdrive in "The trust collapse: Infinite AI content is awful"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Doesn't matter. We must keep building more and more technology no matter the cost. Have an idea for a business? Build it. Does your business make the lives of people worse? Doesn't matter, keep pushing. Could some new technology ruin the lives and relationships that people have? Doesn't matter, just build it. We always need more, need to do more. Every experiment is valid, every impulse must be followed. More complexity, more control, more distraction, more outrage, more engagement. Just keep building forever no matter the cost.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2025 13:30:40 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45835020</link><dc:creator>everdrive</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45835020</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45835020</guid></item><item><title>New comment by kibwen in "Ratatui – App Showcase"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;No, the people making TUIs in Rust are making TUIs because they love TUIs, and because Ratatui is pretty delightful. The state of GUI frameworks in Rust is irrelevant for this purpose, because even if there existed your ideal of Qt in Rust (putting aside the debatable notion that Qt is some sort of pinnacle of design), the people making TUIs wouldn't care, because that's not what they want to make.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2025 12:22:22 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45834419</link><dc:creator>kibwen</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45834419</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45834419</guid></item><item><title>New comment by sixeyes in "End of Japanese community"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Maybe "open a communication channel" is what Mozilla should have done BEFORE they turned on this thing.&lt;p&gt;From the article: "It has been working now without our acceptance, without controls, without communications".&lt;p&gt;This person has been doing volunteer work for a long time, attempting to create a helpful environment. Then suddenly, from above a machine is turned on that shits all over that effort. Makes one feel unwelcome, and unseen...&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2025 10:06:59 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45833462</link><dc:creator>sixeyes</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45833462</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45833462</guid></item><item><title>New comment by apexalpha in "End of Japanese community"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;As someone from the Netherlands I read absolutely 0 condescending or patronising behaviour in this.&lt;p&gt;It just looks like someone trying to get in contact and help out. I could've written this myself, genuinely trying to help.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2025 08:51:30 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45832970</link><dc:creator>apexalpha</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45832970</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45832970</guid></item><item><title>New comment by MrsPeaches in "Solarpunk is happening in Africa"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;This revolution also has a dark side:&lt;p&gt;People are paying off these devices and then once they have paid them off, they break and people in these areas don’t have the skills or resources to fix them.&lt;p&gt;This has led to over 250 million of the units lying around broken in peoples homes, leading to solar being one of the fastest growing e-waste streams in the world.&lt;p&gt;It’s hardly solar punk to sell people cheap crap at a 10x mark up that pretty much immediately breaks once the warranty period is over.&lt;p&gt;More details for the interested here: &lt;a href="https://solar-aid.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/10/State-of-Repair-Off-Grid-Solar-Sector-Oct-2024.-UNSW-SolarAid.pdf" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://solar-aid.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/10/State-of-Re...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2025 07:51:04 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45832597</link><dc:creator>MrsPeaches</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45832597</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45832597</guid></item><item><title>New comment by davidw in "I may have found a way to spot U.S. at-sea strikes before they're announced"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;"narco-trafficking boats"&lt;p&gt;There's no public evidence of that though. No trial. It's the same as if we sent the navy to board those boats, put a gun to people's heads and execute them in cold blood.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2025 05:08:41 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45831715</link><dc:creator>davidw</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45831715</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45831715</guid></item><item><title>New comment by getnormality in "End of Japanese community"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I'm sorry for how you feel about us kicking you in the balls.&lt;p&gt;Would you like to hop on a quick call to chat about this further?&lt;p&gt;Just a quick lil call.&lt;p&gt;Quick lil ol' callerino.&lt;p&gt;Hoppity hip hop.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2025 03:35:35 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45831090</link><dc:creator>getnormality</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45831090</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45831090</guid></item><item><title>New comment by kaveh_h in "End of Japanese community"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Some people do these type of contribution or charity work not just to do some good but also to feel some autonomy and mastery in a world were much of the regular top down driven  drudgery work does not provide much of that feeling. 
 These people are canaries in the coal mine. I expect more people feel a loss of purpose and rise of anxiety and depression in the world.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2025 03:26:43 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45831033</link><dc:creator>kaveh_h</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45831033</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45831033</guid></item><item><title>New comment by jahsome in "End of Japanese community"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I'm not really able to understand the finer details but I think I picked up enough to get the broad strokes.&lt;p&gt;Really though, all I needed to see was the phrase "jump on a quick call" to form an irrationally strong opinion. That phrase instantly warms my entire body with rage.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2025 03:15:57 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45830974</link><dc:creator>jahsome</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45830974</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45830974</guid></item><item><title>New comment by adeptima in "End of Japanese community"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;10+ years in Japan. The message here is much deeper from my perspective. “Let’s jump on the call” is not the solution. The guy was stripped off of his face. I love Japan for being human. Small business bar or restaurant with 3 tables. Not everything should be streamlined for a quick call solution… the process was pushed on his head. Google nemawashi decision making process&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2025 03:04:57 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45830907</link><dc:creator>adeptima</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45830907</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45830907</guid></item><item><title>New comment by ares623 in "End of Japanese community"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;This is rich&lt;p&gt;&gt; We want to make sure we trully understand what you're struggling with.&lt;p&gt;The post literally starts with a list of grievances. Maybe ask the AI for an executive summary and the key points.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2025 02:52:27 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45830843</link><dc:creator>ares623</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45830843</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45830843</guid></item><item><title>New comment by rodarima in "Dillo, a multi-platform graphical web browser"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Many reasons, in no particular order:&lt;p&gt;- It is extremely slow and resource intensive. Opening any link/page takes at least 3 seconds on my fastest computer, but the content is mostly text with images.&lt;p&gt;- It cannot be used without JS (it used to be at least readable, now only the issue description loads). I want the bug tracker to be readable from Dillo itself. There are several CLI options but those are no better than just storing the issues as files and using my editor.&lt;p&gt;- It forces users to create an account to interact and it doesn't interoperate with other forges. It is a walled garden owned by a for-profit corporation.&lt;p&gt;- You need an Internet connection to use it and a good one. Loading the main page of the dillo repo requires 3 MiB of traffic (compressed) This is more than twice the size of a release of Dillo (we use a floppy disk as limit). Loading our index of &lt;i&gt;all&lt;/i&gt; opened issues downloads 7.6 KiB (compressed).&lt;p&gt;- Replying by email mangles the content (there is no Markdown?).&lt;p&gt;- I cannot add (built-in) dependencies across issues.&lt;p&gt;I'll probably write some post with more details when we finally consider the migration complete.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2025 23:26:35 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45829453</link><dc:creator>rodarima</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45829453</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45829453</guid></item></channel></rss>