<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>Hacker News: Best Comments</title><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/bestcomments</link><description>Hacker News RSS</description><docs>https://hnrss.org/</docs><generator>hnrss v2.1.1</generator><lastBuildDate>Sun, 24 Aug 2025 23:58:10 +0000</lastBuildDate><ns0:link href="https://hnrss.org/bestcomments" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item><title>New comment by Joeri in "Why was Apache Kafka created?"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Kafka isn’t a queue, it’s a distributed log. A partitioned topic can take very large volumes of message writes, persist them indefinitely, deliver them to any subscriber in-order and at-least-once (even for subscribers added after the message was published), and do all of that distributed and HA.&lt;p&gt;If you need all those things, there just are not a lot of options.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 23 Aug 2025 20:26:17 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44998863</link><dc:creator>Joeri</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44998863</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44998863</guid></item><item><title>New comment by koolba in "The ROI of Exercise"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&gt; We know from one study that people who played tennis a few times per week lived roughly 10 years longer than average. So we'll use that value going forward.&lt;p&gt;There has to be some incredible correlation between having the time and money to play tennis “a few times per week” and being significantly wealthier than the average person. And being wealthy is clearly the healthiest thing you can do.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 23 Aug 2025 10:54:51 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44995011</link><dc:creator>koolba</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44995011</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44995011</guid></item><item><title>New comment by jjcm in "U.S. government takes 10% stake in Intel"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;In general I would rather the government take a stake in corporations they're bailing out. I think the "too big to fail" bailouts in the past should have come with more of a cost for the business, so on one hand I'm glad this is finally happening.&lt;p&gt;On the other hand, I wish it were a more formalized process rather than this politicized "our president made a deal to save america!" / "Intel is back and the government is investing BUY INTEL SHARES" media event. These things should follow a strict set of rules and processes so investors and companies know what to expect. These kind of deals should be boring, not a media event.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 22 Aug 2025 22:36:27 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44990743</link><dc:creator>jjcm</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44990743</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44990743</guid></item><item><title>New comment by sobiolite in "U.S. government takes 10% stake in Intel"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Ironic, Western politicians thought opening up to trade with China would lead to it adopting a Western model of government. Instead it's lead to the USA adopting the Chinese one.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 22 Aug 2025 22:04:07 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44990406</link><dc:creator>sobiolite</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44990406</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44990406</guid></item><item><title>New comment by afcool83 in "Waymo granted permit to begin testing in New York City"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I live in one of the areas they are actively testing/training in. Their cars consistently behave better and more safely than most human drivers that I’m forced to share the road with.&lt;p&gt;As semi-autonomous and autonomous cars become the norm, I would adore to see obtaining a drivers license ratchet up in difficulty in order to remove dangerous &lt;i&gt;human&lt;/i&gt; drivers from the road.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 22 Aug 2025 19:20:26 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44988724</link><dc:creator>afcool83</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44988724</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44988724</guid></item><item><title>New comment by nickdothutton in "4chan will refuse to pay daily online safety fines, lawyer tells BBC"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Step 1, pass law.&lt;p&gt;Step 2, demand compliance.&lt;p&gt;Step 3, upon not hearing of compliance, levy fines.&lt;p&gt;Step 4, upon non payment of fines, declare in breach of (2).&lt;p&gt;Step 5, block site from UK using DNS, in the same manner as torrent sites etc.&lt;p&gt;5 was always the goal, 2 to 4 are largely just performative.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 22 Aug 2025 12:15:59 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44983582</link><dc:creator>nickdothutton</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44983582</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44983582</guid></item><item><title>New comment by blixt in "Go is still not good"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I've been using Go more or less in every full-time job I've had since pre-1.0. It's simple for people on the team to pick up the basics, it generally chugs along (I'm rarely worried about updating to latest version of Go), it has most useful things built in, it compiles fast. Concurrency is tricky but if you spend some time with it, it's nice to express data flow in Go. The type system is most of the time very convenient, if sometimes a bit verbose. Just all-around a trusty tool in the belt.&lt;p&gt;But I can't help but agree with a lot of points in this article. Go was designed by some old-school folks that maybe stuck a bit too hard to their principles, losing sight of the practical conveniences. That said, it's a _feeling_ I have, and maybe Go would be much worse if it had solved all these quirks. To be fair, I see more leniency in fixing quirks in the last few years, like at some point I didn't think we'd ever see generics, or custom iterators, etc.&lt;p&gt;The points about RAM and portability seem mostly like personal grievances though. If it was better, that would be nice, of course. But the GC in Go is very unlikely to cause issues in most programs even at very large scale, and it's not that hard to debug. And Go runs on most platforms anyone could ever wish to ship their software on.&lt;p&gt;But yeah the whole error / nil situation still bothers me. I find myself wishing for Result[Ok, Err] and Optional[T] quite often.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 22 Aug 2025 11:35:29 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44983245</link><dc:creator>blixt</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44983245</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44983245</guid></item><item><title>New comment by xg15 in "The issue of anti-cheat on Linux (2024)"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;This article gave me more appreciation for the stance of the Linux community.&lt;p&gt;So to sum up. Valorant's anti-cheat, which the author sees something like an ideal solution:&lt;p&gt;- starts up and loads its kernel driver on boot.&lt;p&gt;- generates a persistent unique ID based on hardware serial numbers and associates this with my game account.&lt;p&gt;- stays active the entire time the system is up, whether I play the game or not. But don't worry, it only does some unspecified logging.&lt;p&gt;- is somehow not a spyware or data protection risk at all...&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 22 Aug 2025 11:10:06 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44983069</link><dc:creator>xg15</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44983069</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44983069</guid></item><item><title>New comment by cambaceres in "AWS CEO says using AI to replace junior staff is 'Dumbest thing I've ever heard'"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&gt; “I think the skills that should be emphasized are how do you think for yourself? How do you develop critical reasoning for solving problems? How do you develop creativity? How do you develop a learning mindset that you're going to go learn to do the next thing?”&lt;p&gt;In the Swedish schoolsystem, the idea for the past 20 years has been exactly this, that is to try to teach critical thinking, reasoning, problem solving etc rather than hard facts. The results has been...not great. We discovered that reasoning and critical thinking is impossible without a foundational knowledge about what to be critical about. 
I think the same can be said about software development.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 22 Aug 2025 08:11:43 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44982050</link><dc:creator>cambaceres</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44982050</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44982050</guid></item><item><title>New comment by seu in "Mark Zuckerberg freezes AI hiring amid bubble fears"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;These changes in direction (spending billions, freezing hiring) over just a few months show that these people are as clueless as to what's going to happen with AI, as everyone else. They just have the billions and therefore dictate where money goes, but that's it.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 21 Aug 2025 16:50:52 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44975026</link><dc:creator>seu</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44975026</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44975026</guid></item><item><title>New comment by dcastonguay in "I forced every engineer to take sales calls and they rewrote our platform"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&gt; At the end of it, they were sketching a completely different architecture without my "PMing". Because they finally understood who was actually using our product.&lt;p&gt;I cannot help but read this whole experience as: “We forced an engineer to take sales calls and we found out that the issue was that our PMs are doing a terrible job communicating between customer and engineering, and our DevOps engineer is more capable/actionable at turning customer needs into working solutions.”&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 21 Aug 2025 16:17:52 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44974574</link><dc:creator>dcastonguay</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44974574</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44974574</guid></item><item><title>New comment by moi2388 in "AWS CEO says using AI to replace junior staff is 'Dumbest thing I've ever heard'"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I completely agree.&lt;p&gt;On a side note.. ya’ll must be prompt wizards if you can actually use the LLM code.&lt;p&gt;I use it for debugging sometimes to get an idea, or a quick sketch up of an UI.&lt;p&gt;As for actual code.. the code it writes is a huge mess of spaghetti code, overly verbose, with serious performance and security risks, and complete misunderstanding of pretty much every design pattern I give it..&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 21 Aug 2025 15:01:50 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44973640</link><dc:creator>moi2388</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44973640</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44973640</guid></item><item><title>New comment by miki123211 in "Mark Zuckerberg freezes AI hiring amid bubble fears"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I have an overwhelming feeling that what we're trying to do here is "Netflix over DialUp."&lt;p&gt;We're clearly seeing what AI will eventually be able to do, just like many VOD, smartphone and grocery delivery companies of the 90s did with the internet. The groundwork has been laid, and it's not too hard to see the shape of things to come.&lt;p&gt;This tech, however, is still far too immature for a lot of use cases. There's enough of it available that things feel like they ought to work, but we aren't quite there yet. It's not quite useless, there's a lot you can do with AI already, but a lot of use cases that are obvious not only in retrospect will only be possible once it matures.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 21 Aug 2025 14:44:12 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44973432</link><dc:creator>miki123211</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44973432</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44973432</guid></item><item><title>New comment by simpaticoder in "AWS CEO says using AI to replace junior staff is 'Dumbest thing I've ever heard'"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;In undergrad I took an abstract algebra class. It was very difficult and one of the things the teacher did was have us memorize proofs. In fact, all of his tests were the same format: reproduce a well-known proof from memory, and then complete a novel proof. At first I was aghast at this rote memorization - I maybe even found it offensive. But an amazing thing happened - I realized that it was impossible to memorize a proof without understanding it! Moreover, producing the novel proofs required the same kinds of "components" and now because they were "installed" in my brain I could use them more intuitively. (Looking back I'd say it enabled an efficient search of a tree of sequences of steps).&lt;p&gt;Memorization is not a panacea. I never found memorizing l33t code problems to be edifying. I think it's because those kinds of tight, self-referential, clever programs are far removed from the activity of writing &lt;i&gt;applications&lt;/i&gt;. Most working programmers do not run into a novel algorithm problem but once or twice a career. Application programming has more the flavor of a human-mediated graph-traversal, where the human has access to a node's local state and they improvise movement and mutation using only that local state plus some rapidly decaying stack. That is, there is no well-defined sequence for any given real-world problem, only heuristics.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 21 Aug 2025 13:57:25 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44972862</link><dc:creator>simpaticoder</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44972862</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44972862</guid></item><item><title>New comment by alsetmusic in "Mark Zuckerberg freezes AI hiring amid bubble fears"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;It almost seems as though the record-setting bonuses they were dolling out to hire the top minds in AI might have been a little shortsighted.&lt;p&gt;A couple of years ago, I asked a financial investment person about AI as a trick question. She did well by recommending investing in companies that invest in AI (like MS) but who had other profitable businesses (like Azure). I was waiting for her to put her foot in her mouth and buy into the hype.She skillfully navigated the question in a way that won my respect.&lt;p&gt;I personally believe that a lot of investment money is going to evaporate before the market resets. What we're calling AI will continue to have certain uses, but investors will realize that the moonshot being promised is undeliverable and a lot of jobs will disappear. This will hurt the wider industry, and the economy by extension.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 21 Aug 2025 13:48:15 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44972755</link><dc:creator>alsetmusic</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44972755</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44972755</guid></item><item><title>New comment by jqpabc123 in "AWS CEO says using AI to replace junior staff is 'Dumbest thing I've ever heard'"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;He wants educators to instead teach “how do you think and how do you decompose problems”&lt;/i&gt;&lt;p&gt;Ahmen! I attend this same church.&lt;p&gt;My favorite professor in engineering school always gave open book tests.&lt;p&gt;In the real world of work, everyone has full access to all the available data and information.&lt;p&gt;Very few jobs involve paying someone simply to look up data in a book or on the internet. What they will pay for is someone who can analyze, understand, reason and apply data and information in unique ways needed to solve problems.&lt;p&gt;Doing this is called "engineering". And this is what this professor taught.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 21 Aug 2025 13:18:36 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44972416</link><dc:creator>jqpabc123</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44972416</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44972416</guid></item><item><title>New comment by johnklos in "Why are anime catgirls blocking my access to the Linux kernel?"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;This is a usually technical crowd, so I can't help but wonder if many people genuinely don't get it, or if they are just feigning a lack of understanding to be dismissive of Anubis.&lt;p&gt;Sure, the people who make the AI scraper bots are going to figure out how to actually do the work. The point is that they hadn't, and this worked for quite a while.&lt;p&gt;As the botmakers circumvent, new methods of proof-of-notbot will be made available.&lt;p&gt;It's really as simple as that. If a new method comes out and your site is safe for a month or two, great! That's better than dealing with fifty requests a second, wondering if you can block whole netblocks, and if so, which.&lt;p&gt;This is like those simple things on submission forms that ask you what 7 + 2 is. Of course everyone knows that a crawler can calculate that! But it takes a human some time and work to tell the crawler HOW.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 20 Aug 2025 23:30:30 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44967573</link><dc:creator>johnklos</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44967573</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44967573</guid></item><item><title>New comment by pnathan in "Zedless: Zed fork focused on privacy and being local-first"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I'm glad to see this. I'm happy to plan to pay for Zed - its not there yet but its well on its way - But I don't want essentially _any_ of the AI and telemetry features.&lt;p&gt;The fact of the matter is, I am not even using AI features much in my editor anymore. I've tried Copilot and friends over and over and it's just not _there_. It needs to be in a different location in the software development pipeline (Probably code reviews and RAG'ing up for documentation).&lt;p&gt;- I can kick out some money for a settings sync service. 
- I can kick out some money to essentially "subscribe" for maintenance.&lt;p&gt;I don't personally think that an editor is going to return the kinds of ROI VCs look for. So.... yeah. I might be back to Emacs in a year with IntelliJ for powerful IDE needs....&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 20 Aug 2025 19:26:14 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44965393</link><dc:creator>pnathan</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44965393</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44965393</guid></item><item><title>New comment by mg in "Pixel 10 Phones"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;The people at Google seem to think much more like me than the people at Apple.&lt;p&gt;There are 3 primary decisions Google made that click with me, while Apple's choices are a mystery to me:&lt;p&gt;1: When I put a Pixel on a table, it sits there stable. Because the backside is symmetrical. When I put an iPhone on a table, it wobbles.&lt;p&gt;2: When I sort my photos on a Pixel, I sort them in folders. The "camera" folder is where the unsorted photos are. When I sit in a bus or in a cafe, I go through it and sort the new photos into folders. This seems impossible on iPhones. Everything stays in the main folder forever. You can add photos to albums, but that does not remove them from the main folder. So there is no way to know which photos I have already sorted.&lt;p&gt;3: On Android I can use Chrome. Which means web apps can use the File System Access API. This makes web apps first class productivity applications I can use to work on my local files. Impossible on iPhones.&lt;p&gt;I'm sure people who prefer iPhones have their own set of "this clicks with me on iPhones and puzzles me on Pixels" aspects?&lt;p&gt;Is this a "left brain vs right brain" type of thing? Do most HNers prefer Androids?&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 20 Aug 2025 18:16:09 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44964579</link><dc:creator>mg</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44964579</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44964579</guid></item><item><title>New comment by mccoyb in "Sequoia backs Zed"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I love the spirit of Zed. From the principles to the low-level implementation details, it all screams "good taste". It's immensely interesting as an object of study (the code is great, from GPUI all the way up).&lt;p&gt;Having said that, I don't think an editor should be VC backed. It's the obvious pragmatic choice to get a team together to support a thing, but I'm concerned by it.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 20 Aug 2025 16:13:29 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44963229</link><dc:creator>mccoyb</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44963229</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44963229</guid></item><item><title>New comment by CharlesW in "AGENTS.md – Open format for guiding coding agents"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;This should've been an .agents¹ with an index.md.&lt;p&gt;For tiny, throwaway projects, a monolithic .md file is fine. A folder allows more complex projects to use "just enough hierarchy" to provide structure, with index.md as the entry point. Along with top-level universal guidance, it can include an organization guide (easily maintained with the help of LLMs).&lt;p&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;  index.md
  ├── auth.md
  ├── performance.md
  ├── code_quality
  ├── data_layer
  ├── testing
  └── etc
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
In my experience, this works loads better than the "one giant file" method. It lets LLMs/agents add relevant context without wasting tokens on unrelated context, reduces noise/improves response accuracy, and is easier to maintain for both humans and LLMs alike.&lt;p&gt;¹ Ideally with a better name than ".agents", like ".codebots" or ".context".&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 20 Aug 2025 01:03:04 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44957726</link><dc:creator>CharlesW</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44957726</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44957726</guid></item><item><title>New comment by tptacek in "Vendors that treat single sign-on as a luxury feature"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;This pops up on HN about once a year, and it's worth calling out that the SSO tax has mostly nothing to do with technology or with support costs and mostly everything to do with market segmentation. One of the clearest segmentation signals you get is that bigger, less price-sensitive customers all require SSO (because their SOC2 attestations require it).&lt;p&gt;You can get irritated about pricing systems that soak price-insensitive customers, but remember that the big price-insensitive customers pay for the price-sensitive customers, which is why this kind of segmentation is practically universal.&lt;p&gt;Previously, on this, from me:&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=29892664"&gt;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=29892664&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 19 Aug 2025 20:21:03 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44955882</link><dc:creator>tptacek</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44955882</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44955882</guid></item><item><title>New comment by newfocogi in "AnduinOS"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I made it half way down the page before I realized this wasn’t “ArduinOS”.&lt;p&gt;I can’t be the only one.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 19 Aug 2025 19:08:32 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44955114</link><dc:creator>newfocogi</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44955114</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44955114</guid></item><item><title>New comment by spankalee in ""Remove mentions of XSLT from the html spec""</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;A few things to note:&lt;p&gt;- This isn't Chrome doing this unilaterally. &lt;a href="https://github.com/whatwg/html/issues/11523" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://github.com/whatwg/html/issues/11523&lt;/a&gt; shows that representatives from every browser are supportive and there have been discussions about this in standards meetings: &lt;a href="https://github.com/whatwg/html/issues/11146#issuecomment-2759059949" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://github.com/whatwg/html/issues/11146#issuecomment-275...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;- You can see from the WHATNOT meeting agenda that it was a Mozilla engineer who brought it up last time.&lt;p&gt;- Opening a PR doesn't necessarily mean that it'll be merged. Notice the unchecked tasks - there's a lot to still do on this one. Even so, give the cross-vendor support for this is seems likely to proceed at some point.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 19 Aug 2025 16:03:38 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44953117</link><dc:creator>spankalee</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44953117</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44953117</guid></item><item><title>New comment by NikxDa in "Lazy-brush – smooth drawing with mouse or finger"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;An alternative that works very well for signatures too is Perfect Freehand (by the guy behind TLDRaw)&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://perfect-freehand-example.vercel.app/" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://perfect-freehand-example.vercel.app/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 19 Aug 2025 07:33:01 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44949160</link><dc:creator>NikxDa</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44949160</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44949160</guid></item><item><title>New comment by racemic in "Counter-Strike: A billion-dollar game built in a dorm room"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I've lurked on HN for years, but I had to create an account just to respond to your post. I operated these servers – perhaps my handle is still familiar. I remember you for sure! I'm touched that you and so many others still have fond memories of that time.&lt;p&gt;It was such a gratifying experience to build out that server network and the accompanying integrations that attracted so many and built such a great community. I miss the days in college when I had time to work on stuff like that just for the love of it. I hope you are doing well!&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 19 Aug 2025 05:45:42 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44948602</link><dc:creator>racemic</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44948602</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44948602</guid></item><item><title>New comment by rimunroe in "Counter-Strike: A billion-dollar game built in a dorm room"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I will forever mourn the general demise of server browsers. Too many games require you to use matchmaking systems, which means it's very hard to build up a small community in-game anymore. You either have to rely on forming small parties with people you've stumbled upon one by one, or you have to seek out people from some much larger area like Reddit or Discord. It takes a lot of the serendipity out of the experience. Without a small community it becomes much harder to ensure you're not playing with people who make the game less fun by whatever metric you care about.&lt;p&gt;I used to be an admin on a group of about 18 or so connected Counter-Strike 1.6 servers called T3Houston*. We ran modified versions of various Warcraft 3 mods which added persistent XP/leveling, as well as integration with an external item store and player database the owner maintained. Most of those servers were filled to the brim during peak US gaming times, and our forum was quite active.&lt;p&gt;There aren't many games these days where you could do something like that. I discovered the community because one day I was just looking for a server with open slots for me to join. I was fairly skeptical of whatever a Warcraft mod would be like, but ended up enjoying it so I added it to my favorites. Eventually I got to know the regulars and joined the forum. Notably, the place felt far less toxic than the average server I'd join back then. I can completely believe this is just me looking at the past through rose tinted glasses, but it feels like the general toxicity has gotten worse at the same time as we've lost a lot of tools to manage it.&lt;p&gt;* If anyone else here remembers the name T3Houston: hi! I'm Stealth Penguin&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 18 Aug 2025 19:27:03 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44944319</link><dc:creator>rimunroe</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44944319</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44944319</guid></item><item><title>New comment by juancn in "Left to Right Programming"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;SQL shows it's age by having exactly the same problem.&lt;p&gt;Queries should start by the `FROM` clause, that way which entities are involved can be quickly resolved and a smart editor can aid you in writing a sensible query faster.&lt;p&gt;The order should be FROM -&gt; SELECT -&gt; WHERE, since SELECT commonly gives names to columns, which WHERE will reference.&lt;p&gt;You could even avoid crap like `SELECT * FROM table`, and just write `FROM table` and have the select clause implied.&lt;p&gt;Never mind me, I'm just an old man with a grudge, I'll go back to my cave...&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 18 Aug 2025 18:24:50 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44943723</link><dc:creator>juancn</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44943723</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44943723</guid></item><item><title>New comment by ofou in "Anna's Archive: An Update from the Team"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Shadow libraries maintainers deserve a Nobel prize for their contributions to humanity. Satoshi would be proud.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 18 Aug 2025 17:51:00 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44943389</link><dc:creator>ofou</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44943389</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44943389</guid></item><item><title>New comment by jauntywundrkind in "Electricity prices are climbing more than twice as fast as inflation"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;[flagged]&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 17 Aug 2025 16:07:48 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44932597</link><dc:creator>jauntywundrkind</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44932597</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44932597</guid></item></channel></rss>