<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>Hacker News: Best Comments</title><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/bestcomments</link><description>Hacker News RSS</description><docs>https://hnrss.org/</docs><generator>hnrss v2.1.1</generator><lastBuildDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 01:51:45 +0000</lastBuildDate><ns0:link href="https://hnrss.org/bestcomments" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item><title>New comment by shetaye in "Why are 38 percent of Stanford students saying they're disabled?"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Regarding Stanford specifically, I did not see the number broken down by academic or residential disability (in the underlying Atlantic article). This is relevant, because&lt;p&gt;&gt; Some students get approved for housing accommodations, including single rooms and emotional-support animals.&lt;p&gt;buries the lede, at least for Stanford. It is incredibly commonplace for students to "get an OAE" (Office of Accessible Education) exclusively to get a single room. Moreover, residential accommodations allow you to be placed in housing prior to the general population and thus grant larger (&amp; better) housing selection.&lt;p&gt;I would not be surprised if a majority of the cited Stanford accommodations were not used for test taking but instead used exclusively for housing (there are different processes internally for each).&lt;p&gt;edit: there is even a practice of "stacking" where certain disabilities are used to strategically reduce the subset of dorms in which you can live, to the point where the only intersection between your requirements is a comfy single, forcing Admin to put you there. It is well known, for example, that a particularly popular dorm is the nearest to the campus clinic. If you can get an accommodation requiring proximity to the clinic, you have narrowed your choices to that dorm or another. One more accommodation and you are guaranteed the good dorm.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 19:08:42 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46151492</link><dc:creator>shetaye</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46151492</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46151492</guid></item><item><title>New comment by __MatrixMan__ in "Autism should not be treated as a single condition"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;It has always bothered me that by "spectrum" they mean not the sort of continuous thing that spectra actually are, but instead some disjoint set of "colors" any one of which might describe a person.  That's called a partition, and its in an entirely separate thing.&lt;p&gt;When I tell this to people they understand immediately that I am in fact on that "spectrum".&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 17:27:29 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46150224</link><dc:creator>__MatrixMan__</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46150224</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46150224</guid></item><item><title>New comment by ceroxylon in "Microsoft drops AI sales targets in half after salespeople miss their quotas"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;As someone who appreciates machine learning, the main dissonance I have with interacting with Microsoft's implementation of AI feels like "don't worry, we will do the thinking for you".&lt;p&gt;This appears everywhere, with every tool trying to autocomplete every sentence and action, creating a very clunky ecosystem where I am constantly pressing 'escape' and 'backspace' to undo some action that is trying to rewrite what I am doing to something I don't want or didn't intend.&lt;p&gt;It is wasting time and none of the things I want are optimized, their tools feel like they are helping people write "good morning team, today we are going to do a Business, but first we must discuss the dinner reservations" emails.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 17:05:59 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46149915</link><dc:creator>ceroxylon</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46149915</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46149915</guid></item><item><title>New comment by postit in "I ignore the spotlight as a staff engineer"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;One thing I’ve learned in my 25+ year career is that if you don't own your narrative and your work, someone else will claim it - especially in corporate America.&lt;p&gt;I have lost count of the brilliant engineers who were passed over for credit simply because someone less technically capable, but extremely popular, pulled the strings to steal the spotlight.&lt;p&gt;You don't necessarily need to be in the spotlight, but you do need to leave a paper trail. Claim your work and inventions both internally and externally. You don't need to be a 'LinkedIn thought leader' to do this, just submit talks to conferences and find peers at other companies who understand the difference between those who build and those who only talk about building.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 15:56:26 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46149009</link><dc:creator>postit</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46149009</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46149009</guid></item><item><title>New comment by jqpabc123 in "Microsoft drops AI sales targets in half after salespeople miss their quotas"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;AI agent technology likely isn’t ready for the kind of high-stakes autonomous business work Microsoft is promising.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;p&gt;It's unbelievable to me that tech leaders lack the insight to recognize this.&lt;p&gt;So how to explain the current AI mania being widely promoted?&lt;p&gt;I think the best fit explanation is simple con artistry. They know the product is fundamentally flawed and won't perform as being promised. But the money to be made selling the fantasy is simply too good to ignore.&lt;p&gt;In other words --- pure greed.  Over the longer term, this is a weakness, not a strength.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 15:50:09 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46148928</link><dc:creator>jqpabc123</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46148928</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46148928</guid></item><item><title>New comment by CodeMage in "Transparent leadership beats servant leadership"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;From the post: "The middle manager that doesn't perform any useful work is a fun stereotype, but I also think it's a good target to aim for."&lt;p&gt;This is the kind of argument that makes people come up with middle manager stereotypes in the first place. In fact, the whole post is a great example of why middle manager stereotypes exist: it starts with a straw man argument and comes up with a "better alternative" that makes life easier for the manager, regardless of what the manager's reports really &lt;i&gt;need&lt;/i&gt;.&lt;p&gt;I've seen this whole "I will empower you to do everything on your own" principle in action and it's &lt;i&gt;exhausting&lt;/i&gt;. Especially when the word "empower" is a used as a euphemism for "have you take on additional responsibilities".&lt;p&gt;Look, boss, sometimes empowering me is just what I need, but sometimes I need you to solve a specific problem for me, so I can keep solving all the other problems I already have on my plate.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 14:53:11 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46148293</link><dc:creator>CodeMage</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46148293</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46148293</guid></item><item><title>New comment by linguae in "Micron Announces Exit from Crucial Consumer Business"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I'm sad.  I'm a software guy, not much of a hardware expert, so please bear with me if I"m too pessimistic.  However, I feel that if trends like this continue, it might be the end of enthusiast-level personal computing as we know it.  No more being able to head down to the electronics store and purchase RAM, motherboards, processors, GPUs, storage, and other components.  We're going to be limited to locked-down terminals connected to cloud services, both of which provided by a small number of multinational corporations.  If we're lucky, we might still have USB peripherals.&lt;p&gt;The sad thing is that we enthusiasts are a small market compared to the overwhelming majority of computer users who don't mind locked-down devices, or at least until they've been bitten by the restrictions, but if there are no alternatives other than retrocomputing, then it's too late.  For decades we enthusiasts have been able to benefit from other markets with overlapping needs such as gaming, workstations, and corporate servers.  However, many on-premise servers have been replaced by cloud services, the workstation market has been subsumed by the broader PC market, and PC gaming has faced challenges, from a push toward locked-down consoles to challenges in the GPU market due to competition with cryptocurrency mining and now AI.&lt;p&gt;One of the things I'm increasingly disappointed with is the dominance of large corporations in computing.  It seems harder for small players to survive in this ecosystem.  Software has to deal with network effects and large companies owning major platforms, and building your own hardware requires tons of capital.&lt;p&gt;I wonder if it's possible even for a company to make even 1980s-era electronics without massive capital expenditures?  How feasible is it for a small company to manufacture the equivalent of a Motorola 68000 or Intel 386?&lt;p&gt;I'd like to see a market for hobbyist computing by hobbyist computer shops, but I'm not sure it's economically feasible.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 00:30:27 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46142265</link><dc:creator>linguae</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46142265</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46142265</guid></item><item><title>New comment by xbmcuser in "Valve reveals it’s the architect behind a push to bring Windows games to Arm"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;The major reason is they are a private company with good business. The don't have a need to keep adding to shareholder value ie stock price instead just need to generate a yearly income. We have reached a point where the shareholders are a companies real customers and that is who they all try to attract.Everytthing else a company does is just to attract shareholders&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 21:16:37 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46140250</link><dc:creator>xbmcuser</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46140250</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46140250</guid></item><item><title>New comment by averyvery in "Everyone in Seattle hates AI"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Yeah, "Engineers don't try" is a frustrating statement. We've all tried generative AI, and there's not that much to it — you put text in, you get text back out. Some models are better at some tasks, some tools are better at finding the right text and connecting it to the right actions, some tools provide a better wrapper around the text-generation process. Certain jobs are very easy for AI to do, others are impossible (but the AI lies about them).&lt;p&gt;A lot of us tried it and just said, "huh, that's interesting" and then went back to work. We hear AI advocates say that their workflow is amazing, but we watch videos of their workflow, and it doesn't look that great. We hear AI advocates say "the next release is about to change everything!", but this knowledge isn't actionable or even accurate.&lt;p&gt;There's just not much value in chasing the endless AI news cycle, constantly believing that I'll fall behind if I don't read the latest details of Gemini 3.1 and ChatGPT 6.Y (Game Of The Year Edition). The engineers I know who use AI don't seem to have any particular insights about it aside from an encyclopedic knowledge of product details, all of which are changing on a monthly basis anyway.&lt;p&gt;New products that use gen AI are — by default — uninteresting to me because I know that under the hood, they're just sending text and getting text back, and the thing they're sending to is the same thing that &lt;i&gt;everyone&lt;/i&gt; is sending to. Sure, the wrapper is nice, but I'm not paying an overhead fee for that.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 20:49:07 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46139928</link><dc:creator>averyvery</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46139928</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46139928</guid></item><item><title>New comment by Animats in "Micron Announces Exit from Crucial Consumer Business"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Wow. They're not selling off the business, they're totally exiting it.&lt;p&gt;This is a big loss. Crucial offered a supply chain direct from Micron. Most other consumer DRAM sources pass through middlemen, where fake parts and re-labeled rejects can be inserted.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 20:24:15 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46139607</link><dc:creator>Animats</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46139607</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46139607</guid></item><item><title>New comment by bccdee in "Everyone in Seattle hates AI"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&gt; Engineers don't try because they think they can't.&lt;p&gt;This article assumes that AI is the centre of the universe, failing to understand that that assumption is exactly what's causing the attitude they're pointing to.&lt;p&gt;There's a dichotomy in the software world between real products (which have customers and use cases and make money by giving people things they need) and hype products (which exist to get investors excited, so they'll fork over more money). This isn't a strict dichotomy; often companies with real products will mix in tidbits of hype, such as Microsoft's "pivot to AI" which is discussed in the article. But moving toward one pole moves you away from the other.&lt;p&gt;I think many engineers want to stay as far from hype-driven tech as they can. LLMs are a more substantive technology than blockchain ever was, but like blockchain, their potential has been greatly overstated. I'd rather spend my time delivering value to customers than performing "big potential" to investors.&lt;p&gt;So, no. I don't think "engineers don't try because they think they can't." I think engineers KNOW they CAN and resent being asked to look pretty and do nothing of value.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 20:11:50 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46139440</link><dc:creator>bccdee</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46139440</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46139440</guid></item><item><title>New comment by pkasting in "Everyone in Seattle hates AI"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Ex-Google here; there are many people both current and past-Google that feel the same way as the composite coworker in the linked post.&lt;p&gt;I haven't escaped this mindset myself. I'm convinced there are a small number of places where LLMs make truly effective tools (see: generation of "must be plausible, need not be accurate" data, e.g. concept art or crowd animations in movies), a large number of places where LLMs make apparently-effective tools that have negative long-term consequences (see: anything involving learning a new skill, anything where correctness is critical), and a large number of places where LLMs are simply ineffective from the get-go but will increasingly be rammed down consumers' throats.&lt;p&gt;Accordingly I tend to be overly skeptical of AI proponents and anything touching AI. It would be nice if I was more rational, but I'm not; I want everyone working on AI and making money from AI to crash and burn hard. (See also: cryptocurrency)&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 20:11:50 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46139439</link><dc:creator>pkasting</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46139439</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46139439</guid></item><item><title>New comment by levocardia in "Valve reveals it’s the architect behind a push to bring Windows games to Arm"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Valve is one of the few companies regularly seen on HN where the headline is something like "[company] is secretly doing something really great" as opposed to "[company] is secretly doing something evil"&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 19:19:32 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46138720</link><dc:creator>levocardia</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46138720</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46138720</guid></item><item><title>New comment by simonw in "Ghostty is now non-profit"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I wasn't aware of Hack Club before and wow, their fiscal sponsorship program is enormous: &lt;a href="https://hackclub.com/fiscal-sponsorship/directory/" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://hackclub.com/fiscal-sponsorship/directory/&lt;/a&gt; - looks like they cover more than 2,500 organizations!&lt;p&gt;The Python Software Foundation acts as a fiscal sponsor for a much smaller set of orgs (20 listed on &lt;a href="https://www.python.org/psf/fiscal-sponsorees/" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://www.python.org/psf/fiscal-sponsorees/&lt;/a&gt;) and it keeps our accounting team pretty busy just looking after those. Hack Club must have this down to a very fine art.&lt;p&gt;I wrote a bit more about PSF fiscal sponsorship here: &lt;a href="https://simonwillison.net/2024/Sep/18/board-of-the-python-software-foundation/#acting-as-a-fiscal-sponsor" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://simonwillison.net/2024/Sep/18/board-of-the-python-so...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 19:13:27 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46138641</link><dc:creator>simonw</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46138641</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46138641</guid></item><item><title>New comment by adverbly in "Valve reveals it’s the architect behind a push to bring Windows games to Arm"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Everything valve doing for linux is making such a huge impact.&lt;p&gt;The HL3 memes don't even seem fair to use anymore. I don't even want to un-seriously make joke fun of them at this point. They are just genuinely doing so much for the community.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 18:47:45 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46138331</link><dc:creator>adverbly</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46138331</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46138331</guid></item><item><title>New comment by coffeecoders in "RCE Vulnerability in React and Next.js"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;This vulnerability is basically the worst-case version of what people have been warning about since RSC/server actions were introduced.&lt;p&gt;The server was deserializing untrusted input from the client directly into module+export name lookups, and then invoking whatever the client asked for (without verifying that metadata.name was an own property).&lt;p&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;    return moduleExports[metadata.name]

&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
We can patch hasOwnProperty and tighten the deserializer, but there is deeper issue. React never really acknowledged that it was building an RPC layer. If you look at actual RPC frameworks like gPRC or even old school SOAP, they all start with schemas, explicit service definitions and a bunch of tooling to prevent boundary confusion. React went the opposite way: the API surface is whatever your bundler can see, and the endpoint is whatever the client asks for.&lt;p&gt;My guess is this won't be the last time we see security fallout from that design choice. Not because React is sloppy, but because it’s trying to solve a problem category that traditionally requires explicitness, not magic.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 18:34:31 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46138157</link><dc:creator>coffeecoders</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46138157</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46138157</guid></item><item><title>New comment by flufluflufluffy in "1D Conway's Life glider found, 3.7B cells long"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Me: oh cool, this is interesting, I don’t quite understand what exactly that means, let me read the thread to learn more…&lt;p&gt;The thread:
&gt; Replacing ECCA1 by version with step after the direction change could save something like 1% of the ecca1 bits size. Compiling agnosticized program instead of fixed lane program by ecca1 could save something like 1% as well (just guesses). Build of smaller ECCA1 would shorten binary portion, but it would be hardly seen in the ship size.&lt;p&gt;&gt; Using agnosticized recipe in the fuse portion would definitely reduce its size. Better cordership seed and better salvo for gpse90 would help…&lt;p&gt;Dear lord I had no idea there’s this much jargon in the game of life community. Gonna be reading the wiki for hours&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 18:18:07 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46137951</link><dc:creator>flufluflufluffy</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46137951</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46137951</guid></item><item><title>New comment by hyperbovine in "Anthropic taps IPO lawyers as it races OpenAI to go public"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;LOL of course they don't want to own Anthropic, else they themselves would be responsible for coming up with the $10s of billions in Monopoly money that Anthropic has committed to pay AMZN for compute in the next few years. Better to take an impressive looking stake and leave some other idiot holding the buck.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 15:00:45 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46135253</link><dc:creator>hyperbovine</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46135253</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46135253</guid></item><item><title>New comment by ApolloFortyNine in "“Captain Gains” on Capitol Hill"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&gt;This is saying that people in congressional leadership positions do 47% better than other members of Congress.&lt;p&gt;It's even more damning than that I think.&lt;p&gt;&gt;we find that lawmakers who later ascend to leadership positions perform similarly to matched peers beforehand but outperform them by 47 percentage points annually after ascension.&lt;p&gt;The same person makes more after being put in a leadership position than before. That essentially removes any possibility of 'well maybe they're just more knowledgable and that's why they're in leadership.'&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 14:28:54 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46134860</link><dc:creator>ApolloFortyNine</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46134860</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46134860</guid></item><item><title>New comment by burkaman in "“Captain Gains” on Capitol Hill"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Incorrect title, the finding is "lawmakers who later ascend to leadership positions perform similarly to matched peers beforehand but outperform them by 47 percentage points annually after ascension." This is saying that people in congressional leadership positions do 47% better than other members of Congress.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 14:07:20 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46134623</link><dc:creator>burkaman</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46134623</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46134623</guid></item><item><title>New comment by snet0 in "Helldivers 2 devs slash install size from 154GB to 23GB"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&gt; With their latest data measurements specific to the game, the developers have confirmed the small number of players (11% last week) using mechanical hard drives will witness mission load times increase by only a few seconds in worst cases. Additionally, the post reads, “the majority of the loading time in Helldivers 2 is due to level-generation rather than asset loading. This level generation happens in parallel with loading assets from the disk and so is the main determining factor of the loading time.”&lt;p&gt;It seems bizarre to me that they'd have accepted such a high cost (150GB+ installation size!) without entirely verifying that it was necessary!&lt;p&gt;I expect it's a story that'll never get told in enough detail to satisfy curiosity, but it certainly seems strange from the outside for this optimisation to be both possible and acceptable.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 14:01:12 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46134547</link><dc:creator>snet0</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46134547</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46134547</guid></item><item><title>New comment by dannersy in "Zig quits GitHub, says Microsoft's AI obsession has ruined the service"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I often find we don't appreciate enough people accepting their failures and changing their mind. For some reason I see the opposite: people respecting those who "stick to their guns" or double down when something is clearly wrong. As you say, the context matters and these edits seem to be learning from the feedback rather than saving face since the sentiment stands, just in a less needlessly targeted way.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 12:29:48 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46133742</link><dc:creator>dannersy</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46133742</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46133742</guid></item><item><title>New comment by styanax in "Zig quits GitHub, says Microsoft's AI obsession has ruined the service"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;On the previous HN article, I recall many a comment talking about how they should change this, leave the politics/negative juju out because it was a bad look for the Zig community.&lt;p&gt;It would appear they listened to that feedback, swallowed their ego/pride and did what was best for the Zig community with these edits. I commend them for their actions in doing what's best for the community at the cost of some personal mea culpa edits.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 11:23:34 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46133219</link><dc:creator>styanax</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46133219</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46133219</guid></item><item><title>New comment by brushfoot in "Zig quits GitHub, says Microsoft's AI obsession has ruined the service"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;The edit history of the announcement is quite a ride:&lt;p&gt;&gt; [2025-11-27T02:10:07Z] it’s abundantly clear that the talented folks who used to work on the product have moved on to bigger and better things, with the remaining losers eager to inflict some kind of bloated, buggy JavaScript framework on us in the name of progress [1]&lt;p&gt;&gt; [2025-11-27T14:04:47Z] it’s abundantly clear that the talented folks who used to work on the product have moved on to bigger and better things, with the remaining rookies eager to inflict some kind of bloated, buggy JavaScript framework on us in the name of progress [2]&lt;p&gt;&gt; [2025-11-28T09:21:12Z] it’s abundantly clear that the engineering excellence that created GitHub’s success is no longer driving it [3]&lt;p&gt;---&lt;p&gt;1: &lt;a href="https://web.archive.org/web/20251127021007/https://ziglang.org/news/migrating-from-github-to-codeberg/" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://web.archive.org/web/20251127021007/https://ziglang.o...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;2: &lt;a href="https://web.archive.org/web/20251127140447/https://ziglang.org/news/migrating-from-github-to-codeberg/" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://web.archive.org/web/20251127140447/https://ziglang.o...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;3: &lt;a href="https://web.archive.org/web/20251128092112/https://ziglang.org/news/migrating-from-github-to-codeberg/" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://web.archive.org/web/20251128092112/https://ziglang.o...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 11:19:04 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46133179</link><dc:creator>brushfoot</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46133179</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46133179</guid></item><item><title>New comment by sigmoid10 in "Accepting US car standards would risk European lives"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&gt;EU vehicle safety regulations have supported a 36% reduction in European road deaths since 2010. By contrast, road deaths in the US over the same period increased 30%, with pedestrian deaths up 80% and cyclist deaths up 50%&lt;p&gt;I didn't know this, but it is absolutely crazy. Every EU politician who tries to subvert car safety should be dismissed and tried for endangering public safety.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 08:15:06 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46131574</link><dc:creator>sigmoid10</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46131574</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46131574</guid></item><item><title>New comment by CalRobert in "Accepting US car standards would risk European lives"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;NotJustBikes just put out a video about this issue - &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=--832LV9a3I" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=--832LV9a3I&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;A couple years ago he also made a video about these trucks more broadly - &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=jN7mSXMruEo" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=jN7mSXMruEo&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;What's truly maddening is how many of these vehicles which _do not_ meet European safety standards are _already_ in Europe. Walk around Hilversum in the Netherlands and you will see plenty of Dodge Rams (mostly 1500's, but there's even a 2500 Dually usually parked on the sidewalk ("pavement "for Brits) where my kids used to go to school). They're imported under "Individual Vehicle Approval" rules, exempting them from type safety requirements, and on top of that are almost always registered as "business vehicles" (you can tell from the V plate) which means they pay an absolute pittance in tax.&lt;p&gt;I moved here to get away from American kindercrushers (among other reasons) and I am profoundly concerned that Europe is being invaded by these machines.&lt;p&gt;(Edit)
Worth noting is that a lot of Dutch street design is based on the idea that people _can_ share space with cars in dense, low speed environments, but that assumption flies out the window when the vehicles are so large you can't even see a kid walking or biking to school.&lt;p&gt;Further edit - source - &lt;a href="https://www.motorfinanceonline.com/news/dodge-ram-registrations-surge-in-europe-prompting-calls-for-regulatory-action/" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://www.motorfinanceonline.com/news/dodge-ram-registrati...&lt;/a&gt;
5,000 Dodge Rams imported in to Europe in 2023 alone.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 08:12:46 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46131554</link><dc:creator>CalRobert</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46131554</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46131554</guid></item><item><title>New comment by helsinkiandrew in "IBM CEO says there is 'no way' spending on AI data centers will pay off"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&gt; IBM has not exactly had a stellar record at identifying the future.&lt;p&gt;IBM invented/developed/introduced magnetic stripe cards, UPC Barcodes, the modern ATM, Hard drives, floppies, DRAM, SQL, the 360 Family of Mainframes, the PC, Apollo guidance computers, Deep Blue.  IBM created a far share of the future we're living in.&lt;p&gt;I'm no fan of much of what IBM is doing at the moment but it could be argued that its consultancy/service orientation gives it a good view of how business is and is planning to use AI.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 07:28:02 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46131245</link><dc:creator>helsinkiandrew</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46131245</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46131245</guid></item><item><title>New comment by mattkevan in "Japanese game devs face font dilemma as license increases from $380 to $20k"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Ah Monotype. Knew before reading the article it would be them. Their whole MO is buying up smaller type foundries, massively increasing the licensing fees and shaking down the previous customers. They send in auditors, demand to see traffic data and threaten fines. Happened to me twice now.&lt;p&gt;Creating type is an extremely difficult and skilled discipline and designers deserve to be compensated fairly. However Monotype’s business practices are such that I won’t approve anything but open source fonts for new projects.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 07:15:13 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46131149</link><dc:creator>mattkevan</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46131149</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46131149</guid></item><item><title>New comment by hxtk in "AI agents break rules under everyday pressure"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Blameless postmortem culture recognizes human error as an inevitability and asks those with influence to design systems that maintain safety in the face of human error. In the software engineering world, this typically means automation, because while automation can and usually does have faults, it doesn't suffer from human error.&lt;p&gt;Now we've invented automation that commits human-like error at scale.&lt;p&gt;I wouldn't call myself anti-AI, but it does seem fairly obvious to me that directly automating things with AI will probably always have substantial risk and you have much more assurance, if you involve AI in the process, using it to develop a traditional automation. As a low-stakes personal example, instead of using AI to generate boilerplate code, I'll often try to use AI to generate a traditional code generator to convert whatever DSL specification into the chosen development language source code, rather than asking AI to generate the development language source code directly from the DSL.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 05:44:22 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46130680</link><dc:creator>hxtk</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46130680</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46130680</guid></item><item><title>New comment by kentonv in "Anthropic acquires Bun"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I built Cloudflare Workers?&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 01:03:34 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46129044</link><dc:creator>kentonv</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46129044</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46129044</guid></item></channel></rss>