<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>Hacker News: Best Comments</title><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/bestcomments</link><description>Hacker News RSS</description><docs>https://hnrss.org/</docs><generator>hnrss v2.1.1</generator><lastBuildDate>Sat, 07 Feb 2026 02:22:07 +0000</lastBuildDate><ns0:link href="https://hnrss.org/bestcomments" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item><title>New comment by mattlondon in "The Waymo World Model"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Suddenly all this focus on world models by Deep mind starts to make sense. I've never really thought of Waymo as a robot in the same way as e.g. a Boston Dynamics humanoid, but of course it is a robot of sorts.&lt;p&gt;Google/Alphabet are so vertically integrated for AI when you think about it. Compare what they're doing - their own power generation , their own silicon, their own data centers, search Gmail YouTube Gemini workspace wallet, billions and billions of Android and Chromebook users, their ads everywhere, their browser everywhere, waymo, probably buy back Boston dynamics soon enough (they're recently partnered together), fusion research, drugs discovery.... and then look at ChatGPT's chatbot or grok's porn. Pales in comparison.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 18:09:31 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46916092</link><dc:creator>mattlondon</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46916092</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46916092</guid></item><item><title>New comment by simonw in "An Update on Heroku"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;"We know changes like this can raise questions, and we want to be clear about what this means for customers."&lt;p&gt;Proceeds to not be clear about what this means for customers.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 15:51:53 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46914321</link><dc:creator>simonw</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46914321</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46914321</guid></item><item><title>New comment by jamesblonde in "TikTok's 'addictive design' found to be illegal in Europe"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I gave a talk at PyData Berlin on how to build your own TikTok recommendation algorithm. The TikTok personalized recommendation engine is the world's most valuable AI. It's TikTok's differentiation. It updates recommendations within 1 second of you clicking - at human perceivable latency. If your AI recommender has poor feature freshness, it will be perceived as slow, not intelligent - no matter how good the recommendations are.&lt;p&gt;TikTok's recommender is partly built on European Technology (Apache Flink for real-time feature computation), along with Kafka, and distributed model training infrastructure. The Monolith paper is misleading that the 'online training' is key. It is not. It is that your clicks are made available as features for predicitons in less than 1 second. You need a per-event stream processing architecture for this (like Flink - Feldera would be my modern choice as an incremental streaming engine).&lt;p&gt;* &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=skZ1HcF7AsM" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=skZ1HcF7AsM&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;* Monolith paper - &lt;a href="https://arxiv.org/pdf/2209.07663" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://arxiv.org/pdf/2209.07663&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 13:27:26 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46912562</link><dc:creator>jamesblonde</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46912562</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46912562</guid></item><item><title>New comment by elashri in "I now assume that all ads on Apple news are scams"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;We should assume that all ads in general are scams. The noise to signal ratio is too large to care. Word of mouth and maybe trusted communities like HN is the only way to reliably discover new things.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 13:09:21 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46912393</link><dc:creator>elashri</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46912393</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46912393</guid></item><item><title>New comment by speak_plainly in "I now assume that all ads on Apple news are scams"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Apple News and News+ represent everything wrong with modern Apple: a ham-fisted approach to simplicity that ignores the end user. It is their most mediocre service, jarringly jamming cheap clickbait next to serious journalism in a layout that makes no sense.&lt;p&gt;The technical execution is just as lazy. While some magazines are tailored, many are just flat, low-res PDFs that look terrible on the high-end Retina screens Apple sells. Worst of all, Apple had the leverage to revolutionize a struggling industry; instead, they settled for a half-baked aggregator.&lt;p&gt;It’s a toxic mix of Apple tropes that simply weren't thought through. The ads are the cherry on the cake.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 13:04:11 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46912336</link><dc:creator>speak_plainly</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46912336</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46912336</guid></item><item><title>New comment by golfer in "Claude Opus 4.6"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;There's lots of websites that list the spells. It's well documented. Could Claude simply be regurgitating knowledge from the web? Example:&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://harrypotter.fandom.com/wiki/List_of_spells" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://harrypotter.fandom.com/wiki/List_of_spells&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 22:41:13 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46906441</link><dc:creator>golfer</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46906441</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46906441</guid></item><item><title>New comment by ndesaulniers in "We tasked Opus 4.6 using agent teams to build a C Compiler"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I spent a good part of my career (nearly a decade) at Google working on getting Clang to build the linux kernel. &lt;a href="https://clangbuiltlinux.github.io/" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://clangbuiltlinux.github.io/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;This LLM did it in (checks notes):&lt;p&gt;&gt; Over nearly 2,000 Claude Code sessions and $20,000 in API costs&lt;p&gt;It may build, but does it boot (was also a significant and distinct next milestone)? (Also, will it blend?). Looks like yes!&lt;p&gt;&gt; The 100,000-line compiler can build a bootable Linux 6.9 on x86, ARM, and RISC-V.&lt;p&gt;The next milestone is:&lt;p&gt;Is the generated code correct? The jury is still out on that one for production compilers. And then you have performance of generated code.&lt;p&gt;&gt; The generated code is not very efficient. Even with all optimizations enabled, it outputs less efficient code than GCC with all optimizations disabled.&lt;p&gt;Still a really cool project!&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 21:41:17 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46905771</link><dc:creator>ndesaulniers</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46905771</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46905771</guid></item><item><title>New comment by ck_one in "Claude Opus 4.6"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Just tested the new Opus 4.6 (1M context) on a fun needle-in-a-haystack challenge: finding every spell in all Harry Potter books.&lt;p&gt;All 7 books come to ~1.75M tokens, so they don't quite fit yet. (At this rate of progress, mid-April should do it ) For now you can fit the first 4 books (~733K tokens).&lt;p&gt;Results: Opus 4.6 found 49 out of 50 officially documented spells across those 4 books. The only miss was "Slugulus Eructo" (a vomiting spell).&lt;p&gt;Freaking impressive!&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 21:38:32 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46905735</link><dc:creator>ck_one</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46905735</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46905735</guid></item><item><title>New comment by rchaud in "LinkedIn checks for 2953 browser extensions"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;And they said that using a browser with sub-5%  market share would cause us to miss out on the latest and greatest in web technology!&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 21:24:48 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46905566</link><dc:creator>rchaud</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46905566</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46905566</guid></item><item><title>New comment by cbsks in "LinkedIn checks for 2953 browser extensions"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Looks like Firefox is immune.&lt;p&gt;This works by looking for web accessible resources that are provided by the extensions. For Chrome, these are are available in a webpage via the URL chrome-extension://[PACKAGE ID]/[PATH] &lt;a href="https://developer.chrome.com/docs/extensions/reference/manifest/web-accessible-resources" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://developer.chrome.com/docs/extensions/reference/manif...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;On Firefox, web accessible resources are available at "moz-extension://&lt;extension-UUID&gt;/myfile.png" &lt;extension-UUID&gt; is not your extension's ID. This ID is randomly generated for every browser instance. This prevents websites from fingerprinting a browser by examining the extensions it has installed. &lt;a href="https://developer.mozilla.org/en-US/docs/Mozilla/Add-ons/WebExtensions/manifest.json/web_accessible_resources" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://developer.mozilla.org/en-US/docs/Mozilla/Add-ons/Web...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 20:58:05 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46905200</link><dc:creator>cbsks</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46905200</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46905200</guid></item><item><title>New comment by ian_d in "Flock CEO calls Deflock a “terrorist organization” (2025) [video]"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Mountain View recently turned off their Flock installs after they discovered Flock had enabled data sharing without notice and other agencies were searching through MV data.&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.malwarebytes.com/blog/privacy/2026/02/flock-cameras-shared-license-plate-data-without-permission" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://www.malwarebytes.com/blog/privacy/2026/02/flock-came...&lt;/a&gt;
&gt; A separate “statewide lookup” feature had also been active on 29 of the city’s 30 cameras since the initial installation, running for 17 straight months until Mountain View found and disabled it on January 5. Through that tool, more than 250 agencies that had never signed any data agreement with Mountain View ran an estimated 600,000 searches over a single year, according to local paper the Mountain View Voice, which first uncovered the issue after filing a public records request.&lt;p&gt;A different town (Staunton, VA) also turned of their Flock installs after their CEO sent out an email claming:&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.aclu.org/news/privacy-technology/flock-ceo-goes-ballistic" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://www.aclu.org/news/privacy-technology/flock-ceo-goes-...&lt;/a&gt;
&gt; The attacks aren't new. You've been dealing with this for forever, and we've been dealing with this since our founding, from the same activist groups who want to defund the police, weaken public safety, and normalize lawlessness. Now, they're producing YouTube videos with misleading headlines.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 20:53:54 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46905139</link><dc:creator>ian_d</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46905139</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46905139</guid></item><item><title>New comment by toomanyrichies in "Flock CEO calls Deflock a “terrorist organization” (2025) [video]"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;"Thankfully, we live in a beautifully democratic and capitalistic society where we can fight in court."&lt;p&gt;Of course he's "thankful" for that, since in our "beautifully democratic and capitalistic" society, Flock can use their $658 million of VC funding [1] to wage lawfare against the have-nots with their armies of lobbyists and lawyers. [2]&lt;p&gt;1. &lt;a href="https://websets.exa.ai/websets/directory/flock-safety-funding"&gt;https://websets.exa.ai/websets/directory/flock-safety-fundin...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;2. &lt;a href="https://www.opensecrets.org/federal-lobbying/clients/lobbyists?cycle=2025&amp;id=D000116304" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://www.opensecrets.org/federal-lobbying/clients/lobbyis...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 20:12:15 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46904525</link><dc:creator>toomanyrichies</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46904525</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46904525</guid></item><item><title>New comment by tedsanders in "Claude Opus 4.6"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;We don't vary our model quality with time of day or load (beyond negligible non-determinism). It's the same weights all day long with no quantization or other gimmicks. They can get slower under heavy load, though.&lt;p&gt;(I'm from OpenAI.)&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 20:09:42 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46904493</link><dc:creator>tedsanders</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46904493</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46904493</guid></item><item><title>New comment by Rperry2174 in "GPT-5.3-Codex"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Whats interesting to me is that these gpt-5.3 and opus-4.6 are diverging philosophically and really in the same way that actual engineers and orgs have diverged philosophically&lt;p&gt;With Codex (5.3), the framing is an interactive collaborator: you steer it mid-execution, stay in the loop, course-correct as it works.&lt;p&gt;With Opus 4.6, the emphasis is the opposite: a more autonomous, agentic, thoughtful system that plans deeply, runs longer, and asks less of the human.&lt;p&gt;that feels like a reflection of a real split in how people think llm-based coding should work...&lt;p&gt;some want tight human-in-the-loop control and others want to delegate whole chunks of work and review the result&lt;p&gt;Interested to see if we eventually see models optimize for those two philosophies and 3rd, 4th, 5th philosophies that will emerge in the coming years.&lt;p&gt;Maybe it will be less about benchmarks and more about different ideas of what working-with-ai means&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 20:01:26 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46904367</link><dc:creator>Rperry2174</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46904367</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46904367</guid></item><item><title>New comment by tylerchilds in "Flock CEO calls Deflock a “terrorist organization” (2025) [video]"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Pointing cameras at people? Law and order&lt;p&gt;Pointing cameras at cameras? Terrorist organization&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 19:43:44 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46904105</link><dc:creator>tylerchilds</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46904105</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46904105</guid></item><item><title>New comment by geraneum in "We tasked Opus 4.6 using agent teams to build a C Compiler"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&gt; This was a clean-room implementation&lt;p&gt;This is really pushing it, considering it’s trained on… internet, with all available c compilers. The work is already impressive enough, no need for such misleading statements.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 19:39:38 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46904041</link><dc:creator>geraneum</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46904041</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46904041</guid></item><item><title>New comment by rationalist in "Flock CEO calls Deflock a “terrorist organization” (2025) [video]"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Wow...&lt;p&gt;"...and then unfortunately there is terroristic organizations like DeFlock, whose primary motivation is chaos.  They are closer to Antifa than they are anything else."&lt;p&gt;"We're not forcing Flock on anyone..."&lt;p&gt;It is a short 1:32 video, I encourage people to watch it for themselves.&lt;p&gt;I thought DeFlock was just publishing locations of cameras and lawfully convincing local governments to not use Flock, primarily through FOIA requests.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 19:35:34 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46903996</link><dc:creator>rationalist</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46903996</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46903996</guid></item><item><title>New comment by NitpickLawyer in "We tasked Opus 4.6 using agent teams to build a C Compiler"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;This is a much more reasonable take than the cursor-browser thing. A few things that make it pretty impressive:&lt;p&gt;&gt; This was a clean-room implementation (Claude did not have internet access at any point during its development); it depends only on the Rust standard library. The 100,000-line compiler can build Linux 6.9 on x86, ARM, and RISC-V. It can also compile QEMU, FFmpeg, SQlite, postgres, redis&lt;p&gt;&gt;  I started by drafting what I wanted: a from-scratch optimizing compiler with no dependencies, GCC-compatible, able to compile the Linux kernel, and designed to support multiple backends. While I specified some aspects of the design (e.g., that it should have an SSA IR to enable multiple optimization passes) I did not go into any detail on how to do so.&lt;p&gt;&gt; Previous Opus 4 models were barely capable of producing a functional compiler. Opus 4.5 was the first to cross a threshold that allowed it to produce a functional compiler which could pass large test suites, but it was still incapable of compiling any real large projects.&lt;p&gt;And the very open points about limitations (and hacks, as cc loves hacks):&lt;p&gt;&gt; It lacks the 16-bit x86 compiler that is necessary to boot [...] Opus was unable to implement a 16-bit x86 code generator needed to boot into 16-bit real mode. While the compiler can output correct 16-bit x86 via the 66/67 opcode prefixes, the resulting compiled output is over 60kb, far exceeding the 32k code limit enforced by Linux. Instead, Claude simply cheats here and calls out to GCC for this phase&lt;p&gt;&gt; It does not have its own assembler and linker;&lt;p&gt;&gt; Even with all optimizations enabled, it outputs less efficient code than GCC with all optimizations disabled.&lt;p&gt;Ending with a very down to earth take:&lt;p&gt;&gt; The resulting compiler has nearly reached the limits of Opus’s abilities. I tried (hard!) to fix several of the above limitations but wasn’t fully successful. New features and bugfixes frequently broke existing functionality.&lt;p&gt;All in all, I'd say it's a cool little experiment, impressive even with the limitations, and a good test-case as the author says "The resulting compiler has nearly reached the limits of Opus’s abilities". Yeah, that's fair, but still highly imrpessive IMO.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 19:28:13 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46903907</link><dc:creator>NitpickLawyer</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46903907</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46903907</guid></item><item><title>New comment by clintfred in "CIA suddenly stops publishing, removes archives of The World Factbook"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Facts are the enemy.&lt;p&gt;I remember reading books like 1984 and Fahrenheit 451 as a teen thinking, "Cool story, but the US will never look like that." Oof.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 18:31:09 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46903021</link><dc:creator>clintfred</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46903021</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46903021</guid></item><item><title>New comment by gizmodo59 in "Claude Opus 4.6"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;5.3 codex &lt;a href="https://openai.com/index/introducing-gpt-5-3-codex/" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://openai.com/index/introducing-gpt-5-3-codex/&lt;/a&gt; crushes with a 77.3% in Terminal Bench. The shortest lived lead in less than 35 minutes. What a time to be alive!&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 18:14:01 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46902729</link><dc:creator>gizmodo59</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46902729</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46902729</guid></item><item><title>New comment by granzymes in "GPT-5.3-Codex"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I think Anthropic rushed out the release before 10am this morning to avoid having to put in comparisons to GPT-5.3-codex!&lt;p&gt;The new Opus 4.6 scores 65.4 on Terminal-Bench 2.0, up from 64.7 from GPT-5.2-codex.&lt;p&gt;GPT-5.3-codex scores 77.3.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 18:12:39 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46902712</link><dc:creator>granzymes</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46902712</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46902712</guid></item><item><title>New comment by simonw in "Claude Opus 4.6"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;The bicycle frame is a bit wonky but the pelican itself is great: &lt;a href="https://gist.github.com/simonw/a6806ce41b4c721e240a4548ecdbe216?permalink_comment_id=5972110#gistcomment-5972110" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://gist.github.com/simonw/a6806ce41b4c721e240a4548ecdbe...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 17:58:52 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46902495</link><dc:creator>simonw</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46902495</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46902495</guid></item><item><title>New comment by GenerocUsername in "Claude Opus 4.6"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;This is huge. It only came out 8 minutes ago but I was already able to bootstrap a 12k per month revenue SaaS startup!&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 17:50:06 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46902369</link><dc:creator>GenerocUsername</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46902369</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46902369</guid></item><item><title>New comment by adamcharnock in "Don't rent the cloud, own instead"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;This is an industry we're[0] in. Owning is at one end of the spectrum, with cloud at the other, and a broadly couple of options in-between:&lt;p&gt;1 - Cloud – This is minimising cap-ex, hiring, and risk, while largely maximising operational costs (its expensive) and cost variability (usage based).&lt;p&gt;2 - Managed Private Cloud - What we do. Still minimal-to-no cap-ex, hiring, risk, and medium-sized operational cost (around 50% cheaper than AWS et al). We rent or colocate bare metal, manage it for you, handle software deployments, deploy only open-source, etc. Only really makes sense above €$5k/month spend.&lt;p&gt;3 - Rented Bare Metal – Let someone else handle the hardware financing for you. Still minimal cap-ex, but with greater hiring/skilling and risk. Around 90% cheaper than AWS et al (plus time).&lt;p&gt;4 - Buy and colocate the hardware yourself – Certainly the cheapest option if you have the skills, scale, cap-ex, and if you plan to run the servers for at least 3-5 years.&lt;p&gt;A good provider for option 3 is someone like Hetzner. Their internal ROI on server hardware seems to be around the 3 year mark. After which I assume it is either still running with a client, or goes into their server auction system.&lt;p&gt;Options 3 &amp; 4 generally become more appealing either at scale, or when infrastructure is part of the core business. Option 1 is great for startups who want to spend very little initially, but then grow very quickly. Option 2 is pretty good for SMEs with baseline load, regular-sized business growth, and maybe an overworked DevOps team!&lt;p&gt;[0] &lt;a href="https://lithus.eu" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://lithus.eu&lt;/a&gt;, adam@&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 08:57:13 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46897416</link><dc:creator>adamcharnock</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46897416</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46897416</guid></item><item><title>New comment by Stratoscope in "Why more companies are recognizing the benefits of keeping older employees"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Many years ago, I worked at a company with a product that ran on Mac and Windows. The Mac version was pretty solid, but the Windows version had some problems.&lt;p&gt;They had a talented team of developers who were mostly Mac experts and just starting to get a grip on Windows.&lt;p&gt;I was known at the time as a "Windows expert", so they hired me to help the team get the Windows version into shape.&lt;p&gt;My typical day started with "house calls". People would ping me with their Windows questions and I'd go door to door to help solve them - &lt;i&gt;and&lt;/i&gt; to make sure they understood how to do things on Windows.&lt;p&gt;In the afternoon, I would work on my own code, but I told everyone they could always call on me for help with a Windows problem, any time of day.&lt;p&gt;One colleague asked me: "Mike, how can you afford to be so generous with your time?"&lt;p&gt;Then in a performance review, I got this feedback:&lt;p&gt;"Mike, we're worried. Your productivity has been OK lately, but not great. And it's surprising, because the productivity of the rest of the team has improved a &lt;i&gt;lot&lt;/i&gt; during this time."&lt;p&gt;I bit my tongue, but in retrospect I should have said:&lt;p&gt;"Isn't that what you hired me for?"&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 05:51:21 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46896158</link><dc:creator>Stratoscope</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46896158</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46896158</guid></item><item><title>New comment by doctoboggan in "ICE seeks industry input on ad tech location data for investigative use"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Hopefully this is a wakeup call to the software engineers and other employees at those companies - it's no longer a hypothetical future where the tools you are building might be abused, it's today.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 05:33:23 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46896048</link><dc:creator>doctoboggan</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46896048</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46896048</guid></item><item><title>New comment by FeteCommuniste in "Child prodigies rarely become elite performers"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&gt; Around 90% of superstar adults had not been superstars as children, while only 10% of top-level kids had gone on to become exceptional adults (see chart 1). It is not just that exceptional performance in childhood did not predict exceptional performance as an adult. The two were actually negatively correlated, says Dr Güllich.&lt;p&gt;Even if "only" 10% of elite kids go on to become elite adults, 10% is orders of magnitude larger than the base percentage of adults who are elite athletes, musicians, etc. This doesn't sound "uncorrelated" to me so much as "not as strongly correlated as one might expect."&lt;p&gt;And describing something that happens 10% of the time as "rare" sounds a bit weird, like referring to left-handedness (also about 1 in 10) as rare.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 04:04:10 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46895551</link><dc:creator>FeteCommuniste</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46895551</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46895551</guid></item><item><title>New comment by rr808 in "Why more companies are recognizing the benefits of keeping older employees"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I'm now in my 50s. I tried management but prefer working as an IC. I think I'm good but I know most companies would never hire me. One thing I do now is try to look after all the youngest grads and new joiners. Its so cutthroat now it seems no one has time to help anyone else, so I like helping people get up and running and encouraging them to enjoy their work while being productive and getting their skills up. No one else seems to care.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 04:04:06 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46895550</link><dc:creator>rr808</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46895550</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46895550</guid></item><item><title>New comment by kstrauser in "AI is killing B2B SaaS"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;OTOH, I was hired by an enterprise that was many months into a giant backend rewrite. After wrapping my head around the many plans, I realized they were rewriting Django, badly. One weekend I prototyped the whole thing… in Django. It worked. It met the specs. It was a CRUD app with a REST API.&lt;p&gt;I came in to work Monday morning, showed it off, and inadvertently triggered a firestorm. Later my boss told me not to do that again because it caused havoc with schedules and such.&lt;p&gt;So I quit and found a better job. Sometimes the new guy can make a better version themselves over the weekend, not because they’re a supergenius, but because they’re not hampered by 47 teams all trying to get their stamp on the project.&lt;p&gt;(In before “prime example of overconfidence!”: feel free to doubt. It was a CRUD app with a handful of models on a PostgreSQL backend. They were writing a new Python web framework to serve it, complete with their own ORM and forms library and validation library. Not because the existing ones wouldn’t work, mind you, but more out of not realizing that all these problems were already sufficiently solved for their requirements.)&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 02:33:55 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46894917</link><dc:creator>kstrauser</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46894917</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46894917</guid></item><item><title>New comment by huwsername in "OpenClaw is what Apple intelligence should have been"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I don’t believe this was ever confirmed by Apple, but there was widespread speculation at the time[1] that the delay was due to the very prompt injection attacks OpenClaw users are now discovering. It would be genuinely catastrophic to ship an insecure system with this kind of data access, even with an ‘unsafe mode’.&lt;p&gt;These kinds of risks can only be _consented to_ by technical people who correctly understand them, let alone borne by them, but if this shipped there would be thousands of Facebook videos explaining to the elderly how to disable the safety features and open themselves up to identity theft.&lt;p&gt;The article also confuses me because Apple _are_ shipping this, it’s pretty much exactly the demo they gave at WWDC24, it’s just delayed while they iron this out (if that is at all possible). By all accounts it might ship as early as next week in the iOS 26.4 beta.&lt;p&gt;[1]: &lt;a href="https://simonwillison.net/2025/Mar/8/delaying-personalized-siri/" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://simonwillison.net/2025/Mar/8/delaying-personalized-s...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 01:52:10 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46894613</link><dc:creator>huwsername</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46894613</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46894613</guid></item></channel></rss>