<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>Hacker News: Best Comments</title><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/bestcomments</link><description>Hacker News RSS</description><docs>https://hnrss.org/</docs><generator>hnrss v2.1.1</generator><lastBuildDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2025 00:10:49 +0000</lastBuildDate><ns0:link href="https://hnrss.org/bestcomments" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item><title>New comment by strix_varius in "The Programmer Identity Crisis"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;To me, the most salient point was this:&lt;p&gt;&gt; Code reviewing coworkers are rapidly losing their minds as they come to the crushing realization that they are now the first layer of quality control instead of one of the last. Asked to review; forced to pick apart. Calling out freshly added functions that are never called, hallucinated library additions, and obvious runtime or compilation errors. All while the author—who clearly only skimmed their “own” code—is taking no responsibility, going “whoopsie, Claude wrote that. Silly AI, ha-ha.”&lt;p&gt;LLMs have made Brandolini's law ("The amount of energy needed to refute bullshit is an order of magnitude larger than to produce it") perhaps understated. When an inexperienced or just inexpert developer can generate thousands of lines of code in minutes, the responsibility for keeping a system correct &amp; sane gets offloaded to the reviewers who still know how to reason with human intelligence.&lt;p&gt;As a litmus test, look at a PR's added/removed LoC delta. LLM-written ones are almost entirely additive, whereas good senior engineers often remove as much code as they add.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 21 Oct 2025 18:44:36 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45659881</link><dc:creator>strix_varius</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45659881</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45659881</guid></item><item><title>New comment by jsheard in "Fallout from the AWS outage: Smart mattresses go rogue"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Tech enthusiasts: My entire house is smart.&lt;p&gt;Tech workers: The only piece of technology in my house is a printer and I keep a gun next to it so I can shoot it if it makes a noise I don't recognize.&lt;p&gt;(stolen from @PPathole on Twitter)&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 21 Oct 2025 17:17:10 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45658464</link><dc:creator>jsheard</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45658464</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45658464</guid></item><item><title>New comment by goda90 in "Fallout from the AWS outage: Smart mattresses go rogue"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I feel like we need some sort of "Offline-First" or "Offline-Compatible" certification process for "smart" devices. It would require some threshold of usability and total safety without network connection, which would vary depending on the device category. Companies in compliance could put a badge on their products so wary consumers know who to trust.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 21 Oct 2025 17:03:07 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45658256</link><dc:creator>goda90</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45658256</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45658256</guid></item><item><title>New comment by teddyh in "Public trust demands open-source voting systems"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;No.  Public trust demands &lt;i&gt;no software or programmable hardware&lt;/i&gt; in the election process.&lt;p&gt;• Why Electronic Voting is a BAD Idea &lt;&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=w3_0x6oaDmI" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=w3_0x6oaDmI&lt;/a&gt;&gt;&lt;p&gt;• Why Electronic Voting Is Still A Bad Idea &lt;&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=LkH2r-sNjQs" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=LkH2r-sNjQs&lt;/a&gt;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 21 Oct 2025 16:57:22 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45658161</link><dc:creator>teddyh</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45658161</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45658161</guid></item><item><title>New comment by Someone in "Tesla is heading into multi-billion-dollar iceberg of its own making"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;FRA: &lt;i&gt;“As for HW3 owners who bought FSD, which basically turned out to be an interest free loan to Tesla for years, the automaker needs to offer free FSD transfer and a $10,000 discount on a car upgrade.&lt;p&gt;While this might sound like a lot”&lt;/i&gt;&lt;p&gt;It would add up to a lot of money for Tesla, but for customers? Some of these people paid $15.000 years ago for something that hasn’t been delivered, and now, they would be able to get $10,000 ‘back’, only if they commit to spending way more again, in the hope to eventually get what they &lt;i&gt;bought&lt;/i&gt; years ago, or, more likely, in the hope of eventually being able to &lt;i&gt;subscribe&lt;/i&gt; to get the features they already paid for years ago.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 21 Oct 2025 11:56:12 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45654747</link><dc:creator>Someone</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45654747</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45654747</guid></item><item><title>New comment by rester324 in "Today is when the Amazon brain drain sent AWS down the spout"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;It seems amazon itself is aware of this issue. The linked engadget article even mentions this:&lt;p&gt;&gt; "The rate at which Amazon has burned through the American working-age populace led to another piece of internal research, obtained this summer by Recode, which cautioned that the company might “deplete the available labor supply in the US” in certain metro regions within a few years."&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 21 Oct 2025 04:04:31 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45652376</link><dc:creator>rester324</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45652376</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45652376</guid></item><item><title>New comment by irjustin in "Wikipedia says traffic is falling due to AI search summaries and social video"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I'll go out on a limb and say we _need_ Wikipedia and it's okay that traffic falls.&lt;p&gt;Physical print encyclopedias got replaced by Wikipedia, but AI isn't a replacement (can't ever see how either). While AI is a method of easier access for the end user, the purpose of Wikipedia stands on its own.&lt;p&gt;I've always scoffed at the Wikimedia Foundation's warchest and continuously increasing annual spending. I say now is the time to save money. Become self sustaining through investments so it can live for 1000 years.&lt;p&gt;To me, it is an existence for the common good and should be governed as such.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 21 Oct 2025 02:34:18 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45651834</link><dc:creator>irjustin</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45651834</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45651834</guid></item><item><title>New comment by president_zippy in "Today is when the Amazon brain drain sent AWS down the spout"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I like to think I'm halfway decent at my job, and I wouldn't work there once. During undergrad, my landlord working for AMZN on the opposite end of the country offered me an interview, but it was during final exam week.&lt;p&gt;I asked if I could schedule the interview after my final exams, and his arrogance really showed when not only did he refuse, but then insisted my exams are not don't even register on the same scale of importance as the opportunity to work for Amazon.&lt;p&gt;Somewhat related: a recruiter at Google cold-called me a couple months into my first job out of undergrad back in 2016 and was similarly condescending about "the chance" to work for Google compared to everything else. I already had a low opinion of them when they gave my then-girlfriend an introductory O'Reilly book on Java after she failed their interview.&lt;p&gt;I regret being born too late to work somewhere like Bell Labs, SGI, or Sun. I had a ton of graybeard wizard coworkers from these places, and they were all a pleasure to learn from and even better friends. For the first 2 years of my first job, every day of work was like walking into the Shire and talking magic spells with 20 Gandalfs.&lt;p&gt;That job was great until I got put on a team with a guy who was a former middle manager at some IBM-like company and went from being surrounded by people lightyears ahead of me to being surrounded by Dilbert characters. The messed-up part was that it wasn't even punishment. I was rewarded after completing a project with my choice of which team I joined next, and I joined the wrong one. I assumed that joining a new team to utilize this newfangled "cloud computing" thing would be trailblazing, and I didn't do any diligence on who I would work with.&lt;p&gt;To this day, I still regret not rejoining the first team I worked for, otherwise I would still be at that company and happy about it. Then again, the boredom and discontent while being on that sucky team is the reason I started investing, and now I can buy a house in cash and fund myself to do whatever I want for at least a decade. Hard to complain about the way things turned out.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 21 Oct 2025 00:15:41 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45651013</link><dc:creator>president_zippy</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45651013</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45651013</guid></item><item><title>New comment by president_zippy in "Today is when the Amazon brain drain sent AWS down the spout"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Between the engineering staff and the warehouse workers, I wonder how long it will be until they have already fired everyone who ever would have been willing to work there.&lt;p&gt;Even with candidate pools of hundreds of thousands of H1-B engineers and tens of millions of illegal immigrant warehouse workers, there still comes a point where such a big company firing so many people so quickly exhausts all their options.&lt;p&gt;It reminds me of the Robot Chicken Sketch where Imperial Officers aboard the Death Star all pretend to be force choked to death by Darth Vader so they can avoid getting killed by lightsaber, then come back in under different names in different jobs. It's worse though for Amazon: nobody wants to come back.&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=fFihTRIxCkg" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=fFihTRIxCkg&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 20 Oct 2025 23:51:51 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45650861</link><dc:creator>president_zippy</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45650861</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45650861</guid></item><item><title>New comment by didgeoridoo in "The scariest "user support" email I've received"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I can’t even exfiltrate my MacOS Notes on &lt;i&gt;purpose&lt;/i&gt;. Maybe I’ll download it and give it a spin.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 20 Oct 2025 22:42:24 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45650356</link><dc:creator>didgeoridoo</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45650356</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45650356</guid></item><item><title>New comment by CaptainOfCoit in "Postman which I thought worked locally on my computer, is down"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I remember when one of the "Core Goals" of Postman was "Complete control over your data - Keep simple JSON based data formats which can be exported and shared as per user needs".&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://web.archive.org/web/20140604204111/http://www.getpostman.com/docs/" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://web.archive.org/web/20140604204111/http://www.getpos...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 20 Oct 2025 22:36:46 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45650305</link><dc:creator>CaptainOfCoit</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45650305</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45650305</guid></item><item><title>New comment by tantalor in "The scariest "user support" email I've received"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&gt; as ChatGPT confirmed when I asked it to analyze it&lt;p&gt;lol we are so cooked&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 20 Oct 2025 21:36:00 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45649704</link><dc:creator>tantalor</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45649704</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45649704</guid></item><item><title>New comment by Someone1234 in "When a stadium adds AI to everything, it's worse experience for everyone"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I was recently at an events center, that has replaced all of their vending machines with machines that require me to install an app(!) to purchase a product. Literally, didn't take cash or credit - just via app.&lt;p&gt;Per the marketing on the side, this is meant to be for my &lt;i&gt;benefit&lt;/i&gt; in order to earn "points" and get offered "deals." I don't think I have to tell you that I did NOT install the app, and just walked further to buy one from a vendor.&lt;p&gt;There is a massive arrogance problem within tech. Everyone thinks their product should be the center of everyone else's universe. The best products are invisible/get out of the way.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 20 Oct 2025 20:34:41 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45648954</link><dc:creator>Someone1234</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45648954</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45648954</guid></item><item><title>New comment by gschier in "Postman which I thought worked locally on my computer, is down"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;This is exactly why I made Yaak [1]. It's fully offline, no telemetry, open source, and can even sync with Git.&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://yaak.app" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://yaak.app&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 20 Oct 2025 20:27:53 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45648871</link><dc:creator>gschier</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45648871</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45648871</guid></item><item><title>New comment by seanhunter in "J.P. Morgan's OpenAI loan is strange"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;What a weird analysis.&lt;p&gt;A company that has revenues and is extremely well-capitalized gets debt finance. That is not news. That is totally commonplace. "Shouldn't all their capital come from investors?" No. Companies at all stages typically use a mixture of debt and equity finance.&lt;p&gt;His EV calculation is completely flawed also.  Debt finance is typically senior to equity in recovery at bankruptcy, so when JPMC do this analysis (and believe me they did this analysis) they are not assuming 0% recovery. They are thinking it is most likely in a bankruptcy that they get some x&gt;0% recovery.&lt;p&gt;Finally, banks don't think about their relationship with a multi-billion-dollar company in terms of the ROI on a single revolving credit. (even though this will in all likelihood be very profitable for JPMC). They think about how giving this revolving credit makes it more likely they get advisory on any future bond issuance and I-banking work when OpenAI want to do takeovers, and a foot in the door at IPO time etc.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 20 Oct 2025 20:06:27 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45648617</link><dc:creator>seanhunter</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45648617</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45648617</guid></item><item><title>New comment by 0x5345414e in "AWS multiple services outage in us-east-1"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;This is having a direct impact on my wellbeing. I was at Whole Foods in Hudson Yards NYC and I couldn’t get the prime discount on my chocolate bar because the system isn’t working. Decided not to get the chocolate bar. Now my chocolate levels are way too low.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 20 Oct 2025 18:04:41 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45647080</link><dc:creator>0x5345414e</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45647080</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45647080</guid></item><item><title>New comment by rdtsc in "AWS multiple services outage in us-east-1"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;9s don’t have to drop if you increase the time period! “We still guarantee the same 9s just over 3450 years now”.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 20 Oct 2025 17:44:32 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45646824</link><dc:creator>rdtsc</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45646824</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45646824</guid></item><item><title>New comment by indoordin0saur in "AWS multiple services outage in us-east-1"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Seems like major issues are still ongoing. If anything it seems &lt;i&gt;worse&lt;/i&gt; than it did ~4 hours ago. For reference I'm a data engineer and it's Redshift and Airflow (AWS managed) that is FUBAR for me.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 20 Oct 2025 16:31:11 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45645786</link><dc:creator>indoordin0saur</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45645786</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45645786</guid></item><item><title>New comment by time0ut in "AWS multiple services outage in us-east-1"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Interesting day. I've been on an incident bridge since 3AM. Our systems have mostly recovered now with a few back office stragglers fighting for compute.&lt;p&gt;The biggest miss on our side is that, although we designed a multi-region capable application, we could not run the failover process because our security org migrated us to Identity Center and only put it in us-east-1, hard locking the entire company out of the AWS control plane. By the time we'd gotten the root credentials out of the vault, things were coming back up.&lt;p&gt;Good reminder that you are only as strong as your weakest link.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 20 Oct 2025 13:44:18 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45643848</link><dc:creator>time0ut</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45643848</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45643848</guid></item><item><title>New comment by jvanderbot in "Space Elevator"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Very cool. One thing I wish was better shown: space is close, it's just hard to go up. Our liveable breathable atmosphere is razor thin compared to the size of earth.&lt;p&gt;In most cases, 100km is less than the distance between sizeable metropolitan areas. It's a day long bike ride. Air runs out less than a bus ride across town.  A 15k jog/hike would put you in the stratosphere. Those jet aircraft that seem so high are closer than that. Closer than your friends house or the local stadium probably.&lt;p&gt;Look at a map or globe with that in mind and everything feels so thin!&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 20 Oct 2025 13:03:32 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45643427</link><dc:creator>jvanderbot</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45643427</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45643427</guid></item><item><title>New comment by JCM9 in "AWS multiple services outage in us-east-1"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;US-East-1 is more than just a normal region. It also provides the backbone for other services, including those in other regions. Thus simply being in another region doesn’t protect you from the consistent us-east-1 shenanigans.&lt;p&gt;AWS doesn’t talk about that much publicly, but if you press them they will admit in private that there are some pretty nasty single points of failure in the design of AWS that can materialize if us-east-1 has an issue. Most people would say that means AWS isn’t truly multi-region in some areas.&lt;p&gt;Not entirely clear yet if those single points of failure were at play here, but risk mitigation isn’t as simple as just “don’t use us-east-1” or “deploy in multiple regions with load balancing failover.”&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 20 Oct 2025 12:45:59 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45643276</link><dc:creator>JCM9</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45643276</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45643276</guid></item><item><title>New comment by miki123211 in "DeepSeek OCR"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Text tokens are quantized and represent subword units, vision tokens only exist in the embedding space.&lt;p&gt;The way text tokenization works in LLMs is that you have a "lookup table" of (small) token ids to (large) vector embeddings. To pass text to the LLM, you split it at token boundaries, convert strings to token ids, and then construct the "context", a matrix where each row is a vector taken from that lookup table.&lt;p&gt;Transmitting text token sequences can be relatively efficient, you just transmit the token IDs themselves[1]. They're small integers (~100k possible token ids is typical for large models). Transmitting the actual embeddings matrix would be far less efficient, as embeddings often consist of thousands of floating point numbers.&lt;p&gt;Images are encoded differently. After some basic preprocessing, image data is passed straight to a neural- network-based image encoder. That encoder encodes the image into vectors, which are then appended to the context. There are no token ids, there's no lookup table, we go straight from image data to token embeddings.&lt;p&gt;This means transmitting image tokens cannot be done as efficiently, as you'd have to transmit the embeddings themselves. Even though an image is encoded in fewer tokens, the most efficient representation of those tokens takes more bytes.&lt;p&gt;You can think of a text token as an integer between 0 and n, which we know how to map to a vector. This means you have `n` possible choices of tokens. In contrast, an image token is an array of m floating point numbers (the vector itself), each of which can take on many possible values. This means the "token space" of vision tokens is actually much larger.&lt;p&gt;There's also the issue of patterns. Text tokens correspond directly to a contiguous span of UTF-8 bytes, and most tokenizers won't create tokens that span word boundaries. This means they can't encode global patterns efficiently. You can't have a "Hamlet's monologue" or "the text that follows is in Spanish" token.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 20 Oct 2025 11:13:17 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45642598</link><dc:creator>miki123211</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45642598</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45642598</guid></item><item><title>New comment by padjo in "AWS multiple services outage in us-east-1"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Planning for an AWS outage is a complete waste of time and energy for most companies. Yes it does happen but very rarely to the tune of a few hours every 5-10 years. I can almost guarantee that whatever plans you have won’t get you fully operational faster than just waiting for AWS to fix it.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 20 Oct 2025 10:13:38 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45642182</link><dc:creator>padjo</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45642182</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45642182</guid></item><item><title>New comment by JCM9 in "AWS multiple services outage in us-east-1"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Have a meeting today with our AWS account team about how we’re no longer going to be “All in on AWS” as we diversify workloads away. Was mostly about the pace of innovation on core services slowing and AWS being too far behind on AI services so we’re buying those from elsewhere.&lt;p&gt;The AWS team keeps touting the rock solid reliability of AWS as a reason why we shouldn’t diversify our cloud. Should be a fun meeting!&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 20 Oct 2025 10:09:16 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45642146</link><dc:creator>JCM9</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45642146</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45642146</guid></item><item><title>New comment by jacquesm in "AWS multiple services outage in us-east-1"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Every week or so we interview a company and ask them if they have a fall-back plan in case AWS goes down or their cloud account disappears. They always have this deer-in-the-headlights look. 'That can't happen, right?'&lt;p&gt;Now imagine for a bit that it will never come back up. See where that leads you. The internet got its main strengths from the fact that it was completely decentralized. We've been systematically eroding that strength.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 20 Oct 2025 10:05:03 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45642107</link><dc:creator>jacquesm</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45642107</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45642107</guid></item><item><title>New comment by jpalomaki in "AWS multiple services outage in us-east-1"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;When AWS is down, everybody knows it. People don’t really question your hosting choice. It’s the IBM of cloud era.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 20 Oct 2025 09:13:07 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45641689</link><dc:creator>jpalomaki</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45641689</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45641689</guid></item><item><title>New comment by stepri in "AWS multiple services outage in us-east-1"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;“Based on our investigation, the issue appears to be related to DNS resolution of the DynamoDB API endpoint in US-EAST-1. We are working on multiple parallel paths to accelerate recovery.”&lt;p&gt;It’s always DNS.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 20 Oct 2025 09:07:40 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45641627</link><dc:creator>stepri</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45641627</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45641627</guid></item><item><title>New comment by littlecranky67 in "AWS multiple services outage in us-east-1"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Just a couple of days ago in this HN thread [0] there were quite some users claiming Hetzner is not an options as their uptime isn't as good as AWS, hence the higher AWS pricing is worth the investment. Oh, the irony.&lt;p&gt;[0]: &lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45614922"&gt;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45614922&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 20 Oct 2025 09:07:19 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45641625</link><dc:creator>littlecranky67</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45641625</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45641625</guid></item><item><title>New comment by amadeoeoeo in "AWS multiple services outage in us-east-1"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Oh no... may be LaLiga found out pirates hosting on AWS?&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 20 Oct 2025 08:20:21 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45641213</link><dc:creator>amadeoeoeo</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45641213</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45641213</guid></item><item><title>New comment by nikolay in "AWS multiple services outage in us-east-1"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Choosing us-east-1 as your primary region is good, because when you're down, everybody's down, too. You don't get this luxury with other US regions!&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 20 Oct 2025 07:57:12 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45641031</link><dc:creator>nikolay</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45641031</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45641031</guid></item></channel></rss>