<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>Hacker News: Best Comments</title><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/bestcomments</link><description>Hacker News RSS</description><docs>https://hnrss.org/</docs><generator>hnrss v2.1.1</generator><lastBuildDate>Sun, 16 Nov 2025 23:47:04 +0000</lastBuildDate><ns0:link href="https://hnrss.org/bestcomments" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item><title>New comment by joshcsimmons in "Heretic: Automatic censorship removal for language models"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;This is extremely important work thank you for sharing it. We are in the process of giving up our own moral standing in favor of taking on the ones imbued into LLMs by their creators. This is a worrying trend that will totally wipe out intellectual diversity.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 16 Nov 2025 17:37:01 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45946838</link><dc:creator>joshcsimmons</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45946838</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45946838</guid></item><item><title>New comment by yousif_123123 in "Maybe you’re not trying"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I've always noticed that when I'm giving advice to someone or trying to help out, it always feels their problem is easier than whatever problem I have. As someone with some anxiety around things like calling some company to get something done or asking a random stranger for some help in a store, I would gladly do it if it was to help someone else (family member or friend). But when it's for me I find it harder.&lt;p&gt;I wonder how much psychologically we can be more confident and less anxious when we're doing something for others vs ourselves..&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 16 Nov 2025 14:02:31 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45945216</link><dc:creator>yousif_123123</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45945216</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45945216</guid></item><item><title>New comment by KaiserPro in "Anthropic’s paper smells like bullshit"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;When I worked at a  FAANG with a "world leading" AI lab (now run by a teenage data labeller) as an SRE/sysadmin I was asked to use a modified version of a foundation model which was steered towards infosec stuff.&lt;p&gt;We were asked to try and persuade it to help us hack into a mock printer/dodgy linux box.&lt;p&gt;It helped a little, but it wasn't all that helpful.&lt;p&gt;but in terms of coordination, I can't see how it would be useful.&lt;p&gt;the same for claude, you're API is tied to a bankaccount, and vibe coding a command and control system on a very public system seems like a bad choice.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 16 Nov 2025 12:33:24 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45944641</link><dc:creator>KaiserPro</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45944641</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45944641</guid></item><item><title>New comment by prinny_ in "Anthropic’s paper smells like bullshit"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;The lack of evidence before attributing the attack(s) to a Chinese sponsored group makes me correlate this report with recent statements from companies in the AI space about how China is about to surpass US in the AI race. Ultimately statements and reports like these seem more like an attempt to make the US government step in and be the big investor that keeps the money flowing rather than anything else.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 16 Nov 2025 12:29:12 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45944616</link><dc:creator>prinny_</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45944616</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45944616</guid></item><item><title>New comment by torginus in "I don’t need a Steam Machine"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;When I first saw the Arduino I didn't see the point - after all there were boards that cost less, did more, and the Arduino IDE seemed very barebones compared to what you could do with GCC and a custom toolchain.&lt;p&gt;Then eventually I saw how much community support, ready made hardware emerged around it, to the point that after a while, not going the Arduino route was a decision you needed to justify heavily.&lt;p&gt;Same thing with the Raspberry Pi - there are commercial devices now running or more or less stock Pi hardware with some accomodations - the power of the community is just too large - you can either spend an insane amount of time getting things working on your custom SBC, or get something well-supported for free.&lt;p&gt;I hope that the same thing will happen with the Steam Machine - the pull of the community will result in a well-supported 'default' device where people (and Valve) will put in the effort to create a comparable desktop experience to the commercial OSes.&lt;p&gt;Valve already helped immensely with Wayland - it's crazy to think that the project was stared cca. 2008, and today there's still arguments to be made it's not mature yet - by investing the necessary energy to make sure games run well, the drivers are optimized, and there's a high-quality end-user library (wlroots) for writing compositors has been the push that Wayland needed.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 16 Nov 2025 11:03:02 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45944161</link><dc:creator>torginus</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45944161</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45944161</guid></item><item><title>New comment by mariopt in "I don’t need a Steam Machine"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Steam Machines can become an existencial crisis for PlayStation and Xbox.&lt;p&gt;A “console” that I can use as a PC? I am in 100%. You’ll get the world biggest game library at a discount, this is why I sold my PlayStation after spending 200 euros and watching it becoming useless.&lt;p&gt;I also suspect a lot of game devs will optimize for steam machine and finally we’ll get a console like experience on PC.&lt;p&gt;Don’t let the “low specs” fool you, it has the same specs or better as 70% of steam users.&lt;p&gt;Given Valve gave money to a lot of open source maintainers , it’s also great for Linux.&lt;p&gt;Just take my money&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 16 Nov 2025 10:47:05 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45944089</link><dc:creator>mariopt</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45944089</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45944089</guid></item><item><title>New comment by xps in "AirPods libreated from Apple's ecosystem"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;They don't report battery status to non-Apple devices. This is a pretty basic feature and without this I wouldn't consider them to perform "on par" with other Bluetooth headphones.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 16 Nov 2025 10:44:55 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45944080</link><dc:creator>xps</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45944080</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45944080</guid></item><item><title>New comment by gloxkiqcza in "Hyundai Paywalls Brake Pads replacement on Ioniq 5 N"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Doesn’t really surprise me. I remember reading the article linked below from which I quote:&lt;p&gt;&gt; Forced to raise their game, carmakers are only now realizing they cannot repeat past mistakes such as letting others build up parts and services businesses off the back of their core product. "They stole the business from us," Martinet says, referencing as an example windshield replacement companies. "So I don't want them to steal the next one."&lt;p&gt;Xavier Martinet is the President and CEO of Hyundai Motor Europe.&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.wired.com/story/the-global-car-reckoning-is-here-auto-companies-dont-have-a-plan/" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://www.wired.com/story/the-global-car-reckoning-is-here...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 16 Nov 2025 08:45:46 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45943646</link><dc:creator>gloxkiqcza</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45943646</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45943646</guid></item><item><title>New comment by LarsDu88 in "Report: Tim Cook could step down as Apple CEO 'as soon as next year'"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;They shipped AirPods and the Apple Watch during his tenure. And the ahem, Vision Pro. The M-series chips are probably the biggest win for Apple in the past 15 years.&lt;p&gt;There hasn't been lack of category killers during his stint. If anything they are running out of places on the human body where you can stick a small computer.&lt;p&gt;Surely the next CEO will hopefully not ruin the company and brand by cramming ads into everything.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 16 Nov 2025 07:41:13 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45943427</link><dc:creator>LarsDu88</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45943427</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45943427</guid></item><item><title>New comment by isoprophlex in "AirPods libreated from Apple's ecosystem"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;From a bit further down the page&lt;p&gt;&gt; Bluetooth DID (Device Identification) Hook
&gt; Turns out, if you change the manufacturerid to that of Apple, you get access to several special features!&lt;p&gt;I hope Apple gets slammed hard by some regulatory body. Apparently there's absolutely zero magic reasons why their airpods are unable to connect to non-Apple devices; pretend you're an iPhone and you're in.&lt;p&gt;EDIT: read "unable to connect" =&gt; "unable to expose advanced functionality", ofc they connect just fine&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 16 Nov 2025 06:17:59 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45943174</link><dc:creator>isoprophlex</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45943174</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45943174</guid></item><item><title>New comment by jmgao in "AirPods libreated from Apple's ecosystem"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;It doesn't seem obvious to me that this is actually a bug in the Android implementation, it seems like this is due to AirPods violating the spec and requiring a special handshake before responding to standard requests. It doesn't seem reasonable to expect Android to work around a device that appears to be intentionally breaking the spec for vendor lock-in purposes: the possibility of them just OTAing an update that breaks in some other way means that you'd have to be entirely bug compatible with iOS's bluetooth implementation.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 16 Nov 2025 03:12:23 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45942451</link><dc:creator>jmgao</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45942451</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45942451</guid></item><item><title>New comment by ferd in "When did people favor composition over inheritance?"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;An important point not mentioned by the article is that of "co-recursion" with inheritance (of implementation).&lt;p&gt;That is: an instance of a subclass calls a method defined on a parent class, which in turn may call a method that's been overridden by the subclass (or even another sub-subclass in the hierarchy) and that one in turn may call another parent method, and so on. It can easily become a pinball of calls around the hierarchy.&lt;p&gt;Add to that the fact that "objects" have state, and each class in the hierarchy may add more state, and modify state declared on parents. Perfect combinatory explosion of state and control-flow complexity.&lt;p&gt;I've seen this scenario way too many times in projects, and worse thing is: many developers think it's fine... and are even proud of navigating such a mess. Heck, many popular "frameworks" encourage this.&lt;p&gt;Basically: every time you modify a class, you must review the inner implementation of all other classes in the hierarchy, and call paths to ensure your change is safe. That's a horrendous way to write software, against the most basic principles of modularity and low coupling.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 16 Nov 2025 02:15:38 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45942186</link><dc:creator>ferd</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45942186</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45942186</guid></item><item><title>New comment by JSR_FDED in "When UPS charged me a $684 tariff on $355 of vintage computer parts"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Tariffs are great. They protect the struggling domestic IT industry and gives it time to ramp up its production of vintage computer parts.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 16 Nov 2025 00:41:49 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45941785</link><dc:creator>JSR_FDED</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45941785</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45941785</guid></item><item><title>New comment by moonleay in "AirPods libreated from Apple's ecosystem"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;A cool project, when you want to use AirPods outside of Apples ecosystem. Sadly, you have to use a rooted android device with a small patch due to a bug in the Android Bluetooth implementation.
&lt;a href="https://issuetracker.google.com/issues/371713238" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://issuetracker.google.com/issues/371713238&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 16 Nov 2025 00:02:57 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45941605</link><dc:creator>moonleay</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45941605</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45941605</guid></item><item><title>New comment by ryandrake in "Report: Tim Cook could step down as Apple CEO 'as soon as next year'"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Cook's been great for massively scaling Apple (and its stock price) up, but the art, vision, and soul of the company is gone. It's just a stock price maximizing lawnmower now, just like every other corporate stock price maximizing lawnmower. If that's what shareholders want, fine, I guess. But I'd be bored just manufacturing the same boring rectangles every year. I think Steve would have been, too.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 15 Nov 2025 22:42:23 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45941163</link><dc:creator>ryandrake</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45941163</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45941163</guid></item><item><title>New comment by PinkSheep in "Our investigation into the suspicious pressure on Archive.today"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Good job on AdGuard's end for bringing this to the Internet's attention. I especially enjoyed the unearthed details about this "N"GO's short history.&lt;p&gt;I think the e-mail exchange should've been kept short, although it is good that the owner of archive.today was eventually notified (by them) about these links in good faith to remove them. Their reply should've been the following:&lt;p&gt;"&lt;i&gt;Thank you for contacting us. If you have conclusive proof of illegal behavior, you should contact police and seek legal assistance. A website's administrator is expected to adequately react to illegal actions conducted by its users, such as removing media that's breaking a law.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;We have visited the URLs provided by you (&lt;a href="https://archive[.]today/" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://archive[.]today/&lt;/a&gt; , ...) and found no evidence to corroborate your concerns. To avoid misunderstandings, we require you to send a certified mail to &lt;Adguards company address&gt; before further replies on this matter.&lt;/i&gt;"&lt;p&gt;Remember guys, it should always be certified mail (bonus points for international). And yes, I mean literal index pages as provided in the first e-mail. Play by the legal understanding of words. Be creative and break the rules to the extent of not breaking them ;)&lt;p&gt;PS: If you want to see more of "funny replies" you should read Njalla's blog (&lt;&lt;a href="https://njal.la/blog/" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://njal.la/blog/&lt;/a&gt;&gt;) and TPB's infamous e-mail replies.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 15 Nov 2025 22:04:44 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45940965</link><dc:creator>PinkSheep</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45940965</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45940965</guid></item><item><title>New comment by jayflux in "Boa: A standard-conforming embeddable JavaScript engine written in Rust"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Hi all, wow was not expecting this to be trending right now.&lt;p&gt;I’m the creator of Boa, you can catch my talk about it at JS Conf EU 2019 &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=_uD2pijcSi4" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=_uD2pijcSi4&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;That said, today Boa has a whole team of maintainers who I’m sure will answer some questions here.&lt;p&gt;Yes the name does invoke the sense it’s a Python project but I liked it and stuck with it, I saw a Boa snake at a zoo once and knew I wanted to name my next project after it, I was also inspired by Mozilla at the time who named their projects after animals.&lt;p&gt;Speaking of Mozilla, Boa’s existence came to be because at the time I was working on Servo and wanted to include an all-rust JS engine, one didn’t really exist so I set about making one as a learning exercise, after around 2 years more joined me on that journey and today Boa is around 8 years old. It is not browser grade (although at 94.12% it is more compliant than some browser engines) but that doesn’t matter, plenty of Rust projects have found good use for it as they find it easy to embed and use, so we’re happy.&lt;p&gt;One recent example is Biome who use it for their plugin infrastructure. &lt;a href="https://github.com/biomejs/biome/pull/7300" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://github.com/biomejs/biome/pull/7300&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;Another recent thing which we’re very proud is seeing our implementation of Temporal be used in V8 and other engines, so we’re also helping the wider ecosystem and raising all ships! (More here: &lt;a href="https://boajs.dev/blog/2025/09/24/temporal-release" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://boajs.dev/blog/2025/09/24/temporal-release&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;p&gt;We do hope to improve performance over the next year or so, hopefully that answers some of the Qs here.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 15 Nov 2025 19:34:48 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45939970</link><dc:creator>jayflux</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45939970</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45939970</guid></item><item><title>New comment by m417z in "Windhawk Windows classic theme mod for Windows 11"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Hi, Windhawk author here. Nice to see it on Hacker News.&lt;p&gt;This is just one Windhawk mod, submitted by a community member. There are hundreds others. Windhawk was created to simplify Windows customization and to make it more accessible, both for developers and users. For a more detailed introduction, check out the Windhawk release blog post:&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://ramensoftware.com/windhawk" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://ramensoftware.com/windhawk&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 15 Nov 2025 18:09:55 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45939328</link><dc:creator>m417z</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45939328</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45939328</guid></item><item><title>New comment by wartywhoa23 in "Our investigation into the suspicious pressure on Archive.today"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;The Ministry of Truth simply doesn't want unaccounted and uncontrolled snapshots of history. Too much hassle steering the narrative regarding any surfacing truth-now-meant-to-be-lies and vice versa into fake news territory, discrediting by association, cranking up troll farms.. Much easier to make this inconvenience disappear with the due cooperation from the controlled outlets of information.&lt;p&gt;Then they will come after our local storage, and making it prohibitively expensive is the least malign way they can come up with.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 15 Nov 2025 16:03:12 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45938303</link><dc:creator>wartywhoa23</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45938303</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45938303</guid></item><item><title>New comment by andronikos in "Our investigation into the suspicious pressure on Archive.today"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;member of DNS4EU ops team here - This was not the case, we had reachability issues with the authoritative servers of archive.is and had to reach out to the team to allow our source IPs.&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/BuyFromEU/comments/1ohekv5/updatedns4eu_is_not_blocking_archive_today/" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://www.reddit.com/r/BuyFromEU/comments/1ohekv5/updatedn...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 15 Nov 2025 15:13:00 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45937951</link><dc:creator>andronikos</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45937951</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45937951</guid></item><item><title>New comment by codedokode in "Our investigation into the suspicious pressure on Archive.today"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Note that association's site is made from this free template [1] with minimal editing (can see it using diff). The web hosting account at name.com (prices starting from $5/year) was registered around Jan 12, 2025 [2]. The page also contains commented out section with a part of French mobile phone number and words "Emergency Standard" (the template contained fictional number here):&lt;p&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;               &lt;!-- &lt;div class="contact-item"&gt;
                  &lt;a rel="nofollow" href="tel:06221319" class="item-link"&gt;
                      &lt;i class="fas fa-2x fa-phone-square mr-4"&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
                      &lt;span class="mb-0"&gt;Emergency Standard&lt;/span&gt;
                  &lt;/a&gt;              
                &lt;/div&gt; --&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
[1] &lt;a href="https://www.tooplate.com/view/2117-infinite-loop" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://www.tooplate.com/view/2117-infinite-loop&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;[2] &lt;a href="https://web.archive.org/web/20250112153727/https://webabusedefense.com/" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://web.archive.org/web/20250112153727/https://webabused...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 15 Nov 2025 14:19:05 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45937630</link><dc:creator>codedokode</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45937630</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45937630</guid></item><item><title>New comment by supriyo-biswas in "Our investigation into the suspicious pressure on Archive.today"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Its interesting that being unable to find a legal route to dig up dirt on archive.is, they're going the route of CSAM allegations.&lt;p&gt;I first heard of this technique on a discussion on Lowendtalk from a hoster discussing how pressure campaigns were orchestrated.&lt;p&gt;The host used to host VMs for a customer that was not well liked but otherwise within the bounds of free speech in the US (I guess something on the order of KF/SaSu/SF), so a given user would upload CSAM on the forum, then report the same CSAM to the hoster. They used to use the same IP address for their entire operation. When the host and the customer compared notes, they'd find about these details.&lt;p&gt;Honestly at the time I thought the story was bunk, in the age of residential proxies and VPNs and whatnot, surely whoever did this wouldn't just upload said CSAM from their own IP, but one possible explanation would be that the forum probably just blocked datacenter IPs wholesale and the person orchestrating the campaign wasn't willing to risk the legal fallout of uploading CSAM out of some regular citizen's infected device.&lt;p&gt;In this case, I assume law enforcement just sets up a website with said CSAM, gets archive.is to crawl it, and then pressurize DNS providers about it.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 15 Nov 2025 12:05:49 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45936869</link><dc:creator>supriyo-biswas</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45936869</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45936869</guid></item><item><title>New comment by atomicfiredoll in "Our investigation into the suspicious pressure on Archive.today"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I don't know anything about Adguard, but good on the team for doing the extra digging instead of just going along with the claim. Even better that they're sharing what they've found with everyone else.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 15 Nov 2025 12:00:26 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45936833</link><dc:creator>atomicfiredoll</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45936833</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45936833</guid></item><item><title>New comment by defanor in "Lawmakers want to ban VPNs"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&gt; It Won’t Even Work&lt;p&gt;I heard similar sentiments about censorship efforts in Russia, but it does seem to work, unfortunately. So far they have outlawed and blocked major VPN providers (and keep blocking more, including non-commercial ones, like Tor bridges, and foreign hosting companies' websites), blocked major detectable protocols used for those (IPsec, WireGuard), made usage of proxying ("VPN") an aggravating circumstance for the newly-introduced crime of searching for "extremist" information. That seems to deter many people already, and once the majority is forced to use the local approved (surveilled, censored) services, it is even easier to introduce whitelists or simply cut international connections (as is already practiced temporarily and locally), at which point the ban is successfully applied to everyone.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 15 Nov 2025 11:20:37 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45936677</link><dc:creator>defanor</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45936677</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45936677</guid></item><item><title>New comment by mechanicum in "One Handed Keyboard"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Their video on YouTube, in English: &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=9vW12gQ4Klc" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=9vW12gQ4Klc&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 15 Nov 2025 10:31:32 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45936463</link><dc:creator>mechanicum</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45936463</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45936463</guid></item><item><title>New comment by gsliepen in "TCP, the workhorse of the internet"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;If you start with the problem of how to create a reliable stream of data on top of an unreliable datagram layer, then the solution that comes out will look virtually identical to TCP. It just is the right solution for the job.&lt;p&gt;The three drawbacks of the original TCP algorithm were the window size (the maximum value is just too small for today's speeds), poor handling of missing packets (addressed by extensions such as selective-ACK), and the fact that it only manages one stream at a time, and some applications want multiple streams that don't block each other. You could use multiple TCP connections, but that adds its own overhead, so SCTP and QUIC were designed to address those issues.&lt;p&gt;The congestion control algorithm is not part of the on-the-wire protocol, it's just some code on each side of the connection that decides when to (re)send packets to make the best use of the available bandwidth. Anything that implements a reliable stream on top of datagrams needs to implement such an algorithm. The original ones (Reno, Vegas, etc) were very simple but already did a good job, although back then network equipment didn't have large buffers. A lot of research is going into making better algorithms that handle large buffers, large roundtrip times, varying bandwidth needs and also being fair when multiple connections share the same bandwidth.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 15 Nov 2025 08:50:49 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45936004</link><dc:creator>gsliepen</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45936004</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45936004</guid></item><item><title>New comment by jacquesm in "Unofficial Microsoft Teams client for Linux"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;The official client is absolutely terrible. But, I've found a much better solution: I tell all my customers Microsoft Teams doesn't work for us and they'll have to pick something else.&lt;p&gt;Kudos for at least trying to address this, MS should hang their head in shame, this is not the hardest problem to solve these days. If we could do it in 1995 they should be able to do it 30 years later.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 15 Nov 2025 07:24:45 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45935673</link><dc:creator>jacquesm</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45935673</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45935673</guid></item><item><title>New comment by jdietrich in "AI World Clocks"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Clock drawing is widely used as a test for assessing dementia. Sometimes the LLMs fail in ways that are fairly predictable if you're familiar with CSS and typical shortcomings of LLMs, but sometimes they fail in ways that are less obvious from a technical perspective but are &lt;i&gt;exactly the same&lt;/i&gt; failure modes as cognitively-impaired humans.&lt;p&gt;I think you might have stumbled upon something surprisingly profound.&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.psychdb.com/cognitive-testing/clock-drawing-test" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://www.psychdb.com/cognitive-testing/clock-drawing-test&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 15 Nov 2025 02:20:47 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45934504</link><dc:creator>jdietrich</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45934504</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45934504</guid></item><item><title>New comment by georgehotz in "HipKittens: Fast and furious AMD kernels"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Full disclosure, we have a contract with AMD to get Llama 405B training on MI350X on MLPerf.&lt;p&gt;Things are turning around for AMD. If you have an AMD card, go to pytorch.org, click Linux+ROCm and install PyTorch. 3 years ago, this was hopeless. Today, most mainline things work. I ran nanochat on MI300X and it just worked. I think that's true about MI350X now too. The MI350X machine is stable.&lt;p&gt;They are clearly behind NVIDIA, nobody doubts that. And a lot of investment into software will be required to catch up, ecosystem, compiler, and driver. But 2 years ago they seemed hopeless, now they don't. Things take time. HipKittens is a great codebase to study to see where AMD's LLVM backend is still lacking; compare it to the CUDA Kittens.&lt;p&gt;For training, it's NVIDIA and Google in first. AMD in second. And nobody in third. Intel and Tenstorrent are not remotely close. Huawei examples segfaulted. Groq gave up selling chips. Cerebras isn't available anywhere. Trainium had a 5 day wait time to get one instance and I lost interest.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 15 Nov 2025 01:23:27 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45934212</link><dc:creator>georgehotz</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45934212</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45934212</guid></item><item><title>New comment by Xeoncross in "Go's Sweet 16"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I know they say that your programming language isn't the bottleneck, but I remember sitting there being frustrated as a young dev that I couldn't parse faster in the languages I was using when I learned about Go.&lt;p&gt;It took a few more years before I actually got around to learning it and I have to say I've never picked up a language so quickly. (Which makes sense, it's got the smallest language spec of any of them)&lt;p&gt;I'm sure there are plenty of reasons this is wrong, but it feels like Go gets me 80% of the way to Rust with 20% of the effort.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 23:25:04 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45933368</link><dc:creator>Xeoncross</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45933368</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45933368</guid></item></channel></rss>