<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>Hacker News: Best Comments</title><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/bestcomments</link><description>Hacker News RSS</description><docs>https://hnrss.org/</docs><generator>hnrss v2.1.1</generator><lastBuildDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 23:40:07 +0000</lastBuildDate><ns0:link href="https://hnrss.org/bestcomments" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item><title>New comment by purple_turtle in "The peaceful transfer of power in open source projects"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&gt; I'm begging project leaders everywhere - please read up on the social contract and the consent of the governed.&lt;p&gt;I do not need consent as I am not governing anyone like king or president governs.&lt;p&gt;If someone is using my project they are also not really entitled to anything, beyond what stated in license and similar documents if any.&lt;p&gt;If they dislike it, they can fork my project and go away.&lt;p&gt;If someone wants to be entitled to anything, they are free to make a contract and pay for service they desire. But while many are happy to demand nearly noone is willing to help. Or even fork project.
Instead they make entitled demand and treat open source developers as servants or slaves or their pets.&lt;p&gt;No, you are not entitled to your preferred governance model to be used in my software project.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 14:55:19 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45980305</link><dc:creator>purple_turtle</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45980305</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45980305</guid></item><item><title>New comment by abalone in "Cloudflare outage on November 18, 2025 post mortem"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I’ve led multiple incident responses at a FAANG, here’s my take. The fundamental problem here is not Rust or the coding error. The problem is:&lt;p&gt;1. Their bot management system is designed to push a configuration out to their entire network rapidly. This is necessary so they can rapidly respond to attacks, but it creates risk as compared to systems that roll out changes gradually.&lt;p&gt;2. Despite the elevated risk of system wide rapid config propagation, it took them 2 hours to identify the config as the proximate cause, and another hour to roll it back.&lt;p&gt;SOP for stuff breaking is you roll back to a known good state. If you roll out gradually and your canaries break, you have a clear signal to roll back. Here was a special case where they needed their system to rapidly propagate changes everywhere, which is a huge risk, but didn’t quite have the visibility and rapid rollback capability in place to match that risk.&lt;p&gt;While it’s certainly useful to examine the root cause in the code, you’re never going to have defect free code. Reliability isn’t just about avoiding bugs. It’s about understanding how to give yourself clear visibility into the relationship between changes and behavior and the rollback capability to quickly revert to a known good state.&lt;p&gt;Cloudflare has done an amazing job with availability for many years and their Rust code now powers 20% of internet traffic. Truly a great team.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 05:04:38 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45976044</link><dc:creator>abalone</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45976044</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45976044</guid></item><item><title>New comment by eastdakota in "Cloudflare outage on November 18, 2025 post mortem"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Well… we have a culture of transparency we take seriously. I spent 3 years in law school that many times over my career have seemed like wastes but days like today prove useful. I was in the triage video bridge call nearly the whole time. Spent some time after we got things under control talking to customers. Then went home. I’m currently in Lisbon at our EUHQ. I texted John Graham-Cumming, our former CTO and current Board member whose clarity of writing I’ve always admired. He came over. Brought his son (“to show that work isn’t always fun”). Our Chief Legal Officer (Doug) happened to be in town. He came over too. The team had put together a technical doc with all the details. A tick-tock of what had happened and when. I locked myself on a balcony and started writing the intro and conclusion in my trusty BBEdit text editor. John started working on the technical middle. Doug provided edits here and there on places we weren’t clear. At some point John ordered sushi but from a place with limited delivery selection options, and I’m allergic to shellfish, so I ordered a burrito. The team continued to flesh out what happened. As we’d write we’d discover questions: how could a database permission change impact query results? Why were we making a permission change in the first place? We asked in the Google Doc. Answers came back. A few hours ago we declared it done. I read it top-to-bottom out loud for Doug, John, and John’s son. None of us were happy — we were embarrassed by what had happened — but we declared it true and accurate. I sent a draft to Michelle, who’s in SF. The technical teams gave it a once over. Our social media team staged it to our blog. I texted John to see if he wanted to post it to HN. He didn’t reply after a few minutes so I did. That was the process.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 00:38:43 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45974320</link><dc:creator>eastdakota</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45974320</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45974320</guid></item><item><title>New comment by porphyra in "Blender 5.0"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Blender is really an amazing case study of open source software. Apart from the Linux kernel and web browsers/tools, it is perhaps the only open source software that managed to beat all the commercial software in its niche. It has rendered Maya nearly obsolete.&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile, in other niches, Microsoft Office still beats open source office suites like LibreOffice; Photoshop isn't about to give up its crown to GIMP; Lightroom isn't losing to Darktable; and FreeCAD isn't even in the rear view mirror of Solidworks.&lt;p&gt;I wonder what will be the next category of open source to pull ahead? Godot is rapidly gaining users/mindshare while Unity seems to be collapsing, but Unreal is still the king of game engines for now. Krita is a viable alternative for digital painting.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 00:20:12 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45974156</link><dc:creator>porphyra</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45974156</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45974156</guid></item><item><title>New comment by ojosilva in "Cloudflare outage on November 18, 2025 post mortem"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;This is the multi-million dollar .unwrap() story. In a critical path of infrastructure serving a significant chunk of the internet, calling .unwrap() on a Result means you're saying "this can never fail, and if it does, crash the thread immediately."The Rust compiler forced them to acknowledge this could fail (that's what Result is for), but they explicitly chose to panic instead of handle it gracefully. This is textbook "parse, don't validate" anti-pattern.&lt;p&gt;I know, this is "Monday morning quarterbacking", but that's what you get for an outage this big that had me tied up for half a day.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 00:10:04 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45974052</link><dc:creator>ojosilva</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45974052</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45974052</guid></item><item><title>New comment by eastdakota in "Cloudflare outage on November 18, 2025 post mortem"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Because we initially thought it was an attack. And then when we figured it out we didn’t have a way to insert a good file into the queue. And then we needed to reboot processes on (a lot) of machines worldwide to get them to flush their bad files.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 00:07:27 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45974030</link><dc:creator>eastdakota</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45974030</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45974030</guid></item><item><title>New comment by SerCe in "Cloudflare outage on November 18, 2025 post mortem"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;As always, kudos for releasing a post mortem in less than 24 hours after the outage, very few tech organisations are capable of doing this.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 23:51:06 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45973869</link><dc:creator>SerCe</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45973869</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45973869</guid></item><item><title>New comment by falcor84 in "Gemini 3"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I love it that there's a "Read AI-generated summary" button on their post about their new AI.&lt;p&gt;I can only expect that the next step is something like "Have your AI read our AI's auto-generated summary", and so forth until we are all the way at Douglas Adams's Electric Monk:&lt;p&gt;&gt; The Electric Monk was a labour-saving device, like a dishwasher or a video recorder. Dishwashers washed tedious dishes for you, thus saving you the bother of washing them yourself; video recorders watched tedious television for you, thus saving you the bother of looking at it yourself. Electric Monks believed things for you, thus saving you what was becoming an increasingly onerous task, that of believing all the things the world expected you to believe.&lt;p&gt;- from "Dirk Gently's Holistic Detective Agency"&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 20:55:34 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45971919</link><dc:creator>falcor84</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45971919</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45971919</guid></item><item><title>New comment by cedws in "Google boss says AI investment boom has 'elements of irrationality'"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I don't even know what the selling point of AI is for regular people. In the 60s it was possible for a man to work an ordinary job, buy a house, settle down with a wife and support two or three children. That's completely out of the realm of reality for many young people now and the plummeting birth rates show it.&lt;p&gt;The middle class have financially benefited very little from the past 20+ years of productivity gains.&lt;p&gt;Social media is driving society apart, making people selfish, jealous, and angry.&lt;p&gt;Do people really think &lt;i&gt;more&lt;/i&gt; technology is going to be the path to a better society? Because to me it looks like the opposite. It will just be used to stomp on ordinary people and create even more inequality.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 20:46:32 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45971794</link><dc:creator>cedws</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45971794</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45971794</guid></item><item><title>New comment by throwaway13337 in "Google Antigravity"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I gave it a fair shot.&lt;p&gt;It is a vs code fork. There were some UI glitches. Some usability was better. Cursor has some real annoying usability issues - like their previous/next code change never going away and no way to disable it. Design of this one looks more polished and less muddy.&lt;p&gt;I was working on a project and just continued with it. It was easy because they import setting from cursor. Feels like the browser wars.&lt;p&gt;Anyway, I figured it was the only way to use gemini 3 so I got started. A fast model that doesn't look for much context. Could be a preprompt issue. But you have to prod it do stuff - no ambition and a kinda offputting atitude like 2.5.&lt;p&gt;But hey - a smarter, less context rich Cursor composer model. And that's a complement because the latest composer is a hidden gem. Gemini has potential.&lt;p&gt;So I start using it for my project and after about 20 mins - oh, no. Out of credits.&lt;p&gt;What can I do? Is there a buy a plan button? No? Just use a different model?&lt;p&gt;What's the strategy here? If I am into your IDE and your LLM, how do I actually use it? I can't pay for it and it has 20 minutes of use.&lt;p&gt;I switched back to cursor. And you know? it had gemini 3 pro. Likely a less hobbled version. Day one. Seems like a mistake in the eyes of the big evil companies but I'll take it.&lt;p&gt;Real developers want to pay real money for real useful things.&lt;p&gt;Google needs to not set themselves up for failure with every product release.&lt;p&gt;If you release a product, let those who actually want to use it have a path to do so.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 19:53:00 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45971152</link><dc:creator>throwaway13337</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45971152</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45971152</guid></item><item><title>New comment by uatec in "Google Antigravity"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;"Congratulations, you have been elevated to manager to agents."&lt;p&gt;That's not exactly really where I hoped my career would lead. It's like managing junior developers, but without having nice people to work with.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 19:17:07 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45970675</link><dc:creator>uatec</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45970675</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45970675</guid></item><item><title>New comment by lairv in "Gemini 3"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Out of curiosity, I gave it the latest project euler problem published on 11/16/2025, very likely out of the training data&lt;p&gt;Gemini thought for 5m10s before giving me a python snippet that produced the correct answer. The leaderboard says that the 3 fastest human to solve this problem took 14min, 20min and 1h14min respectively&lt;p&gt;Even thought I expect this sort of problem to very much be in the distribution of what the model has been RL-tuned to do, it's wild that frontier model can now solve in minutes what would take me days&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 17:37:15 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45969422</link><dc:creator>lairv</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45969422</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45969422</guid></item><item><title>New comment by djdelorie in "How Quake.exe got its TCP/IP stack"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Back then, DJGPP was a much bigger group, and most of the Quake kudos go to Charles Sandmann, author of cwsdpmi, who worked directly with Id to help them optimize their code for our environment.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 17:08:07 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45969020</link><dc:creator>djdelorie</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45969020</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45969020</guid></item><item><title>New comment by kUdtiHaEX in "Google Antigravity"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;2020: every day a new JS framework is announced&lt;p&gt;2024: every day a new Chrome fork browser is announced&lt;p&gt;2025: every day a new AI IDE vscode fork is announced&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 16:52:45 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45968798</link><dc:creator>kUdtiHaEX</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45968798</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45968798</guid></item><item><title>New comment by modeless in "Google Antigravity"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Thank you for saying what this entire blog post doesn't. It's actually disrespectful of Google to launch this without even a mention of the fact that it is based on VSCode.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 16:42:09 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45968618</link><dc:creator>modeless</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45968618</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45968618</guid></item><item><title>New comment by nateb2022 in "Google Antigravity"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I went ahead and downloaded it, it looks to be a VSCode fork very similar to Cursor, with support for the following models:&lt;p&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;  - Gemini 3 Pro (High)
  - Gemini 3 Pro (Low)
  - Claude Sonnet 4.5
  - Claude Sonnet 4.5 (Thinking)
  - GPT-OSS 120B (Medium)&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 16:30:36 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45968432</link><dc:creator>nateb2022</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45968432</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45968432</guid></item><item><title>New comment by njarboe in "Nearly all UK drivers say headlights are too bright"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;One of the main reasons people want/need brighter headlights is that there is much more light inside the car from screens. These don't let your eyes adjust to the dark properly. Older cars had dim green lighting for the gauges and even had a knob to adjust the brightness up and down. You could create a very dim interior instead of the huge amount of white light you get with modern cars and the multiple screens.&lt;p&gt;I'm happy my Tesla does a decent job of having the screen be quite dark at night but the headlights are quite bad with the horizontal cutoff style that only lights the first few feet of horizontal ahead of the car. I need to see those deer and elk on the side of the road, damn it.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 15:11:13 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45967241</link><dc:creator>njarboe</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45967241</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45967241</guid></item><item><title>New comment by throwaway150 in "Do not put your site behind Cloudflare if you don't need to"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&gt; For your small blog with one hundred visitors per month, it's probably the same: "no one will burn their DDoS capabilities on you!"&lt;p&gt;If this is their core argument for not using CDN, then this post sounds like a terribly bad advice. Hopes and prayers do not make a valid security strategy. Appropriate controls and defenses do. The author seems to be completely missing that it takes only a few bucks to buy DDoS as a service. Sometimes people do DDoS your small blog because some random stranger didn't like something you said somewhere online. Speaking from experience. Very much the reason I'm posting this with a throwaway account. If your website receives DDoS, your hosts will take down your server. Nobody wants to be in this situation even if for a personal, small blog.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 14:36:12 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45966683</link><dc:creator>throwaway150</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45966683</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45966683</guid></item><item><title>New comment by abelanger in "Cloudflare Global Network experiencing issues"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;If anyone needs commands for turning off the CF proxy for their domains and happens to have a Cloudflare API token.&lt;p&gt;First you can grab the zone ID via:&lt;p&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;    curl -X GET "https://api.cloudflare.com/client/v4/zones" -H "Authorization: Bearer $API_TOKEN" -H "Content-Type: application/json" | jq -r '.result[] | "\(.id) \(.name)"'
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
And a list of DNS records using:&lt;p&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;    curl -X GET "https://api.cloudflare.com/client/v4/zones/$ZONE_ID/dns_records" -H "Authorization: Bearer $API_TOKEN" -H "Content-Type: application/json"
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
Each DNS record will have an ID associated. Finally patch the relevant records:&lt;p&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;    curl -X PATCH "https://api.cloudflare.com/client/v4/zones/$ZONE_ID/dns_records/$RECORD_ID" -H "Authorization: Bearer $API_TOKEN" -H "Content-Type: application/json" --data '{"proxied":false}'
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
Copying from a sibling comment - some warnings:&lt;p&gt;- SSL/TLS: You will likely lose your Cloudflare-provided SSL certificate. Your site will only work if your origin server has its own valid certificate.&lt;p&gt;- Security &amp; Performance: You will lose the performance benefits (caching, minification, global edge network) and security protections (DDoS mitigation, WAF) that Cloudflare provides.&lt;p&gt;- This will also reveal your backend internal IP addresses. Anyone can find permanent logs of public IP addresses used by even obscure domain names, so potential adversaries don't necessarily have to be paying attention at the exact right time to find it.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 13:57:53 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45966041</link><dc:creator>abelanger</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45966041</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45966041</guid></item><item><title>New comment by afavour in "Cloudflare Global Network experiencing issues"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Because no one cares enough, including users.&lt;p&gt;Oddly this centralization allows a complete deferral of blame without you even doing anything: if you’re down, that’s bad. But if you’re down, Spotify is down, social media is down… then “the internet is broken” and you don’t look so bad.&lt;p&gt;It also reduces your incentive to change, if “the internet is down” people will put down their device and do something else. Even if your web site is up they’ll assume it isn’t.&lt;p&gt;I’m not saying this is a good thing but I’m simply being realistic about why we ended up where we are.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 13:43:53 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45965824</link><dc:creator>afavour</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45965824</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45965824</guid></item><item><title>New comment by arbuge in "Cloudflare Global Network experiencing issues"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Tell him it's worse than he thinks. He obviously brought the entire Cloudflare system down.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 13:15:20 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45965344</link><dc:creator>arbuge</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45965344</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45965344</guid></item><item><title>New comment by lordofgibbons in "Cloudflare Global Network experiencing issues"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;How did we get to a place where either Cloudflare or AWS having an outage means a large part of the web going down? This centralization is very worrying.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 13:12:53 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45965293</link><dc:creator>lordofgibbons</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45965293</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45965293</guid></item><item><title>New comment by rollulus in "Cloudflare Global Network experiencing issues"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Classic. I see issues. Vendor’s status page is all green. Go to HN to find the confirmation. Applies to AWS, GH, everyone.&lt;p&gt;Edit: beautiful, this decentralised design of the internet.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 12:07:55 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45964342</link><dc:creator>rollulus</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45964342</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45964342</guid></item><item><title>New comment by jpmonette in "Cloudflare Global Network experiencing issues"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;phewphoria&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 11:44:14 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45963886</link><dc:creator>jpmonette</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45963886</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45963886</guid></item><item><title>New comment by gwd in "Cloudflare Global Network experiencing issues"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I do appreciate the visual "mea culpa":&lt;p&gt;Your browser: Working&lt;p&gt;Host:  Working&lt;p&gt;Cloudflare: Error&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 11:44:04 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45963883</link><dc:creator>gwd</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45963883</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45963883</guid></item><item><title>New comment by itzjacki in "Cloudflare Global Network experiencing issues"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;A colleague of mine just came bursting through my office door in a panic, thinking he brought our site down since this happened just as he made some changes to our Cloudflare config. He was pretty relieved to see this post.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 11:37:47 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45963808</link><dc:creator>itzjacki</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45963808</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45963808</guid></item><item><title>New comment by powerclue in "How many video games include a marriage proposal? At least one"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;That's me! I made that 17 years ago, still happily married. Took me like two weeks of full time tinkering. It involved a lot of trial and error messing with a hex editor.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 06:54:42 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45962129</link><dc:creator>powerclue</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45962129</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45962129</guid></item><item><title>New comment by ChicagoDave in "Windows 11 adds AI agent that runs in background with access to personal folders"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Microsoft has gone full-blown evil corporation again. No customer validation on any of the AI cruft. No full OPT OUT. Office products are bastardized with copilot buttons everywhere.&lt;p&gt;I've been a Windows user from day one and I now see a future without it. Satya had been a bright spot in Microsoft, but this blind lust for AI, especially in bed with Altman who is pure con artist, is unforgivable.&lt;p&gt;Some of the investment sells recently are starting to look like the beginning of the end for OpenAI. That will have a wide range impact on everything.&lt;p&gt;I use Claude for coding (and mostly in WSL). OpenAI enabled its users to have a sext conversation.&lt;p&gt;Seriously. And Satya just keeps on at full speed.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 04:50:06 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45961517</link><dc:creator>ChicagoDave</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45961517</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45961517</guid></item><item><title>New comment by astrocat in "How many video games include a marriage proposal? At least one"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;The heart-warming gem:&lt;p&gt;&gt; I sent a note about these Easter eggs to Scott Corley [the game's developer]. He said that he had recently pulled out the game to show the marriage proposal to his son. But he’d forgotten the code and couldn’t make it work! He and Melissa did indeed live happily ever after.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 04:19:38 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45961344</link><dc:creator>astrocat</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45961344</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45961344</guid></item><item><title>New comment by everdrive in "Windows 11 adds AI agent that runs in background with access to personal folders"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;It's an agentic OS now. It acts as an agent on behalf of Microsoft and its business partners, and against your interests.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 00:27:08 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45960047</link><dc:creator>everdrive</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45960047</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45960047</guid></item></channel></rss>