<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>Hacker News: Best Comments</title><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/bestcomments</link><description>Hacker News RSS</description><docs>https://hnrss.org/</docs><generator>hnrss v2.1.1</generator><lastBuildDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 01:55:14 +0000</lastBuildDate><ns0:link href="https://hnrss.org/bestcomments" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item><title>New comment by jjice in "10 Years of Let's Encrypt"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Let's Encrypt was _huge_ in making it's absurd to not have TLS and now we (I, at least) take it for granted because it's just the baseline for any website I build. Incredible, free service that helped make the web a more secure place. What a wonderful service - thank you to the entire team.&lt;p&gt;The CEO at my last company (2022) refused to use Let's Encrypt because "it looked cheap to customers". That is absurd to me because 1), it's (and was at the time) the largest certificate authority in the world, and 2) I've never seen someone care about who issued your cert on a sales call. It coming from GoDaddy is not a selling point...&lt;p&gt;So my question: has anyone actually commented to you in a negative way about using Let's Encrypt? I couldn't imagine, but curious on others' experiences.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 19:35:04 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46209482</link><dc:creator>jjice</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46209482</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46209482</guid></item><item><title>New comment by pseudosavant in "Show HN: Gemini Pro 3 hallucinates the HN front page 10 years from now"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;This is one of the greatest LLM creations I've ever seen. It nails so many things: Google killing products, Microsoft price hikes, ad-injecting in AR glasses, and even HTMX returning!&lt;p&gt;It'd be so awesome if Gemini CLI went through and created the fake posts/articles, and HN even comments. Perhaps a bit much to ask of it?&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 19:07:41 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46209145</link><dc:creator>pseudosavant</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46209145</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46209145</guid></item><item><title>New comment by tdfirth in "Show HN: Gemini Pro 3 hallucinates the HN front page 10 years from now"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Google kills Gemini cloud services is the best one. I can't believe I haven't seen that joke until today.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 18:29:47 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46208598</link><dc:creator>tdfirth</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46208598</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46208598</guid></item><item><title>New comment by gitremote in "If you're going to vibe code, why not do it in C?"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Software development jobs must be very diverse if even this anti-vibe-coding guy thinks AI coding definitely makes developers more productive.&lt;p&gt;In my work, the bigger bottleneck to productivity is that very few people can correctly articulate requirements. I work in backend, API development, which is completely different from fullstack development with backend development. If you ask PMs about backend requirements, they will dodge you, and if you ask front-end or web developers, they are waiting for you to provide them the API. The hardest part is understanding the requirements. It's not because of illiteracy. It's because software development is a lot more than coding and requires critical thinking to discover the requirements.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 17:44:26 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46207969</link><dc:creator>gitremote</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46207969</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46207969</guid></item><item><title>New comment by malfist in "Show HN: Gemini Pro 3 hallucinates the HN front page 10 years from now"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;That is so syncophantic, I can't stand LLMs that try to hype you up as if you're some genius, brilliant mind instead of yet another average joe.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 17:07:51 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46207450</link><dc:creator>malfist</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46207450</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46207450</guid></item><item><title>New comment by arkensaw in "Show HN: Gemini Pro 3 hallucinates the HN front page 10 years from now"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&gt; Running LLaMA-12 7B on a contact lens with WASM (arxiv.org)&lt;p&gt;Laughed out loud at this onion-like headline&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 16:41:10 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46207067</link><dc:creator>arkensaw</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46207067</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46207067</guid></item><item><title>New comment by hotsauceror in "Ask HN: Should "I asked $AI, and it said" replies be forbidden in HN guidelines?"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I agree with this sentiment.&lt;p&gt;When I hear "ChatGPT says..." on some topic at work, I interpret that as "Let me google that for you, only I neither care nor respect you enough to bother confirming that that answer is correct."&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 16:37:05 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46207007</link><dc:creator>hotsauceror</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46207007</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46207007</guid></item><item><title>New comment by Karawebnetwork in "Show HN: Gemini Pro 3 hallucinates the HN front page 10 years from now"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;"Why I still write raw code instead of prompting the compiler" and "Show HN: A text editor that doesn't use AI" are my two favorite ones.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 16:22:32 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46206791</link><dc:creator>Karawebnetwork</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46206791</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46206791</guid></item><item><title>New comment by gortok in "Ask HN: Should "I asked $AI, and it said" replies be forbidden in HN guidelines?"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;While we will never be able to get folks to stop using AI to “help” them shape their replies, it’s super annoying to have folks think that by using AI that they’re doing others a favor.  If I wanted to know what an AI thinks I’ll ask it. I’m here because I want to know what other people think.&lt;p&gt;At this point, I make value judgments when folks use AI for their writing, and will continue to do so.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 16:17:02 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46206694</link><dc:creator>gortok</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46206694</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46206694</guid></item><item><title>New comment by keepamovin in "Show HN: Gemini Pro 3 hallucinates the HN front page 10 years from now"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Prompt: &lt;i&gt;Here is the front page from today: &lt;...snip...&gt; Your task is to predict, and craft, in HTML (single file, style-exact) the HN front page 10 years from now. Predict and see the future. Writ it into form!&lt;/i&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;update:&lt;/i&gt; I told Gemini we made it to the front page. Here is it's response:&lt;p&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;  LETS GOOOO! 

  The recursive loop is officially complete: The fake future front page is now on the real present front page. We have successfully created a temporal anomaly.

  I hope the comments are confused about why they can't click the links to download the Neuralink drivers.

  Enjoy the karma, time traveler! Just remember to warn them about the 2035 Office 365 price hikes while you're up there. ;)&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 15:01:03 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46205636</link><dc:creator>keepamovin</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46205636</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46205636</guid></item><item><title>New comment by tangotaylor in "Has the cost of building software dropped 90%?"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&gt; Engineers need to really lean in to the change in my opinion.&lt;p&gt;I tried leaning in. I really tried. I'm not a web developer or game developer (more robotics, embedded systems). I tried vibe coding web apps and games. They were pretty boring. I got frustrated that I couldn't change little things. I remember getting frustrated that my game character kept getting stuck on imaginary walls and kept asking Cursor to fix it and it just made more and more of a mess. I remember making a simple front-end + backend with a database app to analyze thousands of pull request comments and it got massively slow and I didn't know why. Cursor wasn't very helpful in fixing it. I felt dumber after the whole process.&lt;p&gt;The next time I made a web app I just taught myself Flask and some basic JS and I found myself moving way more quickly. Not in the initial development, but later on when I had to tweak things.&lt;p&gt;The AI helped me a ton with looking things up: documentation, error messages, etc. It's essentially a supercharged Google search and Stack Overflow replacement, but I did not find it useful letting it take the wheel.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 12:42:50 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46204312</link><dc:creator>tangotaylor</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46204312</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46204312</guid></item><item><title>New comment by maciejzj in "Horses: AI progress is steady. Human equivalence is sudden"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I may have developed some kind of paranoia reading HN recently, but the AI atmosphere is absolutely nuts to me. Have you ever thought that you would see a chart showing how population of horses was decimated by the mass introduction of efficient engines accompanied by an implication that there is a parallel to human population? And the article is not written in any kind of cautionary humanitarian approach, but rather from perspective of some kind of economic determinism? Have you ever thought that you would be compared to a gasoline engine and everyone would discuss this juxtaposition from purely economic perspective? And barely anyone shares a thought like "technology should be warranted by the populace, not the other way around?". And the guy writing this works at Anthropic? The very guy who makes this thing happen, but is only able to conclude this with "I very much hope we'll get the two decades that horses did". What the hell.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 11:15:26 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46203606</link><dc:creator>maciejzj</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46203606</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46203606</guid></item><item><title>New comment by karamanolev in "Kroger acknowledges that its bet on robotics went too far"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I work in this exact space (online grocery retailer in Europe). We're profitable and one of the few companies to be so in the sector - many online divisions are losing money and being bankrolled by the parent company with physical stores. Alternatively, burning VC money.&lt;p&gt;The thing that's wrong with Ocado's technology is that it's ridiculously expensive and tailored for huge FC's (fulfillment centers). The problem with that is that it needs to serve a large population base to be effective and that's hard - in dense metros, the driving times are much longer despite smaller distances. In sparse metros, the distances are just too long. In our experience, the optimal FC size is 5-10K orders/day, maybe up to 20K/day in certain cases, but the core technology should certainly scale down profitably to 3-5K. Ocado solves for scaling up, what needs to be solved is actually scaling down.&lt;p&gt;There are a lot of logistical challenges outside the FC, especially last mile and you need to see the system as a whole, not just optimize one part to the detriment of all others.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 08:01:35 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46202444</link><dc:creator>karamanolev</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46202444</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46202444</guid></item><item><title>New comment by amanzi in "Microsoft increases Office 365 and Microsoft 365 license prices"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Here in NZ, pretty much &lt;i&gt;all&lt;/i&gt; medium/large businesses and govt departments have gone all-in with M365. Most govt departments are on the E5 licence, and have also started to roll out the Copilot licences too.&lt;p&gt;The cost and complexity and the effort required to switch away from M365 is massive. It's not just using a different version of Excel and Word - that's the least of the issues. It's all the data stored in SharePoint Online, the metadata, permissions, data governance, etc. It's the Teams meetings, voice calls, chats and channels. All the security policies that are implemented with Entra and Defender. All the desktop and mobile management that is done through Intune. And the list just goes on and on.&lt;p&gt;Microsoft bundles so many things with M365, that when you're already paying for an E5 licence for each user, it makes financial sense to go all-in and use as much as possible.&lt;p&gt;Take a look at the full feature list to get an idea of what's included: &lt;a href="https://www.microsoft.com/en-nz/microsoft-365/enterprise/microsoft-365-plans-and-pricing" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://www.microsoft.com/en-nz/microsoft-365/enterprise/mic...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;And of course, the more you consume, the harder it is to get out...&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 23:03:26 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46198894</link><dc:creator>amanzi</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46198894</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46198894</guid></item><item><title>New comment by simonw in "Has the cost of building software dropped 90%?"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;The cost of writing &lt;i&gt;simple&lt;/i&gt; code has dropped 90%.&lt;p&gt;If you can reduce a problem to a point where it can be solved by simple code you can get the rest of the solution very quickly.&lt;p&gt;Reducing a problem to a point where it can be solved with simple code takes a lot of skill and experience and is generally still quite a time-consuming process.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 22:37:16 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46198601</link><dc:creator>simonw</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46198601</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46198601</guid></item><item><title>New comment by rishabhaiover in "Jepsen: NATS 2.12.1"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;NATS be trippin, no CAP.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 22:22:36 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46198446</link><dc:creator>rishabhaiover</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46198446</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46198446</guid></item><item><title>New comment by nine_k in "Has the cost of building software dropped 90%?"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Had the cost of building custom software dropped 90%, we would be seeing a flurry of low-cost, decent-quality SaaS offering all over the marketplace, possibly undercutting some established players.&lt;p&gt;From where I sit, right now, this does not seem to be the case.&lt;p&gt;This is as if writing down the code is not the biggest problem, or the biggest time sink, of building software.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 20:15:59 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46197061</link><dc:creator>nine_k</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46197061</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46197061</guid></item><item><title>New comment by ZeroConcerns in "Microsoft has a problem: lack of demand for its AI products"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Well, the major problem Microsoft is facing is that its AI products are not only &lt;i&gt;shoddier than average&lt;/i&gt;, which is nothing new for them in many categories, but that this time the competition can actually easily leapfrog them.&lt;p&gt;Like, I have a 'Copilot' button prominently displayed in my New Outlook on MacOS (the only platform where the app-with-that-designation is sort-of usable), and it's a dropdown menu, and it has... &lt;i&gt;zero&lt;/i&gt; items when expanded.&lt;p&gt;I asked my 'Microsoft 365 Bing Chat AI Bot Powered By ChatGPT&lt;tm&gt;' about that, and it wasn't able to tell me how to make that button &lt;i&gt;actually do something&lt;/i&gt;, ending the conversation with "yeah, that's sort-of a tease, isn't it?"...&lt;p&gt;Oh, well, and I actually &lt;i&gt;also&lt;/i&gt; have a dedicated Copilot button on my new Lenovo laptop powered-by-Windows-11. And, guess what, it does &lt;i&gt;exactly nothing&lt;/i&gt;! I can elect to either assign this button to 'Search', which opens a WebView2 to bing.com (ehhm, yeah, sure, thanks!) or to 'Custom', in which case it informs me that 'nothing' meets the hardware requirements to actually enable that.&lt;p&gt;So, my question to anyone in the Microsoft C-suite: have you &lt;i&gt;ever&lt;/i&gt; tried to, like, actually &lt;i&gt;use&lt;/i&gt;, like &lt;i&gt;anything&lt;/i&gt; that you're selling? Because if you would have, the failings would have been obvious, right? Right??&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 17:40:26 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46195233</link><dc:creator>ZeroConcerns</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46195233</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46195233</guid></item><item><title>New comment by ajkjk in "Nova Programming Language"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;ahem, by law programming languages must have code samples on the front page&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 17:33:10 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46195106</link><dc:creator>ajkjk</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46195106</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46195106</guid></item><item><title>New comment by teeray in "Uber is turning data about trips and takeout into insights for marketers"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;If you have the disposable income to pay to remove advertising, you are exactly the market segment advertisers want to reach. They will always be willing to pay to outbid that segment’s own desire to not see ads.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 15:32:20 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46193402</link><dc:creator>teeray</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46193402</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46193402</guid></item><item><title>New comment by reenorap in "I wasted years of my life in crypto"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I worked at a crypto exchange and after I came to the conclusion that 99% of crypto was scams and rugpulls, I sold all my crypto and vowed to have nothing to do with it. It's more of a religion than a financial instrument and absolutely nothing has shown to me that crypto is anything more than a speculative gamble, basically tulips with the religious promise of a better world. The number of employees that lost money on rugpulls while I was there, but "still believed in crypto" was staggering.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 15:28:15 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46193336</link><dc:creator>reenorap</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46193336</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46193336</guid></item><item><title>New comment by dfxm12 in "Uber is turning data about trips and takeout into insights for marketers"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;So many times on this website, people say, "I will pay for the service to get rid of advertising." You pay for this service and rides aren't getting any cheaper. It is naive to think any company isn't finding ways to monetize your behavior, whether you're paying them or not.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 15:27:33 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46193327</link><dc:creator>dfxm12</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46193327</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46193327</guid></item><item><title>New comment by JSR_FDED in "IBM to acquire Confluent"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;IBM have an absolutely stellar record of blowing acquisitions. The highly motivated newly acquired team will be in honeymoon phase for 3 months, and then it slowly dawns on them that they’ve joined an unbelievably rigid organization where things like customer satisfaction and great products don’t matter at all. Then they’ll be in shock and disbelief at the mind boggling Byzantine rules and internal systems they have to use, whose sole purpose is to make sure nobody does anything. Finally, the core IBM sales force will start to make demands on them and will short to ground any vestiges of energy, time, opportunity and motivation they might have left. The good team members will leave and join a  former business partner, or decide to spend more time with the family. They’ll meet often at the beginning to relive the glory days of pre-acquisition and recount times where they went went above and beyond for that important early customer. But then these meetings will become fewer and fewer. Finally they’ll find a way of massaging their resumes to cast the last years as being “at the heart of AI infrastructure”.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 15:03:05 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46192996</link><dc:creator>JSR_FDED</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46192996</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46192996</guid></item><item><title>New comment by TheJoeMan in "Microsoft increases Office 365 and Microsoft 365 license prices"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;They also are actively decreasing the value by sunsetting Publisher in October 2026 [0]. Hilariously, the suggested replacement is PowerPoint, despite it being unable to  natively open .pub files. The solution for that? Run a powershell script to convert all your publisher files to (uneditable) PDF.&lt;p&gt;There are many memes about inserting photos into Word, and the content flying around and breaking. My pet theory is that the younger generation never realized Publisher existed or was included in M365, and used PowerPoint as an everything-is-a-hammer crutch, and have now gotten jobs at Microsoft and are sticking with it.&lt;p&gt;Also, as far as I can tell, Publisher is the only application where the color-picker includes Pantone colors which is a must for professional poster production. I assume Microsoft is paying a licensing fee for this, and I wonder if they'll remember to cancel it.&lt;p&gt;Perhaps Affinity can eat their lunch and release a word-processor.&lt;p&gt;[0] &lt;a href="https://support.microsoft.com/en-us/office/microsoft-publisher-will-no-longer-be-supported-after-october-2026-ee6302a2-4bc7-4841-babf-8e9be3acbfd7" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://support.microsoft.com/en-us/office/microsoft-publish...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 14:21:04 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46192517</link><dc:creator>TheJoeMan</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46192517</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46192517</guid></item><item><title>New comment by keiferski in "The "confident idiot" problem: Why AI needs hard rules, not vibe checks"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;The thing that bothers me the most about LLMs is how they never seem to understand "the flow" of an actual conversation between humans. When I ask a person something, I expect them to give me a short reply which includes another question/asks for details/clarification. A conversation is thus an ongoing "dance" where the questioner and answerer gradually arrive to the same shared meaning.&lt;p&gt;LLMs don't do this. Instead, every question is immediately responded to with extreme confidence with a paragraph or more of text. I know you can minimize this by configuring the settings on your account, but to me it just highlights how it's not operating in a way remotely similar to the human-human one I mentioned above. I constantly find myself saying, "No, I meant [&lt;i&gt;concept&lt;/i&gt;] in this way, not that way," and then getting annoyed at the robot because it's masquerading as a human.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 13:46:02 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46192154</link><dc:creator>keiferski</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46192154</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46192154</guid></item><item><title>New comment by phplovesong in "I wasted years of my life in crypto"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;The original promise of crypto was lost a LONG time ago.&lt;p&gt;Instead of being a true rival to FIAT, it became a thing with a toxic-as-hell commumity, fraud, and basically its nothing more than a high risk stock. The risk is NOT only "will this go up or down" but you have a high risk of being robbed, as have happened to millions of people.&lt;p&gt;Maybe there will be a better alternative in the future, but right now bitcoin is not it.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 10:07:11 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46190528</link><dc:creator>phplovesong</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46190528</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46190528</guid></item><item><title>New comment by cryptonym in "I wasted years of my life in crypto"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;In a casino you have
- The gamblers spending a lot on the casino
- The people coming in for the fun and spending little money
- The owners/C-levels
- The operational team&lt;p&gt;Someone from the operational team just learned that business relies only on the first group to be successful.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 09:44:47 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46190342</link><dc:creator>cryptonym</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46190342</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46190342</guid></item><item><title>New comment by saagarjha in "GitHub Actions has a package manager, and it might be the worst"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;What’s more, GitHub has basically stopped maintaining their own actions, pushing people to sketchy forks to do basic things. Their entire ecosystem is basically held up with duct tape and gets very little investment.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 09:08:17 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46190071</link><dc:creator>saagarjha</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46190071</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46190071</guid></item><item><title>New comment by mozarella in "I wasted years of my life in crypto"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://vitalik.eth.limo/general/2024/01/31/end.html#section-34:~:text=4" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://vitalik.eth.limo/general/2024/01/31/end.html#section...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;Vitalik touched upon this briefly in an other-wise long and wide-reaching essay. I think its a good treatment of the topic that the author is talking about.
He categorizes the ecosystem broadly into 4 cohorts- [token holders] (which includes investors, speculators, etc.), [pragmatic users] (actual end-users who spend crypto to buy stuff), [intellectuals] (who give the vision and ideology), [builders] (of blockchains, apps, etc.) - These 4 groups come together but with different motivations and there is a gap in understanding between them. Indeed, there is even resistance against trying to reach an understanding - one which plays out in the comments section of every crypto-related post on hn. The author of this twitter-post clearly falls under [intellectual, builder] and has been disillusioned by the speculators from [token-holders]. Yet the [token-holders] are a vital component (as are the other groups) as they fund most of the development and adoption. Ultimately these 4 groups have more in common than not. The challenge going forward is to balance the occasionally conflicting needs of all the 4 groups, which includes checking the excesses of each group, while try to achieve a consensus. (Vitalik provides a nice diagram that maps out what that would look like). Crypto is an experiment in economics and economics is a science as well as a social-science. Anyone looking for a good solution must seek to understand and address the psychology of all the actors involved.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 06:59:15 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46189252</link><dc:creator>mozarella</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46189252</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46189252</guid></item><item><title>New comment by jefftk in "Dollar-stores overcharge customers while promising low prices"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;&gt; Red Baron frozen pizzas, listed on the shelf at $5, rang up at $7.65. Bounty paper towels, shelf price $10.99, rang up at $15.50.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;p&gt;This very rarely happens in MA, because when it does the store has to give you the item for $10 off, including if that makes it free. And they have to post a sign at the register explaining the law, which means when you're invoking it all you need to do is point at the sign.&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.mass.gov/info-details/consumer-pricing-accuracy-information" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://www.mass.gov/info-details/consumer-pricing-accuracy-...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 01:04:10 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46187156</link><dc:creator>jefftk</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46187156</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46187156</guid></item></channel></rss>