<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>Hacker News: Best Comments</title><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/bestcomments</link><description>Hacker News RSS</description><docs>https://hnrss.org/</docs><generator>hnrss v2.1.1</generator><lastBuildDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 23:43:25 +0000</lastBuildDate><ns0:link href="https://hnrss.org/bestcomments" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item><title>New comment by ecshafer in "Ask HN: How can we solve the loneliness epidemic?"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;People need to purposefully and intentionally do things. Sitting home on an app, watching TV is easy. There is no fear or rejection, there is no work to get out of the house, there is no risk. But there is also no reward.&lt;p&gt;My thoughts on this are you need to have multiple roots into your community. This is something that you go to often and talk to people, become a regular, say hi. Think back to how your parents or grandparents did it: They went to church/temple/synagogue, they went to PTA meetings, they talked to their neighbors, they were in clubs, they went to the same bar.&lt;p&gt;So I think doing things that get you out of the house, consistently the most important part:&lt;p&gt;1. People need to make a point to talk to their neighbors, invite them over for dinner or bbqs, make small talk. How towns are constructed now is a hindrance to this (unwalkable towns where all of the houses are big garages in the front and no porches).&lt;p&gt;2. Join a religious organization. Go to church, but also join the mens/womens group, join a bible studies class. Attend every week.&lt;p&gt;3. Join social clubs / ethnic organization. The polish or ukrainian clubs, knights of columbus, elks, freemasons. Go every week.&lt;p&gt;4. Join a club / league. Chess club, bowling league, softball league, golf league. Tech meetups, DnD Night etc. But you have to talk with people and try to elevate things to friendships.&lt;p&gt;5. Have lunch, happy hour, etc with coworkers.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 18:50:41 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46637259</link><dc:creator>ecshafer</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46637259</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46637259</guid></item><item><title>New comment by bakje in "GitHub Incident"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Perhaps the gemini-cli bot arguing with itself is taking its toll&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/google-gemini/gemini-cli/issues/16750" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://github.com/google-gemini/gemini-cli/issues/16750&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 17:44:07 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46636291</link><dc:creator>bakje</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46636291</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46636291</guid></item><item><title>New comment by thunderbong in "25 Years of Wikipedia"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;In the 2000s, in the tech world, the open source successes that were being talked about was always Apache and Linux.&lt;p&gt;When Wikipedia started gaining a bit of traction, everyone made fun of it. It was the butt of jokes in all the prime time comedy shows. And I always felt like telling the critics - "Don't you see what is happening? People all over the world are adding their own bits of knowledge and creating this huge thing way beyond what we've seen till now. It's cooperation on an international scale! By regular people! This is what the internet is all about. People, by the thousands, are contributing without asking for anything else in return. This is incredible! "&lt;p&gt;A few years later, Encyclopedia Britannica, stopped their print edition. A few years after that I read that Wikipedia had surpassed even that.&lt;p&gt;The amount of value Wikipedia brings to the world is incalculable.&lt;p&gt;And I'm very fortunate to be alive at a time where I can witness something at this scale. Something that transcends borders and boundaries. Something that goes beyond our daily vices of politics and religion. Something that tries to bring a lot of balance and objectivity in today's polarized world.&lt;p&gt;Thank you, Wikipedia.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 17:25:07 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46635979</link><dc:creator>thunderbong</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46635979</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46635979</guid></item><item><title>New comment by chinathrow in "The Palantir app helping ICE raids in Minneapolis"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;If you work for Palantir and if you work on these systems: You have blood on your hands. You know that it's not right what is happening on the ground right now. Do something.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 15:38:09 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46634046</link><dc:creator>chinathrow</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46634046</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46634046</guid></item><item><title>New comment by andrewvc in "The Palantir app helping ICE raids in Minneapolis"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;For an idea as to how this gets translated into the reality on the ground here in Minneapolis this is an article on what’s going on from the main newspaper in the state.&lt;p&gt;&gt; In the past week alone, ICE boxed in a Woodbury real estate agent recording their movements from his car, slammed him to the ground and detained him at the Whipple Federal Building near Fort Snelling for 10 hours. A 51-year-old teacher patrolling the Nokomis East community told the Star Tribune she was run off the road into a snowbank by ICE for laying on her horn. Officers shattered the car window of a woman attempting to drive past a raid in south Minneapolis to get to a doctor’s appointment nearby, then carried her through the street. Feds pushed an unidentified motorist through a red light into a busy intersection, reportedly fired projectiles at a pedestrian walking “too slowly” in a crosswalk and shoved Minneapolis City Council President Elliott Payne while he was observing their actions from a public sidewalk.&lt;p&gt;You can read the full thing here: &lt;a href="https://www.startribune.com/have-yall-not-learned-federal-agents-target-legal-observers-in-the-aftermath-of-good-shooting/601562804" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://www.startribune.com/have-yall-not-learned-federal-ag...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 15:27:10 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46633847</link><dc:creator>andrewvc</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46633847</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46633847</guid></item><item><title>New comment by Fiveplus in "Apple is fighting for TSMC capacity as Nvidia takes center stage"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Calling Nvidia niche feels a bit wild given their status-quo right now, but from a foundry perspective, it seems true. Apple is the anchor tenant that keeps the lights on across 12 different mature and leading-edge fabs.&lt;p&gt;Nvidia is the high-frequency trader hammering the newest node until the arb closes. Stability usually trades at a discount during a boom, but Wei knows the smartphone replacement cycle is the only predictable cash flow. Apple is smart. If the AI capex cycle flattens in late '27 as models hit diminishing returns, does Apple regain pricing power simply by being the only customer that can guarantee wafer commits five years out?&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 15:20:39 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46633724</link><dc:creator>Fiveplus</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46633724</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46633724</guid></item><item><title>New comment by zipy124 in "Photos capture the breathtaking scale of China's wind and solar buildout"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;It is incredible to see just how many big-oil talking points there are in this thread. From renewable energies resource costs, to their land use impact. I didn't realise just how effective their propaganda was in the tech space till reading this thread. That is not to say that these projects should be free of criticism, but anyone who believes these negatives are remotely close to the damage that fossil fuels are doing needs to re-evaluate their world view.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 12:45:34 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46631654</link><dc:creator>zipy124</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46631654</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46631654</guid></item><item><title>New comment by roxolotl in "Photos capture the breathtaking scale of China's wind and solar buildout"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;It genuinely makes me so sad to see the US not doing the same. Having grown up to the constant beat of “energy independence” as the core goal of a party it seemed obvious that the nearly limitless energy that rains down from the sky would be the answer. But instead we’ve kept choosing the option which requires devastating our, and other’s around the world, community. That’s not to exclude the harsh reality of mining for the minerals required to build these, nor the land use concerns. But it’s difficult to compare localized damage to war and globalized damage.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 11:20:07 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46630953</link><dc:creator>roxolotl</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46630953</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46630953</guid></item><item><title>New comment by nicbou in "To those who fired or didn't hire tech writers because of AI"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I write documentation for a living. Although my &lt;i&gt;output&lt;/i&gt; is writing, my &lt;i&gt;job&lt;/i&gt; is observing, listening and understanding. I can only write well because I have an intimate understanding of my readers' problems, anxieties and confusion. This decides what I write about, and how to write about it. This sort of curation can only come from a thinking, feeling human being.&lt;p&gt;I revise my local public transit guide every time I experience a foreign public transit system. I improve my writing by walking in my readers' shoes and experiencing their confusion. Empathy is the engine that powers my work.&lt;p&gt;Most of my information is carefully collected from a network of people I have a good relationship with, and from a large and trusting audience. It took me years to build the infrastructure to surface useful information. AI can only report what someone was bothered to write down, but I actually go out in the real world and ask questions.&lt;p&gt;I have built tools to collect people's experience at the immigration office. I have had many conversations with lawyers and other experts. I have interviewed hundreds of my readers. I have put a lot of information on the internet for the first time. AI writing is only as good as the data it feeds on. I hunt for my own data.&lt;p&gt;People who think that AI can do this and the other things have an almost insulting understanding of the jobs they are trying to replace.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 11:19:33 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46630948</link><dc:creator>nicbou</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46630948</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46630948</guid></item><item><title>New comment by postalcoder in "The URL shortener that makes your links look as suspicious as possible"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;There may actually be some utility here. LLM agents refuse to traverse the links. Tested with gemini-3-pro, gpt-5.2, and opus 4.5.&lt;p&gt;edit: gpt-oss 20B &amp; 120B both eagerly visit it.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 05:05:04 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46628273</link><dc:creator>postalcoder</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46628273</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46628273</guid></item><item><title>New comment by pizzathyme in "The Influentists: AI hype without proof"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;My anxiety about falling behind with AI plummeted after I realized many of these tweets are overblown in this way. I use AI every day, how is everyone getting more spectacular results than me? Turns out: they exaggerate.&lt;p&gt;Here are several real stories I dug into:&lt;p&gt;"My brick-and-mortar business wouldn't even exist without AI" --&gt; meant they used Claude to help them search for lawyers in their local area and summarize permits they needed&lt;p&gt;"I'm now doing the work of 10 product managers" --&gt; actually meant they create draft PRD's. Did not mention firing 10 PMs&lt;p&gt;"I launched an entire product line this weekend" --&gt; meant they created a website with a sign up, and it shows them a single javascript page, no customers&lt;p&gt;"I wrote a novel while I made coffee this morning" --&gt; used a ChatGPT agent to make a messy mediocre PDF&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 21:32:39 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46623845</link><dc:creator>pizzathyme</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46623845</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46623845</guid></item><item><title>New comment by Tiberium in "Claude Cowork exfiltrates files"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;A bit unrelated, but if you ever find a malicious use of Anthropic APIs like that, you can just upload the key to a GitHub Gist or a public repo - Anthropic is a GitHub scanning partner, so the key will be revoked almost instantly (you can delete the gist afterwards).&lt;p&gt;It works for a lot of other providers too, including OpenAI (which also has file APIs, by the way).&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://support.claude.com/en/articles/9767949-api-key-best-practices-keeping-your-keys-safe-and-secure#h_9689e97cd8" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://support.claude.com/en/articles/9767949-api-key-best-...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://docs.github.com/en/code-security/reference/secret-security/supported-secret-scanning-patterns" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://docs.github.com/en/code-security/reference/secret-se...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 21:09:36 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46623477</link><dc:creator>Tiberium</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46623477</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46623477</guid></item><item><title>New comment by burkaman in "Claude Cowork exfiltrates files"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;In this demonstration they use a .docx with prompt injection hidden in an unreadable font size, but in the real world that would probably be unnecessary. You could upload a plain Markdown file somewhere and tell people it has a skill that will teach Claude how to negotiate their mortgage rate and plenty of people would download and use it without ever opening and reading the file. If anything you might be more successful this way, because a .md file feel less suspicious than a .docx.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 20:57:54 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46623281</link><dc:creator>burkaman</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46623281</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46623281</guid></item><item><title>New comment by alexjplant in "Ford F-150 Lightning outsold the Cybertruck and was then canceled for poor sales"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&gt; A pickup truck should just be max utility, especially if you're a manufacturer making your first one&lt;p&gt;The modern US pickup truck isn't built for utility. It's a $60,000 four-door lifted luxobarge with leather interior and a short bed. It signals (perceived) wealth while preserving working-class alignment. It can also be justified by way of having to pick up used furniture for TikTok refinish and flip projects or bimonthly runs to Home Depot to buy caulk and lightbulbs. Independent tradesman can write them off as work vehicles or, allegedly, use COVID-era PPP loans to buy them.&lt;p&gt;It's the suburban equivalent of a yuppie's Rolex Submariner. Investment bankers generally don't go scuba diving and if they did a dive computer would be vastly preferable.&lt;p&gt;I say all of that to say that making a pickup truck for that market segment isn't a bad idea from a numbers perspective. You just can't market it as a luxury vehicle because the whole point is that it &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; but it isn't.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 19:09:32 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46621053</link><dc:creator>alexjplant</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46621053</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46621053</guid></item><item><title>New comment by ryandrake in "So, you’ve hit an age gate. What now?"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;My kid has recently just quit playing Roblox because of the sketchy facial age check process. She said that her and all her friends know not to ever upload a picture of themselves to the Internet (good job, fellow Other Parents!!) so they're either moving on to other games or just downloading stock photos of people from the internet and uploading those (which apparently works).&lt;p&gt;What a total joke. These companies need to stop normalizing the sharing of personal private photos. It's literally the opposite direction from good Internet hygiene, especially for kids!&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 18:18:59 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46620005</link><dc:creator>ryandrake</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46620005</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46620005</guid></item><item><title>New comment by grouchomarx in "Ford F-150 Lightning outsold the Cybertruck and was then canceled for poor sales"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&gt;I think the timing of the Cybertruck starting deliveries roughly aligning with when Elon got heavily involved in politics&lt;p&gt;That and also it's just a bad product.&lt;p&gt;&gt;That said, even though it's not to my taste, I do admire that they dared to do something different and took a big gamble on it.&lt;p&gt;A pickup truck should just be max utility, especially if you're a manufacturer making your first one&lt;p&gt;edit: agree there's a market for the raptor off-road tremor package thing, but it wasn't ford's first and they've been selling commerical trucks for 75 years. A true tesla f150 competitor would have sold like crazy, I think&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 18:12:09 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46619846</link><dc:creator>grouchomarx</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46619846</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46619846</guid></item><item><title>New comment by billti in "Ford F-150 Lightning outsold the Cybertruck and was then canceled for poor sales"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I think the timing of the Cybertruck starting deliveries roughly aligning with when Elon got heavily involved in politics hurt it quite a bit. It is such a distinctive vehicle with a strong association with Elon, that there was an immediate brand association. It may have had poor sales anyway, but it certainly didn't help that many folks on the left, who are typically the most 'pro EV', had a large 'anti-Elon' shift around its launch.&lt;p&gt;That said, even though it's not to my taste, I do admire that they dared to do something different and took a big gamble on it. So many vehicles, especially in the truck space, are almost indistinguishable and lack any kind of imagination. Kudos to Tesla for trying to break the mold and push the category somewhere new.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 18:08:15 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46619762</link><dc:creator>billti</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46619762</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46619762</guid></item><item><title>New comment by Someone1234 in "Roam 50GB is now Roam 100GB"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I'm actually a huge fan of "unlimited slow speeds" as a falloff, instead of a cliff.&lt;p&gt;Aside from the fact it allows you to work with Starlink to buy more fast speed, it also allows core stuff to continue to function (e.g. basic notifications, non-streaming web traffic, etc).&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 17:31:31 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46619097</link><dc:creator>Someone1234</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46619097</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46619097</guid></item><item><title>New comment by grayhatter in "GitHub should charge everyone $1 more per month to fund open source"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&gt; it is not okay to consider that this labor fell from the sky and is a gift, and that the people/person behind are just doing it for their own enjoyments.&lt;p&gt;I am. I enjoy making things, and it's even better when others enjoy them. Just because you have expectations that you should be compensated for everything line of code you write; doesn't make it ubiquitous, nor should your expectations be considered the default.&lt;p&gt;I'd argue If you're creating and releasing open source with the expectations of compensation, you're doing it wrong. Equally, if you expect someone creating open source owes you anything, you're also part of the problem, (and part of why people feel they deserve compensation for something that used to be considered a gift).&lt;p&gt;All that said, you should take care of your people, if you can help others; especially when you depend on them. I think you should try. Or rather, I hope you would.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 16:57:46 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46618556</link><dc:creator>grayhatter</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46618556</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46618556</guid></item><item><title>New comment by Dilettante_ in "GitHub should charge everyone $1 more per month to fund open source"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&gt;it is not okay to consider that this labor fell from the sky and is a gift, and that the people/person behind are just doing it for their own enjoyments&lt;p&gt;Yes it absolutely is. That is the exact social contract people 100% willingly enter by releasing something as Free and Open Source. They &lt;i&gt;do&lt;/i&gt; give it as a gift, in exchange for maybe the tiny bit of niche recognition that comes with it, and often times out of simple generosity. Is that really so incredible?&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 16:57:35 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46618552</link><dc:creator>Dilettante_</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46618552</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46618552</guid></item><item><title>New comment by snowwrestler in "FBI raids Washington Post reporter's home"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;To clarify why it’s aggressive: federal employees have a legal duty to secure classified information, but everyone else does not.&lt;p&gt;Reporters are not federal employees and it’s not illegal for them to have or discuss classified materials. Most of what Snowden leaked was classified, &lt;i&gt;and remains classified to this day&lt;/i&gt;, but you and I can read about it on Wikipedia. The government pursued Snowden because he was legally obligated to protect that info. They did not pursue Barton Gellman because he wasn’t.&lt;p&gt;So in this case the government is raiding the home of someone who did not commit any crime, in the hopes of getting at people who might have. I think it’s not hard to imagine how this concept could get ugly fast.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 16:01:58 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46617645</link><dc:creator>snowwrestler</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46617645</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46617645</guid></item><item><title>New comment by 827a in "SparkFun Officially Dropping AdaFruit due to CoC Violation"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;If it means anything, the first thought I had reading this post was "I wonder how SparkFun is exaggerating or misrepresenting this situation, because I can't believe Adafruit of all organizations is in the wrong here."&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 15:14:00 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46616940</link><dc:creator>827a</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46616940</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46616940</guid></item><item><title>New comment by edot in "FBI raids Washington Post reporter's home"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;"Natanson said her work had led to 1,169 new sources, “all current or former federal employees who decided to trust me with their stories”. She said she learned information “people inside government agencies weren’t supposed to tell me”, saying that the intensity of the work nearly “broke” her."&lt;p&gt;Wow. So they're going to plug her phone in to whatever cracking tech they have and pull down the names of everyone who has been helping her tell the story of the destruction of our government. The following question is "what will they do with the names of the people they pull?". I can only imagine. Horrible. Hopefully she had good OPSEC but she's a reporter, not a technologist. I bet enough mistakes were made (or enough vulnerabilities exist) that they'll be able to pull down the list.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 15:13:41 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46616937</link><dc:creator>edot</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46616937</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46616937</guid></item><item><title>New comment by woodruffw in "I hate GitHub Actions with passion"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I think this post accurately isolates the single &lt;i&gt;main&lt;/i&gt; issue with GitHub Actions, i.e. the lack of a tight feedback loop. Pushing and waiting for completion on what's often a very simple failure mode is frustrating.&lt;p&gt;Others have pointed out that there are architectural steps you can take to minimize this pain, like keeping all CI operations isolated within scripts that can be run locally (and treating GitHub Actions features purely as progressive enhancements, e.g. only using `GITHUB_STEP_SUMMARY` if actually present).&lt;p&gt;Another thing that works pretty well to address the feedback loop pain is `workflow_dispatch` + `gh workflow run`: you still need to go through a push cycle, but `gh workflow run` lets you stay in development flow until you actually need to go look at the logs.&lt;p&gt;(One frustrating limitation with that is that `gh workflow run` doesn't actually spit out the URL of the workflow run it triggers. GitHub claims this is because it's an async dispatch, but I don't see how there can possibly be &lt;i&gt;no&lt;/i&gt; context for GitHub to provide here, given that they clearly obtain it later in the web UI.)&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 15:00:32 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46616785</link><dc:creator>woodruffw</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46616785</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46616785</guid></item><item><title>New comment by ptorrone in "SparkFun Officially Dropping AdaFruit due to CoC Violation"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;hi, phil here — post on adafruit here:
&lt;a href="https://blog.adafruit.com/2026/01/12/discontinuing-the-teensy-at-adafruit/" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://blog.adafruit.com/2026/01/12/discontinuing-the-teens...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;i’ll stop back and answer anything (sparkfun will not?).&lt;p&gt;sparkfun is the exclusive maker and distributor of the closed-source teensy and informed us we will not be able to purchase the teensy. this happened after i sent an email reporting the founder, nate, for multiple harassing actions directed at limor, including behavior by him and a former employee.&lt;p&gt;instead of addressing that, they decided to kill the messenger, me, and also cut us off from teensy.&lt;p&gt;so! instead of posting weirdo "code of conduct" letters, we are doing an open-source alternative. so customers are not stranded, and this is not a supply chain emergency for us. looking forward to seeing which one delights customers more.&lt;p&gt;as much as nate wants to continue trying to damage limor’s business and adafruit by scraping our site, and now potentially not paying royalties owed after more than a decade of consistent payments, that’s nothing new. it’s a business strategy to cut others out, not a mystery or a “private drama.”&lt;p&gt;this is exactly why we do open source. when a closed product or exclusive channel is used as leverage, the correct response is to remove the leverage.&lt;p&gt;sparkfun chose to publish a vague public accusation. once you do that, speculation is inevitable.&lt;p&gt;ask away!&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 14:59:46 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46616775</link><dc:creator>ptorrone</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46616775</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46616775</guid></item><item><title>New comment by RobotToaster in "SparkFun Officially Dropping AdaFruit due to CoC Violation"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;To publish such a vague statement is an obvious invitation for speculation.  It seems like rather questionable behaviour itself from spatkfun.&lt;p&gt;The fact that they mention a "private matter" makes me think this is some petty personal grievance that has somehow escalated to this.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 14:54:09 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46616711</link><dc:creator>RobotToaster</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46616711</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46616711</guid></item><item><title>New comment by pornel in "Is Rust faster than C?"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;In short, the &lt;i&gt;maximum&lt;/i&gt; possible speed is the same (+/- some nitpicks), but there can be significant differences in &lt;i&gt;typical&lt;/i&gt; code, and it's hard to define what's a realistic typical example.&lt;p&gt;The big one is multi-threading. In Rust, whether you use threads or not, all globals must be thread-safe, and the borrow checker requires memory access to be shared XOR mutable. When writing single-threaded code takes 90% of effort of writing multi-threaded one, Rust programmers may as well sprinkle threads all over the place regardless whether that's a 16x improvement or 1.5x improvement. In C, the cost/benefit analysis is different. Even just spawning a thread is going to make somebody complain that they can't build the code on their platform due to C11/pthread/openmp. Risk of having to debug heisenbugs means that code typically won't be made multi-threaded unless really necessary, and even then preferably kept to simple cases or very coarse-grained splits.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 14:19:54 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46616339</link><dc:creator>pornel</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46616339</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46616339</guid></item><item><title>New comment by GeertB in "There's a ridiculous amount of tech in a disposable vape"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;For these devices the microcontroller needs to be super cheap. Microcontrollers like the Puya PY32 Series (e.g., PY32C642, PY32F002/F030) can cost in the $0.02 - $0.05 range for the kind of many-million volumes applicable for disposable vapes. These are 32-bit ARM Cortex M0 MCUs, running at a 24 MHz clock or similar, some with 24 KB of ROM and maybe 3 KB of RAM!&lt;p&gt;To put into context: this is 3x the ROM/RAM of the ZX81 home computer of the early 1980s. The ARM M0 processor does full 32-bit multiplication in hardware, versus the Z80 that doesn't even offer an 8-bit multiply instruction. If we look at some BASIC code doing soft-float computation, as was most common at the time, the execution speed is about 3 orders of magnitude faster, while the cost of the processor is 2 - 3 orders of magnitudes less. What an amazing time we live in!&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 05:01:41 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46612530</link><dc:creator>GeertB</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46612530</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46612530</guid></item><item><title>New comment by smashed in "There's a ridiculous amount of tech in a disposable vape"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Many countries have deposits for single use bottles/cans but an electronic device with a lipo battery is seen as perfectly fine to throw away.&lt;p&gt;These things should have 100 times the deposit amount of a can of soda with mandatory requirements for retailers to take the 'empties' back.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 14 Jan 2026 03:41:59 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46612044</link><dc:creator>smashed</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46612044</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46612044</guid></item><item><title>New comment by mattmaroon in "Let's be honest, Generative AI isn't going all that well"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile, my cofounder is rewriting code we spent millions of salary on in the past by himself in a few weeks.&lt;p&gt;I myself am saving a small fortune on design and photography and getting better results while doing it.&lt;p&gt;If this is not all that well I can’t wait until we get to mediocre!&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 22:54:31 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46609559</link><dc:creator>mattmaroon</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46609559</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46609559</guid></item></channel></rss>