<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>Hacker News: Best Comments</title><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/bestcomments</link><description>Hacker News RSS</description><docs>https://hnrss.org/</docs><generator>hnrss v2.1.1</generator><lastBuildDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 01:51:16 +0000</lastBuildDate><ns0:link href="https://hnrss.org/bestcomments" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item><title>New comment by shibel in "I taught my neighbor to keep the volume down"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Reminds of a neighbor I had back when I was renting in a big city. He didn’t seem to understand what’s wrong with keeping his TV on for very long periods broadcasting the sleaziest (at least at the time) reality show on full volume.&lt;p&gt;I tried talking to him multiple times to no avail. He’d basically say “yeah I’ll pay attention no problem” but nothing changed for weeks.&lt;p&gt;Coincidentally at that time I was working morning shifts at a radio station. Those start really early so you gotta wake up at around 4am.&lt;p&gt;I decided one day to change my alarm (triggered on my Sony Vaio) from the peaceful iPhone-like tunes to System of a Down’s “Chop Suey”. I also decided to forget it on, on repeat, full volume, while leaving the apartment.&lt;p&gt;I don’t think 3 days passed before he knocked loudly at my door, moaning and complaining.&lt;p&gt;I told him: “you gotta understand, your TV was so loud I couldn’t sleep for nights on end, the old tune wouldn’t wake me up anymore. I had to change it. I’m so tired that I even forget to turn it off.&lt;p&gt;But yeah, I’ll try to pay attention to it”&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2026 20:29:08 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46849079</link><dc:creator>shibel</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46849079</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46849079</guid></item><item><title>New comment by recursivedoubts in "English professors double down on requiring printed copies of readings"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I have mentioned this in a few comments: for my CS classes I have gone from a historical 60-80% projects / 40-20% quizzes grade split, to a 50/50 split, and have moved my quizzes from being online to being in-person, pen-on-paper with one sheet of hand-written notes&lt;p&gt;Rather than banning AI, I'm showing students how to use it effectively as a personalized TA.  I'm giving them this AGENTS.md file:&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://gist.github.com/1cg/a6c6f2276a1fe5ee172282580a44a7ac" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://gist.github.com/1cg/a6c6f2276a1fe5ee172282580a44a7ac&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;And showing them how to use AI to summarize the slides into a quiz review sheet, generate example questions with answer walk throughs, etc.&lt;p&gt;Of course I can't ensure they aren't just having AI do the projects, but I tell them that if they do that they are cheating themselves: the projects are designed to draw them into the art of programming and give them decent, real-world coding experience that they will need, even if they end up working at a higher level in the future.&lt;p&gt;AI can be a very effective tool for education if used properly.  I have used it to create a ton of extremely useful visualizations (e.g. how twos complement works) that I wouldn't have otherwise.  But it is obviously extremely dangerous as well.&lt;p&gt;"It is impossible to design a system so perfect that no one needs to be good."&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2026 16:28:41 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46847278</link><dc:creator>recursivedoubts</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46847278</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46847278</guid></item><item><title>New comment by donatj in "Mobile carriers can get your GPS location"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;My friend was going through a pretty massive depression after his mom passed. He'd been with my wife and I at our house for a number of hours talking through it, and apparently not texting his sisters back. They called in a welfare check.&lt;p&gt;We live in a reasonably dense suburb. Police showed up at our front door and asked to speak with him. They just wanted to make sure he was doing OK. He asked them "how did you find me?" and their response was just "we pinged your phone".&lt;p&gt;Watching my security camera, they did not stop at any of my neighbors houses first. It was very direct to my front door. This leads me to believe whatever sort of coordinates they had were pretty spot on. His car was parked well down the block and not in front of our house so that was no give away.&lt;p&gt;This was five years ago and always struck me as a "Huh"&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2026 11:10:31 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46845326</link><dc:creator>donatj</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46845326</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46845326</guid></item><item><title>New comment by muvlon in "In praise of –dry-run"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;If you're interacting with stateful systems (which you usually are with this kind of command), --dry-run can still have a race condition.&lt;p&gt;The tool tells you what it would do in the current situation, you take a look and confirm that that's alright. Then you run it again without --dry-run, in a potentially different situation.&lt;p&gt;That's why I prefer Terraform's approach of having a "plan" mode. It doesn't just tell you what it would do but does so in the form of a plan it can later execute programmatically. Then, if any of the assumptions made during planning have changed, it can abort and roll back.&lt;p&gt;As a nice bonus, this pattern gives a good answer to the problem of having "if dry_run:" sprinkled everywhere: You have to separate the planning and execution in code anyway, so you can make the "just apply immediately" mode simply execute(plan()).&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2026 08:18:52 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46844483</link><dc:creator>muvlon</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46844483</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46844483</guid></item><item><title>New comment by themk in "List animals until failure"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;One of the few sites with a fun "you have javascript turned off" message.&lt;p&gt;&gt; This game requires JavaScript. Or, if you've superior taste, take out a pen and paper and start listing animals.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2026 05:41:27 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46843942</link><dc:creator>themk</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46843942</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46843942</guid></item><item><title>New comment by NewUser76312 in "Best of Moltbook"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Is anyone else entirely unimpressed / bored with this? It's just AI mimicking reddit... I really don't see the big deal or technical innovations, if any.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2026 04:55:30 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46843730</link><dc:creator>NewUser76312</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46843730</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46843730</guid></item><item><title>New comment by tzury in "Ferrari vs. Markets"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Enigma Technologies sells customs manifest search; the Ferraris are marketing bait. Their headline correlations (Bitcoin +0.70, S&amp;P +0.75) are meaningless — any two trending series from 2020–2026 will correlate due to shared macro shocks. Their own showcase contains VINs from Jaguar and Land Rover misclassified as Ferraris, revealing mechanical parsing without validation.&lt;p&gt;Look at these VINs:&lt;p&gt;SAJWA4GB2DLB50982 — This is a Jaguar VIN prefix, not Ferrari. Listed under “458 458 ITALIA”&lt;p&gt;SALLDHMV8BA298639 — This is Land Rover. Listed under “488 GTB TURBO ABS”&lt;p&gt;The page is data about data-selling, dressed as analysis.&lt;p&gt;This is the flat-earther epistemology problem.&lt;p&gt;Flat-earthers’ beliefs tell you nothing about the shape of the Earth, but their existence tells you something about humans. Similarly, this page tells you nothing about Ferraris or markets. It tells you what a B2B data company believes will attract clicks: luxury objects, stock tickers, correlation coefficients presented without methodology. The content is a signal about marketing culture, not economic signal about anything.&lt;p&gt;The web is saturated with this species of artifact, simply put, web pages built not to inform but to rank, to appear in searches, to gesture at sophistication while delivering none.&lt;p&gt;B2B is particularly fertile ground because the audience is assumed to be busy, skimming, and impressed by dashboards. The dozens of Ferrari photos aren’t information; they’re texture. The correlation numbers aren’t findings; they’re decoration.&lt;p&gt;This is the substrate on which large language models train. Not a library with noise, but a noise machine with library fragments embedded.&lt;p&gt;Billions of dollars spent to grow models that simply learn to reproduce the texture of authority with extreme confident tone, the fake mathematician with a white coat, the implied rigor.&lt;p&gt;No one is coming to clean this up because the garbage is the product. Pollution is the business model.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2026 04:52:51 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46843719</link><dc:creator>tzury</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46843719</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46843719</guid></item><item><title>New comment by JackYoustra in "Swift is a more convenient Rust (2023)"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Broadly agree but, as is most things, the devil is in the details!&lt;p&gt;- Xcode. A really rough ide that has a hard time at scale, choking on package refreshes, many targets, and more. It has a special entitlement so you can't even binary patch it if you want to fix it!&lt;p&gt;- Build systems. Cargo is _much_ easier to work with than SPM.&lt;p&gt;- Macros support, codegen is still largely done outside of the macro system, which should indicate its use.&lt;p&gt;- Linter / format support. Yeah, it exists, last I checked it's just a good bit worse.&lt;p&gt;- Performance. There are MANY performance cliffs in Swift; most can be fixed by a sufficiently determined compiler developer, but at this point we've kinda departed talking about the language as-is.&lt;p&gt;- Type inference time. Swift's bidirectional type inference causes a ton of choking on complex expressions, which is a real problem with its number one use case, SwiftUI.&lt;p&gt;- An exacerbating factor on the above, imports are all implicitly module-scoped, meaning that changing a single file means recomputing the types for all files in the module. And because SPM and Xcode have such a rough time with multiple targets, that usually means that a single change can lead to recompiling all Swift files.&lt;p&gt;- Weirdness around classes and structs? I understand that they had to do it for objc compatibility, but I would've found it much cleaner if they'd just from the start had something replacing class, like a fully-sugared `final class Box&lt;T&gt;` that replaces all uses of class.&lt;p&gt;I agree that for the most part it _could_ be an easier rust, but between including bidirectional type inference without a cut operator and poor tooling I struggle to find where it's actually easier in cases that you can't just use typescript and dodge all the non-typecheck compilation headaches entirely.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 31 Jan 2026 22:56:47 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46841752</link><dc:creator>JackYoustra</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46841752</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46841752</guid></item><item><title>New comment by SkiFire13 in "Swift is a more convenient Rust (2023)"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&gt; Consider an enum that represents a tree. Since, it is a recursive type, Rust will force you to use something like Box&lt;&gt; for referencing a type within itself.
&gt; 
&gt; enum TreeNode&lt;T&gt; {
&gt;    Leaf(T),
&gt;    Branch(Vec&lt;Box&lt;TreeNode&lt;T&gt;&gt;&gt;),
&gt; }
&gt; 
&gt; (You could also us Box&lt;Vec&lt;TreeNode&lt;T&gt;&gt;&gt; instead)&lt;p&gt;This is wrong, you don't need a `Box` here. The Rust compiler forces you to have a layer of indirection, but `Vec` already does that.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 31 Jan 2026 22:50:05 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46841710</link><dc:creator>SkiFire13</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46841710</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46841710</guid></item><item><title>New comment by alexjplant in "Finland looks to introduce Australia-style ban on social media"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Reddit has been a cesspit of recycled pablum, populist image macros and low effort reply comments for more than a decade. Enthusiast subreddits are astroturfed to hell and back by people with a Shopify storefront and a dream trying to growth hack their way to a hockey stick. The low barrier to entry to each community means that this vapid culture eventually diffuses itself across subreddits that might otherwise be good. It's a postmodern toilet that flushes into its own tank.&lt;p&gt;I don't care if I sound old and salty when I say this: I miss phpBB and Invision forums. Even those are being bought up by marketing companies to sell ads and transformed with social media features... Xenforo (which everybody uses now) allows liking posts and supports Instagram-style content feeds.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 31 Jan 2026 21:19:54 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46840973</link><dc:creator>alexjplant</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46840973</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46840973</guid></item><item><title>New comment by cheeseface in "Finland looks to introduce Australia-style ban on social media"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Agree on how the platform’s have changed.&lt;p&gt;However, I don’t think Reddit is an exception. Popular is often filled with content that is driven by the feelings of fear and hate. Not something I’d like to continually expose kids or teens to.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 31 Jan 2026 20:04:11 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46840239</link><dc:creator>cheeseface</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46840239</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46840239</guid></item><item><title>New comment by andix in "Finland looks to introduce Australia-style ban on social media"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Modern social media is nothing like social media in early days (myspace, early Facebook and even early Instagram). Back then it was a platform to communicate with friends, and maybe even find new friends to meet up with.&lt;p&gt;Today social media is more like a drug, to keep the user engaged and to push content to them. The content must either be addictive/engaging or paid advertisements. Quality of the content doesn't matter at all. Connecting people to do stuff outside of the virtual world would actually hurt their business model. People turn off their devices and go outside, instead of watching ads.&lt;p&gt;So it's probably fine to just block the big platforms. Forums or messengers (without ads and public channels) are probably fine. Probably even Reddit - which does have an algorithm to show specific content - is not as bad.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 31 Jan 2026 19:33:17 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46839952</link><dc:creator>andix</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46839952</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46839952</guid></item><item><title>New comment by _drg9 in "Google Cloud suspended my account for 2 years, only automated replies"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I had my GCP quota algorithmically set to 0 after spending 6 months working with them to launch a startup.&lt;p&gt;I went through a ton of hoops to get approval for our quota. We sent them system diagrams, code samples, financial reports, growth predictions, etc. It was months of back and forth. I'll also add that it was very annoying because they auto-reject your quota request if you don't respond to their emails within 48 hours but their responses take 1-3 weeks. In any case, after 6 months, they eventually approved us for our quota, we launched, and they shut us down to 0 quota across all services the instant our production app got traffic.&lt;p&gt;We contacted them again asking for help. We never got any human response. We got a boiler plate template a few times, but that was it.&lt;p&gt;I will never ever ever again use a cloud service where I can't guarantee that I can get good customer service. Unfortunately for a small business that means no big clouds like AWS, GCP, etc.&lt;p&gt;Yes, I am bitter.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 31 Jan 2026 19:11:23 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46839742</link><dc:creator>_drg9</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46839742</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46839742</guid></item><item><title>New comment by jmward01 in "Mobile carriers can get your GPS location"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;"and notify the user when such attempts are made to their device."&lt;p&gt;We aren't going to remove the security state. We should make all attempts to, but it won't happen. What needs to happen is accountability. I should be able to turn off sharing personal information and if someone tries I should be notified and have recourse. This should also be retroactive. If I have turned off sharing and someone finds a technical loophole and uses it, there should be consequences. The only way to stop the rampant abuse is to treat data like fire. If you have it and it gets out of control you get burned, badly.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 31 Jan 2026 19:06:20 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46839680</link><dc:creator>jmward01</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46839680</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46839680</guid></item><item><title>New comment by semilin in "Film students who can no longer sit through films"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;If you really care about something, screen addiction does not interfere. A friend of mine has a terrible Instagram addiction, yet has developed for himself a certain degree of cinephilia lately -- we've watched long movies together in theaters and not once has he been on his phone during the screenings. When one has faith that sustained attention might hold more value than that gained by interruption, they tend to prioritize the former.&lt;p&gt;But the article points out that the students here don't even watch movies themselves -- "students have struggled to name any film" they recently watched. Why are these people even studying film? The inattention is clearly caused by disinterest.&lt;p&gt;The phenomenon observed here must be caused by a combination of the general loss of discipline (which is the fallback attentive mechanism when interest is absent) and students' disinterest in the field they &lt;i&gt;chose&lt;/i&gt; to study. The former has been well known; the latter is worth considering more.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 31 Jan 2026 17:14:03 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46838512</link><dc:creator>semilin</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46838512</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46838512</guid></item><item><title>New comment by martinralbrecht in "US has investigated claims WhatsApp chats aren't private"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;WhatsApp's end-to-end encryption has been independently investigated: &lt;a href="https://kclpure.kcl.ac.uk/ws/files/324396471/whatsapp.pdf" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://kclpure.kcl.ac.uk/ws/files/324396471/whatsapp.pdf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;Full version here: &lt;a href="https://eprint.iacr.org/2025/794.pdf" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://eprint.iacr.org/2025/794.pdf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;We didn't review the entire source code, only the cryptographic core. That said, the main issue we found was that the WhatsApp servers ultimately decide who is and isn't in a particular chat. Dan Goodin wrote about it here: &lt;a href="https://arstechnica.com/security/2025/05/whatsapp-provides-no-cryptographic-management-for-group-messages/" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://arstechnica.com/security/2025/05/whatsapp-provides-n...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 31 Jan 2026 17:04:39 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46838392</link><dc:creator>martinralbrecht</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46838392</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46838392</guid></item><item><title>New comment by rendaw in "Giving up upstream-ing my patches and feel free to pick them up"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Regardless of the contents,&lt;p&gt;&gt; For each of my emails, I got a reply, saying that they "sincerely apologize" and "@Dalibor Topic Can you please review...", with no actual progress being made.&lt;p&gt;then&lt;p&gt;&gt; Sorry to hear this. .... @Dalibor Topic &lt;dalibor.topic at oracle.com&gt;, can we get this prioritized?&lt;p&gt;This is pretty morbidly funny.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 31 Jan 2026 16:27:52 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46838039</link><dc:creator>rendaw</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46838039</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46838039</guid></item><item><title>New comment by BadBadJellyBean in "Euro firms must ditch Uncle Sam's clouds and go EU-native"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I dislike the idea that if a cloud provider can not provide every service it's not even worth considering. Where is the problem solving. Maybe don't lock yourself into a single vendor and shop around for solutions. Apart from that the cloud offerings of companies like OVH and Scaleway are constantly expanding.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 31 Jan 2026 13:42:23 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46836624</link><dc:creator>BadBadJellyBean</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46836624</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46836624</guid></item><item><title>New comment by 202508042147 in "Euro firms must ditch Uncle Sam's clouds and go EU-native"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Last week I migrated our db away from AWS RDS to a European cloud provider. Everything runs fine and we also have it cheaper!&lt;p&gt;One of our domains is due for renewal in a couple of months. I'm setting up the transfer to a EU registrar for it next week.&lt;p&gt;This all takes time and it's not the most important thing for the bottom line, but on the long run I'm sure I'll look back and say it was a great investment.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 31 Jan 2026 12:24:53 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46836002</link><dc:creator>202508042147</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46836002</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46836002</guid></item><item><title>New comment by kioku in "Euro firms must ditch Uncle Sam's clouds and go EU-native"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&gt; This isn't just compliance theater; it's a straight‑up national economic security play.&lt;p&gt;The woes of LLM contrasts…&lt;p&gt;In all seriousness, the points made ring true not only for European companies and should make everyone consider the implications of the current situation, as dreary as they are.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 31 Jan 2026 12:13:17 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46835939</link><dc:creator>kioku</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46835939</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46835939</guid></item><item><title>New comment by dugmartin in "Automatic Programming"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I have 30+ years of industry experience and I've been leaning heavily into spec driven development at work and it is a game changer.  I love programming and now I get to program at one level higher: the spec.&lt;p&gt;I spend hours on a spec, working with Claude Code to first generate and iterate on all the requirements, going over the requirements using self-reviews in Claude first using Opus 4.5 and then CoPilot using GPT-5.2.  The self-reviews are prompts to review the spec using all the roles and perspectives it thinks are appropriate.  This self review process is critical and really polishes the requirements (I normally run 7-8 rounds of self-review).&lt;p&gt;Once the requirements are polished and any questions answered by stakeholders I use Claude Code again to create a extremely detailed and phased implementation plan with full code, again all in the spec (using a new file is the requirements doc is so large is fills the context window).  The implementation plan then goes though the same multi-round self review using two models to polish (again, 7 or 8 rounds), finalized with a review by me.&lt;p&gt;The result?  I can then tell Claude Code to implement the plan and it is usually done in 20 minutes.  I've delivered major features using this process with zero changes in acceptance testing.&lt;p&gt;What is funny is that everything old is new again. When I started in industry I worked in defense contracting, working on the project to build the "black box" for the F-22.  When I joined the team they were already a year into the spec writing process with zero code produced and they had (iirc) another year on the schedule for the spec.  At my third job I found a literal shelf containing multiple binders that laid out the spec for a mainframe hosted publishing application written in the 1970s.&lt;p&gt;Looking back I've come to realize the agile movement, which was a backlash against this kind of heavy waterfall process I experienced at the start of my career, was basically an attempt to "vibe code" the overall system design.  At least for me AI assisted mini-waterfall ("augmented cascade"?) seems a path back to producing better quality software that doesn't suffer from the agile "oh, I didn't think of that".&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 31 Jan 2026 11:24:03 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46835618</link><dc:creator>dugmartin</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46835618</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46835618</guid></item><item><title>New comment by kurito in "YouTube blocks background video playback on Brave and other browsers"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;What a waste of resources. Imagine employing some of the most brilliant engineers on the planet and allocating man-hours towards artificially worsening the experience for your userbase in order to blackmail them into paying you, and giving them back what they had in the first place.&lt;p&gt;At least this is a loosing game for Google, since this is client side behaviour.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 31 Jan 2026 09:35:16 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46834983</link><dc:creator>kurito</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46834983</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46834983</guid></item><item><title>New comment by urxvtcd in "Sumerian Star Map Recorded the Impact of an Asteroid (2024)"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;We found an ancient tablet, dated it, reconstruded a long-dead language well enough to read it, reconstructed the night sky on that day, five and a half thousand years ago, found the orbit of this thing, and connected it to a geological formation thousands of kilometers away. Humans can do some amazing stuff.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 31 Jan 2026 09:12:29 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46834864</link><dc:creator>urxvtcd</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46834864</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46834864</guid></item><item><title>New comment by rogeriopvl in "HTTP Cats"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;http.cat author here.&lt;p&gt;A shout out to Tomomi Imura, because HTTP Status Cats was her idea and I just made the images available through an API.&lt;p&gt;It's crazy to think that since 2010 this still pops up on the HN front page from time to time. Thank you for that!&lt;p&gt;http.cat is a testament of how simple, fun and silly the internet was back then. I'll try to keep it online for as long as I can.&lt;p&gt;I love reading the stories you all share online about it, they fuel my motivation to keep it up and I'm always open to feedback and new ideas. So feel free to share them here or on the github repo.&lt;p&gt;Cheers!&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 31 Jan 2026 09:04:13 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46834813</link><dc:creator>rogeriopvl</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46834813</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46834813</guid></item><item><title>New comment by BobbyJo in "Surely the crash of the US economy has to be soon"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&gt; It's mostly in forms of treasuries purchased in USD that pay in USD - this means the indebtedness creates a huge amount of dollars abroad that foreigners have to then spend on US services, driving demand.&lt;p&gt;Strangely enough, this is exactly the opposite of how it works. The dollars abroad tend to stay abroad, as either a more stable alternative to local currencies, or a reserve currency. Likewise, treasuries held abroad tend to stay there as reserves. This is how the US is able to run both a huge debt, and a huge trade deficit. If the dollars were being repatriated, the trade deficit would close, and the influx of money would cause hotter inflation. Same with treasuries, yields would spike as demand fell.&lt;p&gt;There are lots of second order effects there, good and bad, but, basically, those dollars not coming home has funded America for quite some time.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 31 Jan 2026 06:43:56 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46834102</link><dc:creator>BobbyJo</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46834102</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46834102</guid></item><item><title>New comment by elmerfud in "Court Filings: ICE App Identifies Protesters; Global Entry, PreCheck Get Revoked"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;So that whole not using facial recognition and deleting the data after use wasn't real. How shocking. You wonder why the NRA has such a strong lobby against gun registration. It's for the same reasons. Political abuse of exercising of rights.&lt;p&gt;By the time this makes it through the courts people will have forgotten.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 31 Jan 2026 02:34:52 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46832778</link><dc:creator>elmerfud</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46832778</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46832778</guid></item><item><title>New comment by cschep in "The $100B megadeal between OpenAI and Nvidia is on ice"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;#2 cannot be understated&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 31 Jan 2026 02:09:55 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46832634</link><dc:creator>cschep</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46832634</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46832634</guid></item><item><title>New comment by panarky in "Surely the crash of the US economy has to be soon"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;The international "rules-based order" is a good idea when most nations play by the rules most of the time, and when the most powerful at least pretend to follow the same rules as everyone else.&lt;p&gt;A world order based on rules makes it possible to live at a much higher level of abstraction.&lt;p&gt;Abstractions like rule of law, democracy, government currencies and stock exchanges are intangible and imaginary. They're mostly just figments of collective belief. But these wispy and unreal ideas that everyone believes in make it possible for most people to live longer, healthier and less difficult lives.&lt;p&gt;The "rules-based order" was always partly mythical, but as long as everyone kept pretending, it mostly continued to function.&lt;p&gt;But when we devolve from the rules-based order to the old order of pure power and might-makes-right, kings and dictators, when there's no more collective belief that the rules apply to the rich and powerful, then the tower of abstractions collapses, and we're back to the cold, hard, brutal and difficult real world.&lt;p&gt;People will find out that life in the real world is a lot poorer and more miserable than life at the top of the tower of abstractions, even if your brokerage account appears to double.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 31 Jan 2026 02:01:22 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46832583</link><dc:creator>panarky</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46832583</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46832583</guid></item><item><title>New comment by jjcm in "The $100B megadeal between OpenAI and Nvidia is on ice"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Not only has OpenAI's market share gone down significantly in the last 6mo, Nvidia has been using its newfound liquid funds to train its own family of models[1]. An alliance with OpenAI just makes less sense today than it did 6mo ago.&lt;p&gt;[1] &lt;a href="https://blogs.nvidia.com/blog/open-models-data-tools-accelerate-ai/" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://blogs.nvidia.com/blog/open-models-data-tools-acceler...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 31 Jan 2026 01:09:33 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46832239</link><dc:creator>jjcm</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46832239</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46832239</guid></item><item><title>New comment by nlh in "Silver plunges 30% in worst day since 1980, gold tumbles"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;A very excellent question and totally reasonable thing not to know (congrats on being one of today's lucky 10,000!)&lt;p&gt;I'm speaking from the perspective of US coins because that's what I specialize in but this generally applies to coins all over the world as well:&lt;p&gt;Prior to (and including) 1964, US 10c, 25c, 50c, (and when they were made, $1) coins were made of 90% silver.  We made A LOT of these, so in terms of outright rarity, most are not rare.  Today they're referred to as "junk silver" because in terms of collectibility, they're junk, but the 90% silver content means there's some inherent precious metal value (as of this moment on Jan 30, 2026, they have ~approximately~ 60x their face value in silver content, eg $6, $15, $30, and $60 in silver respectively.)&lt;p&gt;So that's their basal value that fluctuates with the silver market.  But the next layer is actual rarity / collectibility -- if a given coin is desirable enough that it surpasses its metal content, you get a different set of values.&lt;p&gt;Now to your actual question:  Do they get smelted/melted down?  The answer is...sometimes.  They trade somewhat like financial instruments, based on the assumption that you &lt;i&gt;could&lt;/i&gt; melt them down (and there's a cost to doing so), so that's how people value the various silver coins.  In reality, there's usually enough demand from people who want to hold physical silver in various forms that they don't actually need to be melted down.&lt;p&gt;There's obviously a lot more to it, but that's the 5c version ;)&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 31 Jan 2026 01:02:31 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46832175</link><dc:creator>nlh</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46832175</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46832175</guid></item></channel></rss>