<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>Hacker News: Best Comments</title><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/bestcomments</link><description>Hacker News RSS</description><docs>https://hnrss.org/</docs><generator>hnrss v2.1.1</generator><lastBuildDate>Fri, 08 Aug 2025 00:15:02 +0000</lastBuildDate><ns0:link href="https://hnrss.org/bestcomments" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item><title>New comment by beeflet in "GPT-5"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Perhaps it is not possible to simulate higher-level intelligence using a stochastic model for predicting text.&lt;p&gt;I am not an AI researcher, but I have friends who do work in the field, and they are not worried about LLM-based AGI because of the diminishing returns on results vs amount of training data required. Maybe this is the bottleneck.&lt;p&gt;Human intelligence is markedly different from LLMs: it requires far fewer examples to train on, and generalizes way better. Whereas LLMs tend to regurgitate solutions to solved problems, where the solutions tend to be well-published in training data.&lt;p&gt;That being said, AGI is not a necessary requirement for AI to be totally world-changing. There are possibly applications of existing AI/ML/SL technology which could be more impactful than general intelligence. Search is one example where the ability to regurgitate knowledge from many domains is desirable&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 07 Aug 2025 18:17:24 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44828331</link><dc:creator>beeflet</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44828331</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44828331</guid></item><item><title>New comment by highfrequency in "GPT-5"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;It is frequently suggested that once one of the AI companies reaches an AGI threshold, they will take off ahead of the rest. It's interesting to note that at least so far, the trend has been the opposite: as time goes on and the models get better, the performance of the different company's gets clustered closer together. Right now GPT-5, Claude Opus, Grok 4, Gemini 2.5 Pro all seem quite good across the board (ie they can all basically solve moderately challenging math and coding problems).&lt;p&gt;As a user, it feels like the race has never been as close as it is now. Perhaps dumb to extrapolate, but it makes me lean more skeptical about the hard take-off / winner-take-all mental model that has been pushed.&lt;p&gt;Would be curious to hear the take of a researcher at one of these firms - do you expect the AI offerings across competitors to become more competitive and clustered over the next few years, or less so?&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 07 Aug 2025 18:05:12 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44828137</link><dc:creator>highfrequency</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44828137</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44828137</guid></item><item><title>New comment by mtlynch in "GPT-5"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;What's going on with their SWE bench graph?[0]&lt;p&gt;GPT-5 non-thinking is labeled 52.8% accuracy, but o3 is shown as a much shorter bar, yet it's labeled 69.1%. And 4o is an identical bar to o3, but it's labeled 30.8%...&lt;p&gt;[0] &lt;a href="https://i.postimg.cc/DzkZZLry/y-axis.png" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://i.postimg.cc/DzkZZLry/y-axis.png&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 07 Aug 2025 17:10:12 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44827179</link><dc:creator>mtlynch</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44827179</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44827179</guid></item><item><title>New comment by DecoPerson in "Emailing a one-time code is worse than passwords"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;The attack pattern is:&lt;p&gt;1) User goes to BAD website and signs up.&lt;p&gt;2) BAD website says “We’ve sent you an email, please enter the 6-digit code! The email will come from GOOD, as they are our sign-in partner.”&lt;p&gt;3) BAD’s bots start a “Sign in with email one-time code” flow on the GOOD website using the user’s email.&lt;p&gt;4) GOOD sends a one-time login code email to the user’s email address.&lt;p&gt;5) The user is very likely to trust this email, because it’s from GOOD, and why would GOOD send it if it’s not a proper login?&lt;p&gt;6) User enters code into BAD’s website.&lt;p&gt;7) BAD uses code to login to GOOD’s website as the user. BAD now has full access to the user’s GOOD account.&lt;p&gt;This is why “email me a one-time code” is one of the worst authentication flows for phishing. It’s just so hard to stop users from making this mistake.&lt;p&gt;“Click a link in the email” is a tiny bit better because it takes the user straight to the GOOD website, and passing that link to BAD is more tedious and therefore more suspicious. However, if some popular email service suddenly decides your login emails or the login link within should be blocked, then suddenly many of your users cannot login.&lt;p&gt;Passkeys is the way to go. Password manager support for passkeys is getting really good. And I assure you, all passkeys being lost when a user loses their phone is far, far better than what’s been happening with passwords. I’d rather granny needs to visit the bank to get access to her account again, than someone phishes her and steals all her money.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 07 Aug 2025 03:37:03 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44820331</link><dc:creator>DecoPerson</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44820331</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44820331</guid></item><item><title>New comment by pentamassiv in "Ask HN: Have you ever regretted open-sourcing something?"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I am the maintainer of a library to simulate keyboard and mouse input. I didn't start the project but took over the maintenance and have since rewritten pretty much all of the code. I recently found out that Anthropic is shipping it in Claude Desktop for some unreleased feature which is probably like "Computer Use". I noticed they had an open position in exactly the team responsible for the implementation and applied. A few months later I received a rejection. The letter said that the team doesn't have the time to review any more candidates. The code is under MIT so everything is perfectly fine. It is great that a company like Anthropic is using my code, but it would have been nice to benefit from it. I wrote a slightly longer blog post about the topic here:&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://grell.dev/blog/ai_rejection" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://grell.dev/blog/ai_rejection&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 05 Aug 2025 22:59:27 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44805556</link><dc:creator>pentamassiv</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44805556</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44805556</guid></item><item><title>New comment by cco in "Open models by OpenAI"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;The lede is being missed imo.&lt;p&gt;gpt-oss:20b is a top ten model (on MMLU (right behind Gemini-2.5-Pro) and I just ran it locally on my Macbook Air M3 from last year.&lt;p&gt;I've been experimenting with a lot of local models, both on my laptop and on my phone (Pixel 9 Pro), and I figured we'd be here in a year or two.&lt;p&gt;But no, we're here today. A basically frontier model, running for the cost of electricity (free with a rounding error) on my laptop. No $200/month subscription, no lakes being drained, etc.&lt;p&gt;I'm blown away.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 05 Aug 2025 21:13:25 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44804397</link><dc:creator>cco</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44804397</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44804397</guid></item><item><title>New comment by kridsdale3 in "Claude Opus 4.1"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Given the Gregorian Calendar and the planet's path through its orbit, August is just getting started.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 05 Aug 2025 18:26:27 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44802150</link><dc:creator>kridsdale3</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44802150</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44802150</guid></item><item><title>New comment by pitpatagain in "Ozempic shows anti-aging effects in trial"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;This is specifically a study on people with HIV-associated lipohypertrophy, which is associated with accelerated aging. Not clear what this would mean for people generally.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 05 Aug 2025 17:39:12 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44801396</link><dc:creator>pitpatagain</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44801396</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44801396</guid></item><item><title>New comment by simonw in "Things that helped me get out of the AI 10x engineer imposter syndrome"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I found myself agreeing with quite a lot of this article.&lt;p&gt;I'm a pretty huge proponent for AI-assisted development, but I've never found those 10x claims convincing. I've estimated that LLMs make me 2-5x more productive on the parts of my job which involve typing code into a computer, which is itself a small portion of that I do as a software engineer.&lt;p&gt;That's not too far from this article's assumptions. From the article:&lt;p&gt;&gt; I wouldn't be surprised to learn AI helps many engineers do certain tasks 20-50% faster, but the nature of software bottlenecks mean this doesn't translate to a 20% productivity increase and certainly not a 10x increase.&lt;p&gt;I think that's an under-estimation - I suspect engineers that really know how to use this stuff effectively will get more than a 0.2x increase - but I do think all of the &lt;i&gt;other stuff&lt;/i&gt; involved in building software makes the 10x thing unrealistic in most cases.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 05 Aug 2025 14:41:45 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44798605</link><dc:creator>simonw</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44798605</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44798605</guid></item><item><title>New comment by modeless in "Genie 3: A new frontier for world models"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Consistency over multiple minutes &lt;i&gt;and&lt;/i&gt; it runs in real time at 720p? I did not expect world models to be this good yet.&lt;p&gt;&gt; Genie 3’s consistency is an emergent capability&lt;p&gt;So this just happened from scaling the model, rather than being a consequence of deliberate architecture changes?&lt;p&gt;Edit: here is some commentary on limitations from someone who tried it: &lt;a href="https://x.com/tejasdkulkarni/status/1952737669894574264" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://x.com/tejasdkulkarni/status/1952737669894574264&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;&gt; - Physics is still hard and there are obvious failure cases when I tried the classical intuitive physics experiments from psychology (tower of blocks).&lt;p&gt;&gt; - Social and multi-agent interactions are tricky to handle. 1vs1 combat games do not work&lt;p&gt;&gt; - Long instruction following and simple combinatorial game logic fails (e.g. collect some points / keys etc, go to the door, unlock and so on)&lt;p&gt;&gt; - Action space is limited&lt;p&gt;&gt; - It is far from being a real game engines and has a long way to go but this is a clear glimpse into the future.&lt;p&gt;Even with these limitations, this is still bonkers. It suggests to me that world models may have a bigger part to play in robotics and real world AI than I realized. Future robots may learn in their dreams...&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 05 Aug 2025 14:39:25 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44798564</link><dc:creator>modeless</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44798564</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44798564</guid></item><item><title>New comment by rob74 in "Mastercard deflects blame for NSFW games being taken down"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;So... Mastercard's statement is very clear:&lt;p&gt;&gt; &lt;i&gt;Put simply, we allow all lawful purchases on our network.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;p&gt;But their "Rule 5.12.7" is... not so clear:&lt;p&gt;&gt; &lt;i&gt;A Merchant must not submit to its Acquirer, and a Customer must not submit to the Interchange System, any Transaction that is illegal, or in the sole discretion of the Corporation, may damage the goodwill of the Corporation or reflect negatively on the Marks.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;p&gt;Well, which one is it now? All lawful purchases (pretty clear-cut) or only lawful purchases that will not "reflect negatively" on Mastercard in Mastercard's opinion (vague as hell)?&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 04 Aug 2025 15:15:04 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44787005</link><dc:creator>rob74</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44787005</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44787005</guid></item><item><title>New comment by fxtentacle in "Perplexity is using stealth, undeclared crawlers to evade no-crawl directives"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I find this problem quite difficult to solve:&lt;p&gt;1. If I as a human request a website, then I should be shown the content. Everyone agrees.&lt;p&gt;2. If I as the human request the software on my computer to modify the content before displaying it, for example by installing an ad-blocker into my user agent, then that's my choice and the website should not be notified about it. Most users agree, some websites try to nag you into modifying the software you run locally.&lt;p&gt;3. If I now go one step further and use an LLM to summarize content because the authentic presentation is so riddled with ads, JavaScript, and pop-ups, that the content becomes borderline unusable, then why would the LLM accessing the website on my behalf be in a different legal category as my Firefox web browser accessing the website on my behalf?&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 04 Aug 2025 14:12:12 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44786039</link><dc:creator>fxtentacle</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44786039</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44786039</guid></item><item><title>New comment by Balgair in "Job-seekers are dodging AI interviewers"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I did one of these once. &lt;i&gt;Once&lt;/i&gt;.&lt;p&gt;I felt so bad afterwards that I swore them off forever.&lt;p&gt;It's not like the 'interview' was terrible or anything. I knew it was AI from the start.&lt;p&gt;It was just that when I got done with it, I realized that I had talked at a computer for ~45 minutes. And, yet again, I was going to be ghosted by the company (I was), and that I was never going to get those 45 minutes back. That was time I could have used to apply for another job, or cook, or sleep, or exercise, or spend time with family. But no, like an idiot, I talked at a bot for that time for literally no reason.&lt;p&gt;Like, sure &lt;i&gt;maaaaybe&lt;/i&gt; the company is going to use it as a screen for 'real' people. But the odds that it's not just another hoop they have for you to jump through are nil. If they send an AI 'interview' at you, that's the exact same as an email requesting yet more portfolio submissions. Pointless.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 04 Aug 2025 13:40:36 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44785645</link><dc:creator>Balgair</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44785645</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44785645</guid></item><item><title>New comment by cedws in "Mastercard deflects blame for NSFW games being taken down"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I'm glad the Mastercard-Visa duopoly is finally getting some attention, these companies shouldn't be allowed to exercise the financial control they do. Payment infrastructure is not a free market - you can't just choose to pay via some other processor if they turn you down, they ARE the processors. Therefore, they should be under intense scrutiny when they refuse.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 04 Aug 2025 11:30:25 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44784378</link><dc:creator>cedws</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44784378</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44784378</guid></item><item><title>New comment by ronbenton in "If you're remote, ramble"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;“I see you’ve only had 15 rambles this week”&lt;p&gt;“Isn’t 15 the minimum?”&lt;p&gt;“Well, yeah, if you just want to do the bare minimum. But look at Todd over there - he has 37 rambles”&lt;p&gt;“Well if you wanted people to have 37 rambles why wouldn’t you make that the minimum”&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 03 Aug 2025 14:39:21 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44776874</link><dc:creator>ronbenton</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44776874</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44776874</guid></item><item><title>New comment by benreesman in "Lina Khan points to Figma IPO as vindication of M&amp;A scrutiny"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;It absolutely proves that she was right. If you care about market cap? She was right. If you care about employee comp? She was right. If you care about consumer choice, she was right. Number of listings, new potential acquirers for your startup, more diverse office geography, right right right right.&lt;p&gt;The idea that there's a significant lobby on fucking Hacker News unhappy that a startup IPO'd for a zillion bucks and made everyone rich is twilight zone shit. It makes no sense according to the stated values in the fucking masthead.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 03 Aug 2025 13:03:51 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44776302</link><dc:creator>benreesman</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44776302</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44776302</guid></item><item><title>New comment by dabedee in "Lina Khan points to Figma IPO as vindication of M&amp;A scrutiny"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I think the Figma IPO proves Khan was right. $60B market cap today vs the $20B Adobe offered in 2023.
There was some criticism about regulatory overreach when the deal got blocked. Now Figma employees are rich, the design tools market stays competitive, and we have another major independent tech company instead of just another Adobe product line.
This is exactly why we need regulators willing to tell Big Tech "no" sometimes. Competition creates more value than consolidation.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 03 Aug 2025 09:20:29 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44775279</link><dc:creator>dabedee</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44775279</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44775279</guid></item><item><title>New comment by PaulRobinson in "Helsinki records zero traffic deaths for full year"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I was in Helsinki for work a couple of years ago, walking back to my hotel with some colleagues after a few hours drinking (incredibly expensive, but quite nice), beer.&lt;p&gt;It was around midnight and we happened to come across a very large mobile crane on the pavement blocking our way. As we stepped out (carefully), into the road to go around it, one of my Finnish colleagues started bemoaning that no cones or barriers had been put out to safely shepherd pedestrians around it. I was very much "yeah, they're probably only here for a quick job, probably didn't have time for that", because I'm a Londoner and, well, that's what we do in London.&lt;p&gt;My colleague is like "No, that's not acceptable", and he literally pulls out his phone and calls the police. As we carry on on our way, a police car comes up the road and pulls over to have a word with the contractors.&lt;p&gt;They take the basics safely over there in a way I've not seen anywhere else. When you do that, you get the benefits.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 02 Aug 2025 20:49:39 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44771331</link><dc:creator>PaulRobinson</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44771331</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44771331</guid></item><item><title>New comment by fumar in "Telo MT1"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;This is a breath of fresh air. Modern pick up trucks post-2017 are giant vehicles with high danger to pedestrians. They are often touted as off road capable with high utility, and I see them in pristine condition on city streets hauling a totality of one human.&lt;p&gt;Good overviews of the truck &lt;a href="https://youtu.be/aEq-vTLimrQ?si=fS-UhjndoWuxwBip" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://youtu.be/aEq-vTLimrQ?si=fS-UhjndoWuxwBip&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://youtu.be/1OgN_qctcGs?si=nEysWQHzafRpxfRp" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://youtu.be/1OgN_qctcGs?si=nEysWQHzafRpxfRp&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 02 Aug 2025 18:25:04 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44770016</link><dc:creator>fumar</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44770016</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44770016</guid></item><item><title>New comment by dv_dt in "We may not like what we become if A.I. solves loneliness"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Though it's popularized to blame social media and phones, economics should not be overlooked. Pay for young generations is lagging and restaurants and bar prices are super high. Public spaces for informal gatherings has shrunk - eg fewer malls&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 02 Aug 2025 16:12:53 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44768795</link><dc:creator>dv_dt</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44768795</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44768795</guid></item><item><title>New comment by stdvit in "We may not like what we become if A.I. solves loneliness"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&gt; Even in a world brimming with easy distractions—TikTok, Pornhub, Candy Crush, Sudoku—people still manage to meet for drinks, work out at the gym, go on dates, muddle through real life.&lt;p&gt;They actually don't. Everything from dating and fitness to manufacturing and politics is in decline in activities, and more so in effect and understanding. You can't convince (enough) people anymore that it is even important as many don't have capacity to do it. And it isn't even something new at this point.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 02 Aug 2025 14:11:16 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44767790</link><dc:creator>stdvit</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44767790</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44767790</guid></item><item><title>New comment by andrewstuart2 in "Atlassian terminates 150 staff"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;It's a pretty impersonal way to announce layoffs but I think they all tend to be impersonal. I do think the 6 months of pay says a lot more than the fact that they used a video.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2025 19:42:03 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44761465</link><dc:creator>andrewstuart2</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44761465</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44761465</guid></item><item><title>New comment by legitster in "Corporation for Public Broadcasting ceasing operations"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Contrary to the conservative spin over the years, I have found public broadcasting to be one of the least biased sources of headline news and information available. (For their national broadcasts at least - local ... can be hit or miss).&lt;p&gt;In particular, their kids programming is the absolute best. Nothing flashy or exciting, but it's laser focused on education and has zero agenda. And the PBS kids apps are one of the few things I can hand to my kid worry-free. And the fact that it's money-free and ad-free to access in this modern age is a miracle.&lt;p&gt;The only people who could support this are not just wrong, they are people out of touch with reality. These are people who think public parks are a waste of space. Or that having nice things to share is elitist.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2025 17:43:48 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44759929</link><dc:creator>legitster</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44759929</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44759929</guid></item><item><title>New comment by lapcat in "Live coding interviews measure stress, not coding skills"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I won't attempt to generalize from my case, but let me offer a personal anecdote.&lt;p&gt;I'm now a successful, self-employed indie developer. One of the main reasons I stuck with indie development through the hard times—the maxim that it takes 5 years to become an overnight success was true for me—was that I became practically unhireable. There are multiple strikes against me: I'm middle age in an industry rife with age discrimination, I don't have a computer science degree, and I experience brain freeze during live coding interviews.&lt;p&gt;I would note that not all stress is the same. Firefighters rush into burning buildings for a living, and what could be more stressful, yet many of them would panic at the idea of giving a speech to a non-burning roomful of strangers. I have no problem with stress on the job, and I've successfully navigated many work emergencies during my career, but something about strangers standing over my shoulder judging me, determining my financial future by providing or withholding a job, like the sword of Damocles, turns my stomach inside out. And like the article author, I can revisit the coding problems and solve them afterward, as soon as the interview is over. Interviewers must think I'm a fraud who can't code, yet all evidence from my career, now almost 2 decades long, suggests otherwise.&lt;p&gt;A lot of commenters causally speak of "false negatives" as if they were random, but some people, myself included, are &lt;i&gt;always&lt;/i&gt; the false negative. I am consistently filtered out by audition-style interviews. I'm not a stage performer.&lt;p&gt;[Edit:] I didn't expect my comment to rise to the top of an already crowded discussion. I feel a little self-conscious about it. ;-)&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2025 14:20:05 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44757214</link><dc:creator>lapcat</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44757214</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44757214</guid></item><item><title>New comment by a2128 in "Our Farewell from Google Play"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;From a cursory glance, their apps seem to be of the kind that don't need continuous updates and can be considered complete. Self-contained, offline software that serves a specific purpose: &lt;a href="https://search.f-droid.org/?q=SECUSO&amp;lang=en" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://search.f-droid.org/?q=SECUSO&amp;lang=en&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, Google no longer recognizes this as a valid development strategy. If you want to publish on Google Play, you need to continuously release updates targeting an SDK released within the past year[0]. If you don't, they will send you constant warnings about how your app is violating their policies, they might derank your app, and eventually they'll stop making your app available to new users.&lt;p&gt;Updating the SDK is not that simple and it often introduces new bugs if you don't read through the full changelog and test thoroughly. I have 3 apps and it already feels like I spend too much time each year updating SDK, I can't imagine updating 30.&lt;p&gt;They talk about how this somehow improves security and enhances user experience, meanwhile this policy worsens user experience by pushing people towards ad-filled apps that have the resources and courage to release needless updates, and they still publish spyware on their store.&lt;p&gt;[0] &lt;a href="https://developer.android.com/google/play/requirements/target-sdk" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://developer.android.com/google/play/requirements/targe...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2025 12:43:49 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44755954</link><dc:creator>a2128</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44755954</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44755954</guid></item><item><title>New comment by ochronus in "Show HN: I made a website that makes you cry"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;But I already have Jira for that&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2025 06:41:18 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44753654</link><dc:creator>ochronus</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44753654</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44753654</guid></item><item><title>New comment by oellegaard in "“No tax on tips” is an industry plant"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;It’s crazy that this still happens in the US.&lt;p&gt;Tipping is a thing of the past. Pay for your meal and have the restaurant pay their people for their work. End of story.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2025 05:14:57 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44753223</link><dc:creator>oellegaard</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44753223</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44753223</guid></item><item><title>New comment by tptacek in "The anti-abundance critique on housing is wrong"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;So much of the journalism we read is heavily processed and barely-reported and it's startling to see how much of a superpower simple shoe-leather reporting actually is. Derek Thompson's an incredibly sharp writer, but not really a subject matter expert on housing economics; all he did here was read papers and call up the authorities they cited, and the narrative behind those papers collapsed.&lt;p&gt;We're often so down on journalism on HN, and I believe a big part of that is we tend to read so much opinion and analysis and so little basic reporting.&lt;p&gt;I've been loving Thompson's substack (which is mostly not about housing policy so far).&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 31 Jul 2025 22:30:59 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44750898</link><dc:creator>tptacek</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44750898</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44750898</guid></item><item><title>New comment by lubujackson in "Slow"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I'm reminded of the famous story of (I think) the central beam in a building at Oxford. The story goes something like:&lt;p&gt;The central beam was beginning to fail and the Oxford administration knew they needed to replace it. When they went around for quotes, no one could replace the beam because it was 100 ft in length and sourced from an old growth tree. Such logs were simply unavailable to buy. To solve the issue, the staff begin to look at major renovations to the building's architecture.&lt;p&gt;Until the Oxford groundskeeper heard about the problem. "We have a replacement beam," he said.&lt;p&gt;The groundskeeper took the curious admins to the edge of the grounds. There stood two old growth trees, over 150 feet tall.&lt;p&gt;"But these must be over 200 years old! When were they planted?" the admins asked.&lt;p&gt;"The day they replaced the previous beam."&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 31 Jul 2025 19:58:27 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44749473</link><dc:creator>lubujackson</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44749473</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44749473</guid></item><item><title>New comment by nicoburns in "I tried Servo"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&gt; The current roadmap lists Shadow DOM and CSS Grid as priorities&lt;p&gt;I've been working on the CSS Grid support. About to land "named grid lines and areas" support which should make a bunch more websites layout correctly.&lt;p&gt;I'm biased because it's my project, but IMO the approach Servo is using for CSS Grid is pretty cool in that the actual implementation is in an external library (Taffy [0]) that can be used standalone and is widely used accross the Rust UI ecosystem, including in the Blitz [1] web engine (which also uses Taffy for Flexbox and Block layout), the Zed [2] text editor, and the Bevy [3] game engine.&lt;p&gt;I'm hopeful that this approach of breaking down a web engine into independently usable modules with public APIs (which builds upon Servo's earlier work on modular libraries such as Stylo and html5ever) will make it easier for people to get involved in web engine development (as they can understand each piece in isolation), and make it easier for people to create new web engines in future (as they won't have to start completely from scratch).&lt;p&gt;[0]: &lt;a href="https://github.com/DioxusLabs/taffy"&gt;https://github.com/DioxusLabs/taffy&lt;/a&gt;
[1]: &lt;a href="https://github.com/DioxusLabs/blitz"&gt;https://github.com/DioxusLabs/blitz&lt;/a&gt;
[2]: &lt;a href="https://zed.dev" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://zed.dev&lt;/a&gt;
[3]: &lt;a href="https://bevy.org/" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://bevy.org/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 31 Jul 2025 12:11:48 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44744821</link><dc:creator>nicoburns</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44744821</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44744821</guid></item></channel></rss>