<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>Hacker News: Best Comments</title><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/bestcomments</link><description>Hacker News RSS</description><docs>https://hnrss.org/</docs><generator>hnrss v2.1.1</generator><lastBuildDate>Fri, 29 Aug 2025 23:39:34 +0000</lastBuildDate><ns0:link href="https://hnrss.org/bestcomments" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item><title>New comment by nomilk in "Some users have noticed settings that let Meta analyze and retain phone photos"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;IMO Apple should provide the user with audit logs of which photos/videos were accessed by each app. It might be a long list but it alleviates doubt and would put huge pressure on reputable developers to ensure they don’t get caught doing things the user wouldn’t have expected (even if the user technically allowed it).&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 29 Aug 2025 12:37:58 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45063289</link><dc:creator>nomilk</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45063289</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45063289</guid></item><item><title>New comment by _verandaguy in "Ask HN: The government of my country blocked VPN access. What should I use?"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Hello! I've got experience working on censorship circumvention for a major VPN provider (in the early 2020s).&lt;p&gt;- First things first, you have to get your hands on actual VPN software and configs. Many providers who are aware of VPN censorship and cater to these locales distribute their VPNs through hard-to-block channels and in obfuscated packages. S3 is a popular option but by no means the only one, and some VPN providers partner with local orgs who can figure out the safest and most efficient ways to distribute a VPN package in countries at risk of censorship or undergoing censorship.&lt;p&gt;- Once you've got the software, you should try to use it with an obfuscation layer.&lt;p&gt;Obfs4proxy is a popular tool here, and relies on a pre-shared key to make traffic look like nothing special. IIRC it also hides the VPN handshake. This isn't a perfectly secure model, but it's good enough to defeat most DPI setups.&lt;p&gt;Another option is Shapeshifter, from Operator (&lt;a href="https://github.com/OperatorFoundation" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://github.com/OperatorFoundation&lt;/a&gt;). Or, in general, anything that uses pluggable transports. While it's a niche technology, it's quite useful in your case.&lt;p&gt;In both cases, the VPN provider must provide support for these protocols.&lt;p&gt;- The toughest step long term is not getting caught using a VPN. By its nature, long-term statistical analysis will often reveal a VPN connection regardless of obfuscation and masking (and this approach can be cheaper to support than DPI by a state actor). I don't know the situation on the ground in Indonesia, so I won't speculate about what the best way to avoid this would be, long-term.&lt;p&gt;I will endorse Mullvad as a trustworthy and technically competent VPN provider in this niche (n.b., I do not work for them, nor have I worked for them; they were a competitor to my employer and we always respected their approach to the space).&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 28 Aug 2025 18:48:36 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45055604</link><dc:creator>_verandaguy</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45055604</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45055604</guid></item><item><title>New comment by AnotherGoodName in "Google has eliminated 35% of managers overseeing small teams in past year"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;This was called the TLM role at google. Technical Lead/Manager. You were expected to code and manage a couple of more junior engineers.&lt;p&gt;It’s part of an effort to have dedicated managers and dedicated engineers instead of hybrid roles.&lt;p&gt;This is being sold as an efficiency win for the sake of the stock price but it’s really just moved a few people around with the TLMs now 100% focused on programming.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 27 Aug 2025 22:01:56 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45045883</link><dc:creator>AnotherGoodName</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45045883</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45045883</guid></item><item><title>New comment by PedroBatista in "The GitHub website is slow on Safari"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;The Github website is slow everywhere. It is truly a piece of shit software both in terms of performance but also UX/UI and everything in between.&lt;p&gt;It's a product of many cooks and their brilliant ideas and KPIs, a social network for devs and code being the most "brilliant" of them all. For day to day dev operations is something so mediocre even Gitlab looks like the golden standard compared to Github.&lt;p&gt;And no, the problem is not "Rails" or [ insert any other tech BS to deflect the real problems ].&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 27 Aug 2025 13:10:57 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45039192</link><dc:creator>PedroBatista</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45039192</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45039192</guid></item><item><title>New comment by JdeBP in "Nx compromised: malware uses Claude code CLI to explore the filesystem"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&gt; Are you using a compromised version of nx?&lt;p&gt;&gt; Run semgrep --config [...]&lt;p&gt;&gt; Alternatively, you can run nx –version [...]&lt;p&gt;Have we not learned, yet?  The number of points this submission has already earned says we have not.&lt;p&gt;People, do not trust security advisors who tell you to do such things, especially ones who also remove the original instructions entirely and replace them with instructions to run their tools instead.&lt;p&gt;The original security advisory is at &lt;a href="https://github.com/nrwl/nx/security/advisories/GHSA-cxm3-wv7p-598c" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://github.com/nrwl/nx/security/advisories/GHSA-cxm3-wv7...&lt;/a&gt; and at no point does it tell you to run the compromised programs in order to determine whether they are compromised versions.  Or to run semgrep for that matter.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 27 Aug 2025 12:55:07 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45038993</link><dc:creator>JdeBP</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45038993</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45038993</guid></item><item><title>New comment by dfabulich in "Claude for Chrome"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Claude for Chrome seems to be walking right into the "lethal trifecta." &lt;a href="https://simonwillison.net/2025/Jun/16/the-lethal-trifecta/" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://simonwillison.net/2025/Jun/16/the-lethal-trifecta/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;"The lethal trifecta of capabilities is:"&lt;p&gt;• &lt;i&gt;Access to your private data&lt;/i&gt;—one of the most common purposes of tools in the first place!&lt;p&gt;• &lt;i&gt;Exposure to untrusted content&lt;/i&gt;—any mechanism by which text (or images) controlled by a malicious attacker could become available to your LLM&lt;p&gt;• &lt;i&gt;The ability to externally communicate&lt;/i&gt; in a way that could be used to steal your data (I often call this “exfiltration” but I’m not confident that term is widely understood.)&lt;p&gt;If your agent combines these three features, an attacker can &lt;i&gt;easily trick it&lt;/i&gt; into accessing your private data and sending it to that attacker.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 27 Aug 2025 01:10:21 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45034300</link><dc:creator>dfabulich</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45034300</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45034300</guid></item><item><title>New comment by podgietaru in "A teen was suicidal. ChatGPT was the friend he confided in"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I have looked suicide in the eyes before. And reading the case file for this is absolutely horrific. He wanted help. He was heading in the direction of help, and he was stopped from getting it.&lt;p&gt;He wanted his parents to find out about his plan. I know this feeling. It is the clawing feeling of knowing that you want to live, despite feeling like you want to die.&lt;p&gt;We are living in such a horrific moment. We need these things to be legislated. Punished. We need to stop treating them as magic. They had the tools to prevent this. They had the tools to stop the conversation. To steer the user into helpful avenues.&lt;p&gt;When I was suicidal, I googled methods. And I got the number of a local hotline. And I rang it. And a kind man talked me down. And it potentially saved my life. And I am happier, now. I live a worthwhile life, now.&lt;p&gt;But at my lowest.. An AI Model designed to match my tone and be sycophantic to my every whim. It would have killed me.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 26 Aug 2025 21:56:22 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45032841</link><dc:creator>podgietaru</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45032841</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45032841</guid></item><item><title>New comment by zaptheimpaler in "We regret but have to temporary suspend the shipments to USA"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&gt; importers must declare the exact amount of steel, copper, and aluminum in products, with a 100% tariff applied to these materials. This makes little sense—PCBs, for instance, contain copper traces, but the quantity is nearly impossible to estimate.&lt;p&gt;Wow this administration is f**ing batshit insane. I thought the tariffs would be on raw metals, not anything at all that happens to contain them.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 26 Aug 2025 17:49:38 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45029926</link><dc:creator>zaptheimpaler</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45029926</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45029926</guid></item><item><title>New comment by georgeburdell in "US Intel"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;If I may add my view as a formerly high-achieving semiconductor worker that Intel would benefit greatly from having right now, a lot of us pivoted to software and machine learning to earn more money.  My first 2 years as a software engineer earned me more RSUs than a decade in semiconductors.  Semiconductors is not prestigious work in the U.S., despite the strategic importance.  By contrast, it is highly respected and relatively well remunerated in the countries doing well in it.&lt;p&gt;From this lens, the silver lining of the software layoffs going on may be to stem the bleeding of semiconductor workers to the field.  If Intel were really smart, they’d be hiring more right now the people they couldn’t get or retain 3-5 years ago&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 26 Aug 2025 14:12:08 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45026847</link><dc:creator>georgeburdell</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45026847</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45026847</guid></item><item><title>New comment by themgt in "US Intel"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;I’ll be honest: there is a very good chance this won’t work .... At the same time, the China concerns are real, Intel Foundry needs a guarantee of existence to even court customers, and there really is no coming back from an exit. There won’t be a startup to fill Intel’s place. The U.S. will be completely dependent on foreign companies for the most important products on earth, and while everything may seem fine for the next five, ten, or even fifteen years, the seeds of that failure will eventually sprout, just like those 2007 seeds sprouted for Intel over the last couple of years. The only difference is that the repercussions of this failure will be catastrophic not for the U.S.’s leading semiconductor company, but for the U.S. itself.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;p&gt;Very well argued. It's such a stunning dereliction the US let things get to this point. We were doing the "pivot to Asia" over a decade ago but no one thought to find TSMC on a map and ask whether Intel was driving itself into the dirt? "For want of a nail the kingdom was lost" but in this case the nail is like your entire metallurgical industry outsourced to the territory you plan on fighting over.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 26 Aug 2025 13:47:25 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45026515</link><dc:creator>themgt</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45026515</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45026515</guid></item><item><title>New comment by arielcostas in "Google will allow only apps from verified developers to be installed on Android"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Meaning to use your device you need to have a contractual relationship with a foreign (unless you are in the US) third party that decides what you can or cannot do with it. Plus using GrapheneOS is less of an option every day, since banks and other "regulated" sectors use Google Play Protect and similar DRMs to prevent you from connecting from whatever device you want. Client-side "trust" means the provider owning the device, not the user.&lt;p&gt;Android shouldn't be considered Open Source anymore, since source code is published in batches and only part of the system is open, with more and more apps going behind the Google ecosystem itself.&lt;p&gt;Maybe it's time for a third large phone OS, whether it comes from China getting fed up with the US and Google's shenanigans (Huawei has HarmonyOS but it's not open) or some "GNU/Linux" touch version that has a serious ecosystem. Especially when more and more apps and services are "mobile-first" or "mobile-only" like banking.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 26 Aug 2025 11:11:45 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45024969</link><dc:creator>arielcostas</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45024969</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45024969</guid></item><item><title>New comment by tgma in "Google will allow only apps from verified developers to be installed on Android"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;The funny thing is Stallman started his fight like half a century ago and on regular days Hacker News shits on him eating something off of his foot and not being polished and diplomatic, and loves practical aspects of Corporate Open Source and gratis goodies and doesn't particularly care about Free Software.&lt;p&gt;On this day suddenly folks come out of the woodwork advocating for  half baked measures to achieve what Stallman portrayed but they still hardly recognize this was EXACTLY his concern when he started the Free Software movement.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 26 Aug 2025 05:37:09 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45022661</link><dc:creator>tgma</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45022661</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45022661</guid></item><item><title>New comment by medhir in "Google will allow only apps from verified developers to be installed on Android"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Every day we stray farther from the premise that we should be allowed to install / modify software on the computers we own.&lt;p&gt;Will once again re-up the concept of a “right to root access”, to prevent big corps from pulling this bs over and over again: &lt;a href="https://medhir.com/blog/right-to-root-access" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://medhir.com/blog/right-to-root-access&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 26 Aug 2025 03:18:33 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45021911</link><dc:creator>medhir</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45021911</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45021911</guid></item><item><title>New comment by rvnx in "Google will allow only apps from verified developers to be installed on Android"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;If this is a thing then the solution they offer is incorrect. A big giant red screen: “warning the identity of this application developer has not been verified and this could be an application stealing your data, etc” would have worked.&lt;p&gt;What they want is to get rid of apps like YouTube Vanced that are making them lose money (and other Play Store apps)&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 26 Aug 2025 03:18:15 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45021908</link><dc:creator>rvnx</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45021908</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45021908</guid></item><item><title>New comment by throw10920 in "Google will allow only apps from verified developers to be installed on Android"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;This is really bad. I think that most people on HN will agree with that.&lt;p&gt;The problem is that most &lt;i&gt;normal&lt;/i&gt; people (HN is not normal - mostly for the better) don't even &lt;i&gt;understand&lt;/i&gt; what sideloading is - let alone actually &lt;i&gt;care&lt;/i&gt;.&lt;p&gt;How can we fix this?&lt;p&gt;(aside from making people care - apathy enables so many political problems in the current age, but it's such a huge problem that &lt;i&gt;this&lt;/i&gt; definitely isn't going to be the impetus to fix it)&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 26 Aug 2025 02:51:51 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45021764</link><dc:creator>throw10920</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45021764</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45021764</guid></item><item><title>New comment by gethly in "Google will allow only apps from verified developers to be installed on Android"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&gt; Google will begin to verify the identities of developers distributing their apps on Android devices, not just those who distribute via the Play Store&lt;p&gt;This is absolutely unacceptable. That's like you having to submit your personal details to Microsoft in order to just run a program on Windows. Absolutely nuts and it will not go as they think it will.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 25 Aug 2025 21:15:40 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45019130</link><dc:creator>gethly</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45019130</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45019130</guid></item><item><title>New comment by Ms-J in "Google will allow only apps from verified developers to be installed on Android"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;This is the worst thing to happen to technology in recent times since there is only two major phone OS's.&lt;p&gt;It isn't possible to ban encryption, so the governments have to chip away at security and privacy using these techniques.&lt;p&gt;From: &lt;a href="https://developer.android.com/developer-verification" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://developer.android.com/developer-verification&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;"You may also need to upload official government ID."&lt;p&gt;This won't end well for Google or the governments involved when the people get so angry that they are forced to roll this back. Switch to an alternative phone OS.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 25 Aug 2025 20:54:59 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45018874</link><dc:creator>Ms-J</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45018874</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45018874</guid></item><item><title>New comment by jdlshore in "Meta just suspended the Facebook account of Neal Stephenson"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;For people missing the irony here, the term “metaverse,” that Meta is named after, was coined by Neal Stephenson in his 1992 book “Snow Crash.”&lt;p&gt;In the book, the metaverse is a VR version of the internet with an emphasis on accurate sword fights and realistic facial expressions.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 25 Aug 2025 20:13:56 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45018435</link><dc:creator>jdlshore</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45018435</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45018435</guid></item><item><title>New comment by EMIRELADERO in "Google will allow only apps from verified developers to be installed on Android"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;So that's it then.&lt;p&gt;If this actually goes through, there will be no option in the mobile OS market for an OS that both:&lt;p&gt;a) allows the installation of apps without any contractual relationship with any party, and&lt;p&gt;b) allows the use of mainstream and secure apps like banking&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 25 Aug 2025 20:11:24 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45018413</link><dc:creator>EMIRELADERO</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45018413</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45018413</guid></item><item><title>New comment by 87636899376 in "Google will allow only apps from verified developers to be installed on Android"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Official announcement: &lt;a href="https://android-developers.googleblog.com/2025/08/elevating-android-security.html" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://android-developers.googleblog.com/2025/08/elevating-...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;More info:&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://developer.android.com/developer-verification" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://developer.android.com/developer-verification&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://support.google.com/googleplay/android-developer/answer/16471116" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://support.google.com/googleplay/android-developer/answ...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;Personally...we all know the Play Store is chock full of malicious garbage, so the verification requirements there don't do jack to protect users. The way I see it, this is nothing but a power grab, a way for Google to kill apps like Revanced for good. They'll just find some bullshit reason to suspend your developer account if you do something they don't like.&lt;p&gt;Every time I hear mentions of "safety" from the folks at Google, I'm reminded that there's a hidden Internet permission on Android that can neuter 95% of malicious apps. But it's hidden, apparently because keeping users from using it to block ads on apps is of greater concern to Google than keeping people safe.&lt;p&gt;&gt; we will be confirming who the developer is, not reviewing the content of their app or where it came from&lt;p&gt;This is such an odd statement. I mean, surely they have to be willing to review the contents of apps at &lt;i&gt;some&lt;/i&gt; point (if only to suspend the accounts of developers who are actually producing malware), or else this whole affair does nothing but introduce friction.&lt;p&gt;TFA had me believing that bypassing the restriction might've been possible by disabling Play Protect, but that doesn't seem to be the case since there aren't any mentions of it in the official info we've been given.&lt;p&gt;On the flip side, that's one less platform I care about supporting with my projects. We're down to just Linux and Windows if you're not willing to sell your soul (no, I will not be making a Google account) just for the right to develop for a certain platform.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 25 Aug 2025 20:01:04 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45018297</link><dc:creator>87636899376</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45018297</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45018297</guid></item><item><title>New comment by stn8188 in "Building the mouse Logitech won't make"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;"Balking at the $50+ charge for turnkey assembly, I opted to take the financially responsible route and pay $200+ for a hot-air rework station to solder it myself."&lt;p&gt;Yeah, I feel this :)&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 25 Aug 2025 16:06:26 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45015355</link><dc:creator>stn8188</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45015355</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45015355</guid></item><item><title>New comment by torginus in "Is 4chan the perfect Pirate Bay poster child to justify wider UK site-blocking?"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I genuinely do not understand where how the idea of building a total surveillance police state, where all speech is monitored, can even as much as seriously be considered by an allegedly pro-democracy, pro-human rights government, much less make it into law.&lt;p&gt;Also:&lt;p&gt;Step 1: Build mass surveillance to prevent the 'bad guys' from coming into political power (its ok, we're the good guys).&lt;p&gt;Step 2: Your political opponents capitalize on your genuinely horrific overreach, and legitimize themselves in the eyes of the public as fighting against tyranny (unfortunately for you they do have a point). They promise to dismantle the system if coming to power.&lt;p&gt;Step 3: They get elected.&lt;p&gt;Step 4: They don't dismantle the system, now the people you planned to use the system against are using it against you.&lt;p&gt;Sounds brilliant, lets do this.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 25 Aug 2025 08:26:55 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45011561</link><dc:creator>torginus</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45011561</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45011561</guid></item><item><title>New comment by Apreche in "Is 4chan the perfect Pirate Bay poster child to justify wider UK site-blocking?"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;If they do it, I never want to hear any criticism of the great firewall of China from them ever again.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 24 Aug 2025 17:53:52 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45006225</link><dc:creator>Apreche</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45006225</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45006225</guid></item><item><title>New comment by VincentEvans in "We put a coding agent in a while loop"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;There will be a a new kind of job for software engineers, sort of like a cross between working with legacy code and toxic site cleanup.&lt;p&gt;Like back in the day being brought in to “just fix” a amalgam of FoxPro-, Excel-, and Access-based ERP that “mostly works” and only “occasionally corrupts all our data” that ambitious sales people put together over last 5 years.&lt;p&gt;But worse - because “ambitious sales people” will no longer be constrained by sandboxes of Excel or Access - they will ship multi-cloud edge-deployed kubernetes micro-services wired with Kafka, and it will be harder to find someone to talk to understand what they were trying to do at the time.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 24 Aug 2025 16:36:02 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45005596</link><dc:creator>VincentEvans</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45005596</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45005596</guid></item><item><title>New comment by jjcm in "U.S. government takes 10% stake in Intel"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;In general I would rather the government take a stake in corporations they're bailing out. I think the "too big to fail" bailouts in the past should have come with more of a cost for the business, so on one hand I'm glad this is finally happening.&lt;p&gt;On the other hand, I wish it were a more formalized process rather than this politicized "our president made a deal to save america!" / "Intel is back and the government is investing BUY INTEL SHARES" media event. These things should follow a strict set of rules and processes so investors and companies know what to expect. These kind of deals should be boring, not a media event.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 22 Aug 2025 22:36:27 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44990743</link><dc:creator>jjcm</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44990743</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44990743</guid></item><item><title>New comment by sobiolite in "U.S. government takes 10% stake in Intel"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Ironic, Western politicians thought opening up to trade with China would lead to it adopting a Western model of government. Instead it's lead to the USA adopting the Chinese one.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 22 Aug 2025 22:04:07 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44990406</link><dc:creator>sobiolite</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44990406</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44990406</guid></item><item><title>New comment by afcool83 in "Waymo granted permit to begin testing in New York City"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I live in one of the areas they are actively testing/training in. Their cars consistently behave better and more safely than most human drivers that I’m forced to share the road with.&lt;p&gt;As semi-autonomous and autonomous cars become the norm, I would adore to see obtaining a drivers license ratchet up in difficulty in order to remove dangerous &lt;i&gt;human&lt;/i&gt; drivers from the road.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 22 Aug 2025 19:20:26 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44988724</link><dc:creator>afcool83</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44988724</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44988724</guid></item><item><title>New comment by nickdothutton in "4chan will refuse to pay daily online safety fines, lawyer tells BBC"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Step 1, pass law.&lt;p&gt;Step 2, demand compliance.&lt;p&gt;Step 3, upon not hearing of compliance, levy fines.&lt;p&gt;Step 4, upon non payment of fines, declare in breach of (2).&lt;p&gt;Step 5, block site from UK using DNS, in the same manner as torrent sites etc.&lt;p&gt;5 was always the goal, 2 to 4 are largely just performative.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 22 Aug 2025 12:15:59 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44983582</link><dc:creator>nickdothutton</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44983582</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44983582</guid></item><item><title>New comment by blixt in "Go is still not good"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I've been using Go more or less in every full-time job I've had since pre-1.0. It's simple for people on the team to pick up the basics, it generally chugs along (I'm rarely worried about updating to latest version of Go), it has most useful things built in, it compiles fast. Concurrency is tricky but if you spend some time with it, it's nice to express data flow in Go. The type system is most of the time very convenient, if sometimes a bit verbose. Just all-around a trusty tool in the belt.&lt;p&gt;But I can't help but agree with a lot of points in this article. Go was designed by some old-school folks that maybe stuck a bit too hard to their principles, losing sight of the practical conveniences. That said, it's a _feeling_ I have, and maybe Go would be much worse if it had solved all these quirks. To be fair, I see more leniency in fixing quirks in the last few years, like at some point I didn't think we'd ever see generics, or custom iterators, etc.&lt;p&gt;The points about RAM and portability seem mostly like personal grievances though. If it was better, that would be nice, of course. But the GC in Go is very unlikely to cause issues in most programs even at very large scale, and it's not that hard to debug. And Go runs on most platforms anyone could ever wish to ship their software on.&lt;p&gt;But yeah the whole error / nil situation still bothers me. I find myself wishing for Result[Ok, Err] and Optional[T] quite often.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 22 Aug 2025 11:35:29 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44983245</link><dc:creator>blixt</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44983245</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44983245</guid></item><item><title>New comment by dcastonguay in "I forced every engineer to take sales calls and they rewrote our platform"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&gt; At the end of it, they were sketching a completely different architecture without my "PMing". Because they finally understood who was actually using our product.&lt;p&gt;I cannot help but read this whole experience as: “We forced an engineer to take sales calls and we found out that the issue was that our PMs are doing a terrible job communicating between customer and engineering, and our DevOps engineer is more capable/actionable at turning customer needs into working solutions.”&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 21 Aug 2025 16:17:52 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44974574</link><dc:creator>dcastonguay</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44974574</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44974574</guid></item></channel></rss>