<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>Hacker News: Best Comments</title><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/bestcomments</link><description>Hacker News RSS</description><docs>https://hnrss.org/</docs><generator>hnrss v2.1.1</generator><lastBuildDate>Fri, 19 Dec 2025 00:04:12 +0000</lastBuildDate><ns0:link href="https://hnrss.org/bestcomments" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item><title>New comment by mccoyb in "GPT-5.2-Codex"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;If anyone from OpenAI is reading this -- a plea to not screw with the reasoning capabilities!&lt;p&gt;Codex is so so good at finding bugs and little inconsistencies, it's astounding to me. Where Claude Code is good at "raw coding", Codex/GPT5.x are unbeatable in terms of careful, methodical finding of "problems" (be it in code, or in math).&lt;p&gt;Yes, it takes longer (quality, not speed please!) -- but the things that it finds consistently astound me.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 18:31:30 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46316606</link><dc:creator>mccoyb</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46316606</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46316606</guid></item><item><title>New comment by endorphine in "Your job is to deliver code you have proven to work"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&gt; there’s one depressing anecdote that I keep on seeing: the junior engineer, empowered by some class of LLM tool, who deposits giant, untested PRs on their coworkers—or open source maintainers—and expects the “code review” process to handle the rest.&lt;p&gt;It's even worse than that: &lt;i&gt;non&lt;/i&gt;-junior devs are doing it
as well.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 16:10:07 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46314509</link><dc:creator>endorphine</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46314509</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46314509</guid></item><item><title>New comment by recursivedoubts in "Please just try HTMX"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Hey, I created htmx and while I appreciate the publicity, I’m not a huge fan of these types of hyperbolic articles. There are lots of different ways to build web apps with their own strengths and weaknesses.  I try to assess htmx’s strengths and weaknesses here:&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://htmx.org/essays/when-to-use-hypermedia/" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://htmx.org/essays/when-to-use-hypermedia/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;Also, please try unpoly:&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://unpoly.com/" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://unpoly.com/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;It’s another excellent hypermedia oriented library&lt;p&gt;Edit: the article is actually not nearly as unreasonable as I thought based on the just-f*king-use template. Still prefer a chill vibe for htmx though.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 15:26:29 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46313750</link><dc:creator>recursivedoubts</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46313750</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46313750</guid></item><item><title>New comment by oidar in "Are Apple gift cards safe to redeem?"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I'm glad that got resolved for Paris, but what the hell is a normal person supposed to do. Not every one has that kind of public reach to get a satisfactory resolution.  First he had understand what happened technically, then he needed a public platform to tell people about it, then that writing needed to get reposted by others, than PR needed to get involved. Not something that's going to happen for a normal user.&lt;p&gt;Apple, Google, and the big players are not a trustworthy place to entrust precious data. Increasingly, Apple and Google aren't very much different as they are both in the advertisement business: the great misaligner of incentives.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 14:52:40 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46313303</link><dc:creator>oidar</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46313303</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46313303</guid></item><item><title>New comment by Geonode in "Classical statues were not painted horribly"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I will die on this hill, because I'm right. Painters put on the first layer in saturated colors like this, then add detail, highlight and shadow. The base layer stuck to the statues, and the rest was washed away.&lt;p&gt;This whole thing just won't go away because many people are operating outside their area of expertise on this subject.&lt;p&gt;Painters layer paint, starting with a saturated base color. These archaeologists are simply looking at the paint that was left in the crevices.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 14:10:50 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46312879</link><dc:creator>Geonode</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46312879</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46312879</guid></item><item><title>New comment by flowerthoughts in "Independent review of UK national security law warns of overreach"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&gt; He warns that developers of apps like Signal and WhatsApp could technically fall within the legal definition of "hostile activity" simply because their technology "make[s] it more difficult for UK security and intelligence agencies to monitor communications.&lt;p&gt;Sounds like Let's Encrypt would also fall under that.&lt;p&gt;This has got to stop. If you want to stop criminals, then focus on their illegal activites, not the streets they walk on. I walk on them too. And don't use CP as a catch-all argument to insert backdoors.&lt;p&gt;Their big problem here is that previously, it was hard to find people with the same opinion as you. If you couldn't find someone in the same village who wanted to start a rebellion, it probably wouldn't happen. Today, someone can post a Telegram group message and make thousands of people rally to a town square. I see the dangers, and I see why governments think they are doing this to protect the people. No one wants civil war. That is still not a strong enough reason to call road construction a hostile activity.&lt;p&gt;I'm back in Sweden after 12 years abroad. Time to read up on which parties are sane and which aren't when it comes to technical infrastructure.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 12:16:41 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46311760</link><dc:creator>flowerthoughts</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46311760</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46311760</guid></item><item><title>New comment by skwee357 in "Ask HN: Those making $500/month on side projects in 2025 – Show and tell"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I run a dead-simple, one-time, online fax service called JustFax Online[0].
While I don't have a recurring revenue as I operate one one-time payment, for the past months I have been consistently grossing over €500/mo.&lt;p&gt;This also brings tears to my eyes, as I remember[1] browsing these threads and being amazed (still am) by all the people who make side projects and make money from them, and at the same time thinking that I will never reach this milestone, and yet, here I am.&lt;p&gt;[0]: &lt;a href="https://justfaxonline.com" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://justfaxonline.com&lt;/a&gt;
[1]: &lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=39110194#39141819"&gt;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=39110194#39141819&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 08:22:14 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46310161</link><dc:creator>skwee357</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46310161</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46310161</guid></item><item><title>New comment by MathiasPius in "Ask HN: Does anyone understand how Hacker News works?"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;It sometimes blows my mind how questions which essentially boil down to "How do I best manipulate you for personal gain?" can be asked in such an unabashed fashion.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 08:16:45 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46310130</link><dc:creator>MathiasPius</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46310130</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46310130</guid></item><item><title>New comment by jacquesm in "Ask HN: Does anyone understand how Hacker News works?"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;HN is hard to game on purpose. So stop looking for the levers and &lt;i&gt;participate&lt;/i&gt;, that's all there is to it. I've made friends here, have been helped by people on projects that I was busy with, did the reverse, found friends and business partners and spend way too much time. HN is a very interesting slice of the online world, a place that is unlike the rest, sometimes a bit dry but always interesting and &lt;i&gt;extremely&lt;/i&gt; useful. If you're looking at it to try to understand it then you might as well try to understand a rat or a mouse. You won't understand it because it isn't there to be understood, it just is, like any other organism.&lt;p&gt;The root of HN is a thing called 'startup news', that was changed very quickly and since then HN has been a focal point for techies of all sorts but also lots of other people from all walks of life and from a large variety of countries. It isn't 'one thing' to everybody that participates, just like a hammer is a different thing for a carpenter than it is for a masoner or a farmer.&lt;p&gt;The fact that after being a member for a couple of years you have this question indicates a lack of participation, not a lack of understanding.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 07:25:11 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46309842</link><dc:creator>jacquesm</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46309842</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46309842</guid></item><item><title>New comment by dang in "Ask HN: Does anyone understand how Hacker News works?"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;(I'm a mod here)&lt;p&gt;It's true that this place can be cryptic, and that has downsides—specifically, it can be confusing to newcomers, even to some newcomers who would make ideal HN users. That sucks.&lt;p&gt;But there's a key that unlocks most of the puzzles. That is to understand that we're optimizing for exactly one thing: curiosity. (Specifically, intellectual curiosity, since there are other kinds of curiosity too.) Here are links to past explanations about that: &lt;a href="https://hn.algolia.com/?dateRange=all&amp;page=0&amp;prefix=true&amp;sort=byDate&amp;type=comment&amp;query=curiosity%20optimiz%20by:dang" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://hn.algolia.com/?dateRange=all&amp;page=0&amp;prefix=true&amp;sor...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;We try to elevate things that gratify curiosity: creative work, surprising discoveries, deep dives, technical achievements, unusual personal experience, whimsical unpredictability, good conversation, etc. And we try to demote things that run against curiosity, especially repetition, indignation, sensationalism, and promotion.&lt;p&gt;It gets complicated because you'll also see plenty of repetition, indignation, sensationalism, and promotion on HN—alas! This is the internet after all. But the site survives because the balance of these things stays within tolerable ranges, thanks to two factors: an active community which cares greatly about preserving this place for intended purpose (&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/newsguidelines.html"&gt;https://news.ycombinator.com/newsguidelines.html&lt;/a&gt;); and an owner (Y Combinator) which pays us to work on the site full time and mainly just wants us to keep it good, to the extent possible.&lt;p&gt;If you really want to figure this place out, the way to do it is as a &lt;i&gt;reader&lt;/i&gt;. Hang out on the site, look at the mix of articles that make the frontpage, spend time in the discussion threads (hopefully the interesting sectors and not the flamey ones!), and over time your eyes will adjust.&lt;p&gt;What doesn't work—and this is good because we want it not to work—is approaching HN as a platform for promoting content. If you (&lt;-- I don't mean you personally, but anyone) mainly care about "how can I use this thing to get attention for my startup/blog/project/newsletter", then you're operating in 'push' mode rather than 'pull' mode (or, even better, 'idle' mode). In that case you won't be curious because you're too focused on what you're wanting for extraneous reasons—and if you aren't in a state of curiosity, this place won't make sense. At least we hope it won't!&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 06:06:09 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46309399</link><dc:creator>dang</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46309399</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46309399</guid></item><item><title>New comment by 3np in "I got hacked: My Hetzner server started mining Monero"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&gt; I also enabled UFW (which I should have done ages ago)&lt;p&gt;I disrecommend UFW.&lt;p&gt;firewalld is a much better pick in current year and will not grow unmaintainable the way UFW rules can.&lt;p&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;    firewall-cmd --persistent --set-default-zone=block
    firewall-cmd --persistent --zone=block --add-service=ssh
    firewall-cmd --persistent --zone=block --add-service=https
    firewall-cmd --persistent --zone=block --add-port=80/tcp
    firewall-cmd --reload
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
Configuration is backed by xml files in /etc/firewalld and /usr/lib/firewalld instead of the brittle pile of sticks that is the ufw rules files. Use the nftables backend unless you have your own reasons for needing legacy iptables.&lt;p&gt;Specifically for docker it is a very common gotcha that the container runtime can and will bypass firewall rules and open ports anyway. Depending on your configuration, those firewall rules in OP may not actually do anything to prevent docker from opening incoming ports.&lt;p&gt;Newer versions of firewalld gives an easy way to configure this via StrictForwardPorts=yes in /etc/firewalld/firewalld.conf.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 23:18:27 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46306974</link><dc:creator>3np</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46306974</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46306974</guid></item><item><title>New comment by jonny_eh in "Tell HN: HN was down"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Your sleep is more important than our work distraction.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 19:51:33 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46304618</link><dc:creator>jonny_eh</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46304618</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46304618</guid></item><item><title>New comment by rsanek in "AWS CEO says replacing junior devs with AI is 'one of the dumbest ideas'"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;"without losing face"? What culture are you referring to? The Western companies I have worked at do not discourage such questions -- in fact, it's often the sign of someone very senior when they ask a seemingly 'dumb' question that others have taken for granted.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 19:46:30 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46304549</link><dc:creator>rsanek</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46304549</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46304549</guid></item><item><title>New comment by alexgotoi in "AWS CEO says replacing junior devs with AI is 'one of the dumbest ideas'"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;The thing people miss in these “replace juniors with AI” takes is that juniors were never mainly about cheap hands on keyboards. They’re the only people in the org who are still allowed to ask “dumb” questions without losing face, and those questions are often the only signal you get that your abstractions are nonsense.&lt;p&gt;What AI does is remove a bunch of the humiliating, boring parts of being junior: hunting for the right API by cargo-culting Stack Overflow, grinding through boilerplate, getting stuck for hours on a missing import. If a half-decent model can collapse that search space for them, you get to spend more of their ramp time on “here’s how our system actually fits together” instead of “here’s how for-loops work in our house style”.&lt;p&gt;If you take that setup and then decide “cool, now we don’t need juniors at all”, you’re basically saying you want a company with no memory and no farm system – just an ever-shrinking ring of seniors arguing about strategy while no one actually grows into them.&lt;p&gt;Always love to include a good AI x work thread in my &lt;a href="https://hackernewsai.com/" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://hackernewsai.com/&lt;/a&gt; newsletter.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 19:16:40 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46304163</link><dc:creator>alexgotoi</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46304163</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46304163</guid></item><item><title>New comment by dang in "Tell HN: HN was down"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;failing to manage HN in my sleep is more like it&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 18:53:02 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46303812</link><dc:creator>dang</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46303812</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46303812</guid></item><item><title>New comment by shlomo_z in "Tell HN: HN was down"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Crazy that Dang literally manages HN in his sleep!&lt;p&gt;We all knew that but I haven't seen any confirmation before this.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 18:38:06 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46303586</link><dc:creator>shlomo_z</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46303586</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46303586</guid></item><item><title>New comment by beAbU in "AWS CEO says replacing junior devs with AI is 'one of the dumbest ideas'"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Isn't the struggling with docs and learning how and where to find the answers part of the learning process?&lt;p&gt;I would argue a machine that short circuits the process of getting stuck in obtuse documentation is actually harmful long term...&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 18:29:21 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46303471</link><dc:creator>beAbU</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46303471</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46303471</guid></item><item><title>New comment by dang in "Tell HN: HN was down"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Yes, sorry! We're investigating, but my current theory is we got overloaded because I relaxed some of our anti-crawler protections a few days ago.&lt;p&gt;(The reason I did that is that the anti-crawler protections also unfortunately hit some legit users, and we don't want to block legit users. However, it seems that I turned the knobs down too far.)&lt;p&gt;In this case, though, we had a secondary failure: PagerDuty woke me up at 5:24am, I checked HN and it seemed fine, so I told PagerDuty the problem was resolved. But the problem wasn't resolved - at that point I was just sleeping through it.&lt;p&gt;I'll add more as we find out more, but it probably won't be till later this afternoon PST.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 18:09:25 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46303196</link><dc:creator>dang</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46303196</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46303196</guid></item><item><title>New comment by simonw in "AWS CEO says replacing junior devs with AI is 'one of the dumbest ideas'"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Relevant post by Kent Beck from 12th Dec 2025: The Bet On Juniors Just Got Better &lt;a href="https://tidyfirst.substack.com/p/the-bet-on-juniors-just-got-better" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://tidyfirst.substack.com/p/the-bet-on-juniors-just-got...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;&gt; The juniors working this way compress their ramp dramatically. Tasks that used to take days take hours. Not because the AI does the work, but because the AI collapses the search space. Instead of spending three hours figuring out which API to use, they spend twenty minutes evaluating options the AI surfaced. The time freed this way isn’t invested in another unprofitable feature, though, it’s invested in learning. [...]&lt;p&gt;&gt; If you’re an engineering manager thinking about hiring: The junior bet has gotten better. Not because juniors have changed, but because the genie, used well, accelerates learning.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 17:26:47 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46302565</link><dc:creator>simonw</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46302565</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46302565</guid></item><item><title>New comment by Elfener in "Tell HN: HN was down"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I got stuck in an infinite loop.&lt;p&gt;Try opening HN -&gt; it's down, better check HN to see everyone talking about a major website being down -&gt; Try opening HN -&gt; loop&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 17:09:28 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46302283</link><dc:creator>Elfener</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46302283</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46302283</guid></item><item><title>New comment by manbitesdog in "Tell HN: HN was down"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;TIL I have a "open Hacker News" hand reflex&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 16:51:43 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46301962</link><dc:creator>manbitesdog</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46301962</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46301962</guid></item><item><title>New comment by samyok in "Gemini 3 Flash: Frontier intelligence built for speed"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Don’t let the “flash” name fool you, this is an amazing model.&lt;p&gt;I have been playing with it for the past few weeks, it’s genuinely my new favorite; it’s so fast and it has such a vast world knowledge that it’s more performant than Claude Opus 4.5 or GPT 5.2 extra high, for a fraction (basically order of magnitude less!!) of the inference time and price&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 16:46:20 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46301897</link><dc:creator>samyok</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46301897</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46301897</guid></item><item><title>New comment by kace91 in "Coursera to combine with Udemy"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;As someone who had to drop out of school in the 2008 crisis (family trouble), I owe a good chunk of my learning to the first era of online teaching.&lt;p&gt;Those courses that were basically “we’re a top university and we let someone record the class from the back” were a literal life changer. Honestly, that was all I wanted.&lt;p&gt;Everything that came after has been substantially worse. Work is gamified, teachers spend more time building an audience than creating the product… it’s all horribly tainted by profit.&lt;p&gt;If we went back to recording lectures by the worlds best and putting it online for free with attached books and exercises, we could improve the world a lot.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 13:38:39 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46301812</link><dc:creator>kace91</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46301812</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46301812</guid></item><item><title>New comment by throwaway613745 in "Is Mozilla trying hard to kill itself?"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I have used Firefox as my default browser through thick and thin for damn near two decades.&lt;p&gt;If Mozilla killed andblocking extensions I’d switch to Helium Browser in a heartbeat since they’re maintaining manifest v2 support for uBO and even ship it OOTB.&lt;p&gt;The web is unusable without a proper Adblock.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 12:16:20 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46301111</link><dc:creator>throwaway613745</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46301111</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46301111</guid></item><item><title>New comment by JoeJonathan in "Is Mozilla trying hard to kill itself?"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Like many others, the ability to run uBO is the main reason I use Firefox. Otherwise I'd use Chrome or Safari.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 11:37:05 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46300847</link><dc:creator>JoeJonathan</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46300847</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46300847</guid></item><item><title>New comment by nialv7 in "Is Mozilla trying hard to kill itself?"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;The interpretation is not the problem. Whether he will do it, is actually secondary to the fact that he thinks cutting adblock can bringing in money.&lt;p&gt;No, it will just kill the browser. The fact he thinks otherwise tells me how out of touch he is.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 10:41:53 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46300387</link><dc:creator>nialv7</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46300387</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46300387</guid></item><item><title>New comment by lxgr in "Is Mozilla trying hard to kill itself?"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&gt;&gt; He says he could begin to block ad blockers in Firefox and estimates that’d bring in another $150 million, but he doesn’t want to do that. It feels off-mission.&lt;p&gt;&gt; It may be just me, but I read this as “I don't want to   but I'll kill AdBlockers in Firefox for buckerinos ”.&lt;p&gt;Yes, that does seem like a pretty uncharitable interpretation of that quote. I read it as "we won't do it, even though it would bring in $150M USD".&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 10:30:18 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46300288</link><dc:creator>lxgr</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46300288</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46300288</guid></item><item><title>New comment by herobird in "Is Mozilla trying hard to kill itself?"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;It's kinda frustrating that Mozilla's CEO thinks that axing ad-blockers would be financially beneficial for them. Quite the opposite is true (I believe) since a ton of users would leave Firefox for alternatives.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 10:18:56 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46300189</link><dc:creator>herobird</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46300189</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46300189</guid></item><item><title>New comment by QuadrupleA in "AI will make formal verification go mainstream"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I don't think formal verification really addresses most day-to-day programming problems:&lt;p&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;    * A user interface is confusing, or the English around it is unclear
    * An API you rely on changes, is deprecated, etc.
    * Users use something in unexpected ways
    * Updates forced by vendors or open source projects cause things to break
    * The customer isn't clear what they want
    * Complex behavior between interconnected systems, out of the purview of the formal language (OS + database + network + developer + VM + browser + user + web server)
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
For some mathematically pure task, sure, it's great. Or a low-level library like a regular expression parser or a compression codec. But I don't think that represents a lot of what most of us are tasked with, and those low-level "mathematically pure" libraries are generally pretty well handled by now.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 03:46:12 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46298001</link><dc:creator>QuadrupleA</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46298001</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46298001</guid></item><item><title>New comment by inkysigma in "No AI* Here – A Response to Mozilla's Next Chapter"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&gt; Large language models are something else entirely*. They are black boxes. You cannot audit them. You cannot truly understand what they do with your data. You cannot verify their behaviour. And Mozilla wants to put them at the heart of the browser and that doesn't sit well.&lt;p&gt;Am I being overly critical here or is this kind of a silly position to have right after talking about how neural machine translation is okay? Many of Firefox's LLM features like summarization afaik are powered by local models (hell even Chrome has local model options). It's weird to say neural translation is not a black box but LLMs are somehow black boxes that we cannot hope to understand what they do with the data, especially when viewed a bit fuzzily LLMs are scaled up versions of an architecture that was originally used for neural translation. Neural translation also has unverifiable behavior in the same sense.&lt;p&gt;I could interpret some of the data talk as talking about non local models but this very much seems like a more general criticism of LLMs as a whole when talking about Firefox features. Moreover, some of the critiques like verifiability of outputs and unlimited scope still don't make sense in this context. Browser LLM features except for explicitly AI browsers like Comet have so far had some scoping to their behavior, either in very narrow scopes like translation or summarization. The broadest scope I can think of is the side panels that show up which allow you to ask about a web page with context. Even then, I do not see what is inherently problematic about such scoping since the output behavior is confined to the side panel.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 00:13:27 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46296574</link><dc:creator>inkysigma</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46296574</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46296574</guid></item></channel></rss>