<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>Hacker News: Best Comments</title><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/bestcomments</link><description>Hacker News RSS</description><docs>https://hnrss.org/</docs><generator>hnrss v2.1.1</generator><lastBuildDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 01:31:11 +0000</lastBuildDate><ns0:link href="https://hnrss.org/bestcomments" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item><title>New comment by andy99 in "LinkedIn is loud, and corporate is hell"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Is there some legitimate thing people are doing on LinkedIn that the crap is getting in the way of? One can make a profile and (thought it’s terrible for this) search for jobs without ever scrolling the feed. If you don’t like it just don’t use it.&lt;p&gt;It feels like complaining that the strip bar has alcohol and nudity everywhere, why are you there?&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2025 22:03:20 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46073603</link><dc:creator>andy99</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46073603</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46073603</guid></item><item><title>New comment by ricardo81 in "We're losing our voice to LLMs"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I deleted my Facebook account a couple of years ago and my Twitter one yesterday.&lt;p&gt;It's not just LLMs, it's how the algorithms promote engagement. i.e. rage bait, videos with obvious inaccuracies etc. Who gets rewarded, the content creators and the platform. Engaging with it just seems to accentuate the problem.&lt;p&gt;There needs to be algorithms that promote cohorts and individuals preferences.&lt;p&gt;Just because I said to someone 'Brexit was dumb', I don't expect to get fed 1000 accounts talking about it 24/7. It's tedious and unproductive.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2025 16:01:14 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46070473</link><dc:creator>ricardo81</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46070473</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46070473</guid></item><item><title>New comment by m4r1k in "TPUs vs. GPUs and why Google is positioned to win AI race in the long term"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Google's real moat isn't the TPU silicon itself—it's not about cooling, individual performance, or hyper-specialization—but rather the massive parallel scale enabled by their OCS interconnects.&lt;p&gt;To quote The Next Platform: "An Ironwood cluster linked with Google’s absolutely unique optical circuit switch interconnect can bring to bear 9,216 Ironwood TPUs with a combined 1.77 PB of HBM memory... This makes a rackscale Nvidia system based on 144 “Blackwell” GPU chiplets with an aggregate of 20.7 TB of HBM memory look like a joke."&lt;p&gt;Nvidia may have the superior architecture at the single-chip level, but for large-scale distributed training (and inference) they currently have nothing that rivals Google's optical switching scalability.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2025 15:42:27 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46070265</link><dc:creator>m4r1k</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46070265</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46070265</guid></item><item><title>New comment by cobertos in "Mixpanel Security Breach"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I _hate_ how this is written. At no point does it disclose explicitly:&lt;p&gt;* What systems were accessed&lt;p&gt;* What information was potentially exposed&lt;p&gt;* Just how "proactively" they've been about this (no timeline)&lt;p&gt;* Numbers... The scale of any of it&lt;p&gt;---&lt;p&gt;Some comments from quoted portions of article&lt;p&gt;&gt; Mixpanel detected a smishing campaign ...&lt;p&gt;Doesn't give any details on who the companion targeted, or how, or how widespread.&lt;p&gt;&gt; We took comprehensive steps to contain and eradicate unauthorized access and secure impacted user accounts.&lt;p&gt;So there was definitely _some_ sort of unauthorized access, but doesn't say to which accounts or in what systems&lt;p&gt;&gt; Performed global password resets for all Mixpanel employees&lt;p&gt;So... definitely sounds like they expected compromise of Mixpanel employee credentials&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2025 08:48:32 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46067189</link><dc:creator>cobertos</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46067189</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46067189</guid></item><item><title>New comment by jetsnoc in "Tell HN: Happy Thanksgiving"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Sixteen years here, and the half-life decay of this community has been slower than anywhere else. That takes real, consistent work, and we have been lucky to have it. Through good times and rough ones, including the loss of Aaron Swartz (who I only knew of through HN), this has stayed a place for real conversation.&lt;p&gt;The grit, curiosity, and people building things have always been inspiring.&lt;p&gt;Thanks for all the discussions over the years.&lt;p&gt;Happy Thanksgiving!&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2025 05:52:21 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46066132</link><dc:creator>jetsnoc</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46066132</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46066132</guid></item><item><title>New comment by quantummagic in "Migrating the main Zig repository from GitHub to Codeberg"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Codes of conduct are perfunctory virtue signalling.  Do we really need a unique set of "rules" posted on every project?  They all sound like they were written by the same AI bot.  That said, it's telling that the Zig leader can't even follow them.  The rules should just be taken down.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2025 05:03:52 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46065858</link><dc:creator>quantummagic</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46065858</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46065858</guid></item><item><title>New comment by ericpruitt in "Migrating the main Zig repository from GitHub to Codeberg"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Amusingly, this post violates Zig's own code of conduct: &lt;a href="https://ziglang.org/code-of-conduct" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://ziglang.org/code-of-conduct&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;&gt; Examples of behavior that contribute to creating a positive environment include:&lt;p&gt;&gt; - Using welcoming and inclusive language.&lt;p&gt;&gt; - Being respectful of differing viewpoints and experiences.&lt;p&gt;&gt; - Showing empathy towards others.&lt;p&gt;&gt; - Showing appreciation for others’ work.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2025 04:49:02 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46065778</link><dc:creator>ericpruitt</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46065778</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46065778</guid></item><item><title>New comment by ssivark in "Migrating the main Zig repository from GitHub to Codeberg"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&gt;  created by monkeys&lt;p&gt;I don't particularly care for either Zig or Github, but...&lt;p&gt;they do precisely cite the technical issues. That snippet links to a Github discussion comment &lt;a href="https://github.com/actions/runner/issues/3792#issuecomment-3182746514" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://github.com/actions/runner/issues/3792#issuecomment-3...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;(reproduced below)&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;"The bug in this "safe sleep" script is obvious from looking at it: if the process is not scheduled for the one-second interval in which the loop would return (due to $SECONDS having the correct value), then it simply spins forever. That can easily happen on a CI machine under extreme load. When this happens, it's pretty bad: it completely breaks a runner until manual intervention. On Zig's CI runner machines, we observed multiple of these processes which had been running for hundreds of hours, silently taking down two runner services for weeks."&lt;/i&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;"I don't understand how we got here. Even ignoring the pretty clear bug, what makes this Bash script "safer" than calling into the POSIX standard sleep utility? It doesn't seem to solve any problem; meanwhile, it's less portable and needlessly eats CPU time by busy-waiting."&lt;/i&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;"The sloppy coding which is evident here, as well as the inaction on core Actions bugs (in line with the decay in quality of almost every part of GitHub's product), is forcing the Zig project to strongly consider moving away from GitHub Actions entirely. With this bug, and many others (severe workflow scheduling issues resulting in dozens of timeouts; logs randomly becoming inaccessible; random job cancellations without details; perpetually "pending" jobs), we can no longer trust that Actions can be used to implement reliable CI infrastructure. I personally would seriously encourage other projects, particularly any using self-hosted runners, to look carefully at the stability of Actions and ask themselves whether it is a solution worth sticking with long-term when compared with alternatives."&lt;/i&gt;&lt;p&gt;----&lt;p&gt;I agree that the writing in the blog post is more colorful than precise, but sanitizing every bit of expression dulls the internet. Humans invented language for a reason.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2025 04:36:06 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46065705</link><dc:creator>ssivark</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46065705</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46065705</guid></item><item><title>New comment by johnfn in "Migrating the main Zig repository from GitHub to Codeberg"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&gt; it’s abundantly clear that the talented folks who used to work on the product have moved on to bigger and better things, with the remaining losers eager to inflict some kind of bloated, buggy JavaScript framework on us in the name of progress.&lt;p&gt;&gt; More importantly, Actions is created by monkeys&lt;p&gt;This writing really does not reflect well on Zig. If you have technical issues with Github, fine: cite them. But leave ad hominems like "losers" and "monkeys" out of it.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2025 03:47:02 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46065366</link><dc:creator>johnfn</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46065366</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46065366</guid></item><item><title>New comment by nxobject in "Green card interviews end in handcuffs for spouses of U.S. citizens"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;A note that it's easy to "overstay" a visa when waiting for a green card interview - the wait times are often in the 6-16 month range, and if you leave the country you'll be considered to have abandoned your "petition to adjust status". It's a catch-22, and it looks like the only recourse is for an immigration lawyer to file a habeas corpus petition in federal court.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2025 02:51:31 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46065016</link><dc:creator>nxobject</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46065016</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46065016</guid></item><item><title>New comment by quirino in "Migrating the main Zig repository from GitHub to Codeberg"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&gt; As a bonus, we look forward to fewer violations (exhibit A, B, C) of our strict no LLM / no AI policy,&lt;p&gt;Hilarious how the offender on "exhibit A" [1] is the same one from the other post that made the frontpage a couple of days ago [2].&lt;p&gt;[1] &lt;a href="https://github.com/ziglang/zig/issues/25974" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://github.com/ziglang/zig/issues/25974&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;[2] &lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46039274"&gt;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46039274&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2025 02:50:30 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46065008</link><dc:creator>quirino</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46065008</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46065008</guid></item><item><title>New comment by decimalenough in "Bring bathroom doors back to hotels"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I once stayed at a very boutiquey, avant-garde hotel with a platonic friend. We had booked a twin room with separate beds, but what I did not expect was that the shower cubicle, with clear glass on all three sides, would be placed between the beds.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2025 02:41:47 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46064952</link><dc:creator>decimalenough</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46064952</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46064952</guid></item><item><title>New comment by munchler in "Migrating the main Zig repository from GitHub to Codeberg"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Calling the people who work on GitHub “losers” is not cool.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2025 02:33:44 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46064895</link><dc:creator>munchler</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46064895</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46064895</guid></item><item><title>New comment by SoKamil in "Migrating the main Zig repository from GitHub to Codeberg"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&gt; As a bonus, we look forward to fewer violations (exhibit A, B, C) of our strict no LLM / no AI policy, which I believe are at least in part due to GitHub aggressively pushing the “file an issue with Copilot” feature in everyone’s face.&lt;p&gt;Also, the big part of that issue is people are incentivized to make their GitHub profile look good to have a higher chance of getting hired. Any non-mainstream platform is not as compelling to get social credits.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2025 02:16:53 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46064782</link><dc:creator>SoKamil</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46064782</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46064782</guid></item><item><title>New comment by majormajor in "Bring bathroom doors back to hotels"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I don't think that adds up.&lt;p&gt;"Staying in a hotel with a romantic partner and/or family" is &lt;i&gt;at least&lt;/i&gt; as primary a use case for hotels as "staying in a hotel with a platonic friend" and is still a scenario where you want a door but is NOT a scenario where "just get separate rooms" is a logical conclusion. "Get the hell out of that hotel and complain about it to everyone you know," on the other hand, is.&lt;p&gt;The much more specific way to target platonic buddies/coworkers from sharing a room would be &lt;i&gt;eliminating rooms with two beds&lt;/i&gt; since the "couple" scenario would generally be perfectly happy with that still.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2025 01:10:25 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46064316</link><dc:creator>majormajor</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46064316</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46064316</guid></item><item><title>New comment by preommr in "Gemini CLI tips and tricks for agentic coding"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I am not doing any of this.&lt;p&gt;It becomes obsolete in literally weeks, and it also doesn't work 80% of the time. Like why write a mcp server for custom tasks when I don't know if the llm is going to reliably call it.&lt;p&gt;My rule for AI has been steadfast for months (years?) now. I write (myself, not AI because then I spend more time guiding the AI instead of thinking about the problem) documentation for myself (templates, checklist, etc.). I give ai a chance to one-shot it in seconds, if it can't, I am either review my documentation or I just do it manually.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2025 00:24:15 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46063949</link><dc:creator>preommr</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46063949</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46063949</guid></item><item><title>New comment by rjdj377dhabsn in "Bring bathroom doors back to hotels"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Huh.. I've stayed in over 1,000 hotels and Airbnbs over the last 15 years and not once saw a bathroom with no door.  Lots of bathroom windows, but always some kind of door.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 23:46:17 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46063648</link><dc:creator>rjdj377dhabsn</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46063648</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46063648</guid></item><item><title>New comment by akersten in "Bring bathroom doors back to hotels"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;It's not about saving a few bucks on a door. It's about discouraging you and your friends from sharing a single room. Hotel sees the money they're leaving on the table and will trade you for it for the low price of watching your buddies do their business.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 23:21:47 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46063446</link><dc:creator>akersten</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46063446</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46063446</guid></item><item><title>New comment by sebmellen in "Show HN: Safe-NPM – only install packages that are +90 days old"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;"Here, install my new 1-day old NPM package that doesn't let you install packages younger than 90 days."&lt;p&gt;Pardon me, I couldn’t help myself :D&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 22:55:57 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46063257</link><dc:creator>sebmellen</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46063257</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46063257</guid></item><item><title>New comment by usrnm in "The EU made Apple adopt new Wi-Fi standards, and now Android can support AirDrop"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Apple also helped develop USB C more than a decade ago, they still had to be forced to actually use it in their phones. There is no contradiction here&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 21:49:53 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46062756</link><dc:creator>usrnm</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46062756</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46062756</guid></item><item><title>New comment by 3rodents in "S&amp;box is now an open source game engine"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;For those unfamiliar, the studio behind S&amp;box is Facepunch, creators of Garry's Mod and Rust. Facepunch as a company doesn't get much attention but they're wildly successful. Started as just some guy in a bedroom, now ~$100m/year in revenue (all via Steam), $100m in the bank, ~100 employees and almost entirely a company of game developers (maybe 20% of employees are administrative staff). Still owned and ran by the founder, Garry. S&amp;box (and Garry's Mod and Rust) is pure game developers making things they want to make.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 20:44:55 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46062114</link><dc:creator>3rodents</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46062114</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46062114</guid></item><item><title>New comment by liamconnell in "OpenAI needs to raise at least $207B by 2030"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately for OpenAI, they are not positioned to capture value from any of the "big margin" use cases that they highlight as key to their future. I think all of these are pretty unrealistic for them:&lt;p&gt;- Revenue sharing from drug discovery (called out by OpenAI CFO): Why would a pharma company give away the upside to a commoditized intelligence layer? Why would OpenAI have a more compelling story than Google Deep Mind, which has serious accolades in this space?&lt;p&gt;- Media generation for ads and other content: For ads, OpenAI is facing off against Google, Meta and Amazon, all of which have existing relationships with advertisers. For the foreseeable future, AI content will be a major discount product compared to humans. OpenAI will not get to charge $1M for an ad like a production company does. So the TAM of ad production (~$50B) shrinks below $1B because AI deflates prices so much.&lt;p&gt;- Other agent use cases: OpenAI doesnt have a surface to build these on. Google has chrome, Microsoft has office, Apple has OS's. The other use cases like coding will be a low-margin competition between model providers until some of them throw in the towel. The players with the best cash position win - and thats not OAI.&lt;p&gt;I think the place that they could win is retail (also called out by OAI CFO). They made deals with Etsy and other small retailers. I was fixing my guitar the other day and would have instantly bought the tools it had suggested that I would need. The problem is that they have to win against Amazon here, and there is zero chance of a partnership for obvious reasons.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 19:54:02 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46061643</link><dc:creator>liamconnell</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46061643</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46061643</guid></item><item><title>New comment by danishSuri1994 in "Voyager 1 is about to reach one light-day from Earth"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;It’s wild how Voyager forces two truths to sit together:&lt;p&gt;Technically, what we’ve done is almost boringly modest.&lt;p&gt;~17 km/s&lt;p&gt;~1 light-day in ~50 years&lt;p&gt;No realistic way to steer it anywhere meaningful now
On cosmic scales it’s… basically still on our doorstep.&lt;p&gt;Psychologically, it’s still one of the most ambitious things we’ve ever done.&lt;p&gt;We built something meant to work for decades, knowing the people who launched it would never see the end of the story.&lt;p&gt;We pointed a metal box into the dark with the assumption that the future would exist and might care.&lt;p&gt;I keep coming back to this: Voyager isn’t proof that interstellar travel is around the corner. It’s proof that humans will build absurdly long-horizon projects anyway, even when the ROI is almost entirely knowledge and perspective.&lt;p&gt;Whether we ever leave the solar system in a serious way probably depends less on physics and more on whether we ever build a civilization stable enough to think in centuries without collapsing every few decades.&lt;p&gt;Voyager is the test run for that mindset more than for the tech.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 19:15:22 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46061272</link><dc:creator>danishSuri1994</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46061272</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46061272</guid></item><item><title>New comment by vessenes in "Cloudflare outage should not have happened"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;"If they had a perfectly normalized database, no NULLing and formally verified code, this bug would not have happened."&lt;p&gt;That may be. What's not specified there is the immense, immense cost of driving a dev org on those terms. It limits, radically, the percent of engineers you can hire (to those who understand this and are willing to work this way), and it slows deployment radically.&lt;p&gt;Cloudflare may well need to transition to this sort of engineering culture, but there is no doubt that they would not be in the position they are in if they &lt;i&gt;started&lt;/i&gt; with this culture -- they would have been too slow to capture the market.&lt;p&gt;I think critiques that have actionable plans for real dev teams are likely to be more useful than what, to me, reads as a sort of complaint from an ivory tower. Culture matters, shipping speed matters, quality matters, team DNA matters. That's what makes this stuff hard (and interesting!)&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 17:11:32 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46059729</link><dc:creator>vessenes</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46059729</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46059729</guid></item><item><title>New comment by locknitpicker in "Cloudflare outage should not have happened"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;This sort of Monday morning quarterbacking is pointless and only serves as a way for random bloggers to try to grab credit without actually doing or creating any value.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 17:10:17 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46059705</link><dc:creator>locknitpicker</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46059705</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46059705</guid></item><item><title>New comment by glenstein in "Voyager 1 is about to reach one light-day from Earth"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Not that we would literally do this with Voyager, but it makes me wonder at the potential utility of a string of probes, one sent every couple of [insert correct time interval, decades, centuries?], to effectively create a communication relay stretching out into deep space somewhere.&lt;p&gt;My understanding with the Voyagers 1 and 2 is (a) they will run out of power before they would ever get far enough to benefit from a relay and (b) they benefited from gravity slingshots due to planetary alignments that happen only once every 175 years.&lt;p&gt;So building on the Voyager probes is a no-go. But probes sent toward Alpha Centauri that relay signals? Toward the center of the Milky Way? Toward Andromeda? Yes it would take time scales far beyond human lifetimes to build out anything useful, and even at the "closest" scales it's a multi year round trip for information but I think Voyager, among other things, was meant to test our imaginations, our sense of possible and one thing they seem to naturally imply is the possibility of long distance probe relays.&lt;p&gt;Edit: As others rightly note, the probes would have to communicate with lasers, not with the 1970s radio engineering that powered Voyagers 1 and 2.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 15:43:54 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46058528</link><dc:creator>glenstein</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46058528</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46058528</guid></item><item><title>New comment by mattgreenrocks in "I don't care how well your "AI" works"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&gt; This is the culture that replaced hacker culture.&lt;p&gt;Somewhere along the lines of "everybody can code," we threw out the values and aesthetics that attracted people in the first place. What began as a rejection of externally imposed values devolved into a mouthpiece of the current powers and principalities.&lt;p&gt;This is evidenced by the new set of hacker values being almost purely performative when compared against the old set. The tension between money and what you make has been boiled away completely. We lean much more heavily on where someone has worked ("ex-Google") vs their tech chops, which (like management), have given up on trying to actually evaluate. We routinely devalue craftsmanship because it doesn't bow down to almighty Business Impact.&lt;p&gt;We sold out the culture, which paved the way for it to be hollowed out by LLMs.&lt;p&gt;There is a way out: we need to create a culture that values craftmanship and dignifies work done by developers. We need to talk seriously and plainly about the spiritual and existential damage done by LLMs. We need to stop being complicit in propagating that noxious cloud of inevitability and nihilism that is choking our culture. We need to call out the bullshit and extended psyops ("all software jobs are going away!") that have gone on for the past 2-3 years, and mock it ruthlessly: despite hundreds of billions of dollars, it hasn't fully delivered on its promises, and investors are starting to be a bit skeptical.&lt;p&gt;In short, it's time to wake up.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 15:41:36 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46058495</link><dc:creator>mattgreenrocks</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46058495</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46058495</guid></item><item><title>New comment by easterncalculus in "I don't care how well your "AI" works"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&gt; I find it particularly disillusioning to realize how deep the LLM brainworm is able to eat itself even into progressive hacker circles.&lt;p&gt;That's the thing, hacker circles didn't always have this 'progressive' luddite mentality. This is the culture that replaced hacker culture.&lt;p&gt;I don't like AI, generally. I am skeptical of corporate influence, I doubt AI 2027 and so-called 'AGI'. I'm certain we'll be "five years away" from superintelligence for the forseeable future. All that said, the actual workday is absolutely filled with busy work that no one really wants to do, and the refusal of a loud minority to engage with that fact is what's leading to this. It's why people can't post a meme, quote, article, whatever could be interpreted (very often, falsely) as AI-generated in a public channel, or ask a chatbot to explain a hand-drawn image without the off chance that they get an earful from one of these 'progressive' people. These people bring way more toxicity to daily life than who they wage their campaigns against.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 14:58:07 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46057976</link><dc:creator>easterncalculus</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46057976</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46057976</guid></item><item><title>New comment by embedding-shape in "I don't care how well your "AI" works"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&gt; And yeah, I get it. We programmers are currently living through the devaluation of our craft, in a way and rate we never anticipated possible.&lt;p&gt;I'm a programmer, been coding professionally for 10 something years, and coding for myself longer than that.&lt;p&gt;What are they talking about? What is this "devaluation"? I'm getting paid more than ever for a job I feel like I almost shouldn't get paid for (I'm just having fun), and programmers should be some of the most worry-free individuals on this planet, the job is easy, well-paid, not a lot of health drawbacks if you have a proper setup and relatively easy to find a new job when you need it (granted, the US seems to struggle with that specific point as of late, yet it remains true in the rest of the world).&lt;p&gt;And now, we're having a huge explosion of tools for developers, to build software that has to be maintained by developers, made by developers for developers.&lt;p&gt;If anything, it seems like Balmers plea of "Developers, developers, developers" has came true, and if there will be one profession left in 100 year when AI does everything for us (if the vibers are to be believed), then that'd probably be software developers and machine learning experts.&lt;p&gt;What exactly is being de-valuated for a profession that seems to be continuously growing and been doing so for at least 20 years?&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 11:37:21 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46056395</link><dc:creator>embedding-shape</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46056395</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46056395</guid></item><item><title>New comment by pxc in "Ilya Sutskever: We're moving from the age of scaling to the age of research"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;If "Era of Scaling" means "era of rapid and predictable performance improvements that easily attract investors", it sounds a lot like "AI summer". So... is "Era of Research" a euphemism for "AI winter"?&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 01:00:43 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46052864</link><dc:creator>pxc</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46052864</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46052864</guid></item></channel></rss>