<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>Hacker News: Best Comments</title><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/bestcomments</link><description>Hacker News RSS</description><docs>https://hnrss.org/</docs><generator>hnrss v2.1.1</generator><lastBuildDate>Sun, 12 Oct 2025 00:03:30 +0000</lastBuildDate><ns0:link href="https://hnrss.org/bestcomments" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item><title>New comment by themafia in "Microsoft only lets you opt out of AI photo scanning 3x a year"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;"You can only turn off this setting 3 times a year."&lt;p&gt;Astonishing.  They clearly feel their users have no choice but to accept this onerous and ridiculous requirement.  As if users wouldn't understand that they'd have to go way out of their way to write the code which enforces this outcome.  All for a feature which provides me dubious benefit.  I know who the people in my photographs are.  Why is Microsoft so eager to also be able to know this?&lt;p&gt;Privacy legislation is clearly lacking.  This type of action should bring the hammer down swiftly and soundly upon these gross and inappropriate corporate decision makers.  Microsoft has needed that hammer blow for quite some time now.  This should make that obvious.  I guess I'll hold my breath while I see how Congress responds.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 11 Oct 2025 20:02:22 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45552226</link><dc:creator>themafia</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45552226</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45552226</guid></item><item><title>New comment by whatshisface in "Tennessee man arrested, accused of threatening a shooting, after posting meme"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I think this is an example of using slow trials as a nonjudicial weapon. The defendant did not break the law and isn't likely to be convicted (at least not on appeal), but they can hold him in jail for months because they got mad at his Facebook post.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 11 Oct 2025 18:53:36 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45551642</link><dc:creator>whatshisface</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45551642</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45551642</guid></item><item><title>New comment by tptacek in "Vibing a non-trivial Ghostty feature"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Tip: I very often use AI for inspiration. In this case, I ended up keeping a lot (not all) of the UI code it made, but I will very often prompt an agent, throw away everything it did, and redo it myself (manually!). I find the "zero to one" stage of creation very difficult and time consuming and AI is excellent at being my muse.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;p&gt;This right here is the single biggest win for coding agents. I see and directionally agree with all the concerns people have about maintainability and sprawl in AI-mediated projects. I don't care, though, because the moment I can get a project up on its legs, to where I can interact with some substantial part of its functionality and refine it, I'm off to the races. It's getting to that golden moment that constitutes 80% of what's costly about programming for me.&lt;p&gt;This is the part where I simply don't understand the objections people have to coding agents. It seems so self-evidently valuable --- even if you do nothing else with an agent, even if you literally throw all the code away.&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;PS&lt;/i&gt;&lt;p&gt;Put a weight on that bacon!&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 11 Oct 2025 16:57:30 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45550683</link><dc:creator>tptacek</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45550683</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45550683</guid></item><item><title>New comment by Avicebron in "Superpowers: How I'm using coding agents in October 2025"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I often feel these types of blogposts would be more helpful if they demonstrated someone using the tools to build something non-trivial.&lt;p&gt;Is Claude really "learning new skills" when you feed it a book, or does it present it like that because you're prompting encourages that sort of response-behavior.  I feel like it has to demo Claude with the new skills and Claude without.&lt;p&gt;Maybe I'm a curmudgeon but most of these types of blogs feel like marketing pieces with the important bit is that so much is left unsaid and not shown, that it comes off like a kid trying to hype up their own work without the benefit of nuance or depth.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 11 Oct 2025 13:37:18 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45549036</link><dc:creator>Avicebron</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45549036</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45549036</guid></item><item><title>New comment by sillyfluke in "Daniel Kahneman opted for assisted suicide in Switzerland"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;The parent described someone who went above and beyond the norm of other members in his community in his constant positive interaction with his neighbors, collegues, and former students. It is highly likely this kind of person would give a considerable shit if he knew he would become a nightmare for the same community.&lt;p&gt;There may be others reading in the thread who also can relate to the personality of the teacher and may care about their affect on others when they are "not themselves".&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 11 Oct 2025 12:27:03 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45548635</link><dc:creator>sillyfluke</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45548635</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45548635</guid></item><item><title>New comment by AQuantized in "Daniel Kahneman opted for assisted suicide in Switzerland"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&gt; You really don't want to end up with dementia and related illnesses, it totally sours everyone's view of you.&lt;p&gt;This seems like such an absurd conclusion to this, as though the opinions of other people of you are what matter when you functionally lose your personhood and then die.&lt;p&gt;Maybe a better focus would be that there often isn't a good way for a community to manage a person who suddenly becomes irrational because of an illness.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 11 Oct 2025 12:21:03 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45548598</link><dc:creator>AQuantized</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45548598</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45548598</guid></item><item><title>New comment by anilgulecha in "Daniel Kahneman opted for assisted suicide in Switzerland"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I'm part of the Jain community in Bangalore, and the version of this in society exists, called Sallekhna [1], a tradition that's developed over millennia, and this is venerated and celebrated.&lt;p&gt;The philosophical underpinning is giving up of materialness. The practicality of the 5 instances that I witnessed over the past year - typical terminal individuals choose this. They pass away surrounded by loved ones (they typically medicate for any pain, and the body starts shutting down when food and water stops). This is observed with somberness, but celebrated as very positive act.&lt;p&gt;When someone starts this process, it's a unique experience speaking with them, as there's usually nothing that comes up, and the moment does not really lend itself to small talk :)&lt;p&gt;[1] &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sallekhana" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sallekhana&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 11 Oct 2025 11:06:07 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45548178</link><dc:creator>anilgulecha</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45548178</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45548178</guid></item><item><title>New comment by lordnacho in "Daniel Kahneman opted for assisted suicide in Switzerland"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I had an old teacher who died almost a year ago.&lt;p&gt;Great guy, very sociable, knew everyone in the little town he lived in. Kept in touch with a lot of students. Good neighbour, friendly guy who'd talk to everyone.&lt;p&gt;He got Alzheimers. He started forgetting stuff, and it frustrated him. He got caught driving dangerously, and cursed the doctor who took away his license.&lt;p&gt;He argued with me about the state of some chicken he wanted to cook. I told him "this is pink all over, you have to cook it more". He got angry. I understood he'd become like this to everyone.&lt;p&gt;He pissed off everyone on his street, and all police, medical and social workers sent to help him. The disease made him blow up every relationship he had with anyone that he didn't know well, like me and a couple of colleagues.&lt;p&gt;He got found in his house, having left the gas on, endangering the whole street. He ended up in a care home, not knowing who he was, or who I was.&lt;p&gt;If he'd been run over by a car, or died of a heart attack at the age of 80, people he knew would remember him as that nice old guy who had a dog and made a lot of art, and was friendly to everyone. Instead he was that 83 year old guy who pissed off everyone, nearly blew up the neighbourhood, and drove like a maniac.&lt;p&gt;You really don't want to end up with dementia and related illnesses, it totally sours everyone's view of you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 11 Oct 2025 10:35:11 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45548022</link><dc:creator>lordnacho</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45548022</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45548022</guid></item><item><title>New comment by kqr in "Ryanair flight landed at Manchester airport with six minutes of fuel left"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;In safety-critical systems, we distinguish between &lt;i&gt;accidents&lt;/i&gt; (actual loss, e.g. lives, equipment, etc.) and &lt;i&gt;hazardous states&lt;/i&gt;. The equation is&lt;p&gt;hazardous state + environmental conditions = accident&lt;p&gt;Since we can only control the system, and not its environment, we focus on preventing hazardous states, rather than accidents. If we can keep the system out of all hazardous states, we also avoid accidents. (Trying to prevent accidents while not paying attention to hazardous states amounts to relying on the environment always being on our side, and is bound to fail eventually.)&lt;p&gt;One such hazardous state we have defined in aviation is "less than N minutes of fuel remaining when landing". If an aircraft lands with less than N minutes of fuel on board, it would only have taken bad environmental conditions to make it crash, rather than land. Thus we design commercial aviation so that planes always have N minutes of fuel remaining when landing. If they don't, that's a big deal: they've entered a hazardous state, and we never want to see that. (I don't remember if N is 30 or 45 or 60 but somewhere in that region.)&lt;p&gt;For another example, one of my children loves playing around cliffs and rocks. Initially he was very keen on promising me that he wouldn't fall down. I explained the difference between accidents and hazardous states to him in childrens' terms, and he realised slowly that he cannot control whether or not he has an accident, so it's a bad idea to promise me that he won't have an accident. What he can control is whether or not bad environmental conditions lead to an accident, and he does that by keeping out of hazardous states. In this case, the hazardous state would be standing less than a child-height within a ledge when there is nobody below ready to catch. He can promise me to avoid that, and that satisfies me a lot more than a promise to not fall.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 11 Oct 2025 06:28:47 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45547079</link><dc:creator>kqr</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45547079</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45547079</guid></item><item><title>New comment by porcoda in "Liquid Glass Is Cracked, and Usability Suffers in iOS 26"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;This update is one of the rare cases where I really dislike the new version.  I’m usually happy with Apple updates, even ones the commentators dislike.  This time I’m sorta agreeing with them: I don’t like the new iOS.  Same with the Mac and iPad: other than being glitchy, I just don’t like the changes.  It feels like my screen real estate isn’t as efficiently used, UI elements feel jumbled and the transparency makes things harder to read.  I’m sure I’ll get used to it over time but I’m not enjoying it so far, even after going into the settings to try to adjust things I don’t care for.  Not my favorite update cycle from Apple, and I’m usually one of the overly positive folks on whatever Apple ships.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2025 21:54:45 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45544236</link><dc:creator>porcoda</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45544236</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45544236</guid></item><item><title>New comment by mfro in "Liquid Glass Is Cracked, and Usability Suffers in iOS 26"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Literally every change made in iOS 26 feels like a downgrade to me. This is the first time I have ever considered downgrading iOS.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2025 21:45:55 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45544149</link><dc:creator>mfro</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45544149</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45544149</guid></item><item><title>New comment by JoshTriplett in "Does our “need for speed” make our wi-fi suck?"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&gt; The other bit of advice that is buried in there that no-one wants to hear for residences is the best way to speed up your Wi-Fi is to not use it. You might think it's convenient to have your TV connect to Netflix via WiFi and it is, but it is going to make everything else that really needs the Wi-Fi slower. It's a much better answer to hook up everything on Ethernet that you possibly can than it is to follow the more traveled route of more channels and more congestion with mesh Wi-Fi.&lt;p&gt;Absolutely. Everything other than cell phones and laptops-not-at-a-desk should be on Ethernet.&lt;p&gt;I had wires run in 2020 when I started doing even more video calls. Huge improvement in usability.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2025 19:52:26 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45543041</link><dc:creator>JoshTriplett</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45543041</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45543041</guid></item><item><title>New comment by PaulHoule in "Does our “need for speed” make our wi-fi suck?"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I did some experimentation with UniFi hubs and came to the conclusion that if you can give each device its own WiFi channel that would be ideal -- contention is that bad and often an uncontended channel with otherwise poor characteristics will beat a contended channel that otherwise looks good.&lt;p&gt;The other bit of advice that is buried in there that no-one wants to hear for residences is the best way to speed up your Wi-Fi is to &lt;i&gt;not use it&lt;/i&gt;.  You might think it's convenient to have your TV connect to Netflix via WiFi and it is,  but it is going to make everything else that really needs the Wi-Fi slower.  It's a &lt;i&gt;much&lt;/i&gt; better answer to hook up everything on Ethernet that you possibly can than it is to follow the more traveled route of more channels and more congestion with mesh Wi-Fi.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2025 19:07:43 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45542577</link><dc:creator>PaulHoule</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45542577</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45542577</guid></item><item><title>New comment by tdb7893 in "Google, Meta and Microsoft to stop showing political ads in the EU"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Ignoring political implications here and just on a personal level I wish political ads were banned. Quite possibly my least favorite type of ad to see and I've never felt meaningfully informed by them (generally quite the opposite).&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2025 18:56:07 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45542459</link><dc:creator>tdb7893</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45542459</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45542459</guid></item><item><title>New comment by 3D30497420 in "Boring Company cited for almost 800 environmental violations in Las Vegas"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;From the article:&lt;p&gt;&gt; Workers have complained of chemical burns from the waste material generated by the tunneling process, and firefighters must decontaminate their equipment after conducting rescues from the project sites. The company was fined more than $112,000 by Nevada’s Occupational Safety and Health Administration in late 2023 after workers complained of “ankle-deep” water in the tunnels, muck spills and burns.&lt;p&gt;That sounds like a "real environmental hazard" to me.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2025 17:20:21 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45541388</link><dc:creator>3D30497420</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45541388</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45541388</guid></item><item><title>New comment by paulgerhardt in "Ask HN: What's the best hackable smart TV?"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Do recommend the LG C series (C5 or C4 are new or the C1 series if you want a deal on classifieds - same hardware as the higher end models but needs a firmware bit flip). The OS is very rootable and it makes a great TV that doubles as a monitor. Supports free sync / g-sync. OLED is nice at this scale.&lt;p&gt;Text is very readable, refresh rate is good. It uses the same panels as the fancier G series in the larger sizes. One can root the firmware to make it go brighter. (Though this is screen works well in medium or dimly lit rooms. It does not shine in very bright rooms).&lt;p&gt;Plenty of YouTube videos singing the C series praises as a TV / Monitor.[1] LG webOS is also trivial/friendly to root in developer mode and network control of the tv is a nice to have.&lt;p&gt;Would avoid Samsung. I love the matte on the Frame and the design of the Serif but the OS is frustrating / impractical to root.&lt;p&gt;[1] &lt;a href="https://youtu.be/Qtve0u3GJ9Y" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://youtu.be/Qtve0u3GJ9Y&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2025 17:00:26 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45541121</link><dc:creator>paulgerhardt</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45541121</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45541121</guid></item><item><title>New comment by gota in ""Vibe code hell" has replaced "tutorial hell" in coding education"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Minor part of the article, but the thing about "tutorial Hell" is very true:&lt;p&gt;&gt; Students would watch (or fall asleep to) 6-hour videos, code along in their own editors, feel like they got it, and then freeze up the moment they had to write anything from scratch. Classic tutorial hell.&lt;p&gt;This is why, across history, the tried and true method of learning a craft is an &lt;i&gt;apprenticeship&lt;/i&gt;. You, the junior, tag along a senior. You work under a shop that is led by a senior-senior that is called a master. Apprentices become craftsmen, craftsmen become masters. AFAIK, the master does not 'offload' project guidance into non-craftsmen, it is an expected part of the craftsmen role to be project/product managers/owners.&lt;p&gt;I've said this a million times to close friends and at this point I'm only half joking. We, and I'm including myself in the 'developer' crowd although I may not deserve it, have really dropped the ball in not being a 'guild' since way back when. At least since the late 1980's; and certainly since before the Original Boom of software dev as a profession (I'm assuming it was late 90's? I know not)&lt;p&gt;(Although I suspect that if that were the case we'd have fewer developers throughout the 00s and 10s, which may have impacted the development of the field itself in unexpected, but likely negative, ways)&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2025 16:56:53 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45541071</link><dc:creator>gota</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45541071</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45541071</guid></item><item><title>New comment by leakycap in "Boring Company cited for almost 800 environmental violations in Las Vegas"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;All this so a handful of passengers a week can wait for the extremely small pool of vehicles in a dusty hole&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2025 16:22:47 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45540677</link><dc:creator>leakycap</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45540677</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45540677</guid></item><item><title>New comment by gsnedders in "Ryanair flight landed at Manchester airport with six minutes of fuel left"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;As others have said, final fuel reserves are typically at least half an hour, and you shouldn't really be cutting into them. What if their first approach into MAN had led to another go around?&lt;p&gt;With a major storm heading north-easterly across the UK, the planning should have reasonably foreseen that an airport 56 miles east may also be unavailable, and should've further diverted prior to that point.&lt;p&gt;They likely used the majority of their final fuel reserve on the secondary diversion from EDI to MAN, presumably having planned to land at their alternate (EDI) around the time they reached the final fuel reserve.&lt;p&gt;Any CAA report into this, if there is one produced, is going to be interesting, because there's multiple people having made multiple decisions that led to this.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2025 16:16:44 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45540621</link><dc:creator>gsnedders</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45540621</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45540621</guid></item><item><title>New comment by abtinf in "Ryanair flight landed at Manchester airport with six minutes of fuel left"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Naively as an outsider, this situation seems like everything worked as intended?&lt;p&gt;On a nominally 2h45m flight, they spent an &lt;i&gt;extra 2 hours&lt;/i&gt; in the air, presumably doing doing fuel intensive altitude changing maneuvers, and were eventually able to land safely with their reserves almost exhausted.&lt;p&gt;I’m a little confused by what there is to investigate at all.&lt;p&gt;How much fuel &lt;i&gt;should&lt;/i&gt; they have landed with?&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2025 15:57:26 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45540402</link><dc:creator>abtinf</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45540402</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45540402</guid></item><item><title>New comment by jacquesm in "Ryanair flight landed at Manchester airport with six minutes of fuel left"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;That is &lt;i&gt;very&lt;/i&gt; exceptional. I've written fuel estimation software for airliners (cargo, fortunately), and the number of rules regarding go-arounds, alternates and holding time resulted in there usually being quite a bit of fuel in the tanks on landing, by design. I've never heard of '6 minutes left' in practice where it wasn't a massive issue and the investigation into how this could have happened will make for interesting reading. A couple of notes: the wind and the time spent on the three go-arounds + what was necessary to get to the alternate may not be the whole story here, that's actually factored in before you even take off.&lt;p&gt;I'd be very wary to get ahead of the investigation and make speculative statements on how this could have happened, the one thing that I know for sure is that it &lt;i&gt;shouldn't&lt;/i&gt; have happened, no matter what.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2025 15:48:38 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45540315</link><dc:creator>jacquesm</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45540315</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45540315</guid></item><item><title>New comment by SquareWheel in "Google Safe Browsing incident"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;It's generally good advice, but I don't see that Safe Browsing did anything wrong in this case.  First, it sounds like they actually were briefly hosting phishing sites:&lt;p&gt;&gt; All sites on statichost.eu get a SITE-NAME.statichost.eu domain, and during the weekend there was an influx of phishing sites.&lt;p&gt;Second, they should be using the public suffix list (&lt;a href="https://publicsuffix.org/" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://publicsuffix.org/&lt;/a&gt;) to avoid having their entire domain tagged.  How else is Google supposed to know that subdomains belong to different users?  That's what the PSL is for.&lt;p&gt;From my reading, Safe Browsing did its job correctly in this case, and they restored the site quickly once the threat was removed.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2025 13:45:09 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45538971</link><dc:creator>SquareWheel</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45538971</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45538971</guid></item><item><title>New comment by harimau777 in "Examples are the best documentation"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Please don't follow this advice! The best thing about old school Python was that I could reliably pull up the documentation for a library and it would clearly list the arguments and return values for each function.&lt;p&gt;Now when I look at the documentation for many JavaScript, and even Python, libraries it's just examples. That's great if I'm trying to just throw something together as quickly as possible, but not if I need to fix a problem or actually learn the library.&lt;p&gt;Also having examples is fine, but they should be considered a bonus; not documentation.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2025 12:35:51 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45538265</link><dc:creator>harimau777</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45538265</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45538265</guid></item><item><title>New comment by madacol in "Nobel Peace Prize 2025: María Corina Machado"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Even if Venezuela goes to hell even deeper, she still deserves the prize for what she has already done!&lt;p&gt;The way she, and her team, managed to convince venezuelans that the election mattered, and to prepare to gather the evidence of the elections under constant threats from the government, that we all knew they were going to steal, and do it entirely peacefully, was an extremely impressive achievement on its own.&lt;p&gt;What an impressive act of coordination from MCM&lt;p&gt;:standing-ovation:&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2025 11:35:17 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45537701</link><dc:creator>madacol</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45537701</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45537701</guid></item><item><title>New comment by mananoreboton in "Nobel Peace Prize 2025: María Corina Machado"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Don't get me wrong, but perhaps what was missing was greater media coverage and genuine interest in Venezuela's situation.
María Corina Machado orchestrated a HUGE covert months long operation to collect tally sheets from the overwhelming majority of voting machines during the 2024 presidential election. Her team trained poll watchers to demand vote receipts (as legally permitted) then capture and transmit that data through various channels, even from the most remote regions of the country.
There are documented cases of people—poll workers and participants in the plan—being imprisoned or even killed for their involvement.
Thanks to this operation, the website resultadospresidencialesvenezuela2024.com exists, where venezuelan can verify the actual vote count per candidate, backed by fingerprint records and the serial numbers of both the software and hardware used.
These verified results confirm that Edmundo González was the true winner of the election.
The data provides undeniable evidence that Nicolás Maduro installed himself as a dictator, with the full support of the national electoral authority, which, to this day, has refused to release the official election results (a procedure that has historically been routine).&lt;p&gt;You can also verify the results here &lt;a href="https://macedoniadelnorte.com/" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://macedoniadelnorte.com/&lt;/a&gt; (a whole story behind this hostname). Again, only possible by the María Corina's huge effort&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2025 09:49:56 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45537006</link><dc:creator>mananoreboton</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45537006</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45537006</guid></item><item><title>New comment by alejoar in "Nobel Peace Prize 2025: María Corina Machado"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Opposing a dictatorship at great personal risk, being exiled, banned from elections, and still leading a democratic movement isn't "nothing".&lt;p&gt;I think this prize recognizes her courage and fight for human rights.&lt;p&gt;Dismissing that as "just being in the opposition" ignores the reality of what it takes to stand up to Maduro's dictatorship.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2025 09:34:40 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45536915</link><dc:creator>alejoar</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45536915</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45536915</guid></item><item><title>New comment by breadwinner in "Nobel Peace Prize 2025: María Corina Machado"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Notice what they said: This year's peace prize is being given to someone for transitioning a country from dictatorship to democracy. They sure as hell aren't going to give it to someone doing the opposite!&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2025 09:31:35 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45536889</link><dc:creator>breadwinner</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45536889</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45536889</guid></item><item><title>New comment by David-Guillot in "I switched from Htmx to Datastar"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Thanks to Chris to continue challenging his comfort zone (and mine!) and sharing his impressions and learnings with us!&lt;p&gt;I may be a little biased because I've been writing webapps with htmx for 4 years now, but here are my first thoughts:&lt;p&gt;- The examples given in this blogpost show what seems to be the main architectural difference between htmx and Datastar: htmx is HTML-driven, Datastar is server-driven. So yes, the API on client-side is simpler, but that's because the other side has to be more complex: on the first example, if the HTML element doesn't hold the information about where to inject the HTML fragment returned by the server, the server has to know it, so you have to write it somewhere on that side. I guess it's a matter of personal preference then, but from an architecture point-of-view both approaches stand still&lt;p&gt;- The argument of "less attributes" seems unfair when the htmx examples use optional attributes with their default value (yes you can remove the hx-trigger="click" on the first example, that's 20% less attributes, and the argument is now 20% less strong)&lt;p&gt;- Minor but still: the blogpost would gain credibility and its arguments would be stronger if HTML was used more properly: who wants to click on &lt;span&gt; elements? &lt;button&gt; exists just for that, please use it, it's accessible ;-)&lt;p&gt;- In the end I feel that the main Datastar selling point is its integration of client-side features, as if Alpine or Stimulus features were natively included in htmx. And that's a great point!&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2025 09:18:07 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45536797</link><dc:creator>David-Guillot</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45536797</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45536797</guid></item><item><title>New comment by rubenvanwyk in "I switched from Htmx to Datastar"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I recently read this: &lt;a href="https://drshapeless.com/blog/posts/htmx,-datastar,-greedy-developer.html" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://drshapeless.com/blog/posts/htmx,-datastar,-greedy-de...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;Which states some of the basic (great) functionality of Datastar has been moved to the Datastar Pro product (?!).&lt;p&gt;I’m eager to support an open source product financially and think the framework author is great, but the precedent this establishes isn’t great.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2025 08:28:25 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45536535</link><dc:creator>rubenvanwyk</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45536535</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45536535</guid></item><item><title>New comment by bigstrat2003 in "Examples are the best documentation"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Similarly, unix man pages desperately need examples. They are almost without fail written as an exhaustive reference for someone who already knows how to use the tool, which is a totally valid use case. But that means they're generally useless for someone trying to use a tool for the first time. Good documentation needs to have &lt;i&gt;both&lt;/i&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2025 07:03:43 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45536084</link><dc:creator>bigstrat2003</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45536084</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45536084</guid></item></channel></rss>