<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>Hacker News: Best Comments</title><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/bestcomments</link><description>Hacker News RSS</description><docs>https://hnrss.org/</docs><generator>hnrss v2.1.1</generator><lastBuildDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 02:16:56 +0000</lastBuildDate><ns0:link href="https://hnrss.org/bestcomments" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item><title>New comment by thomascgalvin in "Don't push AI down our throats"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I have a pixel watch, and my main use for it is setting reminders, like "reminder 3pm put the laundry in the dryer". It's worked fine since the day I bought it.&lt;p&gt;Last week, they pushed an update that broke all of the features on the watch unless I agreed to allow Google to train their AI on my content.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 30 Nov 2025 19:15:47 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46099488</link><dc:creator>thomascgalvin</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46099488</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46099488</guid></item><item><title>New comment by mikeyk in "Paul Hegarty's updated CS193p SwiftUI course released by Stanford"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I took CS193P when it was first offered in 2007; one of my favorite classes at Stanford because it was so hands-on. At the time few people had iPhones, so everyone in the class got a free iPod Touch for development. My final project was a photo sharing app with a Polaroid shake to reveal mechanic… lightly influenced Instagram which Kevin and I built a few years later!&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 30 Nov 2025 15:13:15 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46097254</link><dc:creator>mikeyk</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46097254</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46097254</guid></item><item><title>New comment by qsort in "Advent of Code 2025"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I'm actually pleasantly surprised to see a 2025 edition, last year being the 10th anniversary and the LLM situation with the leaderboard were solid indications that it would have been a great time to wrap it up and let somebody else carry the torch.&lt;p&gt;It's only going to be 12 problems rather than 24 this year and there isn't going to be a gloabl leaderboard, but I'm still glad we get to take part in this fun Christmas season tradition, and I'm thankful for all those who put in their free time so that we can get to enjoy the problems. It's probably an unpopular stance, but I've never done Advent of Code for the competitive aspect, I've always just enjoyed the puzzles, so as far as I'm concerned nothing was really lost.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 30 Nov 2025 13:53:59 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46096662</link><dc:creator>qsort</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46096662</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46096662</guid></item><item><title>New comment by jtrn in "Bazzite: Operating System for Linux gaming"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I have a special spot that gets extremely annoyed when I feel I have to spend a necessary time just figuring out what something is. The page suffers from "developer-brain" marketing, where they describe the technology used to build it (cloud-native images) rather than what the product actually is. Why not just lead with that it is a Linux distro/version focused on gaming. In the beginning, I thought it was new hardware, then I actually thought it was a streaming service. the website does a poor job of simply stating what it actually is. Then again, I might be stupid, but the problem is that a lot of people are stupid. And I guess many non-developers are going to have a hard time just figuring out what the hell this thing is. I’m probably being too cranky now, but the page reads like a combination of the worst from developers-speak combined with the rest of marketing-speak.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 30 Nov 2025 07:28:11 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46094613</link><dc:creator>jtrn</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46094613</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46094613</guid></item><item><title>New comment by maxglute in "Testing shows automotive glassbreakers can't break modern automotive glass"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Man there needs to be some sort of amusement park where you try out common emergency safety mechanisms.&lt;p&gt;I've never broke / pulled a fire alarm, I'm sure I can, but let me.&lt;p&gt;ALSO EVERY AIRPORT SHOULD HAVE MOCK EMERGENCY AIRPLANE DOORS FOR PEOPLE TO TRY OUT.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 30 Nov 2025 06:11:14 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46094293</link><dc:creator>maxglute</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46094293</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46094293</guid></item><item><title>New comment by collinmcnulty in "Datacenters in space aren't going to work"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;To say the quiet part out loud, I don't think any serious companies have any intention to build a data center in space. There is no benefit in actually trying this. There is however, benefit in &lt;i&gt;saying&lt;/i&gt; you'll do it to advance a narrative and distract from the problems terrestrial data centers are facing to an audience that mostly doesn't understand how heat transfer in a vacuum works.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 30 Nov 2025 05:43:43 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46094171</link><dc:creator>collinmcnulty</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46094171</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46094171</guid></item><item><title>New comment by rayiner in "Americans no longer see four-year college degrees as worth the cost"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;That's historical revisionism. The percentage of American adults over age 25 who have a college degree was only 20% as recently as 1990. When America was truly at the top of the world in the 1950s and 1960s, it was under 10%. A high fraction of college attendance is better correlated with the 21st century decline in America's situation.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 30 Nov 2025 04:31:22 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46093745</link><dc:creator>rayiner</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46093745</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46093745</guid></item><item><title>New comment by collinmcnulty in "Americans no longer see four-year college degrees as worth the cost"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;This view seems to be common, but I think it misses what incredible alchemy comes from making people who come in for “job training” (like I did) spend 4 years in close proximity with research, academic freedom, liberal arts, and at least an attempt at some kind of intellectual idealism separate from economic incentive. It’s peanut butter and chocolate that has served democracy and its people well by having a middle class that is not just productive, but truly educated. It’s weird and it has problems, but it’s also wonderful, and we should not try to sever the two so we can more “efficiently” crank out credentials.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 30 Nov 2025 04:15:19 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46093651</link><dc:creator>collinmcnulty</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46093651</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46093651</guid></item><item><title>New comment by jswelker in "Americans no longer see four-year college degrees as worth the cost"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Higher ed is like employer based health insurance in that they are both weird path dependent historical accidents.&lt;p&gt;People want cheap healthcare, and it got shoehorned into an odd employer fringe benefit system that really is not at all related healthcare in any intrinsic way.&lt;p&gt;People want job training, and it got shoehorned into extra departments at liberal arts universities intended as aristocrat finishing schools. Job training really has little to no relationship to liberal arts.&lt;p&gt;And now both those two systems are failing to deliver those benefits because those benefits which were initially afterthought add-ons have outgrown the institutions that were their hosts. It's akin to a parasitic vine that is now much larger than the tree it grew on and is crushing it under its weight. Both will die as a result.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 30 Nov 2025 03:37:46 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46093419</link><dc:creator>jswelker</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46093419</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46093419</guid></item><item><title>New comment by KyleGospo in "Bazzite: Operating System for Linux gaming"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Hi, I'm the founder.&lt;p&gt;While what you're saying isn't impossible, it's unlikely. In the event it did happen, Bazzite is a fork, a signing key, and a couple forked Fedora Copr repos away from being made completely in someone else's control.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 30 Nov 2025 01:40:44 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46092739</link><dc:creator>KyleGospo</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46092739</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46092739</guid></item><item><title>New comment by dherls in "Let go of StackOverflow; communities must take ownership"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Some of the alternatives that the author suggests (Slack, Discord, Matrix rooms) are so much worse to search for answers in. Stack overflow has many disadvantages, but it is extremely good at being a publicly searchable repository of answers to common questions&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 30 Nov 2025 01:12:29 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46092530</link><dc:creator>dherls</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46092530</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46092530</guid></item><item><title>New comment by haunter in "Bazzite: Operating System for Linux gaming"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;As much as I love Bazzite at end of the day it's still a custom distro and every single day there is a chance they just close the project down and move on. Happened to so many distros in the past, this is not out of question. I’m not saying “big corporate” distros are better but personally I'd rather stick to something more mainline.&lt;p&gt;Hopefully Valve will release a general version of SteamOS with Steam Machine coming (and even they are questionable with their track record)&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 30 Nov 2025 00:25:41 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46092225</link><dc:creator>haunter</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46092225</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46092225</guid></item><item><title>New comment by paulorlando in "Americans no longer see four-year college degrees as worth the cost"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Better than asking "is college worth the cost," and getting into ROI calculations per major is asking "could we provide a similar (or better) educational and social experience at a fraction of the cost"? To that the answer is yes.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 29 Nov 2025 23:48:10 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46091974</link><dc:creator>paulorlando</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46091974</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46091974</guid></item><item><title>New comment by an0malous in "All it takes is for one to work out"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Who are you thinking of? Bezos, Zuckerberg, Gates, Musk all came from wealthy families. They all had the safety net of their family wealth if their business didn’t work out. Even someone who had parents to pay their student loans is relatively privileged, not everyone starts their 20’s debt-free and able to take financial risks.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 29 Nov 2025 23:07:37 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46091675</link><dc:creator>an0malous</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46091675</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46091675</guid></item><item><title>New comment by throwaway150 in "Be Like Clippy"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Clippy was definitely hostile. It would constantly monitor user actions just so that it could interrupt us. Wasted CPU cycles and our time when CPUs weren't very fast. Clippy was hated by everyone. It was not just useless. It was intrusive, wasteful, and hostile. I can't believe my eyes that anyone could think that Clippy is an appropriate mascot for anything good. If anything, Clippy would be a perfect mascot for the trillion dollar companies that exploit our data.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 29 Nov 2025 21:40:07 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46091037</link><dc:creator>throwaway150</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46091037</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46091037</guid></item><item><title>New comment by throwaway643384 in "All it takes is for one to work out"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;The “one that works out” can also give you a misrepresentation of how the world works and a false sense of how lucky one should expect to be over a long period of time.&lt;p&gt;At an earlier point in my life, I had been applying to many well-known big tech companies right out of school (not a top school either). I never got a reply from any of them so I ended up accepting a local job with a non-tech company after months of searching.&lt;p&gt;But I didn’t give up my hopes and kept applying to big tech, and while I did manage to get the occasional interview with some mediocre companies or the random startup, I also miserably failed all of them too.&lt;p&gt;At some point during my long period of despair at never getting a better job, my very top pick (and arguably one of the best tech companies in the world at the time) reached out to me. Even more miraculously, I somehow passed their interview (the only tech interview I passed in the prior year) and accepted a job there.&lt;p&gt;I &lt;i&gt;really&lt;/i&gt; enjoyed working there. Some of the best years of my life. And my performance reviews were great too, so the imposter syndrome from having failed so many tech job interviews sort of faded into the background. But after a while, perhaps due to the “hedonic treadmill” mentality, I thought I could do better. So I left to join a startup.&lt;p&gt;Well, the startup failed, as startups tend to do, but what I didn’t expect and what caught me off guard was that I was now back in the same situation I was in right after graduating from college. Don’t get me wrong—having “the name” on my resume now meant I could get at least one chance at an interview about anywhere. But much like the first round that I tried to forget about, I once again failed all the interviews.&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, this second time around never procured a “get out of jail free” card.&lt;p&gt;So I guess my lesson is: 1) there’s a lot of luck involved in these things, 2) if life gives you a winning lottery ticket at some point, don’t throw it away for the chance to win an even bigger lottery, and 3) that famous saying about “the only actions regretted are those not taken” is absolutely, totally wrong—almost all of my regrets in life relate to taking some action I shouldn’t have rather than inaction.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 29 Nov 2025 21:24:20 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46090919</link><dc:creator>throwaway643384</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46090919</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46090919</guid></item><item><title>New comment by jmward01 in "All it takes is for one to work out"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;This is why having a safety net and resources to try again is so powerful. Given enough chances you will make it, big. That means the #1 factor in success is the number of chances you get to fail and try again, not necessarily how inherently good you are. I try to remind myself of this often. I have been given so many chances, and I took them.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 29 Nov 2025 21:09:48 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46090792</link><dc:creator>jmward01</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46090792</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46090792</guid></item><item><title>New comment by smallmancontrov in "Be Like Clippy"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Quite the opposite: clippy was useless but not hostile which is a sobering contrast to software that &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; hostile and therefore worse than useless.&lt;p&gt;It's a cute nostalgic way to say "the bar was on the floor and you blew it anyway."&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 29 Nov 2025 21:05:12 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46090760</link><dc:creator>smallmancontrov</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46090760</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46090760</guid></item><item><title>New comment by NietTim in "Be Like Clippy"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Clippy was never open source or "good" in any way, it not selling your data was a result of its time, not a conscious choice by its creators. The entire forced clippy "movement" is incredibly poorly thought out&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 29 Nov 2025 20:26:53 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46090463</link><dc:creator>NietTim</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46090463</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46090463</guid></item><item><title>New comment by hfsh in "Be Like Clippy"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;This clippy white-washing is annoying as hell. Just like clipppy was.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 29 Nov 2025 20:23:28 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46090437</link><dc:creator>hfsh</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46090437</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46090437</guid></item><item><title>New comment by jampa in "Major AI conference flooded with peer reviews written by AI"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;While I think there's significant AI "offloading" in writing, the article's methodology relies on "AI-detectors," which reads like PR for Pangram. I don't need to explain why AI detectors are mostly bullshit and harmful for people who have never used LLMs. [1]&lt;p&gt;1: &lt;a href="https://hn.algolia.com/?dateRange=all&amp;page=0&amp;prefix=true&amp;query=ai%20detector&amp;sort=byPopularity&amp;type=story" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://hn.algolia.com/?dateRange=all&amp;page=0&amp;prefix=true&amp;que...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 29 Nov 2025 16:07:29 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46088580</link><dc:creator>jampa</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46088580</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46088580</guid></item><item><title>New comment by serf in "Leak confirms OpenAI is preparing ads on ChatGPT for public roll out"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;this is one of those HN style comments where business acumen and pertinent sarcasm are wholly indistinguishable .&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 29 Nov 2025 15:37:00 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46088304</link><dc:creator>serf</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46088304</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46088304</guid></item><item><title>New comment by SketchySeaBeast in "Leak confirms OpenAI is preparing ads on ChatGPT for public roll out"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I can't wait for the instructions to start having ads embedded.&lt;p&gt;2. Place the turkey in your GE Two in One Oven set to 350, cooking for 10 minutes a lbs.&lt;p&gt;3. While waiting for your Turkey to finish cooking, why not have an ice cold Coke Zero?  Click here for nearby locations.&lt;p&gt;4. Remove Turkey from the oven, let rest for ten minutes while listening to Lady Gaga and Bruno Mars sing "Die with a Smile" on Spotify.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 29 Nov 2025 14:57:24 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46088024</link><dc:creator>SketchySeaBeast</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46088024</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46088024</guid></item><item><title>New comment by jgrahamc in "DNS LOC Record (2014)"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Oh wow. Did I really write that 11 years ago! How time flies.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 29 Nov 2025 14:46:08 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46087940</link><dc:creator>jgrahamc</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46087940</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46087940</guid></item><item><title>New comment by chrisweekly in "It's Always the Process, Stupid"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&gt; &lt;i&gt;Let’s rip the Band-Aid off immediately: If your underlying business process is a mess, sprinkling "AI dust" on it won’t turn it into gold. It will just speed up the rate at which you generate garbage.&lt;p&gt;In the world of Business IT, we get seduced by the shiny new toy. Right now, that toy is Artificial Intelligence. Boardrooms are buzzing with buzzwords like LLMs, agentic workflows, and generative reasoning. Executives are frantically asking, "What is our AI strategy?"&lt;p&gt;But here is the hard truth:&lt;p&gt;There is no such thing as an AI strategy.
There is only Business Process Optimization (BPO).&lt;/i&gt;&lt;p&gt;This is well-expressed, and almost certainly true for an overwhelming majority of companies.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 29 Nov 2025 14:37:09 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46087858</link><dc:creator>chrisweekly</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46087858</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46087858</guid></item><item><title>New comment by afavour in "Leak confirms OpenAI is preparing ads on ChatGPT for public roll out"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&gt; most normal people don't know what Claude or Gemini are&lt;p&gt;In think the point is that they don’t need to know what Gemini is, they just need to know Google, which they most definitely do.&lt;p&gt;IMO ads rollout won’t be as simple as you’re describing it. A lot of people have switched from Google search to AI specifically &lt;i&gt;because&lt;/i&gt; it isn’t filled with SEO, ad filled nonsense. So they’ll need to tread very, very carefully to introduce it without alienating customers. Not to mention mollifying advertisers who are nervous what their product will be shown alongside and OpenAI will probably struggle to offer iron clad guarantees about it. And people generally speaking don’t like ads. If competitors like Google are able to hold out longer with no ads (they certainly aren’t wanting for ad display surfaces) they might be able to pull users away from OpenAI.&lt;p&gt;IMO pivoting to ads is a sign of core weakness for OpenAI. Anyone trying to set up their own ad network in 2025 has to reckon with Google and Meta, the two absolute behemoths of online ads. And both also happen to be major competitors of OpenAI. If they need ads that’s a problem.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 29 Nov 2025 14:06:42 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46087622</link><dc:creator>afavour</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46087622</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46087622</guid></item><item><title>New comment by aurareturn in "Leak confirms OpenAI is preparing ads on ChatGPT for public roll out"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;- ~1 billion users in just 3 years&lt;p&gt;- Extremely personal data on users&lt;p&gt;- Novel way of introducing and learning more about sponsored products&lt;p&gt;- Strong branding for non-techie people (most normal people don't know what Claude or Gemini are)&lt;p&gt;- An app that is getting more and more addictive/indispensable&lt;p&gt;I think OpenAI is going to kill it in ads eventually. This is why Meta and Google went all in on AI. Their lucrative digital ad business is in an existential threat.&lt;p&gt;I think people who kept saying there is no moat in AI is about to be shocked at how strong of a moat there actually is for ChatGPT.&lt;p&gt;All free LLM chat apps will need to support ads or they will eventually die due to worse unit economics or run out of funding.&lt;p&gt;PS. Sam just said OpenAI's revenue will finish at $20b this year. 6x growth from 2024. Zero revenue from non-sub users. What do you guys think their revenue will end up in 2026?&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 29 Nov 2025 12:44:24 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46087109</link><dc:creator>aurareturn</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46087109</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46087109</guid></item><item><title>New comment by jmkni in "Leak confirms OpenAI is preparing ads on ChatGPT for public roll out"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I guess this could also have a knock-on effect, in that ChatGPT will steer it's users away from topics advertisers might find distasteful&lt;p&gt;Like it might not want to tell you about negative health effects from McDonalds, if McDonalds becomes a major source of ad revenue&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 29 Nov 2025 12:39:33 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46087091</link><dc:creator>jmkni</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46087091</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46087091</guid></item><item><title>New comment by addaon in "Airbus A320 – intense solar radiation may corrupt data critical for flight"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I’d really, really like to know what microcontroller family this was found on. Assuming that this is a safety processor (lockstep, ECC, etc) it suggests that ECC was insufficient for the level of bit flips they’re seeing — and if the concern is data corruption, not unintended restart, it means it’s enough flips in one word to be undetectable. The environment they’re operating in isn’t that different from everyone else, so unless they ate some margin elsewhere (bad voltage corner or something), this can definitely be relevant to others. Also would be interesting to know if it’s NVM or SRAM that’s effected.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 29 Nov 2025 02:00:30 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46084635</link><dc:creator>addaon</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46084635</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46084635</guid></item><item><title>New comment by jagged-chisel in "How good engineers write bad code at big companies"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&gt; Why does bad code bother engineers so much?&lt;p&gt;I’ll take a stab.&lt;p&gt;Because I’m being held accountable for the bad results of the bad code. Because I’m being held to task to fix the problems caused by the bad code on a schedule that I didn’t agree with. Because management is using someone else’s bad code to deny me a positive annual review.&lt;p&gt;“You’re a senior engineer - why did fixing this take so long?” Because of the garbage I had to wade through to even find the problem. Because I wasn’t yet working here when this was written and I have to take time to get my head around the insanity.&lt;p&gt;Yes, these are management problems. I’ve spent years managing managers and attempting to educate them on how bad code causes errors and delays. But for many reasons, it’s a Sysiphean task.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 29 Nov 2025 01:22:10 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46084448</link><dc:creator>jagged-chisel</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46084448</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46084448</guid></item></channel></rss>