<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>Hacker News: Best Comments</title><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/bestcomments</link><description>Hacker News RSS</description><docs>https://hnrss.org/</docs><generator>hnrss v2.1.1</generator><lastBuildDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2025 23:57:47 +0000</lastBuildDate><ns0:link href="https://hnrss.org/bestcomments" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item><title>New comment by runjake in "Apple M5 chip"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Let's see if I can turn this into an ASCII table and have it survive HN's reformatting.&lt;p&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;    +------+------------------+--------------+----------+----------------+-------------------+-------------------+---------------------------+
    | Chip | Process          | CPU Cores    | GPU      | Neural Engine  | Memory Bandwidth  | Unified Memory    | Geekbench6 (Single/Multi) |
    +------+------------------+--------------+----------+----------------+-------------------+-------------------+---------------------------+
    | M1   | 5 nm             | 8 (4P+4E)    | 7–8      | 16-core Neural | 68.25 GB/s        | 16 GB             | ~2346 / 8346              |
    | M2   | 5 nm (G2)        | 8 (4P+4E)    | 8–10     | 16-core Neural | 100 GB/s          | 24 GB             | ~2586 / 9672              |
    | M3   | 3 nm (first-gen) | 8 (4P+4E)    | 8–10     | 16-core Neural | 100 GB/s          | 24 GB             | ~2965 / 11565             |
    | M4   | 3 nm (second-gen)| 10 (4P+6E)   | 8–10     | 16-core Neural | 120 GB/s          | 32 GB             | ~3822 / 15031             |
    | M5   | 3 nm (third-gen) | 10 (4P+6E)   | 10       | 16-core Neural | 153 GB/s          | up to 32 GB       | ~4133 / 15437 (9-core)    |
    +------+------------------+--------------+----------+----------------+-------------------+-------------------+---------------------------+&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2025 19:57:40 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45597634</link><dc:creator>runjake</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45597634</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45597634</guid></item><item><title>New comment by hereme888 in "Apple M5 chip"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Base models only:&lt;p&gt;- M1 | 5 nm              | 8 (4P+4E)            | GPU 7–8      | 16-core Neural | Memory Bandwidth: 68.25 GB/s  | Unified Memory: 16 GB                     | Geekbench6 ~2346 / 8346&lt;p&gt;- M2 | 5 nm (G2)         | 8 (4P+4E)            | GPU 8–10     | 16-core Neural | Memory Bandwidth: 100 GB/s    | Unified Memory: 24 GB                     | Geekbench6 ~2586 / 9672&lt;p&gt;- M3 | 3 nm (first-gen)  | 8 (4P+4E)            | GPU 8–10     | 16-core Neural | Memory Bandwidth: 100 GB/s    | Unified Memory: 24 GB                     | Geekbench6 ~2965 / 11565&lt;p&gt;- M4 | 3 nm (second-gen) | 10 (4P+6E)           | GPU 8–10     | 16-core Neural | Memory Bandwidth: 120 GB/s    | Unified Memory: 32 GB                     | Geekbench6 ~3822 / 15031&lt;p&gt;- M5 | 3 nm (third-gen)  | 10 (4P+6E)           | GPU 10       | 16-core Neural | Memory Bandwidth: 153 GB/s    | Unified Memory: up to 32 GB               | Geekbench6 ~4133 / 15,437 (9-core sample)&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2025 18:25:49 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45596586</link><dc:creator>hereme888</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45596586</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45596586</guid></item><item><title>New comment by blactuary in "I almost got hacked by a 'job interview'"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;"transforming real estate with blockchain" is the only red flag needed&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2025 16:40:17 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45595164</link><dc:creator>blactuary</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45595164</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45595164</guid></item><item><title>New comment by 0xfaded in "M5 MacBook Pro"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;To any Linux users, I recently bought a fully loaded M4 MacBook pro to replace my aging Lenovo and strongly regret it. I thought I would use it for playing with LLMs, but local dev on a Mac is not fun and I still don't have it fully set up. I'll probably replace it with a framework at some point in the near future.&lt;p&gt;Edit: okay, that garnered more attention than I expected, I guess I owe a qualification.&lt;p&gt;1. Everything is just slightly different. I had to split all my dot files into common/Linux/Mac specific sections. Don't expect to be able to clone and build any random C++ project unless someone in the project is specifically targeting Mac.&lt;p&gt;2. Not everything is supported natively on arm64. I had an idea and wanted to spin up a project using DynamoRIO, but wasn't supported. Others have mentioned the docker quirks.&lt;p&gt;3. The window manager. I'm not a fan of all the animations and needing to gester between screens (and yes, I've been down the hotkeys rabbit hole). To install a 3rd party window manager you need to disable some security setting because appearantly they work by injecting into the display manager and calling private APIs.&lt;p&gt;So my person takeaway was that I took the openness of the Linux ecosystem for granted (I've always had a local checkout of the kernel so I can grep an error message if needed). Losing that for me felt like wearing a straightjacket. Ironically I have a MBP at work, but spend my day ssh'd into a Linux box. It's a great machine for running a web browser and terminal emulator.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2025 15:23:24 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45593989</link><dc:creator>0xfaded</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45593989</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45593989</guid></item><item><title>New comment by mumber_typhoon in "Apple M5 chip"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;The M5 MacBook Pro still gets the Broadcom WiFi chip but the M5 iPad Pros get the N1 and C1X (Sweet).&lt;p&gt;All in all, apple is doing some incredible things with hardware.&lt;p&gt;Software teams at apple really need to get their act together. The M1 itself is so powerful that nobody really needs to upgrade that for most things most people do on their computers. Tahoe however makes my M1 Air feel sluggish doing the exact same tasks ive been last couple of years. I really hope this is not intentional from Apple to make me upgrade. That would be a big let down.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2025 13:37:29 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45592334</link><dc:creator>mumber_typhoon</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45592334</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45592334</guid></item><item><title>New comment by DennisP in "Apple Vision Pro upgraded with M5 chip"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I was super interested in the Vision Pro when it was first released. Then I found out they went with an app model and the device could only display a single MacOS window. There went my dream of surrounding myself with a bunch of vim windows and terminals.&lt;p&gt;If they'd focused on maximizing the device's usefulness instead of its revenue stream, maybe things would have worked out better.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2025 13:26:56 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45592162</link><dc:creator>DennisP</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45592162</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45592162</guid></item><item><title>New comment by toddmorey in "Apple M5 chip"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;The modern Apple feels like their hardware teams way outperforming the software teams.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2025 13:20:33 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45592057</link><dc:creator>toddmorey</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45592057</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45592057</guid></item><item><title>New comment by CalRobert in "Ireland is making basic income for artists program permanent"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;They tried to call this "universal" until people pointed out it is the opposite of universal. This program is a wild distortion of what UBI is meant to be.&lt;p&gt;Everyone who would _like_ to be an artist, but can't afford to be one, is disqualified. Meanwhile, the acquaintance of mine who sold his house in London at a large profit and retired to a cottage in Westmeath to live off his gains and noodle around on the guitar a bit is a recipient of funds from this program.&lt;p&gt;Tellingly there's very little information about how to _become_ an artist with this program.&lt;p&gt;Edit/addendum: Worth noting they've produced some _very_ dubious numbers to claim this program is a net gain economically. &lt;a href="https://www.rte.ie/culture/2025/0923/1534768-basic-income-for-the-arts-pilot-generated-over-100m-in-benefits/" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://www.rte.ie/culture/2025/0923/1534768-basic-income-fo...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;"""
A key component of the total benefits came from psychological wellbeing, which contributed almost €80 million. In addition, the report estimates that audience engagement with the arts generated €16.9 million in social value, based on public willingness-to-pay for cultural experiences.
"""&lt;p&gt;And, as much as I like psychological wellbeing (who doesn't!) - saying that it's worth €80 million when you didn't actually get €80 million doesn't help things when it comes time to pay for the program. I'm unsurprised that giving people money improved their psychological well being.&lt;p&gt;I'd be more excited to see basic income for Deliveroo riders and people working in chippers.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2025 12:34:37 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45591439</link><dc:creator>CalRobert</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45591439</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45591439</guid></item><item><title>New comment by kburman in "Leaving serverless led to performance improvement and a simplified architecture"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;The takeaway here isn’t that serverless doesn’t work, it’s that the authors didn’t understand what they were building on. Putting a latency-critical API on a stateless edge runtime was a rookie mistake, and the pain they describe was entirely predictable.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2025 12:18:30 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45591246</link><dc:creator>kburman</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45591246</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45591246</guid></item><item><title>New comment by simul007 in "Bots are getting good at mimicking engagement"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Hi HN. I run a marketing agency and fell down this rabbit hole after a client's analytics made no sense (50k visitors, 47 sales). I ended up building a simple script to track user behavior and analyzed 200+ small e-commerce sites. The average was 73% bot traffic that standard analytics counts as real.&lt;p&gt;The bots are getting creepily good at mimicking engagement. I wrote up my findings, including some of the bizarre patterns I saw and the off-the-record conversations I had with ad tech insiders. It seems like a massive, open secret that nobody wants to talk about because the whole system is propped up by it.&lt;p&gt;I'm curious if other developers, founders, or marketers here have seen similar discrepancies in their own data.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2025 11:11:41 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45590682</link><dc:creator>simul007</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45590682</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45590682</guid></item><item><title>New comment by grues-dinner in "The cost of turning down wind turbines in Britain"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;People oppose everything.&lt;p&gt;* Lattice overhead powerlines? Eyesore (should use the new T style ones), house values, wind noise, hums, WiFi interference, cancer, access roads, hazard to planes, birds&lt;p&gt;* T-frame pylons: boring (&lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2015/apr/13/electricity-pylons-britain-duller-place-national-grid-t-pylon-design" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2015/apr/13/electr...&lt;/a&gt;), eyesore (we prefer the lattice ones), most of the above too&lt;p&gt;* Underground: damaging to the environment, end stations are eyesores/light polluters, more construction traffic, should be HVDC not AC, house values&lt;p&gt;* Solar farms: waste of good land (golf courses are fine) noise somehow, construction, eyesore (but a 400 acre field of stinky bright yellow rapeseed is OK), house values&lt;p&gt;* Onshore Wind farms: all the birds all the time, access, eyesore, noise, dangerous, should be offshore, house value, waste of land, I heard on Facebook the CO2 takes 500 years to pay back&lt;p&gt;* Offshore wind farms: eyesores, radar hazard, all the birds, house values somehow, navigation hazard, seabed disruption&lt;p&gt;* Build an access road: destroying the countryside, dust if not surfaced, drainage, house values&lt;p&gt;* Don't build an access road: destroying roads, HGVs on local roads, house values&lt;p&gt;* Nuclear: literally all the reasons plus scary&lt;p&gt;Some of them are fair on their own, but it really adds up to a tendentious bunch of wankers at every turn who think the house they bought for 100k in 1991 and is now worth 900k is the corner of the universe.&lt;p&gt;&gt; As a foreign influence&lt;p&gt;I'm sure these people would never take foreign cash: &lt;a href="https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/articles/c93k584nvgeo" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/articles/c93k584nvgeo&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/articles/clyk1j92195o" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/articles/clyk1j92195o&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2025 11:10:37 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45590673</link><dc:creator>grues-dinner</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45590673</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45590673</guid></item><item><title>New comment by cookiengineer in "FSF announces Librephone project"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Why can't they just partner with postmarketOS here?&lt;p&gt;Why do we have to have /e/OS instead of a better supported LineageOS, because /e/ is a 1:1 copy anyways?&lt;p&gt;Why do we have to have a Librephone project now instead of partnering with say, Fairphone and the Pine64 people?&lt;p&gt;Open source loses this war because proprietary devices are streamlined. The only thing that comes close to this is GrapheneOS, LineageOS, and postmarketOS.&lt;p&gt;LineageOS has huge problems since the mandatory eBPF requirements of late Android versions, which postmarketOS and its upstreamed kernel drivers could fix. GrapheneOS has huge problems because of Pixel devices, which LineageOS could help with.&lt;p&gt;We need a unification of this ecosystem because each on their own is hardly surviving on their own against the megacorporations.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2025 06:53:04 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45588911</link><dc:creator>cookiengineer</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45588911</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45588911</guid></item><item><title>New comment by krackers in "I am a programmer, not a rubber-stamp that approves Copilot generated code"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I find LLM generated code ends up pushing review/maintenance burden onto others. It "looks" right at first glance, and passes superficial tests, so it's easy to get merged. But then as you build on top of it, you realize the foundations are hastily put together, so a lot of it needs to be rewritten. Fine for throwaway or exploratory work, but heaven help you if you're working in a project where people use LLMs to "fix" bugs generated by previous LLM generated code.&lt;p&gt;So yes it does increase "velocity" for the person A who can get away with using it. But then the decrease in velocity for person B trying to build on top of that code is never properly tracked. It's like a game of hot potato, if you want to game the metrics you better be the one working on greenfield code (although I suppose maintenance work has never been looked at favorably in performance review; but now the cycle of code rot is accelerated)&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2025 06:23:26 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45588709</link><dc:creator>krackers</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45588709</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45588709</guid></item><item><title>New comment by bigstrat2003 in "FSF announces Librephone project"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Ultimately, I don't think the most important challenge is in binary firmware blobs, but the software which people depend upon to run their lives. What does it matter if you can run a completely free software stack on your phone, if your bank software (or your required government ID, as is looking depressingly likely) requires you to run a Big Tech approved phone OS? Perhaps the FSF can't do much about that, but that is where I feel they could truly make the biggest difference for freedom for the average user.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2025 00:36:28 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45586695</link><dc:creator>bigstrat2003</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45586695</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45586695</guid></item><item><title>New comment by jasonthorsness in "Why Is SQLite Coded In C"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;“None of the safe programming languages existed for the first 10 years of SQLite's existence. SQLite could be recoded in Go or Rust, but doing so would probably introduce far more bugs than would be fixed, and it may also result in slower code.”&lt;p&gt;Modern languages might do more than C to prevent programmers from writing buggy code, but if you already have bug-free code due to massive time, attention, and testing, and the rate of change is low (or zero), it doesn’t really matter what the language is. SQLIte could be assembly language for all it would matter.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2025 23:36:50 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45586284</link><dc:creator>jasonthorsness</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45586284</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45586284</guid></item><item><title>New comment by freetime2 in "Beliefs that are true for regular software but false when applied to AI"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;For a real world example of the challenges of harnessing LLMs, look at Apple. Over a year ago they had a big product launch focused on "Apple Intelligence" that was supposed to make heavy use of LLMs for agentic workflows. But all we've really gotten since then are a couple of minor tools for making emojis, summarizing notifications, and proof reading. And they even had to roll back the notification summaries for a while for being wildly "out of control". [1] And in this year's iPhone launch the AI marketing was toned down &lt;i&gt;significantly&lt;/i&gt;.&lt;p&gt;I think Apple execs genuinely underestimated how difficult it would be to get LLMs to perform up to Apple's typical standards of polish and control.&lt;p&gt;[1] &lt;a href="https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/cge93de21n0o" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/cge93de21n0o&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2025 22:08:38 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45585648</link><dc:creator>freetime2</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45585648</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45585648</guid></item><item><title>New comment by jrockway in "Let's Not Encrypt (2019)"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I think that if we didn't do TLS, every ISP would be injecting ads into websites these days.  Making it difficult for middle-of-the-road interlopers is a good thing. ISPs don't want the customer service burden of proxy configurations and custom certs (god knows your IT department hates the support aspect of this tampering), so TLS keeps us free of excessive advertising.  (Of course, they like do tampering with DNS which is why we have to do DNS-over-HTTPS. If you make it easy to tamper with your traffic, your ISP has a good business case to tamper with your traffic.  Sad but true.)&lt;p&gt;I'm not as convinced as the author is that nation states can easily tamper with certificates these days.  I am not sure how much CT checking we do before each page load, but either nation states are compelling the issue of certs that aren't in the CT database, or they are and you can just get a list of who the nation states are spying on.  Seems like less of a problem than it was a decade ago.&lt;p&gt;The author seems to miss the one guarantee that certificates provide; "the same people that controlled this site on $ISSUANCE_DATE control the site right now".  That can be a useful guarantee.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2025 14:11:15 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45580233</link><dc:creator>jrockway</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45580233</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45580233</guid></item><item><title>New comment by sgarland in "Why is everything so scalable?"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;THANK YOU. People look at me like I’m insane when I tell them that their overly-complicated pipeline could be easily handled by a couple of beefy servers. Or at best, they’ll argue that “this way, they don’t have to manage infrastructure.” Except you do - you absolutely do. It’s just been partially abstracted away, and some parts like OS maintenance are handled (not that that was ever the difficult part of managing servers), but you absolutely need to configure and monitor your specific XaaS you’re renting.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2025 12:55:19 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45579468</link><dc:creator>sgarland</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45579468</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45579468</guid></item><item><title>New comment by BirAdam in "Why is everything so scalable?"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Just to be honest for a bit here... we also should be asking what kind of scale?&lt;p&gt;Quite a while ago, before containers were a thing at all, I did systems for some very large porn companies. They were doing streaming video at scale before most, and the only other people working on video at that scale were Youtube.&lt;p&gt;The general setup for the largest players in that space was haproxy in front of nginx in front of several PHP servers in front of a MySQL database that had one primary r/w with one read only replica. Storage (at that time) was usually done with glusterfs. This was scalable enough at the time for hundreds of thousands of concurrent users, though the video quality was quite a bit lower than what people expect today.&lt;p&gt;Today at AWS, it is easily possible for people to spend a multiple of the cost of that hardware setup every month for far less compute power and storage.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2025 12:35:50 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45579298</link><dc:creator>BirAdam</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45579298</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45579298</guid></item><item><title>New comment by frameset in "KDE celebrates the 29th birthday and kicks off the yearly fundraiser"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I'm absolutely loving KDE since I returned to desktop Linux after a long absence.&lt;p&gt;What really shocks me is how few of the big distros make KDE a default or "first class" DE choice. If I was a novice user coming from Windows, I'd much prefer KDE, which if you stick to the GUI is very navigable and similar in some ways.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2025 11:34:46 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45578777</link><dc:creator>frameset</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45578777</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45578777</guid></item><item><title>New comment by daan-k in "Dutch government takes control of Chinese-owned chipmaker Nexperia"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Some new information has just emerged in the Dutch press.&lt;p&gt;According to a just published article by the NRC newspaper [0], the owner wanted to use Nexperia's funds to finance another business (WingSkySemi) which was in financial trouble. He would have done this by making Nexperia place large orders for wafers it did not need. The article mentions Nexperia only requiring $70-80 million in wafers, while Nexperia would have ordered wafers from WingSkySemi with a value of $200 million.&lt;p&gt;In order to achieve this, the owner is said to have put strawmen without financial experience in place and fire European directors. When other directors raised the alarm about this, they were fired according to the article.  
This issue was raised to the Dutch government, which then intervened.&lt;p&gt;Have a look at the original article through google translate, it provides a lot of interesting and important details to this story.&lt;p&gt;[0] &lt;a href="https://www.nrc.nl/nieuws/2025/10/14/chinese-topman-gebruikte-geld-van-nexperia-voor-zijn-chinese-chipfabriek-a4909538" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://www.nrc.nl/nieuws/2025/10/14/chinese-topman-gebruikt...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2025 10:48:27 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45578443</link><dc:creator>daan-k</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45578443</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45578443</guid></item><item><title>New comment by perching_aix in "New York Times, AP, Newsmax and others say they won't sign new Pentagon rules"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&gt; Chief Pentagon spokesman Sean Parnell said (...) "This has caused reporters to have a full blown meltdown, crying victim online."&lt;p&gt;Interesting use of language... seems like the mask is coming off everywhere now, not just where I live (Hungary).&lt;p&gt;I've been intentionally skipping on a lot of our local political reporting, so I was really quite surprised to see recently how lowbrow the language used by politicians, specifically those in power, has gotten these days. Especially how flagrant they are about it too.&lt;p&gt;This &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; a very meta, and to many I'm sure trivial, thing to take issue with, yes, but if those in authority are this unashamedly drunk on power, and look down on those they rule over so openly, I'd really question how fit they are to represent people's collective best interest.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2025 10:18:47 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45578256</link><dc:creator>perching_aix</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45578256</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45578256</guid></item><item><title>New comment by joshvince in "Why the push for Agentic when models can barely follow a simple instruction?"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&gt; if you’re working on novel code, LLMs are absolutely horrible&lt;p&gt;This is spot on. Current state-of-the-art models are, in my experience, very good at writing boilerplate code or very simple architecture especially in projects or frameworks where there are extremely well-known opinionated patterns (MVC especially).&lt;p&gt;What they are genuinely impressive at is parsing through large amounts of information to find something (eg: in a codebase, or in stack traces, or in logs). But this hype machine of 'agents creating entire codebases' is surely just smoke and mirrors - at least for now.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2025 08:09:00 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45577441</link><dc:creator>joshvince</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45577441</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45577441</guid></item><item><title>New comment by varun_chopra in "Why the push for Agentic when models can barely follow a simple instruction?"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Marketing is being done really well in 2025, with brands injecting themselves into conversations on Reddit, LinkedIn, and every other public forum. [1]&lt;p&gt;CEOs, AI "thought leaders," and VCs are advertising LLMs as magic, and tools like v0 and Lovable as the next big thing. Every response from leaders is some variation of &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=w61d-NBqafM" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=w61d-NBqafM&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;On the ground, we know that creating CLAUDE.md or cursorrules basically does nothing. It’s up to the LLM to follow instructions, and it does so based on RNG as far as I can tell. I have very simple, basic rules set up that are never followed. This leads me to believe everyone posting on that thread on Cursor is an amateur.&lt;p&gt;Beyond this, if you’re working on novel code, LLMs are absolutely horrible at doing anything. A lot of assumptions are made, non-existent libraries are used, and agents are just great at using tokens to generate no tangible result whatsoever.&lt;p&gt;I’m at a stage where I use LLMs the same way I would use speech-to-text (code) - telling the LLM exactly what I want, what files it should consider, and it adds _some_ value by thinking of edge cases I might’ve missed, best practices I’m unaware of, and writing better grammar than I do.&lt;p&gt;Edit:&lt;p&gt;[1] To add to this, any time you use search or Perplexity or what have you, the results come from all this marketing garbage being pumped into the internet by marketing teams.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2025 08:04:43 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45577405</link><dc:creator>varun_chopra</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45577405</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45577405</guid></item><item><title>New comment by vayup in "Don’t Look Up: Sensitive internal links in the clear on GEO satellites [pdf]"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Some of the stuff that was extracted from the unencrypted traffic in the link:&lt;p&gt;- T-Mobile backhaul: Users' SMS, voice call contents and internet traffic content in plain text.&lt;p&gt;- AT&amp;T Mexico cellular backhaul: Raw user internet traffic&lt;p&gt;- TelMex VOIP on satellite backhaul: Plaintext voice calls&lt;p&gt;- U.S. military: SIP traffic exposing ship names&lt;p&gt;- Mexico government and military: Unencrypted intra-government traffic&lt;p&gt;- Walmart Mexico: Unencrypted corporate emails, plaintext credentials to inventory management systems, inventory records transferred and updated using FTP&lt;p&gt;This is insane!&lt;p&gt;While it is important to work on futuristic threats such as Quantum cryptanalysis, backdoors in standardized cryptographic protocols, etc. - the unfortunate reality is that the vast majority of real-world attacks happen because basic protection is not enabled. Good reminder not take our eyes off the basics.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2025 04:57:13 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45576404</link><dc:creator>vayup</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45576404</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45576404</guid></item><item><title>New comment by lkey in "New York Times, AP, Newsmax and others say they won't sign new Pentagon rules"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;It's a great thing they are not backing down. Given how many institutions have complied in advance, we need as many exemplars of better behaviour as possible.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2025 04:27:10 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45576255</link><dc:creator>lkey</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45576255</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45576255</guid></item><item><title>New comment by jampa in "Palisades Fire suspect's ChatGPT history to be used as evidence"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;The headline and article try to bias and frame the story to make people question: "Is OpenAI snitching on me?"&lt;p&gt;In reality, Uber records and conflicting statements incriminated him. He seems to be the one who provided the ChatGPT record to try to prove that the fire was unintentional.[1]&lt;p&gt;&gt; He was visibly anxious during that interview, according to the complaint. His efforts to call 911 and his question to ChatGPT about a cigarette lighting a fire indicated that he wanted to create a more innocent explanation for the fire's start and to show he tried to assist with suppression, the complaint said.&lt;p&gt;[1] &lt;a href="https://apnews.com/article/california-wildfires-palisades-los-angeles-deb1c78c1d83d233cf3b540644814ea2" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://apnews.com/article/california-wildfires-palisades-lo...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2025 03:41:57 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45576039</link><dc:creator>jampa</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45576039</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45576039</guid></item><item><title>New comment by mikewarot in "America is getting an AI gold rush instead of a factory boom"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Having worked in a job shop, a factory that did gears down to quantity one, I became quite aware of the differences between IT, my previous job, and actual physical production.&lt;p&gt;The machine tools were all made 50+ years ago. Changing &lt;i&gt;anything&lt;/i&gt; was a dangerous thing to do, because you might cause jobs that have known and reliable setups that are done a few times a year in quantity, to fail, erasing the profits for the job, and possibly losing customers.&lt;p&gt;The rush to fill brand new high energy intensive data centers with hardware that has commercially useful lifetimes measured in months (instead of decades for machine tools) seems quite short sighted to me.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2025 03:21:00 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45575908</link><dc:creator>mikewarot</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45575908</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45575908</guid></item><item><title>New comment by gehwartzen in "America's future could hinge on whether AI slightly disappoints"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I work for one of the largest packaging companies in the world. Customers across the board in the US are cutting back on how much packaging they need due to presumably lower sales volume. Make of that information what you will.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2025 02:08:43 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45575511</link><dc:creator>gehwartzen</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45575511</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45575511</guid></item><item><title>New comment by aquova in "Sony PlayStation 2 fixing frenzy"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I've seen a few posters ask already, so I figured I'd answer what the PS2 analog button's function was.&lt;p&gt;The button switches between two modes of the analog joysticks, either to behave with their normal functionality, or to simply be a digital input (so just round all movement to either up/down/left/right). For PS2 games, you typically wouldn't want to do this. Instead, the functionality exists because the PS2 was backwards compatible with PS1 titles. The original PS1 controller didn't have analog sticks at all, just the D-Pad for navigation. After a few years (and the success of Nintendo's N64 analog controller) Sony released a revised version of the controller that included two joysticks, which their controllers still mimic to this day. However, those PS1 games released prior to the analog controller wouldn't always behave correctly if you tried to use an analog input scheme, so Sony added a mode to allow the Joysticks to function the same as the D-Pad, in case players preferred it.&lt;p&gt;Other fun fact, the analog controller was not the same as their more famous Dualshock controller. There was a short-lived PS1 Dual Analog controller which just added the joysticks. It only lasted a few months before Sony replaced it with one that supported rumble functionality (also after being inspired by the N64), this was the Dualshock.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2025 01:04:00 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45575097</link><dc:creator>aquova</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45575097</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45575097</guid></item></channel></rss>