<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>Hacker News: Best Comments</title><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/bestcomments</link><description>Hacker News RSS</description><docs>https://hnrss.org/</docs><generator>hnrss v2.1.1</generator><lastBuildDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 00:30:31 +0000</lastBuildDate><ns0:link href="https://hnrss.org/bestcomments" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item><title>New comment by saltysalt in "AI's Dial-Up Era"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Not sure the dial-up analogy fits, instead I tend to think we are in the mainframe period of AI, with large centralised computing models that are so big and expensive to host, only a few corporations can afford to do so. We rent a computing timeshare from them (tokens = punch cards).&lt;p&gt;I look forward to the "personal computing" period, with small models distributed everywhere...&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 22:32:58 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45805263</link><dc:creator>saltysalt</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45805263</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45805263</guid></item><item><title>New comment by booi in "&lt;/&gt; Htmx – The Fetch()ening"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&gt; So, eventually &amp; reluctantly, I have changed my mind: there will be another major version of htmx.&lt;p&gt;&gt; However, in order to keep my word that there will not be a htmx 3.0, the next release will instead be htmx 4.0.&lt;p&gt;technically correct.. the best kind of correct&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 20:54:11 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45804308</link><dc:creator>booi</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45804308</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45804308</guid></item><item><title>New comment by jervant in "Wikipedia row erupts as Jimmy Wales intervenes on 'Gaza genocide' page"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;From the headline, one might assume he directly edited or locked the page when he just commented on the article's discussion page that it should have a more neutral tone.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 19:54:46 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45803640</link><dc:creator>jervant</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45803640</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45803640</guid></item><item><title>New comment by Symmetry in "The Case That A.I. Is Thinking"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;"The question of whether a computer can think is no more interesting than the question of whether a submarine can swim." - Edsger Dijkstra&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 19:04:40 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45802962</link><dc:creator>Symmetry</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45802962</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45802962</guid></item><item><title>New comment by educasean in "The Case That A.I. Is Thinking"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;The debate around whether or not transformer-architecture-based AIs can "think" or not is so exhausting and I'm over it.&lt;p&gt;What's much more interesting is the question of "If what LLMs do today isn't actual thinking, what is something that only an actually thinking entity can do that LLMs can't?". Otherwise we go in endless circles about language and meaning of words instead of discussing practical, demonstrable capabilities.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 19:03:22 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45802934</link><dc:creator>educasean</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45802934</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45802934</guid></item><item><title>New comment by JCM9 in "OpenAI signs $38B cloud computing deal with Amazon"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;OpenAI is generating $13B a year in revenue. Let’s be generous and say $20B. They’ve signed commitments to spend something like $1.4 trillion on compute. An asset that to date has proven to have a hyper-depreciation cycle.&lt;p&gt;Someone has to come up with $1.4 trillion in actual cash, fast, or this whole thing comes crashing down. Why? At the end of all this circular financing and deals are folks that actually want real cash (eg electricity utilities that aren’t going to accept OpenAI shares for payment).&lt;p&gt;If the above doesn’t freak you about a bit at how bonkers this whole thing has become then you need a reality check. “Selling ads” on ChatGPT ain’t gonna close that hole.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 18:34:25 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45802550</link><dc:creator>JCM9</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45802550</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45802550</guid></item><item><title>New comment by srpablo in "Why we migrated from Python to Node.js"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I'm really torn -- you and your engineers should be excited to work on your codebase. You should enter it and be like "yes, I've made good choices and this is a codebase I appreciate, and it has promise." If you have a set of storylines that make this migration appropriate, and its still early in the company that you can even do this in 3 days, then by all means, do it! And good luck. It'll never be cheaper to do it, and you are going to be "wearing" it for your company's lifetime.&lt;p&gt;But a part of me is reading this and thinking "friend... if PostHog was able to do what they're doing on the stack you're abandoning, do you think that stack is &lt;i&gt;actually&lt;/i&gt; going to limit your scalability in any way that matters?" Like, you have the counterexample right there! Other companies are making the "technically worse" choice but making it work.&lt;p&gt;I love coding and I recognize that human beings are made of narratives, but this feels like 3 days you could have spent on customer needs or feature dev or marketing, and instead you rolled around in the code mud for a bit. It's fine to do that every now and then, and if this was a more radical jump (e.g. a BEAM language like Elixir or Gleam, or hell, even Golang, which has that preemptive scheduler + fast compiles/binary deploys + designed around a type system...) than I'd buy it more. And I'm not in your shoes so it's easy to armchair quarterback. But it smells a bit like getting in your head on technical narratives that are more fun to apply your creativity to, instead of the ones your company really needs.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 18:34:02 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45802544</link><dc:creator>srpablo</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45802544</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45802544</guid></item><item><title>New comment by reenorap in "The problem with farmed seafood"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;You can't have a sustainable ecology when China sends a city of trawlers to devastate fish stocks around the world and then sends it all back to China. It leaves the countries that were depending on that fish suffering with no repercussions for China. As far as I'm concerned, those cities of fishing boats should be sunk because it's an act of war by China.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 16:13:56 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45800648</link><dc:creator>reenorap</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45800648</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45800648</guid></item><item><title>New comment by antman in "Google suspended my company's Google cloud account for the third time"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;People consider google as a trusted partner whereas it is designed as a retail factory. Mass serving of millions and protectioms whose false positives can destroy the lives of thousands. Still they are statistically correct. Nuking everything instead of the offending service? Convenient fir them. Unavailable support reps? Convenient for them? Meaningless automated answers? Convenient for them. Its not a solid system that has defects, it was designed that way. Their unavailability and abrupt cruelty does not serve as cost optimisation, it serves as liability optimisation.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 14:39:00 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45799458</link><dc:creator>antman</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45799458</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45799458</guid></item><item><title>New comment by palata in "Why Nextcloud feels slow to use"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I would love to like Nextcloud, it's pretty great that it does exist. Just that makes it better than... well everything else I haven't found.&lt;p&gt;What frustrates me is that it looks like it works, but once in a while it breaks in a way that is pretty much irreparable (or at least not in a practical way).&lt;p&gt;I want to run an iOS/Android app that backs up images on my server. I tried the iOS app and when it works, it's cool. It's just that once in a while I get errors like "locked webdav" files and it never seems to recover, or sometimes it just stops synchronising and the only way to recover seems to be to restart the sync &lt;i&gt;from zero&lt;/i&gt;. It will gladly upload 80GB of pictures "for nothing", discarding each one when it arrives on the server because it already exists (or so it seems, maybe it just overwrites everything).&lt;p&gt;The thing is that I want my family to use the app, so I can't access their phone for multiple hours every 2 weeks; it has to work reliably.&lt;p&gt;If it was just for backing up &lt;i&gt;my&lt;/i&gt; photos... well I don't need Nextcloud for that.&lt;p&gt;Again, alternatives just don't seem to exist, where I can install an app on my parent's iOS and have it synchronise their photo gallery in the background. Except I guess iCloud, that is.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 14:35:44 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45799410</link><dc:creator>palata</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45799410</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45799410</guid></item><item><title>New comment by xfalcox in "The Case Against PGVector"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&gt; Nobody’s actually run this in production&lt;p&gt;We do at Discourse, in thousands of databases, and it's leveraged in most of the billions of page views we serve.&lt;p&gt;&gt; Pre- vs. Post-Filtering (or: why you need to become a query planner expert)&lt;p&gt;This was fixed in version 0.8.0 via Iterative Scans (&lt;a href="https://github.com/pgvector/pgvector?tab=readme-ov-file#iterative-scan-options" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://github.com/pgvector/pgvector?tab=readme-ov-file#iter...&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;p&gt;&gt; Just use a real vector database&lt;p&gt;If you are running a single service that may be an easier sell, but it's not a silver bullet.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 14:16:36 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45799162</link><dc:creator>xfalcox</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45799162</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45799162</guid></item><item><title>New comment by SirFatty in "Update and shut down no longer restarts PC, 25H2 patch addresses decades-old bug"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;"Microsoft shipped a broken “Update and shut down” toggle with Windows 10, and it never acknowledged it until now."&lt;p&gt;I guess they know what's best for the user base, and this was obviously deemed not important.  But boy did they get Copilot integrated in everything post haste.&lt;p&gt;Typical Microsoft hubris.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 12:43:34 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45798430</link><dc:creator>SirFatty</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45798430</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45798430</guid></item><item><title>New comment by agys in "Tiny electric motor can produce more than 1,000 horsepower"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Everything but the Metric System: “The new YASA axial flux motor weighs just 28 pounds, or about the same as a small dog.” :)&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 10:15:05 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45797535</link><dc:creator>agys</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45797535</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45797535</guid></item><item><title>New comment by davedx in "Tiny electric motor can produce more than 1,000 horsepower"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Could lead to significant efficiency gains for EV's, because 1/4 of the motor weight means better power-to-weight ratio... a lot of things will automatically get better.&lt;p&gt;YASA was founded in 2009, a spin out from Oxford University following the PhD of founder and still CTO, Dr Tim Woolmer.&lt;p&gt;"Over the decades that followed both of these technologies were explored. But despite the potential for weight reduction, smaller size, shorter axle length and increased torque, it was the difficulty in manufacturing the axial flux technology that limited its commercial viability, because the motor could not be made by stacking laminations, as with radial machines."&lt;p&gt;"The breakthrough innovation came by segmenting the axial flux motor in discrete "pole-pieces", so the motor could be manufactured using Soft Magnetic Composite material.&lt;p&gt;SMC can be pressed at low cost into a wide variety of 3D shapes. This removed the need for the complex laminations, overcoming the major manufacturing challenge of the axial flux machine."&lt;p&gt;"In 2025, after a £12m investment, YASA opened the UK's first axial-flux super factory, in Oxfordshire.&lt;p&gt;The opening of this facility boosts YASA’s manufacturing capacity, setting new benchmarks in e-motor technology and quality, and enabling production to scale beyond 25,000 units per year."&lt;p&gt;This is awesome. Lighter motors also make electric flight more viable&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 09:39:58 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45797359</link><dc:creator>davedx</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45797359</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45797359</guid></item><item><title>New comment by darshanime in "First recording of a dying human brain shows waves similar to memory flashbacks (2022)"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;When I was around 15, I used to hang out with a guy who was much senior to me, and he would bully us sometimes. One day, when we were bantering, I cracked a joke that a third guy with us (who was my age) found funny and crackled. The bully grabbed my neck and choked me till I lost consciousness. I remember having memory flashbacks related to missing a train, and someone waiting at the wagon door, waving at me to hurry and jump in before it is too late. I remember feeling stressed about missing the train. The next thing I remember is slowly regaining consciousness to see the bully and the 3rd guy splashing water at my face, looking very amused.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 08:30:20 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45797004</link><dc:creator>darshanime</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45797004</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45797004</guid></item><item><title>New comment by zabumafu in "Simple trick to increase coverage: Lying to users about signal strength"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I implemented the same behavior in a different Google product.&lt;p&gt;I remember the PM working on this feature showing us their research on how iPhones rendered bars across different versions.&lt;p&gt;They had different spectrum ranges, one for each of maybe the last 3 iPhone versions at the time. And overlayed were lines that indicated the "breakpoints" where iPhones would show more bars.&lt;p&gt;And you could clearly see that on every release, iPhones were shifting the all the breakpoints more and more into the left, rendering more bars with less signal strength.&lt;p&gt;We tried to implement something that matched the most recent iPhone version.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 05:47:21 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45796201</link><dc:creator>zabumafu</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45796201</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45796201</guid></item><item><title>New comment by kashnote in "Facts about throwing good parties"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Love all of these tips. I've hosted dozens of events since moving to NYC and figured I'd add 5 more:&lt;p&gt;1. If this is a dinner party (or people are all seated), force people to get up and move in a way that they'll meet new people. Do this when you're about 2/3 of the way through the party. Some will complain - do it anyway.&lt;p&gt;2. Plan 1 (ideally 2) interludes. It can be a small speech, moving people around, changing locations, having people vote on something, etc. For whatever reason, they make the night more memorable.&lt;p&gt;3. Do your best to make introductions natural and low-pressure. Saying things like "you two would really get along" can put pressure on people - especially shy ones. Bring up something they have in common and let them chat while you back away.&lt;p&gt;4. Go easy on folks who cancel last minute. They often don't feel good about doing it and you don't want to add more stress to them or yourself.&lt;p&gt;5. More music != more fun. Some music is good, but if people can't hear each other, turn it down.&lt;p&gt;If you're interested reading more about this stuff, read The Art of Gathering by Priya Parker.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 01:10:17 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45794946</link><dc:creator>kashnote</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45794946</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45794946</guid></item><item><title>New comment by dlisboa in "Facts about throwing good parties"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I feel like this is really an American culture thing where parties or dinner parties are mostly the responsibility of the host. In movies or TV there’s even a common theme of guests judging the host’s hosting abilities.&lt;p&gt;In Brazil you throw a party to people you like and they all have a hand in helping you, sharing the load. Everyone will be responsible for some part of it, all of it is organized informally, there are no real formalities to the event. No one cares about making a science out of it.&lt;p&gt;I’ve never heard of a person complaining about party quality or comparing hosting abilities.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 00:38:43 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45794756</link><dc:creator>dlisboa</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45794756</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45794756</guid></item><item><title>New comment by ssl-3 in "Facts about throwing good parties"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I had a halloween party once.  It had everything:  Substance abuse, debauchery, a proper PA system shaking the floor, good lighting, costumes, good people we knew, random other people we'd never met before, a keg of beer, epic bean dip...  everything but the police, somehow.&lt;p&gt;Anyway, my boss showed up.  I don't know if I invited him or if he just decided to be there on his own.  He was having a great time with everything, and then he went into the back where some folks were enjoying the not-booze.&lt;p&gt;It was at this point that I lost track of him.&lt;p&gt;His jacket was still there.  His motorcycle was still parked on the front sidewalk.  But he was nowhere to be found, and his phone went straight to voicemail.  It was like he'd simply vanished.&lt;p&gt;"Fuck," I thought to myself.  "I've only had this job for a few months."&lt;p&gt;It turns out that he'd walked home, a couple of miles away.  He woke up the next morning sitting at the picnic table in his back yard, shirtless, in the rain.&lt;p&gt;After that, I always made sure that I invited him to my other parties -- and he always made sure to decline, and tell me that he was never doing anything like that ever again.  I consider this to be a win.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 00:31:22 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45794712</link><dc:creator>ssl-3</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45794712</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45794712</guid></item><item><title>New comment by buildsjets in "Facts about throwing good parties"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I sure miss the kind of parties where they have to get an emergency court order to cut power the building at 3am.&lt;p&gt;I learned everything I need to know about throwing parties from Dave Barry.&lt;p&gt;If you throw a party, the worst thing that you can do would be to throw the kind of party where your guests wake up today, and call you to say they had a nice time.  Now you'll be be expected to throw another party next year.&lt;p&gt;What you should do is throw the kind of party where your guest wake up several days from now and call their lawyers to find out if they've been indicted for anything.  You want your guests to be so anxious to avoid a recurrence of your party that they immediately start planning parties of their own, a year in advance, just to prevent you from having another one.&lt;p&gt;If your party is successful, the police will knock on your door, unless your party is very successful in which case they will lob tear gas through your living room window.  As host, your job is to make sure that they don't arrest anybody.  Or if they're dead set on arresting someone, your job is to make sure it isn't you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 02 Nov 2025 23:54:47 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45794494</link><dc:creator>buildsjets</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45794494</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45794494</guid></item><item><title>New comment by ryukoposting in "Is Your Bluetooth Chip Leaking Secrets via RF Signals?"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;As someone who finally recently escaped bluetooth firmware development: yes, Bluetooth is leaking secrets and it doesn't even require any silly RF shenanigans. Almost nothing actually implements LESC. Apple refuses to implement OOB pairing, so no peripherals can force you to use it, so everything is subject to MITM attacks. The entire ecosystem is a mess of consultants and underpaid devs copy-pasting Nordic sample code, with no time or financial incentive to do more than the bare minumum. Never trust any product that moves sensitive data through Bluetooth.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 02 Nov 2025 23:15:44 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45794273</link><dc:creator>ryukoposting</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45794273</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45794273</guid></item><item><title>New comment by tmnvix in "Why does Swiss cheese have holes?"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Tom Scott on why Swiss Cheese was losing its holes (spoiler: the process became too sanitised - reintroducing impurities solved the problem).&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=evV05QeSjAw" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=evV05QeSjAw&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 02 Nov 2025 22:13:00 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45793885</link><dc:creator>tmnvix</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45793885</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45793885</guid></item><item><title>New comment by SteveNuts in "Linux gamers on Steam cross over the 3% mark"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;The only thing windows has focused on has been dark patterns to force users towards cloud and figuring out more and more ways to collect data to sell ads.&lt;p&gt;I’m not naive, I know a ton of huge enterprises still run huge fleets of windows “servers” but I still find it hilarious that a supposedly serious server OS would default to showing you the weather and ads in the start menu.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 02 Nov 2025 20:18:31 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45793048</link><dc:creator>SteveNuts</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45793048</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45793048</guid></item><item><title>New comment by TACIXAT in "Linux gamers on Steam cross over the 3% mark"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I just made the switch. I had been developing on Windows for the last couple of years, mostly to get used to the ecosystem. I wanted to be able to write C and C++ like I do on Linux, without an IDE and with the native toolchain (i.e. no cygwin). On top of that, I play Overwatch every night.&lt;p&gt;Windows just seems to have zero focus on performance though. React based start menu with visible lag, file Explorer (buggily) parsing files to display metadata before listing them, mysterious memory leaks not reflected in task manager processes.&lt;p&gt;I installed Linux Mint. While it didn't just work (TM), and I had to go into recovery mode to install Nvidia drivers, it worked well enough. I can run Overwatch via Steam and pull comparable FPS to Windows (500 FPS on a 3090 with dips into the 400s). Memory usage is stable and at a very low baseline.&lt;p&gt;It is nice to come back to Linux, and with games I don't really have a need to run Windows anymore.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 02 Nov 2025 20:00:56 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45792940</link><dc:creator>TACIXAT</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45792940</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45792940</guid></item><item><title>New comment by jorl17 in "URLs are state containers"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;When I get my way reviewing a codebase, I make sure that as much state as possible is saved in a URL, sometimes (though rarely) down to the scroll position.&lt;p&gt;I genuinely don't understand why people don't get more upset over hitting refresh on a webpage and ending up in a significantly different place. It's mind-boggling and actually insulting as a user. Or grabbing a URL and sending to another person, only to find out it doesn't make sense.&lt;p&gt;Developing like this on small teams also tends, in my experience, to lead to better UX, because it makes you much more aware of how much state you're cramming into a view. I'll admit it makes development slower, but I'll take the hit most days.&lt;p&gt;I've seen some people in this thread comment on how having state in a URL is risky because it then becomes a sort of public API that limits you. While I agree this might be a problem in some scenarios, I think there are many others where that is not the case, as copied URLs tend to be short-lived (bookmarks and "browser history" are an exception), mostly used for refreshing a page (which will later be closed) or for sharing . In the remaining cases, you can always plug in some code to migrate from the old URL to the new URL when loading, which will actually solve the issue if you got there via browser history (won't fix for bookmarks though).&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 02 Nov 2025 13:49:29 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45790346</link><dc:creator>jorl17</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45790346</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45790346</guid></item><item><title>New comment by perlgeek in "We reduced a container image from 800GB to 2GB"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;The real lesson they should learn is to not rely on running images and then using "docker commit" to turn it into an image, but instead to use proper image building tools.&lt;p&gt;If you absolutely have to do it that way, be very deliberate about what you actually need. Don't run an SSH daemon, don't run cron, don't an SMTP daemon, don't run the suite of daemons that run on a typical Linux server. Only run precisely what you need to create the files that you need for a "docker commit".&lt;p&gt;Each service that you run can potentially generate log files, lock files, temp files, named pipes, unix sockets and other things you don't want in your image.&lt;p&gt;Taking a snapshot from a working, regular VM and using that as a docker image is one of the worst ways to built one.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 02 Nov 2025 12:02:51 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45789695</link><dc:creator>perlgeek</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45789695</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45789695</guid></item><item><title>New comment by visopsys in "Visopsys: OS maintained by a single developer since 1997"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I took an OS in college in 2006 and the big project that my prof required us to do was to make modification of visopsys. The software was primitive at that time but still had UI interface.&lt;p&gt;I emailed the author to ask some questions in my project. The author had connection with my prof and informed my prof about this. My prof told me that I was not allowed to ask the author regarding this project. So I had to figured out on my own.&lt;p&gt;It was fun to play around with and learnt how things work at deep OS level. It was a good memory for me :)&lt;p&gt;And you guys notice anything about my username? :)&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 02 Nov 2025 06:09:54 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45788159</link><dc:creator>visopsys</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45788159</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45788159</guid></item><item><title>New comment by keiferski in "Pomelli"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I’ve seen many small businesses do well on TikTok and Instagram by eschewing all fancy graphics and technology, and just talking into their phone’s camera like a normal person. “Hey I’m Joe, I just opened a cafe down here. It’s always been my dream, etc.” The more quirky and human the video, the better it does.&lt;p&gt;I know this new tool looks to be for static graphics; but I do think the same thing applies. Not using AI-generated polished graphics will become a differentiator.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 02 Nov 2025 05:28:20 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45788030</link><dc:creator>keiferski</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45788030</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45788030</guid></item><item><title>New comment by simonw in "How I use every Claude Code feature"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&gt; Finally, we keep this file synced with an AGENTS.md file to maintain compatibility with other AI IDEs that our engineers might be using.&lt;p&gt;I researched this the other day, the recommended (by Anthropic) way to do this is to have a CLAUDE.md with a single line in it:&lt;p&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;  @AGENTS.md
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
Then keep your actual content in the other file: &lt;a href="https://docs.claude.com/en/docs/claude-code/claude-code-on-the-web#best-practices" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://docs.claude.com/en/docs/claude-code/claude-code-on-t...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 02 Nov 2025 02:27:09 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45787397</link><dc:creator>simonw</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45787397</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45787397</guid></item><item><title>New comment by roughly in "Why "everyone dies" gets AGI all wrong"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I’m more optimistic about the possibility of beneficial AGI in general than most folks, I think, but something that caught me in the article was the recourse to mammalian sociality to (effectively) advocate for compassion as an emergent quality of intelligence.&lt;p&gt;A known phenomenon among sociologists is that, while people may be compassionate, when you collect them into a superorganism like a corporation, army, or nation, they will by and large behave and make decisions according to the moral and ideological landscape that superorganism finds itself in. Nobody rational would kill another person for no reason, but a soldier will bomb a village for the sake of their nation’s geostrategic position. Nobody would throw someone out of their home or deny another person lifesaving medicine, but as a bank officer or an insurance agent, they make a living doing these things and sleep untroubled at night. A CEO will lay off 30,000 people - an entire small city cast off into an uncaring market - with all the introspection of a Mongol chieftain subjugating a city (and probably less emotion). Humans may be compassionate, but employees, soldiers, and politicians are not, even though at a glance they’re made of the same stuff.&lt;p&gt;That’s all to say that to just wave generally in the direction of mammalian compassion and say “of course a superintelligence will be compassionate” is to abdicate our responsibility for raising our cognitive children in an environment that rewards the morals we want them to have, which is emphatically not what we’re currently doing for the collective intelligences we’ve already created.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 02 Nov 2025 02:18:00 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45787356</link><dc:creator>roughly</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45787356</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45787356</guid></item></channel></rss>