<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>Hacker News: Best Comments</title><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/bestcomments</link><description>Hacker News RSS</description><docs>https://hnrss.org/</docs><generator>hnrss v2.1.1</generator><lastBuildDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 01:48:13 +0000</lastBuildDate><ns0:link href="https://hnrss.org/bestcomments" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item><title>New comment by rossdavidh in "Trillions spent and big software projects are still failing"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;It's a great article, until the end where they say what the solution would be.  I'm afraid that the solution is: build something small, and use it in production before you add more features.  If you need to make a national payroll, you have to use it for a small town with a payroll of 50 people first, get the bugs worked out, then try it with a larger town, then a small city, then a large city, then a province, and then and only then are you ready to try it at a national level.  There is no software development process which reliably produces software that works at scale without doing it small, and medium sized, first, and fixing what goes wrong before you go big.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 19:30:45 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46049703</link><dc:creator>rossdavidh</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46049703</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46049703</guid></item><item><title>New comment by wingmanjd in "Google Antigravity exfiltrates data via indirect prompt injection attack"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I really liked Simon's Willison's [1] and Meta's [2] approach using the "Rule of Two".  You can have no more than 2 of the following:&lt;p&gt;- A) Process untrustworthy input
- B) Have access to private data
- C) Be able to change external state or communicate externally.&lt;p&gt;It's not bullet-proof, but it has helped communicate to my management that these tools have inherent risk when they hit all three categories above (and any combo of them, imho).&lt;p&gt;[EDIT] added "or communicate externally" to option C.&lt;p&gt;[1] &lt;a href="https://simonwillison.net/2025/Nov/2/new-prompt-injection-papers/" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://simonwillison.net/2025/Nov/2/new-prompt-injection-pa...&lt;/a&gt;
[2] &lt;a href="https://ai.meta.com/blog/practical-ai-agent-security/" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://ai.meta.com/blog/practical-ai-agent-security/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 19:23:06 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46049625</link><dc:creator>wingmanjd</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46049625</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46049625</guid></item><item><title>New comment by malfist in "Trillions spent and big software projects are still failing"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I work at $FANG, every one of our org's big projects go off the rails at the end of the project and there's always a mad rush at the end to push developers to solve all the failures of project management in their off hours before the arbitrary deadline arrives.&lt;p&gt;After every single project, the org comes together to do a retrospective and ask "What can devs do differently next time to keep this from happening again". People leading the project take no action items, management doesn't hold themselves accountable at all, nor product for late changing requirements. And so, the cycle repeats next time.&lt;p&gt;I led and effort one time, after a big bug made it to production after one of those crunches that painted the picture of the root cause being a huge complicated project being handed off to offshore junior devs with no supervision, and then the junior devs managing it being completely switched twice in the 8 month project with no handover, nor introspection by leadership. My manager's manager killed the document and wouldn't allow publication until I removed any action items that would constrain management.&lt;p&gt;And thus, the cycle continues to repeat, balanced on the backs of developers.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 17:14:06 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46048044</link><dc:creator>malfist</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46048044</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46048044</guid></item><item><title>New comment by BirAdam in "Trillions spent and big software projects are still failing"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I study and write quite a bit of tech history. IMHO from what I've learned over the last few years of this hobby, the primary issue is quite simple. While hardware folks study and learn from the successes and failures of past hardware, software folks do not. People do not regularly pull apart old systems for learning. Typically, software folks build new and every generation of software developers must relearn the same problems.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 16:27:27 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46047424</link><dc:creator>BirAdam</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46047424</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46047424</guid></item><item><title>New comment by geerlingguy in "APT Rust requirement raises questions"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I remembered reading about this news back when that first message was posted on the mailing list, and didn't think much of it then (rust has been worming its way into a lot of places over the past few years, just one more thing I tack on for some automation)...&lt;p&gt;But seeing the maintainer works for Canonical, it seems like the tail (Ubuntu) keeps trying to wag the dog (Debian ecosystem) without much regard for the wider non-Ubuntu community.&lt;p&gt;I think the whole message would be more palatable if it weren't written as a decree including the dig on "retro computers", but instead positioned only on the merits of the change.&lt;p&gt;As an end user, it doesn't concern me too much, but someone choosing to add a new dependency chain to critical software plumbing does, at least slightly, if not done for very good reason.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 14:57:48 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46046320</link><dc:creator>geerlingguy</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46046320</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46046320</guid></item><item><title>New comment by benterix in "AI has a deep understanding of how this code works"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Did these Ocaml maintainers undergo some special course for dealing with difficult people? They show enormous amounts of maturity and patience. I'd just give the offender Torvalds' treatment and block them from the repo, case closed.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 13:14:01 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46045482</link><dc:creator>benterix</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46045482</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46045482</guid></item><item><title>New comment by leo_e in "Pebble Watch software is now open source"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;As someone dealing with open-source compliance in distributed systems, the purity tests in these comments are exhausting.&lt;p&gt;Hardware is messy. IP licensing for sensors and radios is a nightmare. Getting a functional OS out with "only" a few binary blobs is a massive engineering and legal victory.&lt;p&gt;I'd rather have a working, 95% open ecosystem that I can actually hack on, than a 100% pure theoretical one that never ships. Kudos to Eric for navigating the legal minefield to make this happen.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 12:56:09 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46045339</link><dc:creator>leo_e</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46045339</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46045339</guid></item><item><title>New comment by Animats in "Human brains are preconfigured with instructions for understanding the world"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Some animals are ready to go as soon as they are born. These are called precocial animals. They are born knowing how to walk.&lt;p&gt;It's interesting seeing what comes built-in. You can see this if you watch a horse being born. Within the first hour, the foal will stand, and despite long legs, this usually works the first time. Lying down, however, is not preprogrammed. I've watched a foal circle trying to figure out how to get down from standing, and finally collapsing to the ground in a heap. Standing up quickly is essential to survival, but smoothly lying down is not.
Within a day, a newborn foal can run with the herd.&lt;p&gt;Of the mammals, most of the equines and some of the rodents (beavers) are precocial.
Pigs are, monkeys are not. It's not closely tied to evolutionary ancestry.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 07:02:32 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46043084</link><dc:creator>Animats</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46043084</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46043084</guid></item><item><title>New comment by autumnstwilight in "AI has a deep understanding of how this code works"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&gt;&gt;&gt; Here's my question: why did the files that you submitted name Mark Shinwell as the author?&lt;p&gt;&gt;&gt;&gt; Beats me. AI decided to do so and I didn't question it.&lt;p&gt;Really sums the whole thing up...&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 01:41:50 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46041467</link><dc:creator>autumnstwilight</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46041467</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46041467</guid></item><item><title>New comment by userbinator in "Unpowered SSDs slowly lose data"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;One key point about retention which is not often mentioned, and indeed neither does this article, is that retention is inversely proportional to program/erase cycles and decreases exponentially with increasing temperature. Hence why retention specs are usually X amount of time after Y cycles at Z temperature. Even a QLC SSD that has only been written to once, and kept in a freezer at -40, may hold data for several decades.&lt;p&gt;Manufacturers have been playing this game with DWPD/TBW numbers too --- by reducing the retention spec, they can advertise a drive as having a higher endurance with the exact same flash. But if you compare the numbers over the years, it's clear that NAND flash has gotten significantly worse; the only thing that has gone up, multiplicatively, is capacity, while endurance and rentention have both gone down by a few orders of magnitude.&lt;p&gt;For a long time, 10 years after 100K cycles was the gold standard of SLC flash.&lt;p&gt;Now we are down to several months after less than 1K cycles for QLC.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 01:37:46 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46041442</link><dc:creator>userbinator</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46041442</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46041442</guid></item><item><title>New comment by fairfeather in "Unpowered SSDs slowly lose data"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;SSD firmware engineer here. I work on enterprise stuff, so ymmv on consumer grade internals.&lt;p&gt;Generally, the data refresh will all happen in the background when the system is powered (depending on the power state). Performance is probably throttled during those operations, so you just see a slightly slower copy while this is happening behind the scenes.&lt;p&gt;The unused space decaying is &lt;i&gt;probably&lt;/i&gt; not an issue, since the internal filesystem data is typically stored on a more robust area of media (an SLC location) which is less susceptible to data loss over time.&lt;p&gt;As far as how a user is supposed to manage it, maybe do an fsck every month or something? Using an SSD like that is probably ok most of the time, but might not be super great as a cold storage backup.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 00:06:02 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46040902</link><dc:creator>fairfeather</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46040902</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46040902</guid></item><item><title>New comment by pmdr in "PS5 now costs less than 64GB of DDR5 memory. RAM jumps to $600 due to shortage"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;So, like, we were already pretty much priced out of higher-end graphic cards, and now it's happening to RAM. All this while jobs are disappearing, layoffs are ongoing and CEOs are touting AI's 'capabilities' left and right.&lt;p&gt;Next is probably CPUs, even if AIs don't use them that much, manufactures will shift production to something more profitable, then gouge prices so that only enterprises will pay for them.&lt;p&gt;What's next? Electricity?&lt;p&gt;Where the f*k is all the abundance that AI was supposed to bring into the world? /rant&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 21:57:18 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46039876</link><dc:creator>pmdr</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46039876</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46039876</guid></item><item><title>New comment by mynameisjody in "Three Years from GPT-3 to Gemini 3"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Every time I see an article like this, it's always missing --- but is it any good, is it correct? They always show you the part that is impressive - "it walked the tricky tightrope of figuring out what might be an interesting topic and how to execute it with the data it had - one of the hardest things to teach."&lt;p&gt;Then it goes on, "After a couple of vague commands (“build it out more, make it better”) I got a 14 page paper."  I hear..."I got 14 pages of words".  But is it a good paper, that another PhD would think is good?  Is it even coherent?&lt;p&gt;When I see the code these systems generate within a complex system, I think okay, well that's kinda close, but this is wrong and this is a security problem, etc etc.  But because I'm not a PhD in these subjects, am I supposed to think,  "Well of course the 14 pages on a topic I'm not an expert in are good"?&lt;p&gt;It just doesn't add up... Things I understand, it looks good at first, but isn't shippable. Things I don't understand must be great?&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 21:12:09 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46039383</link><dc:creator>mynameisjody</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46039383</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46039383</guid></item><item><title>New comment by ArcHound in "What OpenAI did when ChatGPT users lost touch with reality"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;One of the more disturbing things I read this year was the my boyfriend is AI subreddit.&lt;p&gt;I genuinely can't fathom what is going on there. Seems so wrong, yet no one there seems to care.&lt;p&gt;I worry about the damage caused by these things on distressed people. What can be done?&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 19:59:21 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46038488</link><dc:creator>ArcHound</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46038488</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46038488</guid></item><item><title>New comment by unsupp0rted in "Claude Opus 4.5"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;This is gonna be game-changing for the next 2-4 weeks before they nerf the model.&lt;p&gt;Then for the next 2-3 months people complaining about the degradation will be labeled “skill issue”.&lt;p&gt;Then a sacrificial Anthropic engineer will “discover” a couple obscure bugs that “in some cases” might have lead to less than optimal performance. Still largely a user skill issue though.&lt;p&gt;Then a couple months later they’ll release Opus 4.7 and go through the cycle again.&lt;p&gt;My allegiance to these companies is now measured in nerf cycles.&lt;p&gt;I’m a nerf cycle customer.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 19:24:00 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46038081</link><dc:creator>unsupp0rted</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46038081</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46038081</guid></item><item><title>New comment by llamasushi in "Claude Opus 4.5"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;The burying of the lede here is insane. $5/$25 per MTok is a 3x price drop from Opus 4. At that price point, Opus stops being "the model you use for important things" and becomes actually viable for production workloads.&lt;p&gt;Also notable: they're claiming SOTA prompt injection resistance. The industry has largely given up on solving this problem through training alone, so if the numbers in the system card hold up under adversarial testing, that's legitimately significant for anyone deploying agents with tool access.&lt;p&gt;The "most aligned model" framing is doing a lot of heavy lifting though. Would love to see third-party red team results.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 19:17:20 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46037979</link><dc:creator>llamasushi</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46037979</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46037979</guid></item><item><title>New comment by ubj in "Implications of AI to schools"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;One of my students recently came to me with an interesting dilemma. His sister had written (without AI tools) an essay for another class, and her teacher told her that an "AI detection tool" had classified it as having been written by AI with "100% confidence". He was going to give her a zero on the assignment.&lt;p&gt;Putting aside the ludicrous confidence score, the student's question was: how could his sister convince the teacher she had actually written the essay herself? My only suggestion was for her to ask the teacher to sit down with her and have a 30-60 minute oral discussion on the essay so she could demonstrate she in fact knew the material. It's a dilemma that an increasing number of honest students will face, unfortunately.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 18:40:20 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46037449</link><dc:creator>ubj</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46037449</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46037449</guid></item><item><title>New comment by dagi3d in "France threatens GrapheneOS with arrests / server seizure for refusing backdoors"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;so, they are basically confirming Android and Apple have their backdoors as no arrests or seizures on that matter have taken place&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 18:10:15 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46037083</link><dc:creator>dagi3d</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46037083</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46037083</guid></item><item><title>New comment by konmok in "France threatens GrapheneOS with arrests / server seizure for refusing backdoors"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I think your devices should have government-mandated backdoors if and only if you are a public servant. I don't understand why private citizens are held to higher standards of conduct than politicians and cops.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 17:46:25 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46036823</link><dc:creator>konmok</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46036823</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46036823</guid></item><item><title>New comment by twistedpair in "Shai-Hulud Returns: Over 300 NPM Packages Infected"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;ProTip: use PNPM, not NPM.
PNPM 10.x shutdown a lot of these attack vectors.&lt;p&gt;1. Does not default to running post-install scripts (must manually approve each)&lt;p&gt;2. Let's you set a min age for new releases before `pnpm install` will pull them in - e.g. 4 days - so publishers have time to cleanup.&lt;p&gt;NPM is too insecure for production CLI usage.&lt;p&gt;And of course make a very limited scope publisher key, bind it to specific packages (e.g. workflow A can only publish pkg A), and IP bound it to your self hosted CI/CD runners. No one should have publish keys on their local, and even if they got the publish keys, they couldn't publish from local.
(Granted, GHA fans can use OIDC Trusted Publishers as well, but tokens done well are just as secure)&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 17:09:45 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46036328</link><dc:creator>twistedpair</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46036328</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46036328</guid></item><item><title>New comment by seethishat in "NSA and IETF, part 3: Dodging the issues at hand"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;For context, djb has been doing and saying these things since he was a college student:&lt;p&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;    While a graduate student at the University of California at Berkeley, Bernstein completed the development of an encryption equation (an "algorithm") he calls "Snuffle." Bernstein wishes to publish a) the algorithm (b) a mathematical paper describing and explaining the algorithm and (c) the "source code" for a computer program that incorporates the algorithm. Bernstein also wishes to discuss these items at mathematical conferences, college classrooms and other open public meetings. The Arms Export Control Act and the International Traffic in Arms Regulations (the ITAR regulatory scheme) required Bernstein to submit his ideas about cryptography to the government for review, to register as an arms dealer, and to apply for and obtain from the government a license to publish his ideas. Failure to do so would result in severe civil and criminal penalties. Bernstein believes this is a violation of his First Amendment rights and has sued the government. 

    After four years and one regulatory change, the Ninth Circuit Court of Appeals ruled that software source code was speech protected by the First Amendment and that the government's regulations preventing its publication were unconstitutional. 
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
Source &lt;a href="https://www.eff.org/cases/bernstein-v-us-dept-justice" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://www.eff.org/cases/bernstein-v-us-dept-justice&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 13:20:27 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46033811</link><dc:creator>seethishat</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46033811</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46033811</guid></item><item><title>New comment by tdeck in "Japan's gamble to turn island of Hokkaido into global chip hub"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Why are all the comments here so weird? It's like people saw (but didn't read) an article entitled "Man Opens a Taqueria in his Hometown" and the only responses are&lt;p&gt;1) Why didn't he open it in &lt;i&gt;my&lt;/i&gt; hometown? This location isn't convenient for me.&lt;p&gt;2) Wouldn't it be better for someone else to open a taqueria instead? My cousin is looking for work. Shouldn't we be putting resources into helping him open a restaurant instead?&lt;p&gt;It's like people hear "X in Asian country" and all they can think about is their own geopolitical narrative fed to them by the US state department. Obviously Japan is going to want to develop lucrative manufacturing... within Japan.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 13:04:51 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46033675</link><dc:creator>tdeck</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46033675</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46033675</guid></item><item><title>New comment by darkamaul in "Shai-Hulud Returns: Over 300 NPM Packages Infected"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;The "use cooldown" [0] blog post looks particularly relevant today.&lt;p&gt;I'd argue automated dependency updates pose a greater risk than one-day exploits, though I don't have data to back that up. That's harder to undo a compromised package already in thousands of lock files, than to manually patch a already exploited vulnerability in your dependencies.&lt;p&gt;[0] &lt;a href="https://blog.yossarian.net/2025/11/21/We-should-all-be-using-dependency-cooldowns" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://blog.yossarian.net/2025/11/21/We-should-all-be-using...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 11:05:26 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46032719</link><dc:creator>darkamaul</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46032719</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46032719</guid></item><item><title>New comment by sph in "Shai-Hulud Returns: Over 300 NPM Packages Infected"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;It's not "node" or "Javascript" the problem, it's this convenient packaging model.&lt;p&gt;This is gonna ruffle some feathers, but it's only a matter of time until it'll happen on the Rust ecosystem which loves to depend on a billion subpackages, and it won't be fault of the language itself.&lt;p&gt;The more I think about it, the more I believe that C, C++ or Odin's decision not to have a convenient package manager that fosters a cambrian explosion of dependencies to be a very good idea security-wise. Ambivalent about Go: they have a semblance of packaging system, but nothing so reckless like allowing third-party tarballs uploaded in the cloud to effectively run code on the dev's machine.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 11:00:09 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46032672</link><dc:creator>sph</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46032672</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46032672</guid></item><item><title>New comment by timgl in "Shai-Hulud Returns: Over 300 NPM Packages Infected"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;co-founder of PostHog here. We were a victim of this attack. We had a bunch of packages published a couple of hours ago. The main packages/versions affected were:&lt;p&gt;- posthog-node 4.18.1, 5.13.3 and 5.11.3&lt;p&gt;- posthog-js 1.297.3&lt;p&gt;- posthog-react-native 4.11.1&lt;p&gt;- posthog-docusaurus 2.0.6&lt;p&gt;We've rotated keys and passwords, unpublished all affected packages and have pushed new versions, so make sure you're on the latest version of our SDKs.&lt;p&gt;We're still figuring out how this key got compromised, and we'll follow up with a post-mortem. We'll update status.posthog.com with more updates as well.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 10:57:08 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46032650</link><dc:creator>timgl</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46032650</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46032650</guid></item><item><title>New comment by matt-attack in "Git 3.0 will use main as the default branch"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Maybe they resisted because it was completely ridiculous waste of engineering resources all over the country and for absolutely no tangible reason other than white people trying to feel better about themselves.&lt;p&gt;I work in the field of film mastering (with countless product names with the word “master” in it) and luckily no one got the ridiculous idea in their head that we need to change this lingo.&lt;p&gt;Show me a single person who has a valid reason for me not calling my branch “master” or my bedroom “the master”. I honestly think this sort of ridiculing word policing is why we lost this last damned election. And if you’re somehow proud that you’ve renamed your git branches, you’re very likely a contributor to that lost election.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 07:44:12 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46031387</link><dc:creator>matt-attack</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46031387</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46031387</guid></item><item><title>New comment by krick in "The Cloudflare outage might be a good thing"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;It would be a good thing, if it would cause anything to change. It obviously won't. As if a single person reading this post wasn't aware that the Internet is centralized, and couldn't name specifically a few sources of centralization (Cloudflare, AWS, Gmail, Github). As if it's the first time this happens. As if after the last time AWS failed (or the one before that, or one before…) anybody stopped using AWS. As if anybody &lt;i&gt;could&lt;/i&gt; viably stop using them.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 04:43:22 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46030461</link><dc:creator>krick</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46030461</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46030461</guid></item><item><title>New comment by ChrisMarshallNY in "We stopped roadmap work for a week and fixed bugs"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I love the idea, but this line:&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;&gt; 1) no bug should take over 2 days&lt;/i&gt;&lt;p&gt;Is odd. It’s virtually impossible for me to estimate how long it will take to fix a bug, until the job is done.&lt;p&gt;That said, unless fixing a bug requires a significant refactor/rewrite, I can’t imagine spending more than a day on one.&lt;p&gt;Also, I tend to attack bugs by priority/severity, as opposed to difficulty.&lt;p&gt;Some of the most serious bugs are often quite easy to find.&lt;p&gt;Once I find the cause of a bug, the fix is usually just around the corner.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 03:41:31 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46030124</link><dc:creator>ChrisMarshallNY</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46030124</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46030124</guid></item><item><title>New comment by mmooss in "Iowa City made its buses free. Traffic cleared, and so did the air"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&gt; Big-city transit has an equilibrium point, and it is incredibly stable. Every serious transit city in the world ends up in the same place&lt;p&gt;You're cherry-picking your own examples. It worked in Iowa City.&lt;p&gt;Y Combinator and much of SV would be out of business if innovators followed that thinking. One reason is that people do come up with new ideas; that's how the world changes. The other is that the world changes, and what didn't work before now works - costs change and value changes, and now it's worthwhile. For example, with congestion pricing and other rapidly increasong costs of NYC car ownership, there's more value in free transit.&lt;p&gt;Oddly, it's the thinking advocated by many HN posts, denigrating the innovation under discussion as impossible, useless, etc.&lt;p&gt;&gt; without sustainability, a political shift will kill it&lt;p&gt;That can be said of many things. A political shift could kill military funding in the US.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 03:06:48 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46029926</link><dc:creator>mmooss</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46029926</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46029926</guid></item><item><title>New comment by TheAceOfHearts in "Doge 'doesn't exist' with eight months left on its charter"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I knew some people that were initially very optimistic, and I tried to keep an open mind when DOGE got started despite the outlandish claims that they would be able to cut $2 trillion dollars from the budget, but it's apparent at this point that the project has been an extreme failure. It'll probably take a few years to really sort out their damage and overall impact though.&lt;p&gt;It's also imperative to mention in every DOGE-related discussion and conversation that the funding freeze to USAID is directly responsible for killing thousands of people [0]. Most of the damage done by DOGE can probably be reversed, but the thousands of death as a direct result of actions taken by the richest man in the world should not be forgotten. (Although I'm told there is a bit of uncertainty with any specific figures because the funding disruption also impacted the mechanisms for tracking and reporting deaths.)&lt;p&gt;[0] &lt;a href="https://www.newyorker.com/culture/the-new-yorker-documentary/the-shutdown-of-usaid-has-already-killed-hundreds-of-thousands" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://www.newyorker.com/culture/the-new-yorker-documentary...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 01:06:58 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46029151</link><dc:creator>TheAceOfHearts</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46029151</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46029151</guid></item></channel></rss>