<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>Hacker News: Best Comments</title><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/bestcomments</link><description>Hacker News RSS</description><docs>https://hnrss.org/</docs><generator>hnrss v2.1.1</generator><lastBuildDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2026 02:27:49 +0000</lastBuildDate><ns0:link href="https://hnrss.org/bestcomments" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item><title>New comment by crystal_revenge in "xAI joins SpaceX"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Because this move is entirely financial engineering to hide losses just like the roll up of X in to xAI.&lt;p&gt;None of this has anything to do with business or innovation. Do you not immediately see that? Most of my friends reaction to this news was that this is so obvious it's almost funny (or actually it &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; funny, since most were laughing as they read the headline).&lt;p&gt;I'm curious how you could &lt;i&gt;not&lt;/i&gt; understand the relevance of the quote unless you were aggressively trying to not understanding it.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 23:58:09 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46864179</link><dc:creator>crystal_revenge</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46864179</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46864179</guid></item><item><title>New comment by eduardogarza in "xAI joins SpaceX"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;From the Big Short (movie)&lt;p&gt;Jared Vennett (narration):
"In the years that followed, hundreds of bankers and rating agency's executives went to jail. The SEC was completely overhauled, and Congress had no choice but to break up the big banks and regulate the mortgage and derivatives industries."&lt;p&gt;"Just kidding. Banks took the money the American people gave them, and they used it to pay themselves huge bonuses, and lobby the Congress to kill big reform. And then they blamed immigrants and poor people, and this time even teachers."&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 23:31:30 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46863811</link><dc:creator>eduardogarza</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46863811</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46863811</guid></item><item><title>New comment by AndyKelley in "Zig Libc"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;The very same day I sat at home writing this devlog like a coward, less than five miles away, armed forces who are in my city against the will of our elected officials shot tear gas, unprovoked, at peaceful protestors, including my wife.&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.kptv.com/2026/01/31/live-labor-unions-rally-march-portland-ice-facility-protest/" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://www.kptv.com/2026/01/31/live-labor-unions-rally-marc...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;This isn't some hypothetical political agenda I'm using my platform to push. There's a nonzero chance I go out there next weekend to peacefully protest, and get shot like Alex Pretti.&lt;p&gt;Needless to say, if I get shot by ICE, it's not good for the Zig project. And they've brought the battle to my doorstep, almost literally.&lt;p&gt;Abolish ICE.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 23:20:17 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46863669</link><dc:creator>AndyKelley</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46863669</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46863669</guid></item><item><title>New comment by paxys in "xAI joins SpaceX"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Just a neat bit of financial engineering. You can tell because Elon picked SpaceX instead of Tesla – which would have actually made sense at some level (Optimus Robots + AI). But Tesla is public and so he'd need to follow laws and reporting requirements.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 22:23:42 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46862731</link><dc:creator>paxys</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46862731</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46862731</guid></item><item><title>New comment by senko in "xAI joins SpaceX"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;As a SpaceX fan, I am saddened by this news.&lt;p&gt;The only reason for xAI to join SpaceX is to offload Elon's Twitter debt in the upcoming IPO.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 22:22:17 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46862710</link><dc:creator>senko</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46862710</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46862710</guid></item><item><title>New comment by alangibson in "xAI joins SpaceX"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Either this is a straight up con, or Musk found a glitch in physics. It's extremely difficult to keep things cold in space.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 22:13:48 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46862572</link><dc:creator>alangibson</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46862572</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46862572</guid></item><item><title>New comment by rybosworld in "xAI joins SpaceX"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&gt; The basic math is that launching a million tons per year of satellites generating 100 kW of compute power per ton would add 100 gigawatts of AI compute capacity annually, with no ongoing operational or maintenance needs. Ultimately, there is a path to launching 1 TW/year from Earth.&lt;p&gt;&gt; My estimate is that within 2 to 3 years, the lowest cost way to generate AI compute will be in space.&lt;p&gt;This is so obviously false. For one thing, in what fantasy world would the ongoing operational and maintenance needs be 0?&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 22:10:52 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46862510</link><dc:creator>rybosworld</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46862510</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46862510</guid></item><item><title>New comment by Buttons840 in "xAI joins SpaceX"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;SpaceX is too big to fail. It's important for national security.&lt;p&gt;I wonder if Elon wants to tangle all his businesses into SpaceX so they are all kept afloat by SpaceX's importance.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 22:07:23 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46862456</link><dc:creator>Buttons840</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46862456</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46862456</guid></item><item><title>New comment by gok in "xAI joins SpaceX"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&gt; it is possible to put 500 to 1000 TW/year of AI satellites into deep space, meaningfully ascend the Kardashev scale and harness a non-trivial percentage of the Sun’s power&lt;p&gt;We currently make around 1 TW of photovoltaic cells per year, globally. The proposal here is to launch that much to space every 9 hours, complete with attached computers, continuously, from the moon.&lt;p&gt;edit: Also, this would capture a very trivial percentage of the Sun's power. A few trillionths per year.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 22:06:22 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46862435</link><dc:creator>gok</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46862435</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46862435</guid></item><item><title>New comment by OlympicMarmoto in "The Codex App"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;It is baffling how these AI companies, with billions of dollars, cannot build native applications, even with the help of AI. From a UI perspective, these are mostly just chat apps, which are not particularly difficult to code from scratch. Before the usual excuses come about how it is impossible to build a custom UI, consider software that is orders of magnitude more complex, such as raddbg, 10x, Superluminal, Blender, Godot, Unity, and UE5, or any video game with a UI. On top of that, programs like Claude Cowork or Codex should, by design, integrate as deeply with the OS as possible. This requires calling native APIs (e.g., Win32), which is not feasible from Electron.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 21:31:37 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46861884</link><dc:creator>OlympicMarmoto</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46861884</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46861884</guid></item><item><title>New comment by OsamaJaber in "Todd C. Miller – Sudo maintainer for over 30 years"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;30+ years maintaining one of the most critical pieces of infrastructure on nearly every Linux and Unix system, and he's currently looking for a sponsor to fund continued development. Every company running sudo in production owes this man. Someone should fix that&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 18:16:13 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46859228</link><dc:creator>OsamaJaber</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46859228</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46859228</guid></item><item><title>New comment by marssaxman in "Claude Code is suddenly everywhere inside Microsoft"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&gt; Microsoft really needs to get a better handle with the naming conventions.&lt;p&gt;They really won't, though; Microsoft just &lt;i&gt;does&lt;/i&gt; this kind of thing, over and over and over. Before everything was named "365", it was all "One", before that it was "Live"... 20 years ago, everything was called ".NET" whether it had anything to do with the Internet or not. Back in the '90s they went crazy for a while calling everything "Active".&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 17:47:25 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46858855</link><dc:creator>marssaxman</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46858855</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46858855</guid></item><item><title>New comment by jFriedensreich in "Waymo seeking about $16B near $110B valuation"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;No product had such a fast transition from novelty to "omg i never want to interact with a human again". I feel about 100% less stressed and happier using a waymo or riding motorbike or bicycle next to a waymo than with human drivers. I hope this next phase will bring availability and prices down. We need this in europe.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 16:04:07 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46857536</link><dc:creator>jFriedensreich</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46857536</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46857536</guid></item><item><title>New comment by kemotep in "Claude Code is suddenly everywhere inside Microsoft"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Microsoft really needs to get a better handle with the naming conventions.&lt;p&gt;There is Microsoft Copilot, which replaced Bing Chat, Cortana and uses OpenAI’s GPT-4 and 5 models.&lt;p&gt;There is Github Copilot, the coding autocomplete tool.&lt;p&gt;There is Microsoft 365 Copilot, what they now call Office with built in GenAI stuff.&lt;p&gt;There is also a Copilot cli that lets you use whatever agent/model backend you want too?&lt;p&gt;Everything is Copilot. Laptops sell with Copilot buttons now.&lt;p&gt;It is not immediately clear what version of Copilot someone is talking about. 99% of my experience is with the Office and it 100% fails to do the thing it was advertised to do 2 years ago when work initially got the subscription. Point it a SharePoint/OneDrive location, a handful of excel spreadsheets and pdfs/word docs and tell it to make a PowerPoint presentation based on that information.&lt;p&gt;It cannot do this. It will spit out nonsense. You have to hold it by the hand tell it everything to do step by step to the point that making the PowerPoint presentation yourself is significantly faster because you don’t have to type out a bunch of prompts and edit it’s garbage output.&lt;p&gt;And now it’s clear they aren’t even dogfooding their own LLM products so why should anyone pay for Copilot?&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 15:31:05 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46857117</link><dc:creator>kemotep</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46857117</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46857117</guid></item><item><title>New comment by tylerchilds in "Claude Code is suddenly everywhere inside Microsoft"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;This is funny because everyone’s AI strategy should have been&lt;p&gt;“What do we actually need to be productive?”&lt;p&gt;Which is how Anthropic pulled ahead of Microsoft, that prioritized&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;checks notes&lt;/i&gt;&lt;p&gt;Taking screenshots of every windows user’s desktop every few seconds. For productivity.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 15:28:28 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46857092</link><dc:creator>tylerchilds</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46857092</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46857092</guid></item><item><title>New comment by Shank in "Microsoft is walking back Windows 11's AI overload"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&gt; It appears this moment of pushback has resonated with internal teams: According to people familiar with Microsoft’s plans, the company is now reevaluating its AI strategy on Windows 11 and plans changes to streamline or even remove certain AI features where they don’t make sense.&lt;p&gt;Obviously this is a complete failure of governance. The very first thing they should have considered was whether or not these features made sense in the ways that they were being added. There should not be any necessary work to "rollback" features that do not make sense, because they should have not built them in the first place.&lt;p&gt;Even if we accept at face value that AI has made generation of code significantly cheaper, that doesn't justify the existence of worthless code. Taste comes from knowing what not to build.&lt;p&gt;Right now Windows is an unstable mess, filled with things that shouldn't have been built. The question Microsoft should ask themselves is why they built them in the first place, and how they will prevent this from happening again.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 12:08:49 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46855065</link><dc:creator>Shank</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46855065</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46855065</guid></item><item><title>New comment by zcbenz in "My iPhone 16 Pro Max produces garbage output when running MLX LLMs"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;It is a bug in MLX that has been fixed a few days ago:
&lt;a href="https://github.com/ml-explore/mlx/pull/3083" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://github.com/ml-explore/mlx/pull/3083&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 11:46:08 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46854898</link><dc:creator>zcbenz</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46854898</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46854898</guid></item><item><title>New comment by PunchyHamster in "Two kinds of AI users are emerging"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I'd argue 2 types of users are&lt;p&gt;* People using it as a tool, aware of its limitations and treating it basically as  intern/boring task executor (whether its some code boilerplate, or pooping out/shortening some corporate email), or as tool to give themselves summary of topic they can then bite into deeper.&lt;p&gt;* People outsourcing thinking and entire skillset to it - they usually have very little clue in the topic, are interested only in results, and are not interested in knowing more about the topic or honing their skills in the topic&lt;p&gt;The second group is one that thinks talking to a chatbot will replace senior developer&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 08:27:01 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46853721</link><dc:creator>PunchyHamster</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46853721</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46853721</guid></item><item><title>New comment by weinzierl in "Defeating a 40-year-old copy protection dongle"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;These dongles used to be ubiquitous and they broke all the time.&lt;p&gt;As a young intern, I arrived early one morning to find the PCB layout software (PADS PowerPCB) on our &lt;i&gt;"design PC"&lt;/i&gt; wasn’t working. (I use quotes because it was just the beefiest machine we had, naturally our boss’s PC, which he kindly shared)&lt;p&gt;Obviously the dongle. I tried unplugging and replugging it, with and without the printer daisy-chained. Nothing.&lt;p&gt;So I begrudgingly asked my colleague who’d just arrived. He looked at the dongle, looked at me, looked at the dongle again, and started laughing.&lt;p&gt;Turns out our Boss had stayed late the previous night processing customer complaints. One customer had sent back a &lt;i&gt;"broken"&lt;/i&gt; dongle for the product we were selling. Boss tested it on his PC, found it worked fine, and mailed it back on his way home.&lt;p&gt;Except he didn’t send &lt;i&gt;our&lt;/i&gt; dongle back. He had sent &lt;i&gt;my&lt;/i&gt; PowerPCB dongle. More fun was had when the rest of the team and finally our boss arrived. Luckily he took it with good humor.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 04:25:36 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46852384</link><dc:creator>weinzierl</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46852384</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46852384</guid></item><item><title>New comment by ryandrake in "Notepad++ hijacked by state-sponsored actors"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Similar comments also come up in the [now regular] "I don't want to see political articles on HN" threads, and I think the response is similar: Asking for "no politics" is itself a strong political view: One in support/service of whatever the current status quo is. Trying to set oneself apart from (or above) politics is itself political. If you're lucky enough to be one of the fortunate people on earth who are not under attack by political forces or who benefit from status quo politics, I'd encourage you to simply reflect on that good luck and try to ignore the "politics" that others are deeply affected by and care about.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 02:49:36 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46851842</link><dc:creator>ryandrake</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46851842</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46851842</guid></item><item><title>New comment by simlevesque in "Notepad++ hijacked by state-sponsored actors"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Probably related to this: &lt;a href="https://notepad-plus-plus.org/news/v869-about-taiwan/" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://notepad-plus-plus.org/news/v869-about-taiwan/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 02:18:44 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46851664</link><dc:creator>simlevesque</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46851664</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46851664</guid></item><item><title>New comment by danpalmer in "Two kinds of AI users are emerging"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I've noticed a huge gap between AI use on greenfield projects and brownfield projects. The first day of working on a greenfield project I can accomplish a week of work. But the second day I can accomplish a few days of work. By the end of the first week I'm getting a 20% productivity gain.&lt;p&gt;I think AI is just allowing everyone to speed-run the innovator's dilemma. Anyone can create a small version of anything, while big orgs will struggle to move quickly as before.&lt;p&gt;The interesting bit is going to be whether we see AI being used in maturing those small systems into big complex ones that account for the edge cases, meet all the requirements, scale as needed, etc. That's hard for humans to do, and particularly while still moving. I've not see any of this from AI yet outside of either a) very directed small changes to large complex systems, or b) plugins/extensions/etc along a well define set of rails.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 01:44:03 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46851425</link><dc:creator>danpalmer</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46851425</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46851425</guid></item><item><title>New comment by jimminyx in "Show HN: NanoClaw – “Clawdbot” in 500 lines of TS with Apple container isolation"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;OP here. Appreciate your perspective but I don't really accept the framing, which feels like it's implying that I've been caught out for writing and coding with AI.&lt;p&gt;I don't make any attempt to hide it. Nearly every commit message says "Co-Authored-By: Claude Opus 4.5". You correctly pointed out that there were some AI smells in the writing, so I removed them, just like I correct typos, and the writing is now better.&lt;p&gt;I don't care deeply about this code. It's not a masterpiece. It's functional code that is very useful to me. I'm sharing it because I think it can be useful to other people. Not as production code but as a reference or starting point they can use to build (collaboratively with claude code) functional custom software for themselves.&lt;p&gt;I spent a weekend giving instructions to coding agents to build this. I put time and effort into the architecture, especially in relation to security. I chose to post while it's still rough because I need to close out my work on it for now - can't keep going down this rabbit hole the whole week :) I hope it will be useful to others.&lt;p&gt;BTW, I know the readme irked you but if you read it I promise it will make a lot more sense where this project is coming from ;)&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 00:19:13 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46850863</link><dc:creator>jimminyx</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46850863</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46850863</guid></item><item><title>New comment by hebejebelus in "Show HN: NanoClaw – “Clawdbot” in 500 lines of TS with Apple container isolation"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I think these days if I’m going to be actively promoting code I’ve created (with Claude, no shade for that), I’ll make sure to write the documentation, or at the very least the readme, by hand. The smell of LLM from the docs of any project puts me off even when I like the idea of the project itself, as in this case. It’s hard to describe why - maybe it feels like if you care enough to promote it, you should care to try and actually communicate, person to person, to the human being promoted at. Dunno, just my 2c and maybe just my own preference. I’d rather read a typo-ridden five line readme explaining the problem the code is there to solve for you and me,the humans, not dozens of lines of perfectly penned marketing with just the right number of emoji. We all know how easy it is to write code these days. Maybe use some of that extra time to communicate with the humans. I dunno.&lt;p&gt;Edit: I see you, making edits to the readme to make it sound more human-written since I commented ;) &lt;a href="https://github.com/gavrielc/nanoclaw/commit/40d41542d2f335a0ecb431142747a3b62c7111db" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://github.com/gavrielc/nanoclaw/commit/40d41542d2f335a0...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2026 23:29:17 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46850500</link><dc:creator>hebejebelus</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46850500</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46850500</guid></item><item><title>New comment by ruleryak in "Defeating a 40-year-old copy protection dongle"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Many a crack back in the day was even more simple still, we'd just find and alter the right JE or JNE into a JMP and we're off to the races.   As the author found, the tough part is just finding and interpreting where and how the protection was implemented.   If throwing the exe in a hex editor gave you access to String Data References (not always the case, but more common than not) then you'd just fail the check you were trying to skip, find that string, hop over into assembly to see what triggered loading that, and then just alter the logic to jump over it when the time comes.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2026 23:05:23 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46850304</link><dc:creator>ruleryak</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46850304</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46850304</guid></item><item><title>New comment by shibel in "Teaching my neighbor to keep the volume down"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Reminds of a neighbor I had back when I was renting in a big city. He didn’t seem to understand what’s wrong with keeping his TV on for very long periods broadcasting the sleaziest (at least at the time) reality show on full volume.&lt;p&gt;I tried talking to him multiple times to no avail. He’d basically say “yeah I’ll pay attention no problem” but nothing changed for weeks.&lt;p&gt;Coincidentally at that time I was working morning shifts at a radio station. Those start really early so you gotta wake up at around 4am.&lt;p&gt;I decided one day to change my alarm (triggered on my Sony Vaio) from the peaceful iPhone-like tunes to System of a Down’s “Chop Suey”. I also decided to forget it on, on repeat, full volume, while leaving the apartment.&lt;p&gt;I don’t think 3 days passed before he knocked loudly at my door, moaning and complaining.&lt;p&gt;I told him: “you gotta understand, your TV was so loud I couldn’t sleep for nights on end, the old tune wouldn’t wake me up anymore. I had to change it. I’m so tired that I even forget to turn it off.&lt;p&gt;But yeah, I’ll try to pay attention to it”&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2026 20:29:08 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46849079</link><dc:creator>shibel</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46849079</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46849079</guid></item><item><title>New comment by trothamel in "A Crisis comes to Wordle: Reusing old words"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;If I remember correctly, the original version of wordle used a word list that was run past the creator's wife, who had learned English later in life. The result was a really accessible game - none of the words felt like ones you wouldn't know. It probably makes sense to reuse words than risk losing that accessibility.&lt;p&gt;(I kept a copy of original wordle, and it seems to have 2,315 words that are possible answers.)&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2026 20:08:49 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46848937</link><dc:creator>trothamel</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46848937</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46848937</guid></item><item><title>New comment by recursivedoubts in "English professors double down on requiring printed copies of readings"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I have mentioned this in a few comments: for my CS classes I have gone from a historical 60-80% projects / 40-20% quizzes grade split, to a 50/50 split, and have moved my quizzes from being online to being in-person, pen-on-paper with one sheet of hand-written notes&lt;p&gt;Rather than banning AI, I'm showing students how to use it effectively as a personalized TA.  I'm giving them this AGENTS.md file:&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://gist.github.com/1cg/a6c6f2276a1fe5ee172282580a44a7ac" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://gist.github.com/1cg/a6c6f2276a1fe5ee172282580a44a7ac&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;And showing them how to use AI to summarize the slides into a quiz review sheet, generate example questions with answer walk throughs, etc.&lt;p&gt;Of course I can't ensure they aren't just having AI do the projects, but I tell them that if they do that they are cheating themselves: the projects are designed to draw them into the art of programming and give them decent, real-world coding experience that they will need, even if they end up working at a higher level in the future.&lt;p&gt;AI can be a very effective tool for education if used properly.  I have used it to create a ton of extremely useful visualizations (e.g. how twos complement works) that I wouldn't have otherwise.  But it is obviously extremely dangerous as well.&lt;p&gt;"It is impossible to design a system so perfect that no one needs to be good."&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2026 16:28:41 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46847278</link><dc:creator>recursivedoubts</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46847278</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46847278</guid></item><item><title>New comment by muvlon in "In praise of –dry-run"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;If you're interacting with stateful systems (which you usually are with this kind of command), --dry-run can still have a race condition.&lt;p&gt;The tool tells you what it would do in the current situation, you take a look and confirm that that's alright. Then you run it again without --dry-run, in a potentially different situation.&lt;p&gt;That's why I prefer Terraform's approach of having a "plan" mode. It doesn't just tell you what it would do but does so in the form of a plan it can later execute programmatically. Then, if any of the assumptions made during planning have changed, it can abort and roll back.&lt;p&gt;As a nice bonus, this pattern gives a good answer to the problem of having "if dry_run:" sprinkled everywhere: You have to separate the planning and execution in code anyway, so you can make the "just apply immediately" mode simply execute(plan()).&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2026 08:18:52 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46844483</link><dc:creator>muvlon</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46844483</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46844483</guid></item><item><title>New comment by themk in "List animals until failure"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;One of the few sites with a fun "you have javascript turned off" message.&lt;p&gt;&gt; This game requires JavaScript. Or, if you've superior taste, take out a pen and paper and start listing animals.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2026 05:41:27 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46843942</link><dc:creator>themk</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46843942</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46843942</guid></item></channel></rss>