<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>Hacker News: Best Comments</title><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/bestcomments</link><description>Hacker News RSS</description><docs>https://hnrss.org/</docs><generator>hnrss v2.1.1</generator><lastBuildDate>Sat, 11 Oct 2025 00:25:20 +0000</lastBuildDate><ns0:link href="https://hnrss.org/bestcomments" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item><title>New comment by 3D30497420 in "Boring Company cited for almost 800 environmental violations in Las Vegas"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;From the article:&lt;p&gt;&gt; Workers have complained of chemical burns from the waste material generated by the tunneling process, and firefighters must decontaminate their equipment after conducting rescues from the project sites. The company was fined more than $112,000 by Nevada’s Occupational Safety and Health Administration in late 2023 after workers complained of “ankle-deep” water in the tunnels, muck spills and burns.&lt;p&gt;That sounds like a "real environmental hazard" to me.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2025 17:20:21 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45541388</link><dc:creator>3D30497420</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45541388</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45541388</guid></item><item><title>New comment by gsnedders in "Ryanair flight landed at Manchester airport with six minutes of fuel left"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;As others have said, final fuel reserves are typically at least half an hour, and you shouldn't really be cutting into them. What if their first approach into MAN had led to another go around?&lt;p&gt;With a major storm heading north-easterly across the UK, the planning should have reasonably foreseen that an airport 56 miles east may also be unavailable, and should've further diverted prior to that point.&lt;p&gt;They likely used the majority of their final fuel reserve on the secondary diversion from EDI to MAN, presumably having planned to land at their alternate (EDI) around the time they reached the final fuel reserve.&lt;p&gt;Any CAA report into this, if there is one produced, is going to be interesting, because there's multiple people having made multiple decisions that led to this.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2025 16:16:44 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45540621</link><dc:creator>gsnedders</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45540621</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45540621</guid></item><item><title>New comment by jacquesm in "Ryanair flight landed at Manchester airport with six minutes of fuel left"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;That is &lt;i&gt;very&lt;/i&gt; exceptional. I've written fuel estimation software for airliners (cargo, fortunately), and the number of rules regarding go-arounds, alternates and holding time resulted in there usually being quite a bit of fuel in the tanks on landing, by design. I've never heard of '6 minutes left' in practice where it wasn't a massive issue and the investigation into how this could have happened will make for interesting reading. A couple of notes: the wind and the time spent on the three go-arounds + what was necessary to get to the alternate may not be the whole story here, that's actually factored in before you even take off.&lt;p&gt;I'd be very wary to get ahead of the investigation and make speculative statements on how this could have happened, the one thing that I know for sure is that it &lt;i&gt;shouldn't&lt;/i&gt; have happened, no matter what.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2025 15:48:38 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45540315</link><dc:creator>jacquesm</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45540315</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45540315</guid></item><item><title>New comment by SquareWheel in "Google Safe Browsing incident"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;It's generally good advice, but I don't see that Safe Browsing did anything wrong in this case.  First, it sounds like they actually were briefly hosting phishing sites:&lt;p&gt;&gt; All sites on statichost.eu get a SITE-NAME.statichost.eu domain, and during the weekend there was an influx of phishing sites.&lt;p&gt;Second, they should be using the public suffix list (&lt;a href="https://publicsuffix.org/" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://publicsuffix.org/&lt;/a&gt;) to avoid having their entire domain tagged.  How else is Google supposed to know that subdomains belong to different users?  That's what the PSL is for.&lt;p&gt;From my reading, Safe Browsing did its job correctly in this case, and they restored the site quickly once the threat was removed.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2025 13:45:09 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45538971</link><dc:creator>SquareWheel</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45538971</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45538971</guid></item><item><title>New comment by madacol in "Nobel Peace Prize 2025: María Corina Machado"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Even if Venezuela goes to hell even deeper, she still deserves the prize for what she has already done!&lt;p&gt;The way she, and her team, managed to convince venezuelans that the election mattered, and to prepare to gather the evidence of the elections under constant threats from the government, that we all knew they were going to steal, and do it entirely peacefully, was an extremely impressive achievement on its own.&lt;p&gt;What an impressive act of coordination from MCM&lt;p&gt;:standing-ovation:&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2025 11:35:17 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45537701</link><dc:creator>madacol</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45537701</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45537701</guid></item><item><title>New comment by mananoreboton in "Nobel Peace Prize 2025: María Corina Machado"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Don't get me wrong, but perhaps what was missing was greater media coverage and genuine interest in Venezuela's situation.
María Corina Machado orchestrated a HUGE covert months long operation to collect tally sheets from the overwhelming majority of voting machines during the 2024 presidential election. Her team trained poll watchers to demand vote receipts (as legally permitted) then capture and transmit that data through various channels, even from the most remote regions of the country.
There are documented cases of people—poll workers and participants in the plan—being imprisoned or even killed for their involvement.
Thanks to this operation, the website resultadospresidencialesvenezuela2024.com exists, where venezuelan can verify the actual vote count per candidate, backed by fingerprint records and the serial numbers of both the software and hardware used.
These verified results confirm that Edmundo González was the true winner of the election.
The data provides undeniable evidence that Nicolás Maduro installed himself as a dictator, with the full support of the national electoral authority, which, to this day, has refused to release the official election results (a procedure that has historically been routine).&lt;p&gt;You can also verify the results here &lt;a href="https://macedoniadelnorte.com/" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://macedoniadelnorte.com/&lt;/a&gt; (a whole story behind this hostname). Again, only possible by the María Corina's huge effort&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2025 09:49:56 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45537006</link><dc:creator>mananoreboton</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45537006</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45537006</guid></item><item><title>New comment by alejoar in "Nobel Peace Prize 2025: María Corina Machado"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Opposing a dictatorship at great personal risk, being exiled, banned from elections, and still leading a democratic movement isn't "nothing".&lt;p&gt;I think this prize recognizes her courage and fight for human rights.&lt;p&gt;Dismissing that as "just being in the opposition" ignores the reality of what it takes to stand up to Maduro's dictatorship.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2025 09:34:40 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45536915</link><dc:creator>alejoar</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45536915</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45536915</guid></item><item><title>New comment by karpathy in "LLMs are mortally terrified of exceptions"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Sorry I thought it would be clear and could have clarified that the code itself is just a joke illustrating the point, as an exaggeration. This was the thread if anyone is interested&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://chatgpt.com/share/68e82db9-7a28-8007-9a99-bc6f0010d101" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://chatgpt.com/share/68e82db9-7a28-8007-9a99-bc6f0010d1...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2025 21:50:57 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45533475</link><dc:creator>karpathy</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45533475</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45533475</guid></item><item><title>New comment by wiseowise in "Python 3.14 is here. How fast is it?"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&gt; flask&lt;p&gt;Off-topic, but I absolutely &lt;i&gt;loathe&lt;/i&gt; new Flask logo. Old one[0] has this vintage, crafty feel. And the new one[1] looks like it was made by a starving high schooler experimenting with WordArt.&lt;p&gt;[0] - &lt;a href="https://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/3/3c/Flask_logo.svg" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/3/3c/Flask_lo...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;[1] - &lt;a href="https://flask.palletsprojects.com/en/stable/_images/flask-name.svg" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://flask.palletsprojects.com/en/stable/_images/flask-na...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2025 20:06:53 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45532428</link><dc:creator>wiseowise</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45532428</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45532428</guid></item><item><title>New comment by ctoth in "Rubygems.org AWS Root Access Event – September 2025"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;AWS account root access on a language package registry for 11 days. Not EC2 root - AWS account root. Complete control over IAM, S3, CloudTrail, every-damn-thing.&lt;p&gt;They're claiming "no evidence of compromise" based on CloudTrail logs that AWS root could have deleted or modified. They even admit they "Enabled AWS CloudTrail" after regaining control - meaning CloudTrail wasn't running during the compromise window.&lt;p&gt;You cannot verify supply chain integrity from logs on a system where root was compromised, and you definitely can't verify it when the logs didn't exist (they enabled them during remediation?).&lt;p&gt;So basically, somebody correct me here if I'm wrong but ... Every gem published Sept 19-30 is suspect. Production Ruby applications running code from that window have no way to verify it wasn't backdoored. The correct response is to freeze publishing, rebuild from scratch (including re-publishing any packages published at the time? Ugh I don't even know how to do this! ) , and verify against offline backups. Instead they rotated passwords and called it done.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2025 19:07:55 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45531770</link><dc:creator>ctoth</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45531770</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45531770</guid></item><item><title>New comment by i80and in "The fight between doctors and insurance companies over 'downcoding'"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;FSAs are insane, conceptually.&lt;p&gt;"Guess how much money you're spending in a year on healthcare! But beee caaareful: if you guess too high, YOU LOSE IT"&lt;p&gt;I still used mine while I still had access to one, but it was grumpy-making and was usually almost more trouble than it was worth.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2025 18:50:42 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45531576</link><dc:creator>i80and</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45531576</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45531576</guid></item><item><title>New comment by eutropia in "Rubygems.org AWS Root Access Event – September 2025"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;They buried the lede...&lt;p&gt;Arko wanted a copy of the HTTP Access logs from rubygems.org so his consultancy could monetize the data, after RC determined they didn't really have the budget for secondary on-call.&lt;p&gt;Then after they removed him as a maintainer he logged in and changed the AWS root password.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2025 18:05:59 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45531051</link><dc:creator>eutropia</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45531051</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45531051</guid></item><item><title>New comment by miguelgrinberg in "Python 3.14 is here. How fast is it?"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;You have made my day, sir. :)&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2025 17:59:48 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45530977</link><dc:creator>miguelgrinberg</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45530977</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45530977</guid></item><item><title>New comment by nadermx in "Python 3.14 is here. How fast is it?"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Tangential, but I practically owe my life to this guy.  He wrote the flask mega tutorial in what I followed religiously to launch my first website.  Then right before launch, in the most critical part of my entire application; piping a fragged file in flask.  He answered my stackoverflow question, I put his fix live, and the site went viral.  Here's the link for posterity's sake &lt;a href="https://stackoverflow.com/a/34391304/4180276" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://stackoverflow.com/a/34391304/4180276&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2025 17:17:24 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45530499</link><dc:creator>nadermx</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45530499</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45530499</guid></item><item><title>New comment by simonw in "A small number of samples can poison LLMs of any size"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;This looks like a bit of a bombshell:&lt;p&gt;&gt; It reveals a surprising finding: in our experimental setup with simple backdoors designed to trigger low-stakes behaviors, poisoning attacks require a near-constant number of documents regardless of model and training data size. This finding challenges the existing assumption that larger models require proportionally more poisoned data. Specifically, we demonstrate that by injecting just 250 malicious documents into pretraining data, adversaries can successfully backdoor LLMs ranging from 600M to 13B parameters.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2025 16:36:52 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45530023</link><dc:creator>simonw</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45530023</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45530023</guid></item><item><title>New comment by ertgbnm in "The great software quality collapse or, how we normalized catastrophe"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Unrelated but my current AI text flag is the use of "It's not X. It's Y."&lt;p&gt;It's become so repetitive recently. Examples from this post alone:&lt;p&gt;1. "This isn't about AI. The quality crisis started years before ChatGPT existed."&lt;p&gt;2. "The degradation isn't gradual—it's exponential."&lt;p&gt;3. "These aren't feature requirements. They're memory leaks that nobody bothered to fix."&lt;p&gt;4. "This wasn't sophisticated. This was Computer Science 101 error handling that nobody implemented."&lt;p&gt;5. "This isn't an investment. It's capitulation."&lt;p&gt;6. "senior developers don't emerge from thin air. They grow from juniors who:"&lt;p&gt;7. "The solution isn't complex. It's just uncomfortable."&lt;p&gt;Currently this rhetorical device is like nails on a chalkboard for me.&lt;p&gt;Anyway, this isn't a critique of your point. It's pedantry from me. :)&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2025 15:25:24 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45529020</link><dc:creator>ertgbnm</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45529020</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45529020</guid></item><item><title>New comment by 3D30497420 in "The fight between doctors and insurance companies over 'downcoding'"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;This sort of thing gets to two critical problems of the American system:
1. It is largely designed to make money, not actually help patients. So every step in the healthcare chain that can extract a bit of value will do so, largely to boost profits.
2. Insane complexity with limited transparency. How much will something cost? Hard to tell. Will it be covered? Who knows?&lt;p&gt;On the opacity, I have one informative anecdote. I had a single blood test done awhile back and no one knew if insurance would cover it, or which of the dozen or so billing codes it involved (taking the sample, delivering the sample, testing the sample, etc.) might be covered. It was an expensive test so I spent days bouncing between the doctor's billing team and the insurance company until the settled answer was: No one knows, do the test and insurance will decide. So I did it and insurance denied covering the doctor-recommended test. The salaries involved for all the billing people (and my time) would have covered the cost of the test. &lt;/rant&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2025 15:02:31 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45528683</link><dc:creator>3D30497420</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45528683</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45528683</guid></item><item><title>New comment by HAL3000 in "Figure 03, our 3rd generation humanoid robot"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;All of the examples in videos are cherry picked. Go ask anyone working on humanoid robots today, almost everything you see here, if repeated 10 times, will enter failure mode because the happy path is so narrow. There should really be benchmarks where you invite robots from different companies, ask them beforehand about their capabilities, and then create an environment that is within those capabilities but was not used in the training data, and you will see the real failure rate. These things are not ready for anything besides tech demos currently. Most of the training is done in simulations that approximate physics, and the rest is done manually by humans using joysticks (almost everything they do with hands). Failure rates are staggering.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2025 14:59:40 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45528648</link><dc:creator>HAL3000</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45528648</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45528648</guid></item><item><title>New comment by throw-10-8 in "The React Foundation"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Vercel being involved is a huge red flag.&lt;p&gt;NextJS is a pile of garbage, and their platform is absurdly expensive and leans heavily on vendor lock in.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2025 09:20:07 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45525339</link><dc:creator>throw-10-8</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45525339</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45525339</guid></item><item><title>New comment by LaurensBER in "A competitor crippled a $23.5M bootcamp by becoming a Reddit moderator"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Moderation on Reddit has been questionable for a long time and its killing the site. To give some examples:&lt;p&gt;- /r/energy used to ban everyone in favour of nuclear energy&lt;p&gt;- If you post on /r/conservative you can expect to receive a bunch of bans from unrelated (popular) subs. Doesn't matter what you posted, being associated with that subs "taints" your account enough for some moderators.&lt;p&gt;- /r/UnitedKingdom banned me for critizing a government welfare program&lt;p&gt;- /r/assassinscreed banned me for critizing a character in their latest game&lt;p&gt;For me it makes sense that the smaller subreddits should have the freedom to moderate as they want but the larger reddits should aim to at allow opposing viewpoints to prevent echo chambers from forming. Moderation should be focused on quality, not on viewpoints. Obviously it goes without saying that threats of violence and celebration of murder have no place on any platform.&lt;p&gt;The irony is that all this censoring just creates a backlash and further polarisation. If you are only allowed to discuss certain subjects on a "left" space you both create the illusion that the left only cares about a subset of topics and by banning people you create resentment that drives them towards (more welcoming) extreme spaces.&lt;p&gt;There's many factors that form the political preferences and opinions of the younger generation but it would not suprise me if for a subset (young college educated males?) of them Reddit heavily contributes towards increased polarisation.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2025 07:41:51 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45524713</link><dc:creator>LaurensBER</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45524713</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45524713</guid></item><item><title>New comment by rossant in "Two things LLM coding agents are still bad at"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Recently, I asked Codex CLI to refactor some HTML files. It didn't literally copy and pasted snippets here and there as I would have done myself, it rewrote them from memory, removing comments in the process. There was a section with 40 successive &lt;a href...&gt; links with complex URLs.&lt;p&gt;A few days later, just before deployment to production, I wanted to double check all 40 links. First one worked. Second one worked. Third one worked. Fourth one worked. So far so good. Then I tried the last four. Perfect.&lt;p&gt;Just to be sure, I proceeded with the fifth one. 404. Huh. Weird. The domain was correct though and the URL seemed reasonable.&lt;p&gt;I tried the other 31 links. ALL of them 404ed. I was totally confused. The domain was always correct. It seemed highly suspicious that all websites would have had moved internal URLs at the same time. I didn't even remember that this part of the code had gone through an LLM.&lt;p&gt;Fortunately, I could retrieve the old URLs on old git commits. I checked the URLs carefully. The LLM had HALLUCINATED most of the path part of the URLs! Replacing things like domain.com/this-article-is-about-foobar-123456/ by domain.com/foobar-is-so-great-162543/...&lt;p&gt;These kinds of very subtle and silently introduced mistakes are quite dangerous. Be careful out there!&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2025 06:56:32 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45524410</link><dc:creator>rossant</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45524410</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45524410</guid></item><item><title>New comment by SequoiaHope in "Discord says 70k users may have had their government IDs leaked in breach"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;It is a common misconception that facts are reported because they are surprising. Facts are reported because they are important. More and more governments are passing age verification laws which put exactly this data in to the hands of even more shady private companies. This breach serves as evidence that those laws are misguided, and spreading news of this event may help build public support for those efforts.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2025 06:10:31 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45524117</link><dc:creator>SequoiaHope</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45524117</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45524117</guid></item><item><title>New comment by safety1st in "A competitor crippled a $23.5M bootcamp by becoming a Reddit moderator"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Reddit has a moderation problem, and it's a big one.&lt;p&gt;They've now been asked to appear in front of Congress to address concerns about politically motivated violence being incited through their platform: &lt;a href="https://oversight.house.gov/release/chairman-comer-invites-ceos-of-discord-steam-twitch-and-reddit-to-testify-on-radicalization-of-online-forum-users/" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://oversight.house.gov/release/chairman-comer-invites-c...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;Personally I believe I've seen more people in the past few years wish a politically motivated death on somebody else via Reddit, than I have anywhere else in my life.&lt;p&gt;Now if it was "just" the incitements to violence, or if it was "just" the libeling of random businesses, that would be one thing. But the fact that BOTH types of illegal speech are becoming a problem at the same time suggests to me that Reddit's failure to moderate is systemic and total.&lt;p&gt;It is becoming exhausting watching all of these tech companies commit crimes, or enable someone else to do so, and getting off with a slap on the wrist.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2025 05:06:07 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45523732</link><dc:creator>safety1st</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45523732</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45523732</guid></item><item><title>New comment by raincom in "A competitor crippled a $23.5M bootcamp by becoming a Reddit moderator"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;That's common. A marketing company took over r/mattress in order to get rid of any unfavorable reviews and pump up any bed in box mattress company as long as these companies pay to that market company. For more, &lt;a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/MattressMod/comments/1c28g7b/recent_events_on_rmattress/" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://www.reddit.com/r/MattressMod/comments/1c28g7b/recent...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2025 04:31:08 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45523516</link><dc:creator>raincom</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45523516</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45523516</guid></item><item><title>New comment by neilv in "A competitor crippled a $23.5M bootcamp by becoming a Reddit moderator"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I don't know about this particular case, but, generally... bad actor subreddit moderators have been an occasional thing for well over a decade.&lt;p&gt;And it's also been widely known for that long that Reddit is an influential venue in which to take over a corner -- for marketing or propaganda.&lt;p&gt;What's an equal concern to me is how &lt;i&gt;insufficiently resilient&lt;/i&gt; Reddit collectively appears to be, in face of this.&lt;p&gt;A bad actor mod of a popular subreddit can persist for years, visibly, without people managing either to oust the mod, or to take down the sub's influence.&lt;p&gt;(Subreddit peasants sometimes migrate to a new sub over bad mods, but the old sub usually remains, still with a healthy brand.  And still with a lot of members, who (speculating) maybe don't want to possibly miss out on something in the bad old sub, or didn't know what's going on, or the drama they noticed in their feed wasn't worth their effort to do the clicks to unjoin from the sub in question.)&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2025 02:38:43 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45522926</link><dc:creator>neilv</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45522926</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45522926</guid></item><item><title>New comment by fny in "A competitor crippled a $23.5M bootcamp by becoming a Reddit moderator"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;If you really cared, this should have started with: "I am stepping down as the moderator..."&lt;p&gt;Even though you have counter claims, you moderating &lt;i&gt;the forum&lt;/i&gt; for your industry is problematic. You also seem keen to chime in about a competitor when you should be impartial and allow users to discuss their experiences alone.&lt;p&gt;Yes there are two sides to every story, but in no universe should you be the mod of that subreddit.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2025 01:41:28 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45522560</link><dc:creator>fny</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45522560</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45522560</guid></item><item><title>New comment by tifik in "Discord says 70k users may have had their government IDs leaked in breach"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I don't know if I just became cynical and jaded, but is this really surprising to anyone in any way? Any time I give out my personal information to anyone for any reason, I basically treat it as 'any member of public can now access it'.&lt;p&gt;Even if a service doesn't have it in their TOS that they sell it to 3rd parties, they might do it anyway, or there will, sooner or later, be a breach of their poorly secured system.&lt;p&gt;To make it clear - I don't particularly blame any one corporation, this is a systemic issue of governments not having/not enforcing serious security measures. I just completely dropped the expectation of my information being private, and for the very few bits that I do actually want to stay private, I just don't, or allow anyone to, digitalize or reproduce them at all in any way.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2025 01:13:00 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45522379</link><dc:creator>tifik</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45522379</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45522379</guid></item><item><title>New comment by LennyHenrysNuts in "WinBoat: Windows apps on Linux with seamless integration"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;And I had to come here to find out what it actually was. Why don't project pages ever actually tell you what it is, what it does and how it does it?&lt;p&gt;Half the time it's something like "Plorglewurzle leverages your big data block chain to provide sublinear microservices to Azure Cloud infrastructures"&lt;p&gt;At least this one kind of shows you having to install Windows.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2025 01:06:27 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45522341</link><dc:creator>LennyHenrysNuts</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45522341</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45522341</guid></item><item><title>New comment by gruez in "OpenAI, Nvidia fuel $1T AI market with web of circular deals"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;For an interesting interpretation of the recent AMD-OpenAI deal, see Matt Levine's column from a few days ago:&lt;p&gt;&gt; OpenAI: We would like six gigawatts worth of your chips to do inference.&lt;p&gt;&gt; AMD: Terrific. That will be $78 billion. How would you like to pay?&lt;p&gt;&gt; OpenAI: Well, we were thinking that we would announce the deal, and that would add $78 billion to the value of your company, which should cover it.&lt;p&gt;&gt; AMD: …&lt;p&gt;&gt; OpenAI: …&lt;p&gt;&gt; AMD: No I’m pretty sure you have to pay for the chips.&lt;p&gt;&gt; OpenAI: Why?&lt;p&gt;&gt; AMD: I dunno, just seems wrong not to.&lt;p&gt;&gt; OpenAI: Okay. Why don’t we pay you cash for the value of the chips, and you give us back stock, and when we announce the deal the stock will go up and we’ll get our $78 billion back.&lt;p&gt;&gt; AMD: Yeah I guess that works though I feel like we should get some of the value?&lt;p&gt;&gt; OpenAI: Okay you can have half. You give us stock worth like $35 billion and you keep the rest.&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/opinion/newsletters/2025-10-06/openai-is-good-at-deals" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://www.bloomberg.com/opinion/newsletters/2025-10-06/ope...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://archive.is/tS5sy" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://archive.is/tS5sy&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2025 00:19:58 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45522103</link><dc:creator>gruez</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45522103</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45522103</guid></item><item><title>New comment by Angostura in "OpenAI, Nvidia fuel $1T AI market with web of circular deals"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;This reminds me of around 2002 when I wrote an article looking at how all the web behemoths at the time were claiming profitability through ad sales, but actually the vast majority of ads were from one web behemoth advertising on an other's site and vice versa.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2025 00:15:35 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45522071</link><dc:creator>Angostura</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45522071</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45522071</guid></item></channel></rss>