<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>Hacker News: Best Comments</title><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/bestcomments</link><description>Hacker News RSS</description><docs>https://hnrss.org/</docs><generator>hnrss v2.1.1</generator><lastBuildDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2026 23:43:41 +0000</lastBuildDate><ns0:link href="https://hnrss.org/bestcomments" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item><title>New comment by DrewADesign in "Vietnam bans unskippable ads"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;My favorite most annoying ad tactic is the trick slowing down progress bar. It starts off fast making it seem like it’s going to be, say, a ten-second ad so you decide to suffer through it… but progressively slows so you notice at like the 20 second mark you’re only 2/3 of the way through the progress bar, so probably less than halfway done. Murderous rage.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2026 17:18:56 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46515263</link><dc:creator>DrewADesign</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46515263</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46515263</guid></item><item><title>New comment by jason_s in "Vietnam bans unskippable ads"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I just uninstalled a game from my mobile phone this morning that had heavy ad usage. It was interesting to note the different ad display strategies. From least to most annoying:&lt;p&gt;- display a static ad, have the "x" to close appear soon (3-10 seconds)&lt;p&gt;- display an animated ad, have the "x" to close appear soon (3-10 seconds)&lt;p&gt;- display a static ad, have the "x" to close appear after 20-30 seconds&lt;p&gt;- display an animated ad, have the "x" to close appear after 20-30 seconds&lt;p&gt;- display several ads in succession, each short, but it automatically proceeds to the next; the net time after which the "x" to close appears after 20-30 seconds&lt;p&gt;- display several ads in succession, each lasts for 3-10 seconds but you have to click on an "x" to close each one before the next one appears&lt;p&gt;I live in the USA. The well-established consumer product brands (Clorox, McDonalds, etc.) almost all had short ads that were done in 3-5 seconds. The longest ads were for obscure games or websites, or for Temu, and they appeared over and over again, making me hate them with a flaming passion. The several-ads-in-succession were usually British newspaper websites (WHY???? I don't live there) or celebrity-interest websites (I have no interest in these).&lt;p&gt;It seems like the monkey's-paw curse for this kind of legislation is to show several ads in a row, each allowing you to skip them after 5 seconds.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2026 17:12:15 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46515127</link><dc:creator>jason_s</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46515127</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46515127</guid></item><item><title>New comment by HPsquared in "Why is the Gmail app 700 MB?"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;The article doesn't answer the question. The content can be summarised as "The Gmail app is 700 MB!"&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2026 17:04:41 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46514992</link><dc:creator>HPsquared</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46514992</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46514992</guid></item><item><title>New comment by _jab in "Vietnam bans unskippable ads"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I've often wondered whether the world would be better without ads. The incentive to create services (especially in social media) that strive to addict their users feels toxic to society. Often, it feels uncertain whether these services are providing actual value, and I suspect that whether a user would pay for a service in lieu of watching ads is incidentally a good barometer for whether real value is present.&lt;p&gt;Don't get me wrong, I'm well aware this is impractical. But it's fun to think about sometimes.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2026 17:00:25 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46514926</link><dc:creator>_jab</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46514926</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46514926</guid></item><item><title>New comment by ryukoposting in "65% of Hacker News posts have negative sentiment, and they outperform"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;OP's classifiers make two assumptions that I'd bet strongly influence the result:&lt;p&gt;1. Binning skepticism with negativity.&lt;p&gt;2. Not allowing for a "neutral" category.&lt;p&gt;The comment I'm writing right now is critical, but is it "negative?" I certainly don't mean it that way.&lt;p&gt;It's cool that OP made this thing. The data is nicely presented, and the conclusion is articulated cleanly, and that's precisely why I'm able to build a criticism of it!&lt;p&gt;And I'm now realizing that I don't normally feel the need to disclaim my criticism by complimenting the OP's quality work. Maybe I should do that more. Or, maybe my engagement with the material implies that I found it engaging. Hmm.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2026 16:18:33 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46514302</link><dc:creator>ryukoposting</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46514302</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46514302</guid></item><item><title>New comment by california-og in "65% of Hacker News posts have negative sentiment, and they outperform"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Back when Reddit allowed API access, I used a reader (rif) which allowed blocking subreddits. I did an experiment where I would browse /r/all and  block any subreddit that had a toxic, gruesome, nsfw, or other content playing on negative emotions (like a pseudo feel-good post based on an otherwise negative phenomena). After a few years, and hundreds of banned subreddits, my /r/all was very wholesome, but contained only animal or niche hobby related subreddits. It was quite eye-opening on how negative reddit is, and also revealed how boring it is without the kind of algorithmic reaction seeking content.&lt;p&gt;In other words, if 35% of hn content is positive (or neutral?), compared to reddit and most mainstream social media, it's actually very positive!&lt;p&gt;Edit: I found the list of blocked subreddits if anyone is curious to see:&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://hlnet.neocities.org/RIF_filters_categorized.txt" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://hlnet.neocities.org/RIF_filters_categorized.txt&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;Note that it also includes stuff I wasn't interested in at the time, like anime, and only has subreddits up until I quit, around the API ban.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2026 15:25:07 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46513431</link><dc:creator>california-og</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46513431</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46513431</guid></item><item><title>New comment by baranul in "C Is Best (2025)"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Every project and programmer shouldn't feel they have to justify their choice not to use Rust (or Zig), who seem to be strangely and disproportionately pushed on Hacker News and specific other social media platforms. This includes the pressure, though a bit less in recent years, to use OOP.&lt;p&gt;If they are getting good results with C and without OOP, and people like the product, then those from outside the project shouldn't really have any say on it. It's their project.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2026 13:46:48 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46512163</link><dc:creator>baranul</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46512163</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46512163</guid></item><item><title>New comment by muvlon in "AWS raises GPU prices 15% on a Saturday, hopes you weren't paying attention"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I don't know how everyone arrives at that conclusion when the cost of the subscription services is also going up (as evidenced by the very article we're talking about). People who are renting are feeling this immediately, whereas people who bought their computers can wait the price hikes out for a couple years before they &lt;i&gt;really&lt;/i&gt; need an upgrade.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2026 12:58:19 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46511672</link><dc:creator>muvlon</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46511672</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46511672</guid></item><item><title>New comment by xvxvx in "AWS raises GPU prices 15% on a Saturday, hopes you weren't paying attention"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;- GPU prices rising&lt;p&gt;- RAM prices rising&lt;p&gt;- hard drive prices rising&lt;p&gt;Are we looking at a future where home computers are replaced by thin clients and all the power lies in subscription services?&lt;p&gt;‘You don't need storage space, use our cloud subscription’&lt;p&gt;‘You don’t need processing power, stream your games through our subscription service.’&lt;p&gt;Game publishers have already publicly floated the idea of not selling their games but charging per hour. Imagine how that impact Call of Duty or GTA.&lt;p&gt;Physical media could easily be killed off. Does my iPhone need 1TB of storage or will they shrink that and force everything through iCloud?&lt;p&gt;How long before car ownership is replaced with autonomous vehicle car pools? Grocery stores closed to visitors, all shopping done online and delivered to your door by drone.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2026 12:35:03 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46511477</link><dc:creator>xvxvx</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46511477</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46511477</guid></item><item><title>New comment by Quothling in "The Post-American Internet"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I've spent a couple of decades in the Danish public sector of digitalisation and in the private sector for global green energy. 10 years ago people would've laughed if you talked about leaving Microsoft and iOS in enterprise. Now we all have contingency plans for just that, and a lot of organisations are already actually doing it. So I would argue that there is more of a crack, but I'm not sure the post-american internet is going to be all that great. Because unlike the open source and decentralised platforms which are taking the place of US tech, the EU is going to regulate the internet. There is a saying about how us citizens trust companies but not their government, and how Europeans trust their governments but not their companies. Which obviously doesn't apply to everyone, but it's how you can view the EU. With one hand they do so much to protect consumer rights for us citizens, but with the other hand they build a survailance state.&lt;p&gt;Of course that is how democracy works. You'll have multiple factions working toward their own goals with very different ideologies, and the EU has a lot of that. For the most part what comes out is great, because compromise is how you get things done when there aren't just two sides. For survailance, however, there are really just two sides and the wrong one of them is winning.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2026 07:11:18 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46509554</link><dc:creator>Quothling</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46509554</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46509554</guid></item><item><title>New comment by Aloisius in "There were BGP anomalies during the Venezuela blackout"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;&gt; When BGP traffic is being sent from point A to point B, it can be rerouted through a point C. If you control point C, even for a few hours, you can theoretically collect vast amounts of intelligence that would be very useful for government entities. The CANTV AS8048 being prepended to the AS path 10 times means there the traffic would not prioritize this route through AS8048, perhaps that was the goal?&lt;/i&gt;&lt;p&gt;AS prepending is a relatively common method of traffic engineering to reduce traffic from a peer/provider. Looking at CANTV's (AS8048) announcements from outside that period shows they do this a lot.&lt;p&gt;Since this was detected as a BGP route leak, it looks like CANTV (AS8048) propagated routes from Telecom Italia Sparkle (AS6762) to GlobeNet Cabos Sumarinos Columbia (AS52320). This could have simply been a misconfiguration.&lt;p&gt;Nothing nefarious immediately jumps out to me here. I don't see any obvious attempts to hijack routes to Dayco Telecom (AS21980), which was the actual destination. The prepending would have made traffic less likely to transit over CANTV assuming there was any other route available.&lt;p&gt;The prepending done by CANTV does make it slightly easier to hijack traffic destined to it (though not really to Dayco), but that just appears to be something they just normally do.&lt;p&gt;This could be CANTV trying to force some users of GlobeNet to transit over them to Dayco I suppose, but leaving the prepending in would be an odd way of going about it. I suppose if you &lt;i&gt;absolutely&lt;/i&gt; knew you were the shortest path length, there's no reason to remove the prepending, but a misconfiguration is usually the cause of these things.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2026 23:03:30 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46506387</link><dc:creator>Aloisius</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46506387</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46506387</guid></item><item><title>New comment by gorbachev in "Google broke my heart"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;So not only do they process illegitimate copyright strikes / DMCA takedowns, but they also don't process legitimate ones.&lt;p&gt;Google is broken to the very core.&lt;p&gt;This is what happens with a company that tries to minimize costs of support to zero.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2026 22:55:41 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46506310</link><dc:creator>gorbachev</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46506310</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46506310</guid></item><item><title>New comment by GMoromisato in "Try to take my position: The best promotion advice I ever got"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;In my view, the meta-advice is to understand the goals and constraints of your boss (and their boss), and work towards those goals (while adhering to the constraints).&lt;p&gt;With that perspective, we can derive some rules of thumb:&lt;p&gt;1. Promotions are not a reward for past performance. Instead, they are a bet that you will contribute more towards those goals with a promotion than without one.&lt;p&gt;2. As the OP says, if you are demonstrating performance at your boss's level, that's evidence/proof that a promotion is warranted. Your boss's goals get implemented (by you), freeing them to work on &lt;i&gt;their&lt;/i&gt; boss's goals (and maybe get their own promotion).&lt;p&gt;3. The more time you spend with your boss, the better you will understand their goals, and symmetrically, the better they will understand your strengths. That means leaving a job after a year or two is not always optimal. It also means following a good boss to another company is often a good move.&lt;p&gt;4. There will be cases where the goals of your boss (and their boss) diverge from your own goals. They often want to cut costs, but you want a salary increase. There are never easy answers to this dilemma, but seeing their perspective is useful so you can find a win-win scenario. E.g., if you come up with a way to save money in other ways, such as automating an external cost, then your increased salary will be worth it.&lt;p&gt;5. In some cases, of course, there is no way to reconcile your boss's goals with your own. Realizing that is useful so you can find a different company/boss that is more aligned.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2026 20:55:25 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46504830</link><dc:creator>GMoromisato</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46504830</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46504830</guid></item><item><title>New comment by michaelt in "Try to take my position: The best promotion advice I ever got"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;i&gt;second&lt;/i&gt; secret to getting promoted is working at a company that's growing.&lt;p&gt;If you're at a 50 employee company that grows to 250 employees there will be &lt;i&gt;many&lt;/i&gt; empty team leader positions. And what you lack in hands-on management experience you make up for in knowledge of the business, its products/processes, and being a reliable known quantity. That extra responsibility will turn into more money &lt;i&gt;fast&lt;/i&gt;.&lt;p&gt;On the other hand, if the company's headcount is largely stable and the employee turnover low? Well, there might not be an empty position until someone a level above you resigns, retires or gets fired. And when that happens - you're probably not the only ambitious person at your level. In this case, the payoff from extra effort is much less certain.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2026 20:48:37 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46504730</link><dc:creator>michaelt</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46504730</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46504730</guid></item><item><title>New comment by UncleMeat in "X blames users for Grok-generated CSAM; no fixes announced"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;The number of people saying that it is not worthy of intervention that every single woman who posts on twitter has to worry about somebody saying "hey grok, take her clothes off" and then be made into a public sex object is maybe the most acute example of rape culture that I've seen in decades.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2026 19:49:15 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46503816</link><dc:creator>UncleMeat</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46503816</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46503816</guid></item><item><title>New comment by amflare in "Try to take my position: The best promotion advice I ever got"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Taking on extra responsibility is all well and good until someone figures out that they can just get you to do more work for the same amount of money. At that point your only option is to move on, because if you stop performing at the "expected" level due to lack of reciprocation, suddenly you have "performance issues".&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2026 19:46:52 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46503776</link><dc:creator>amflare</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46503776</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46503776</guid></item><item><title>New comment by bpasero in "I switched from VSCode to Zed"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;We maintain a single VS Code setting that allows you to opt out of the AI features provided in VS Code: "chat.disableAIFeatures" (see also: &lt;a href="https://code.visualstudio.com/updates/v1_104#_hide-and-disable-github-copilot-ai-features" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://code.visualstudio.com/updates/v1_104#_hide-and-disab...&lt;/a&gt;). If you can still find AI features appearing after you have configured this setting, then please report an issue at &lt;a href="https://github.com/microsoft/vscode" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://github.com/microsoft/vscode&lt;/a&gt; and we are happy to take a look.&lt;p&gt;It is possible that from time to time a new AI related feature slips in that does not respect that setting, but we try our best to push fixes as soon as possible.&lt;p&gt;Thanks!
Ben (VS Code Team)&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2026 16:52:21 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46501220</link><dc:creator>bpasero</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46501220</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46501220</guid></item><item><title>New comment by solfox in "It's hard to justify Tahoe icons"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;100% this. I recall watching their launch video about Liquid Glass. It was filled with ego-driven "we're changing the world here" nonsense. They were designing in a bubble and wanted to do something different so they could justify the work. It was never about the user.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2026 16:16:20 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46500578</link><dc:creator>solfox</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46500578</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46500578</guid></item><item><title>New comment by xnx in "It's hard to justify Tahoe icons"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&gt; If a PM tells you to shove a UI style&lt;p&gt;More than likely designers are making up work to justify their jobs. Not good for your career if you admit the desktop interface was perfected in ~1995.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2026 16:02:42 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46500400</link><dc:creator>xnx</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46500400</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46500400</guid></item><item><title>New comment by SunshineTheCat in "All AI Videos Are Harmful (2025)"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;One of the arguments I keep seeing from people churning out AI video is that the tech is enabling people "creative freedom" that's been made possible now even without the technical know how.&lt;p&gt;However, 99% of the the "creativity" from what I've seen is done by the AI (how it should look, where the cuts need to happen, the tone, color grading, etc). Which is to say, it's taken from other people's (creative) work.&lt;p&gt;While a big part of being able to create a good video has much to do with storytelling, the craft of shooting and editing a video is a big part of the creative process as well.&lt;p&gt;AI video isn't "enabling people to be more creative," it is quite literally removing creativity from the process all together.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2026 15:42:15 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46500107</link><dc:creator>SunshineTheCat</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46500107</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46500107</guid></item><item><title>New comment by runako in "Jensen: 'We've done our country a great disservice' by offshoring"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;There are so many underlying changes to the established relationship between Labor and Capital in the US that would be a necessary part of keeping jobs here that it would effectively make us a completely different country.&lt;p&gt;For example -- suppose one could snap one's fingers and "bring back" millions of manufacturing jobs. What would lead one to conclude those would be the kind of "good jobs" everyone is envisioning? Historically, they were better jobs due to a strong labor movement, but that movement has been largely destroyed.&lt;p&gt;Similarly, if we want widespread prosperity, there is no reason service jobs should not be "good jobs." There is no economic rule that says that riveting should pay more than taking care of the elderly or food delivery.&lt;p&gt;We have jobs, we have just decided that the people working those jobs are not deserving of prosperity. If we re-shore jobs, what would make anyone think we would treat those jobs differently?&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2026 14:30:34 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46499139</link><dc:creator>runako</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46499139</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46499139</guid></item><item><title>New comment by sirwhinesalot in "It's hard to justify Tahoe icons"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;It's hard to justify Liquid Glass in general. The wastefulness of flat design (in terms of space) married with the visual excess of skeuomorphism, but without even providing any affordances (does the sidebar being raised give you any new information on how to use a sidebar? No).&lt;p&gt;If you're a designer at a top 10 S&amp;P 500 company making 6 figures, you owe it to yourself to have some love for your craft. If a PM tells you to shove a UI style meant for an unsuccessful VR device onto desktop and mobile platforms, say no. Get your colleagues to say no. Make that PM read everything the Nielsen Norman group has ever written. Read it too.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2026 14:02:02 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46498820</link><dc:creator>sirwhinesalot</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46498820</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46498820</guid></item><item><title>New comment by postalcoder in "It's hard to justify Tahoe icons"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;This is an excellent article.&lt;p&gt;Apple has been rudderless on the interaction design front for over a decade now. The windowing mess is evidence of it. We now have the cmd+tab (app switcher), Spaces, Mission Control, (full screen) split screen,  Stage Manager, and now tiled window control. None of those interaction metaphors have been expanded upon since their initial launch.&lt;p&gt;I'm a "mac guy". I understood why Apple initially eschewed windows style alt-tab, given the emphasis on app-centricism. But now, they've created a thousand different ways to switch windows without giving us a proper window switcher. There are apps that bring alt-tab to Mac, but they are all bad because Apple doesn't give developers access to the low-level APIs to create performant and fully featured window management.&lt;p&gt;Before, Apple had an endless well of great ideas to tap. That's how we got the term "Sherlocked".  However, now that they've locked down macOS so much, they've suffocated themselves of new ideas.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2026 12:56:33 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46498249</link><dc:creator>postalcoder</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46498249</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46498249</guid></item><item><title>New comment by Zealotux in "It's hard to justify Tahoe icons"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Tahoe and Liquid Glass™ solidified for me the idea that Apple completely dropped the ball when it comes to design. Clearly they needed an a-hole in charge, Jobs would've crucified a few people.&lt;p&gt;It's painful to see the decay, update after update, into a more confusing, cluttered, and tacky experience.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2026 12:48:49 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46498180</link><dc:creator>Zealotux</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46498180</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46498180</guid></item><item><title>New comment by aylmao in "It's hard to justify Tahoe icons"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;This isn't the only aspect of Tahoe that seems amateurishly designed by someone following "wrong rules", the wrong rule here being "for consistency, let's assign an icon to every action.&lt;p&gt;Another wrong rules I've seen blindly followed is making everything an edge-to-edge canvas, so that the sidebar floats on top. Having a full-window canvas with floating sidebars can make sense for applications where content is expansive and inherently spatial (like say, Figma) or applications where the sidebar is an actual floating element that can be moved around (like Photoshop once was).&lt;p&gt;It doesn't make sense in Finder, or Reminders, where the content is ultimately just a list. Forcing the sidebar "to float on top of the content" yields no benefit because the content wont ever scroll under it, and because it can't be moved anyway, but it does lead to wasted space, that ugly "double border", etc.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2026 12:34:54 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46498069</link><dc:creator>aylmao</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46498069</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46498069</guid></item><item><title>New comment by ulrikrasmussen in "Microsoft Office renamed to “Microsoft 365 Copilot app”"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I genuinely thought this was a joke when I saw the headline, and I had to double check the domain name to verify that this wasn't a parody.&lt;p&gt;Apart from being absolutely abysmal marketing, the front page alone is wildly inconsistent:&lt;p&gt;* "Welcome to Microsoft 365 Copilot"&lt;p&gt;* "The Microsoft 365 Copilot app (formerly Office) [...]"&lt;p&gt;* "Microsoft 365 (formerly Microsoft Office 365) is a subscription service [...]"&lt;p&gt;Which is it, "Microsoft 365 Copilot", "(The) Microsoft 365 Copilot app", "(The) Microsoft 365 Copilot app (formerly Office)", "Microsoft 365" or "Microsoft 365 (formerly Microsoft Office 365)"?&lt;p&gt;I think Microsoft delegated all marketing decisions to AI. Not even joking.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2026 12:33:46 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46498062</link><dc:creator>ulrikrasmussen</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46498062</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46498062</guid></item><item><title>New comment by throwaway_ab in "It's hard to justify Tahoe icons"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;It's hard to justify snowflake animations on your website...&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2026 12:14:44 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46497887</link><dc:creator>throwaway_ab</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46497887</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46497887</guid></item><item><title>New comment by rahimnathwani in "Lessons from 14 years at Google"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;  The more efficient I made the technical part of the job, the more time they had to spend doing the manual labor part of the job to keep up.
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
Imagine you like writing code, and someone automates that part of the job so you have to spend more of your time reviewing PRs and writing specs...&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2026 09:09:53 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46496734</link><dc:creator>rahimnathwani</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46496734</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46496734</guid></item><item><title>New comment by treesknees in "During Helene, I just wanted a plain text website"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Several news sites offer text only versions.&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://lite.cnn.com/" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://lite.cnn.com/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://text.npr.org/" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://text.npr.org/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://wttr.in/" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://wttr.in/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;More listed at &lt;a href="https://greycoder.com/a-list-of-text-only-new-sites" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://greycoder.com/a-list-of-text-only-new-sites&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;It’d be great if there was some standard that allowed these to be easily found, and supported on the local news sites.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2026 02:47:01 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46494788</link><dc:creator>treesknees</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46494788</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46494788</guid></item><item><title>New comment by tomp in "Why does a least squares fit appear to have a bias when applied to simple data?"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Linear Regression a.k.a. &lt;i&gt;Ordinary&lt;/i&gt; Least Squares assumes only &lt;i&gt;Y&lt;/i&gt; has noise, and &lt;i&gt;X&lt;/i&gt; is correct.&lt;p&gt;Your "visual inspection" assumes both &lt;i&gt;X&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Y&lt;/i&gt; have noise. That's called &lt;i&gt;Total&lt;/i&gt; Least Squares.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 04 Jan 2026 23:03:46 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46493322</link><dc:creator>tomp</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46493322</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46493322</guid></item></channel></rss>