<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>Hacker News: Best Comments</title><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/bestcomments</link><description>Hacker News RSS</description><docs>https://hnrss.org/</docs><generator>hnrss v2.1.1</generator><lastBuildDate>Sun, 28 Dec 2025 00:29:33 +0000</lastBuildDate><ns0:link href="https://hnrss.org/bestcomments" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item><title>New comment by Coffeewine in "[dead]"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I think this sums it up pretty well.&lt;p&gt;"When I am weaker than you, I ask you for freedom because that is according to your principles; when I am stronger than you, I take away your freedom because that is according to my principles,"&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 27 Dec 2025 21:41:03 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46405520</link><dc:creator>Coffeewine</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46405520</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46405520</guid></item><item><title>New comment by epistasis in "[dead]"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&gt; "one of the largest sources of climate alarmism in the country."&lt;p&gt;It's amazing how fast free speech has been destroyed in the past year. Especially when it comes to censorship of science and science's conclusions.&lt;p&gt;However, I heard many many more people complaining about a lack of free speech in 2023 and 2024 than now. I really wonder what happened to all those principles! It's shocking.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 27 Dec 2025 21:37:00 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46405485</link><dc:creator>epistasis</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46405485</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46405485</guid></item><item><title>New comment by RobotToaster in "Apple releases open-source model that instantly turns 2D photos into 3D views"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/apple/ml-sharp/refs/heads/main/LICENSE_MODEL" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/apple/ml-sharp/refs/heads/...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;"Exclusively for research purposes" so not actually open source.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 27 Dec 2025 14:43:48 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46402179</link><dc:creator>RobotToaster</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46402179</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46402179</guid></item><item><title>New comment by sccxy in "Exe.dev"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;That must be worst website ever made.&lt;p&gt;Zero information available on mobile.&lt;p&gt;I thought it is some kind of portfolio site that does not work on mobile.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 27 Dec 2025 07:27:33 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46399903</link><dc:creator>sccxy</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46399903</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46399903</guid></item><item><title>New comment by crystal_revenge in "Publishing your work increases your luck"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&gt; Having your OSS library take off&lt;p&gt;All of the other bullet points there are pretty reasonable, but, having worked in OSS professionally, I genuinely &lt;i&gt;hope&lt;/i&gt; none of my GH projects take off in the OSS world.&lt;p&gt;I have a few projects that are in the  &gt;50 stars range, and am both grateful for other people's interests and very glad that none of them crossed the threshold to becoming &lt;i&gt;real&lt;/i&gt; OSS projects. I like sharing my interesting experiments, but I absolutely do not want to be stuck with the nightmare of maintaining OSS software &lt;i&gt;for years&lt;/i&gt;.&lt;p&gt;Even on these small projects, I've had times when I'm pressured to do a bug fix on a 5 year old project where I don't even remember how it works or review and merge an enthusiastic PR solving a problem I don't actually care about. It has eaten up a few weekends, and was a relatively minor annoyance, but it gave me the taste for what OSS work involved. Working professionally for an OSS company gave me even more insight.&lt;p&gt;Maintaining OSS is a royal pain in the butt and I am forever grateful for the people who &lt;i&gt;choose&lt;/i&gt; to do this. Running a popular OSS library is not a prize. It's &lt;i&gt;at least&lt;/i&gt; a part time job you aren't paid for. The benefits are slim; even the "fame" part (name your top 10 favorite OSS tools, now name the maintainers of those), and has really limited rewards outside of that. I've know plenty of brilliant creators of OSS libraries who struggle to find jobs in industry that are appropriate to their skill level.&lt;p&gt;In fact, it's really hard to both run a successful OSS project &lt;i&gt;and&lt;/i&gt; have a full time job (especially a high paying one that wants a lot of your brain and time) if you can't some how manage to make that OSS project your full time job... and even then you will be under constant pressure to find a way to monetize your OSS project (which inevitably leads to either losing that job or making decisions not in the interest of your community of OSS users).&lt;p&gt;OSS maintainers are &lt;i&gt;saints&lt;/i&gt; as far as I'm concerned. So much of the world's software depends on them (even moreso in the age of LLMs) and the &lt;i&gt;vast&lt;/i&gt; majority are compensated way less than your average FAANG engineer.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 27 Dec 2025 07:21:40 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46399871</link><dc:creator>crystal_revenge</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46399871</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46399871</guid></item><item><title>New comment by orliesaurus in "How uv got so fast"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;The most surprising part of uv's success to me isn't Rust at all, it's how much speed we "unlocked" just by finally treating Python packaging as a well-specified systems problem instead of a pile of historical accidents. If uv had been written in Go or even highly optimized CPython, but with the same design decisions (PEP 517/518/621/658 focus, HTTP range tricks, aggressive wheel-first strategy, ignoring obviously defensive upper bounds, etc.), I strongly suspect we'd be debating a 1.3× vs 1.5× speedup instead of a 10× headline — but the conversation here keeps collapsing back to "Rust rewrite good/bad." That feels like cargo-culting the toolchain instead of asking the uncomfortable question: why did it take a greenfield project to give Python the package manager behavior people clearly wanted for the last decade?&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 26 Dec 2025 23:40:11 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46397584</link><dc:creator>orliesaurus</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46397584</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46397584</guid></item><item><title>New comment by numbsafari in "Ask HN: What did you read in 2025?"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;This year:&lt;p&gt;- I read the entire “Frog &amp; Toad” collection. Probably about 30 times, some stories more.&lt;p&gt;- “Little Shrew’s Day”… probably 25 times.&lt;p&gt;- Many of the “Construction Site” series books, especially the OG “Goodnight, Goodnight, Construction Site”. The “Garbage Crew” and “Airport” books featured heavily.&lt;p&gt;- Started to mix in some “Pete the Cat” titles.&lt;p&gt;- “Detective Dog Nell” got a lot of air play.&lt;p&gt;Lots of others, but those are definitely the frequent fliers.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 26 Dec 2025 23:37:56 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46397563</link><dc:creator>numbsafari</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46397563</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46397563</guid></item><item><title>New comment by hijodelsol in "Rob Pike goes nuclear over GenAI"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Sending an automated thank you note also shows disdain for the recipient's time due to the asymmetry of the interaction. The sender clearly sees the thank you note sending as a task not worthy of their time and thus hands it off to a machine, but expects the recipient to read it themselves. This inherently ranks the importance of their respective time and effort.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 26 Dec 2025 21:41:04 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46396589</link><dc:creator>hijodelsol</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46396589</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46396589</guid></item><item><title>New comment by card_zero in "Experts explore new mushroom which causes fairytale-like hallucinations"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;So, about one mushroom species in five is poisonous. Why is the ratio so low, why are there lots of edible ones? Without hard-shelled seeds to spread, why be eaten? And the poisonous ones apparently don't use color as a warning signal, and don't smell all that bad, and some of the poisons have really mild effects, like "gives only some people diarrhea" or "makes a hangover worse". Meanwhile three of the deadliest species seemed to need their toxin (amanitin) so much that they picked it up through &lt;i&gt;horizontal gene transfer.&lt;/i&gt; Why did just &lt;i&gt;those&lt;/i&gt; ones need to be deadly? In addition to which we have these species that don't even make you sick, just make you trip out, a function which looks to have evolved three times over in different ways. What kind of half-assed evolutionary strategies are these? What do mushrooms &lt;i&gt;want?&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 26 Dec 2025 21:05:02 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46396249</link><dc:creator>card_zero</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46396249</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46396249</guid></item><item><title>New comment by trinsic2 in "Rob Pike goes nuclear over GenAI"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&gt;"For myself, the big fraud is getting public to believe that Intellectual Property was a moral principle and not just effective BS to justify corporate rent seeking."&lt;p&gt;If anything, I'm glad people are finally starting to wake up to this fact.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 26 Dec 2025 20:47:59 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46396075</link><dc:creator>trinsic2</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46396075</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46396075</guid></item><item><title>New comment by nemothekid in "How uv got so fast"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Given the context of the article, I think "Rust specific" here means that "it couldn't be done in python".&lt;p&gt;For example "No interpreter startup" is not specific to Rust either.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 26 Dec 2025 20:38:15 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46395977</link><dc:creator>nemothekid</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46395977</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46395977</guid></item><item><title>New comment by suralind in "Rob Pike goes nuclear over GenAI"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I don’t really understand the hate he gets over this. If you want to thank someone for their contribution, do that yourself? Sending thank you from an ML model is anything but respectful. I can only imagine that if I got a message like that I’d be furious too.&lt;p&gt;This reminds me a story from my mom’s work from years ago: the company she was working for announced salary increases to each worker individually. Some, like my mom, got a little bit more, but some got a monthly increase around 2 PLN (about $0.5). At that point, it feels like a slap in the face. A thank you from AI gives the same vibe.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 26 Dec 2025 20:27:52 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46395873</link><dc:creator>suralind</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46395873</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46395873</guid></item><item><title>New comment by woodruffw in "How uv got so fast"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I think this post does a really good job of covering how multi-pronged performance is: it certainly doesn't hurt uv to be written in Rust, but it benefits &lt;i&gt;immensely&lt;/i&gt; from a decade of thoughtful standardization efforts in Python that lifted the ecosystem away from needing `setup.py` on the hot path for most packages.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 26 Dec 2025 20:24:03 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46395821</link><dc:creator>woodruffw</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46395821</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46395821</guid></item><item><title>New comment by teddyh in "My insulin pump controller uses the Linux kernel. It also violates the GPL"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&gt; &lt;i&gt;I then decided to contact Insulet to get the kernel source code for it, being GPLv2 licensed, they're obligated to provide it.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;p&gt;This is technically not true.  It is an oversimplification of the common case, but what actually normally should happen is that:&lt;p&gt;1. The GPL requires the company to send the user a &lt;i&gt;written offer&lt;/i&gt; of source code.&lt;p&gt;2. The user uses this offer to request the source code from the company.&lt;p&gt;3. If the user does not receive the source code, the user can sue the company for not honoring its promises, i.e. the offer of source code.  This is not a GPL violation; it is a straight contract violation; the contract in this case being the explicit offer of source code, and not the GPL.&lt;p&gt;Note that all this is completely off the rails if the user does not receive a written offer of source code in the first place.  In this case, the user has no right to source code, since the user did not receive an offer for source code.&lt;p&gt;However, the copyright holders can immediately sue the company for violating the GPL, since the company did not send a written offer of source code to the user.  It does not matter if the company does or does not send the source code to the user; the fact that the company did not send a written offer to the user in the first place is by itself a GPL violation.&lt;p&gt;(IANAL)&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 26 Dec 2025 20:06:12 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46395668</link><dc:creator>teddyh</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46395668</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46395668</guid></item><item><title>New comment by crawshaw in "Rob Pike got spammed with an AI slop "act of kindness""</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;The important point that Simon makes in careful detail is: an "AI" did not send this email. The three people behind the Sage AI project used a tool to email him.&lt;p&gt;According to their website this email was sent by Adam Binksmith, Zak Miller, and Shoshannah Tekofsky and is the responsibility of the Sage 501(c)3.&lt;p&gt;No-one gets to disclaim ownership of sending an email. A human has to accept the Terms of Service of an email gateway and the credit card used to pay the email gateway. This performance art does not remove the human no matter how much they want to be removed.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 26 Dec 2025 19:13:47 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46395188</link><dc:creator>crawshaw</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46395188</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46395188</guid></item><item><title>New comment by nospice in "Experts explore new mushroom which causes fairytale-like hallucinations"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Could be that the mushroom just temporarily interferes with the substances the elves put in our water supply to keep us in the dark?&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 26 Dec 2025 18:38:15 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46394822</link><dc:creator>nospice</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46394822</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46394822</guid></item><item><title>New comment by merlindru in "FFmpeg has issued a DMCA takedown on GitHub"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;The repo in question incorporated FFmpeg code while claiming their code is Apache 2.0-licensed over 1.5 years ago[1]&lt;p&gt;This is not allowed under the LGPL, which mandates dynamic linking against the library. They copy-pasted FFmpeg code into their repo instead.&lt;p&gt;[1] &lt;a href="https://x.com/HermanChen1982/status/1761230920563233137" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://x.com/HermanChen1982/status/1761230920563233137&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 26 Dec 2025 17:48:25 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46394328</link><dc:creator>merlindru</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46394328</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46394328</guid></item><item><title>New comment by lambda in "Rob Pike goes nuclear over GenAI"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Data center power usage has been fairly flat for the last decade (until 2022 or so). While new capacity has been coming online, efficiency improvements have been keeping up, keeping total usage mostly flat.&lt;p&gt;The AI boom has completely changed that. Data center power usage is rocketing upwards now. It is estimated it will be more than 10% of all electric power usage in the US by 2030.&lt;p&gt;It's a completely different order of magnitude than the pre AI-boom data center usage.&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href="https://escholarship.org/uc/item/32d6m0d1" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://escholarship.org/uc/item/32d6m0d1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 26 Dec 2025 15:21:58 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46392930</link><dc:creator>lambda</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46392930</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46392930</guid></item><item><title>New comment by acheron in "Rob Pike goes nuclear over GenAI"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Google has been burning compute for the past 25 years to shove ads at people. We all lost there, too, but he apparently didn’t mind that.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 26 Dec 2025 15:05:46 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46392719</link><dc:creator>acheron</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46392719</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46392719</guid></item><item><title>New comment by bigbluedots in "Rob Pike goes nuclear over GenAI"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;It is nice to hear someone who is so influential just come out and say it. At my workplace, the expectation is that everyone will use AI in their daily software dev work. It's a difficult position for those of us who feel that using AI is immoral due to the large scale theft of the labor of many of our fellow developers, not to mention the many huge data centers being built and their need for electricity, pushing up prices for people who need to, ya know, heat their homes and eat&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 26 Dec 2025 15:05:05 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46392712</link><dc:creator>bigbluedots</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46392712</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46392712</guid></item><item><title>New comment by Scubabear68 in "Rob Pike goes nuclear over GenAI"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;All I have to say is this post warmed my heart. I'm sure people here associate him with Go lang and Google, but I will always associate him with Bell Labs and Unix and The Practice of Programming, and overall the amazing contributions he has made to computing.&lt;p&gt;To purely associate with him with Google is a mistake, that (ironically?) the AI actually didn't make.&lt;p&gt;Just the haters here.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 26 Dec 2025 14:58:21 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46392626</link><dc:creator>Scubabear68</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46392626</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46392626</guid></item><item><title>New comment by InsideOutSanta in "Rob Pike goes nuclear over GenAI"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Everything humans do is harmful to some degree. I don't want to put words in Pike's mouth, but I'm assuming his point is that the cost-benefit-ratio of how LLMs are often used is out of whack.&lt;p&gt;Somebody burned compute to send him an LLM-generated thank-you note. Everybody involved in this transaction lost, nobody gained anything from it. It's pure destruction of resources.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 26 Dec 2025 14:57:43 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46392621</link><dc:creator>InsideOutSanta</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46392621</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46392621</guid></item><item><title>New comment by nkrisc in "Rob Pike goes nuclear over GenAI"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;If the creators set the LLM in motion, then the creators sent the letter.&lt;p&gt;If I put my car in neutral and push it down a hill, I’m responsible for whatever happens.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 26 Dec 2025 14:53:06 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46392550</link><dc:creator>nkrisc</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46392550</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46392550</guid></item><item><title>New comment by jabedude in "Rob Pike goes nuclear over GenAI"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Did Google, the company currently paying Rob Pike's extravagant salary, just start building data centers in 2025? Before 2025 was Google's infra running on dreams and pixie farts with baby deer and birdies chirping around? Why are the new data centers his company is building suddenly "raping the planet" and "unrecyclable"?&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 26 Dec 2025 14:39:27 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46392387</link><dc:creator>jabedude</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46392387</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46392387</guid></item><item><title>New comment by nkrisc in "Rob Pike goes nuclear over GenAI"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;What is going through the mind of someone who sends an AI-generated thank-you letter instead of writing it themselves? How can you be grateful enough to want to send someone such a letter but not grateful enough to write one?&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 26 Dec 2025 14:34:05 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46392315</link><dc:creator>nkrisc</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46392315</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46392315</guid></item><item><title>New comment by c-linkage in "Package managers keep using Git as a database, it never works out"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;This seems like a tragedy of the commons -- GitHub is free after all, and it has all of these great properties, so why not? -- but this kind of decision making occurs whenever externalities are present.&lt;p&gt;My favorite hill to die on (externality) is user time.  Most software houses spend so much time focusing on how expensive engineering time is that they neglect user time.  Software houses optimize for feature delivery and not user interaction time.  Yet if I spent one hour making my app one second faster for my million users, I can save 277 user hour per year. But since user hours are an externality, such optimization never gets done.&lt;p&gt;Externalities lead to users downloading extra gigabytes of data (wasted time) and waiting for software, all of which is waste that the developer isn't responsible for and doesn't care about.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 26 Dec 2025 13:52:41 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46391981</link><dc:creator>c-linkage</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46391981</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46391981</guid></item><item><title>New comment by nromiun in "Rob Pike goes nuclear over GenAI"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Funny how so many people in this comment section are saying Rob Pike is just feeling insecure about AI. Rob Pike created UTF-8, Go, Plan-9 etc. On the other hand I am trying hard to remember anything famous created by any LLM. Any famous tech product at all.&lt;p&gt;It is always the eternal tomorrow with AI.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 26 Dec 2025 06:52:50 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46389808</link><dc:creator>nromiun</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46389808</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46389808</guid></item><item><title>New comment by wrs in "Rob Pike goes nuclear over GenAI"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;To be clear, this email isn't from Anthropic, it's from "AI Village" [0], which seems to be a bunch of agents run by a 501(c)3 called Sage that are apparently allowed to run amok and send random emails.&lt;p&gt;At this moment, the Opus 4.5 agent is preparing to harass William Kahan similarly.&lt;p&gt;[0] &lt;a href="https://theaidigest.org/village" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://theaidigest.org/village&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 26 Dec 2025 06:05:41 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46389600</link><dc:creator>wrs</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46389600</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46389600</guid></item><item><title>New comment by jimrandomh in "Seven diabetes patients die due to undisclosed bug in Abbott's glucose monitors"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I'm a T1 diabetic, have worked on open source diabetes-tech (OpenAPS), and have used a number of different CGMs (though not this one specifically). This story... does not make very much sense.&lt;p&gt;CGMs (of any brand) are not, and have never been, reliable in the way that this story implies that people want them to be reliable. The physical biology of CGMs makes that sort of reliability infeasible. Where T1s are concerned, patient education has always included the need to check with fingerstick readings sometimes, and to be aware of mismatches between sensor readings and how you're feeling. If a brand of CGMs have an issue that sometimes causes false low readings, then fixing it if it's fixable is great, but that sort of thing was very much expected, and it doesn't seem reasonable to blame it for deaths. Moreover, there are two directions in which readings can be inaccurate (false low, false high) with very asymmetric risk profiles, and the report says that the errors were in the less-dangerous direction.&lt;p&gt;The FDA announcement doesn't say much about what the actual issue was, but given that it was linked to particular production batches, my bet is that it was a chemistry QC fail in one of the reagents used in the sensor wire. That's not something FOSS would be able to solve because it's not a software thing at all.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 26 Dec 2025 03:14:12 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46388885</link><dc:creator>jimrandomh</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46388885</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46388885</guid></item><item><title>New comment by delichon in "Maybe the default settings are too high"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;My dad was a busy construction contractor. One summer he tore himself away from work and took the family to a week long boat camp out next to a big beautiful lake. It turned out that our campsite was actually in the lake by a few inches at high water, but dad saw a way to dam it off and keep it dry, so he grabs the shovel and starts digging trenches and building walls and ordering us around.&lt;p&gt;About an hour into that, pouring sweat, he stops cold and says "what the hell am I doing?" The flooded camp was actually nice on a hot day and all we really had to do was move a couple of tents. He dropped the shovel and spent the rest of the week sunbathing, fishing, snorkeling and water skiing as God intended. He flipped a switch and went from Hyde to Jekyll on vacation. I've had to emulate that a few times.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 23:56:35 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46387876</link><dc:creator>delichon</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46387876</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46387876</guid></item></channel></rss>