<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>Hacker News: Best Comments</title><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/bestcomments</link><description>Hacker News RSS</description><docs>https://hnrss.org/</docs><generator>hnrss v2.1.1</generator><lastBuildDate>Sun, 16 Nov 2025 00:09:23 +0000</lastBuildDate><ns0:link href="https://hnrss.org/bestcomments" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item><title>New comment by andronikos in "Our investigation into the suspicious pressure on Archive.today"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;member of DNS4EU ops team here - This was not the case, we had reachability issues with the authoritative servers of archive.is and had to reach out to the team to allow our source IPs.&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/BuyFromEU/comments/1ohekv5/updatedns4eu_is_not_blocking_archive_today/" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://www.reddit.com/r/BuyFromEU/comments/1ohekv5/updatedn...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 15 Nov 2025 15:13:00 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45937951</link><dc:creator>andronikos</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45937951</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45937951</guid></item><item><title>New comment by supriyo-biswas in "Our investigation into the suspicious pressure on Archive.today"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Its interesting that being unable to find a legal route to dig up dirt on archive.is, they're going the route of CSAM allegations.&lt;p&gt;I first heard of this technique on a discussion on Lowendtalk from a hoster discussing how pressure campaigns were orchestrated.&lt;p&gt;The host used to host VMs for a customer that was not well liked but otherwise within the bounds of free speech in the US (I guess something on the order of KF/SaSu/SF), so a given user would upload CSAM on the forum, then report the same CSAM to the hoster. They used to use the same IP address for their entire operation. When the host and the customer compared notes, they'd find about these details.&lt;p&gt;Honestly at the time I thought the story was bunk, in the age of residential proxies and VPNs and whatnot, surely whoever did this wouldn't just upload said CSAM from their own IP, but one possible explanation would be that the forum probably just blocked datacenter IPs wholesale and the person orchestrating the campaign wasn't willing to risk the legal fallout of uploading CSAM out of some regular citizen's infected device.&lt;p&gt;In this case, I assume law enforcement just sets up a website with said CSAM, gets archive.is to crawl it, and then pressurize DNS providers about it.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 15 Nov 2025 12:05:49 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45936869</link><dc:creator>supriyo-biswas</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45936869</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45936869</guid></item><item><title>New comment by atomicfiredoll in "Our investigation into the suspicious pressure on Archive.today"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I don't know anything about Adguard, but good on the team for doing the extra digging instead of just going along with the claim. Even better that they're sharing what they've found with everyone else.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 15 Nov 2025 12:00:26 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45936833</link><dc:creator>atomicfiredoll</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45936833</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45936833</guid></item><item><title>New comment by defanor in "Lawmakers want to ban VPNs"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&gt; It Won’t Even Work&lt;p&gt;I heard similar sentiments about censorship efforts in Russia, but it does seem to work, unfortunately. So far they have outlawed and blocked major VPN providers (and keep blocking more, including non-commercial ones, like Tor bridges, and foreign hosting companies' websites), blocked major detectable protocols used for those (IPsec, WireGuard), made usage of proxying ("VPN") an aggravating circumstance for the newly-introduced crime of searching for "extremist" information. That seems to deter many people already, and once the majority is forced to use the local approved (surveilled, censored) services, it is even easier to introduce whitelists or simply cut international connections (as is already practiced temporarily and locally), at which point the ban is successfully applied to everyone.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 15 Nov 2025 11:20:37 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45936677</link><dc:creator>defanor</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45936677</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45936677</guid></item><item><title>New comment by gsliepen in "TCP, the workhorse of the internet"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;If you start with the problem of how to create a reliable stream of data on top of an unreliable datagram layer, then the solution that comes out will look virtually identical to TCP. It just is the right solution for the job.&lt;p&gt;The three drawbacks of the original TCP algorithm were the window size (the maximum value is just too small for today's speeds), poor handling of missing packets (addressed by extensions such as selective-ACK), and the fact that it only manages one stream at a time, and some applications want multiple streams that don't block each other. You could use multiple TCP connections, but that adds its own overhead, so SCTP and QUIC were designed to address those issues.&lt;p&gt;The congestion control algorithm is not part of the on-the-wire protocol, it's just some code on each side of the connection that decides when to (re)send packets to make the best use of the available bandwidth. Anything that implements a reliable stream on top of datagrams needs to implement such an algorithm. The original ones (Reno, Vegas, etc) were very simple but already did a good job, although back then network equipment didn't have large buffers. A lot of research is going into making better algorithms that handle large buffers, large roundtrip times, varying bandwidth needs and also being fair when multiple connections share the same bandwidth.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 15 Nov 2025 08:50:49 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45936004</link><dc:creator>gsliepen</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45936004</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45936004</guid></item><item><title>New comment by jacquesm in "Unofficial Microsoft Teams client for Linux"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;The official client is absolutely terrible. But, I've found a much better solution: I tell all my customers Microsoft Teams doesn't work for us and they'll have to pick something else.&lt;p&gt;Kudos for at least trying to address this, MS should hang their head in shame, this is not the hardest problem to solve these days. If we could do it in 1995 they should be able to do it 30 years later.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 15 Nov 2025 07:24:45 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45935673</link><dc:creator>jacquesm</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45935673</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45935673</guid></item><item><title>New comment by jdietrich in "AI World Clocks"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Clock drawing is widely used as a test for assessing dementia. Sometimes the LLMs fail in ways that are fairly predictable if you're familiar with CSS and typical shortcomings of LLMs, but sometimes they fail in ways that are less obvious from a technical perspective but are &lt;i&gt;exactly the same&lt;/i&gt; failure modes as cognitively-impaired humans.&lt;p&gt;I think you might have stumbled upon something surprisingly profound.&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.psychdb.com/cognitive-testing/clock-drawing-test" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://www.psychdb.com/cognitive-testing/clock-drawing-test&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 15 Nov 2025 02:20:47 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45934504</link><dc:creator>jdietrich</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45934504</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45934504</guid></item><item><title>New comment by georgehotz in "HipKittens: Fast and furious AMD kernels"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Full disclosure, we have a contract with AMD to get Llama 405B training on MI350X on MLPerf.&lt;p&gt;Things are turning around for AMD. If you have an AMD card, go to pytorch.org, click Linux+ROCm and install PyTorch. 3 years ago, this was hopeless. Today, most mainline things work. I ran nanochat on MI300X and it just worked. I think that's true about MI350X now too. The MI350X machine is stable.&lt;p&gt;They are clearly behind NVIDIA, nobody doubts that. And a lot of investment into software will be required to catch up, ecosystem, compiler, and driver. But 2 years ago they seemed hopeless, now they don't. Things take time. HipKittens is a great codebase to study to see where AMD's LLVM backend is still lacking; compare it to the CUDA Kittens.&lt;p&gt;For training, it's NVIDIA and Google in first. AMD in second. And nobody in third. Intel and Tenstorrent are not remotely close. Huawei examples segfaulted. Groq gave up selling chips. Cerebras isn't available anywhere. Trainium had a 5 day wait time to get one instance and I lost interest.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 15 Nov 2025 01:23:27 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45934212</link><dc:creator>georgehotz</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45934212</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45934212</guid></item><item><title>New comment by Xeoncross in "Go's Sweet 16"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I know they say that your programming language isn't the bottleneck, but I remember sitting there being frustrated as a young dev that I couldn't parse faster in the languages I was using when I learned about Go.&lt;p&gt;It took a few more years before I actually got around to learning it and I have to say I've never picked up a language so quickly. (Which makes sense, it's got the smallest language spec of any of them)&lt;p&gt;I'm sure there are plenty of reasons this is wrong, but it feels like Go gets me 80% of the way to Rust with 20% of the effort.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 23:25:04 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45933368</link><dc:creator>Xeoncross</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45933368</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45933368</guid></item><item><title>New comment by throwup238 in "A new Google model is nearly perfect on automated handwriting recognition"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I really hope they have because I’ve also been experimenting with LLMs to automate searching through old archival handwritten documents. I’m interested in the Conquistadors and their extensive accounts of their expeditions, but holy cow reading 16th century handwritten Spanish and translating it at the same time is a nightmare, requiring a ton of expertise and inside field knowledge. It doesn’t help that they were often written in the field by semi-literate people who misused lots of words. Even the simplest accounts require quite a lot of detective work to decipher with subtle signals like that pound sign for the sugar loaf.&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;&gt; Whatever it is, users have reported some truly wild things: it codes fully functioning Windows and Apple OS clones, 3D design software, Nintendo emulators, and productivity suites from single prompts.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;p&gt;This I’m a lot more skeptical of. The linked twitter post just looks like something it would replicate via HTML/CSS/JS. Whats the kernel look like?&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 22:16:45 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45932816</link><dc:creator>throwup238</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45932816</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45932816</guid></item><item><title>New comment by dwedge in "Being poor vs. being broke"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&gt; its not uncommon to have the few worthwhile items you own being seized by bailifs to recoup debts, treasured heirlooms that cannot be replaced and have little monetary value so they do no impact to your debt. The hoarding of canned goods to avoid being unable to eat.&lt;p&gt;As a teenager I worked at a bailiffs in the office typing up the paperwork. One case that stuck was me was where the debtor owed somewhere around £400. The bailiff took a motorbike (or scooter) that could easily have covered the debt. It was sold at auction for £50. £35 bailiff fees for taking it there and £15 auctioneer fees, £0 off the debt. It was so unfair it should have been criminal.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 20:44:43 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45931955</link><dc:creator>dwedge</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45931955</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45931955</guid></item><item><title>New comment by lanewinfield in "AI World Clocks"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;hi, I made this. thank you for posting.&lt;p&gt;I love clocks and I love finding the edges of what any given technology is capable of.&lt;p&gt;I've watched this for many hours and Kimi frequently gets the most accurate clock but also the least variation and is most boring. Qwen is often times the most insane and makes me laugh. Which one is "better?"&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 19:59:48 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45931463</link><dc:creator>lanewinfield</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45931463</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45931463</guid></item><item><title>New comment by otterley in "AI World Clocks"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Watching this over the past few minutes, it looks like Kimi K2 generates the best clock face most consistently. I'd never heard of that model before today!&lt;p&gt;Qwen 2.5's clocks, on the other hand, look like they never make it out of the womb.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 19:57:08 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45931435</link><dc:creator>otterley</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45931435</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45931435</guid></item><item><title>New comment by pcrh in "The disguised return of EU Chat Control"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;The right to privacy is enshrined in the European Convention on Human Rights, article 8 [0].&lt;p&gt;It escapes me how politicians can repeatedly attempt to violate this.&lt;p&gt;[0] &lt;a href="https://fra.europa.eu/en/law-reference/european-convention-human-rights-article-8-0" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://fra.europa.eu/en/law-reference/european-convention-h...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 19:00:59 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45930546</link><dc:creator>pcrh</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45930546</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45930546</guid></item><item><title>New comment by dijit in "Being poor vs. being broke"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Even this does a poor job of explaining being poor.&lt;p&gt;The constant open loop on everything you own, terrified to discard anything even if its broken because there are components that might be useful to fix something else; the constant churn of second-hand (and cheap/disposable) things that are already close to death before they come into your possession and- crucially: the crushing weight of knowing that any financial roadbump is existential.&lt;p&gt;As the author mentions, a £50 fine might as well be £50,000- its unpayable, and leads to a sort of doom-spiral of lending to avoid worse consequences. Easily you can end up in unmanageable debt, in rare cases prison, its not uncommon to have the few worthwhile items you own being seized by bailifs to recoup debts, treasured heirlooms that cannot be replaced and have little monetary value so they do no impact to your debt. The hoarding of canned goods to avoid being unable to eat.&lt;p&gt;It’s hard to convey this, and what it does to your mentality- I am now built mentally to think quite fiscally conservative and do not take debts or put savings into investments like my peers. I am well off but a fraction of what I could have been had I not has this mentality.&lt;p&gt;You have to live it to understand it, but I wouldn’t wish it on anyone, its a tarpit and getting out of it without someone handing you a branch (and if you no longer have the strength to pull yourself out) then you’ll be stuck in it forever.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 18:06:41 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45929705</link><dc:creator>dijit</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45929705</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45929705</guid></item><item><title>New comment by ChrisMarshallNY in "Being poor vs. being broke"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I like this guy’s backstory[0].&lt;p&gt;I grew up in Africa. The poverty I saw, as a child, was foundational in my own personal development.&lt;p&gt;There are some places in the US, that have that kind of poverty, but I have not seen them, with my own eyes.&lt;p&gt;I have family that dedicated most of their life to fighting poverty (with very limited success). They believe that poverty is probably the single biggest problem in the world, today. Almost every major issue we face, can be traced back to poverty.&lt;p&gt;Income inequality is one thing, but hardcore poverty, as described by the author, is a different beast, and creates a level of desperation that is &lt;i&gt;incredibly&lt;/i&gt; dangerous.&lt;p&gt;[0] &lt;a href="https://blog.ctms.me/about/" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://blog.ctms.me/about/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 17:38:13 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45929284</link><dc:creator>ChrisMarshallNY</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45929284</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45929284</guid></item><item><title>New comment by foofoo12 in "Oracle hit hard in Wall Street's tech sell-off over its AI bet"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Unfair. Oracle excels at some things, like extortion, blackmailing and litigation.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 17:24:49 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45929120</link><dc:creator>foofoo12</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45929120</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45929120</guid></item><item><title>New comment by railka in "I think nobody wants AI in Firefox, Mozilla"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I am a regular Firefox user; it is literally the tool I use most often during my working hours. I like it more than Chrome.&lt;p&gt;Firefox is steadily losing market share, and any attempts to do something about it are met with negativity. The 2-4% of users who use it care about their privacy. But they are not being deprived of it; the AI tab is optional, and no one is removing the regular tab. (Of course, it would be better if they allowed the integration of local models or aggregators, such as Openrouter, Huggingface...)&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile, developers continue to ignore Firefox, testing only Chromium browsers. Large companies are also choosing the Chromium engine for their browsers.&lt;p&gt;Perhaps if they implement this functionality conveniently, more average users will use Firefox.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 15:20:19 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45927629</link><dc:creator>railka</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45927629</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45927629</guid></item><item><title>New comment by notepad0x90 in "I think nobody wants AI in Firefox, Mozilla"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I think "nobody i know" and nobody are different things. Mozilla wants more firefox users. there are "AI browsers" and ai integrated browsing is becoming more and more the norm. Mozilla is doing the right thing here, the features are there but unobtrusive. But down the road, I fully expect Mozilla to do whatever they have to do to remain in the game. Their small market share is hurting the entire internet, they can't afford to become a browser for retro-techo-luddites or something.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 15:05:42 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45927448</link><dc:creator>notepad0x90</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45927448</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45927448</guid></item><item><title>New comment by the__alchemist in "AGI fantasy is a blocker to actual engineering"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I will go meta into what you posted here: That people are classifying themselves as "AI skeptics". Many people are treating this in terms of tribal conflict and identity politics. On HN, we can do better! IMO the move is drop the politics, and discuss things on their technical merits. If we do talk about it as a debate, we can do it when with open minds, and intellectual honesty.&lt;p&gt;I think much of this may be a reaction to the hype promoted by tech CEOs and media outlets. People are seeing through their lies and exaggerations, and taking positions like "AI/LLMs have no values or uses", then using every argument they hear as a reason why it is &lt;i&gt;bad&lt;/i&gt; in a broad sense. For example: Energy and water concerns. That's my best guess about the concern you're braced against.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 15:01:36 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45927408</link><dc:creator>the__alchemist</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45927408</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45927408</guid></item><item><title>New comment by andy99 in "I think nobody wants AI in Firefox, Mozilla"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;The existence of the features doesn’t bother me. It’s the constant nagging about them. I can’t use a google product without being harassed to the point of not being able to work by offers to “help me write” or whatever.&lt;p&gt;Having the feature on a menu somewhere would be fine. The problem is the confluence of new features now becoming possible, and companies no longer building software for their users but as vehicles to push some agenda. Now we’re seeing this in action.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 14:51:44 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45927274</link><dc:creator>andy99</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45927274</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45927274</guid></item><item><title>New comment by lordleft in "AGI fantasy is a blocker to actual engineering"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;The language around AGI is proof, in my mind, that religious impulses don't die with the withering of religion. A desire for a totalizing solution to all woes still endures.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 14:46:38 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45927212</link><dc:creator>lordleft</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45927212</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45927212</guid></item><item><title>New comment by transcriptase in "I think nobody wants AI in Firefox, Mozilla"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Nobody wants anything from Mozilla except Firefox/Thunderbird to be high-performance alternatives to Chrome/Outlook with fewer restrictions on extensions.&lt;p&gt;That’s it. The rest is just activism and kids playing in a sandbox with non-profit money to pad out their resume with whatever topical keywords might land them their next gig.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 14:26:17 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45926961</link><dc:creator>transcriptase</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45926961</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45926961</guid></item><item><title>New comment by IgorPartola in "AGI fantasy is a blocker to actual engineering"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;It is ultimately a hardware problem. To simplify it greatly, an LLM neuron is a single input single output function. A human brain neuron takes in thousands of inputs and produces thousands of outputs, to the point that some inputs start being processed before they even get inside the cell by structures on the outside of it. An LLM neuron is an approximation of this. We cannot manufacture a human level neuron to be small and fast and energy efficient enough with our manufacturing capabilities today. A human brain has something like 80 or 90 billion of them and there are other types of cells that outnumber neurons by I think two orders of magnitude. The entire architecture is massively parallel and has a complex feedback network instead of the LLM’s rigid mostly forward processing. When I say massively parallel I don’t mean a billion tensor units. I mean a quintillion input superpositions.&lt;p&gt;And the final kicker: the human brain runs on like two dozen Watts. An LLM takes a year of running on a few MW to train and several KW to run.&lt;p&gt;Given this I am not certain we will get to AGI by simulating it in a GPU or TPU. We would need a new hardware paradigm.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 14:25:21 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45926946</link><dc:creator>IgorPartola</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45926946</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45926946</guid></item><item><title>New comment by everdrive in "I think nobody wants AI in Firefox, Mozilla"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Does anyone want AI in anything? I can see the value of navigating to an LLM and asking specific questions, but generally speaking I don't want that just running / waiting on my machine as I open a variety of applications. It's a huge waste of resources and for most normal people is an edge case.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 14:23:42 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45926926</link><dc:creator>everdrive</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45926926</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45926926</guid></item><item><title>New comment by simonw in "AGI fantasy is a blocker to actual engineering"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Tip for AI skeptics: skip the data center water usage argument. At this point I think it harms your credibility - numbers like "millions of liters of water annually" (from the linked article) sound scary when presented without context, but if you compare data centers to farmland or even golf courses they're minuscule.&lt;p&gt;Other energy usage figures, air pollution, gas turbines, CO2 emissions etc are fine - but if you complain about water usage I think it risks discrediting the rest of your argument.&lt;p&gt;(Aside from that I agree with most of this piece, the "AGI" thing is a huge distraction.)&lt;p&gt;UPDATE an hour after posting this: I may be making an ass of myself here in that I've been arguing in this thread about comparisons between data center usage and agricultural usage of water, but that comparison doesn't hold as data centers often use potable drinking water that wouldn't be used in agriculture or for many other industrial purposes.&lt;p&gt;I still think the way these numbers are usually presented - as scary large "gallons of water" figures with no additional context to help people understand what that means - is an anti-pattern.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 14:21:42 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45926914</link><dc:creator>simonw</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45926914</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45926914</guid></item><item><title>New comment by cornonthecobra in "Lawmakers want to ban VPNs"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I'm reminded of efforts in the 1990s to ban strong encryption in email and websites because governments tried to tell us it was used by drug dealers and pedos to do their nefarious activities.&lt;p&gt;Yes, governments really did want to force us to use HTTPS with only broken/weak crypto.&lt;p&gt;Same propaganda, different buzzwords.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 14:11:41 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45926826</link><dc:creator>cornonthecobra</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45926826</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45926826</guid></item><item><title>New comment by 0xbadcafebee in "Disrupting the first reported AI-orchestrated cyber espionage campaign"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&gt; At this point they had to convince Claude—which is extensively trained to avoid harmful behaviors—to engage in the attack. They did so by jailbreaking it, effectively tricking it to bypass its guardrails. They broke down their attacks into small, seemingly innocent tasks that Claude would execute without being provided the full context of their malicious purpose. They also told Claude that it was an employee of a legitimate cybersecurity firm, and was being used in defensive testing.&lt;p&gt;Guardrails in AI are like a $2 luggage padlock on a bicycle in the middle of nowhere. Even a moron, given enough time, and a little dedication, will defeat it. And this is not some kind of inferiority of one AI manufacturer over another. It's inherent to LLMs. They are stupid, but they do contain information. You use language to extract information from them, so there will always be a lexicographical way to extract said information (or make them do things).&lt;p&gt;&gt; This raises an important question: if AI models can be misused for cyberattacks at this scale, why continue to develop and release them? The answer is&lt;p&gt;Money.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 07:37:28 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45924744</link><dc:creator>0xbadcafebee</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45924744</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45924744</guid></item><item><title>New comment by alex_young in "Why I'm Learning Sumerian"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;  …Sumerian, written in cuneiform, was humanity's first writing system. A language that hasn't been spoken in four thousand years.
  The same question circles again: Why am I doing this?
  Why am I trying to learn Sumerian, a language that hasn't been spoken for five thousand years?…
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
Watch out reader, by the end it maybe indeed turn out that Sumerian hasn’t been spoken for 10, 20, or 30 thousand years.  The LLM just doesn’t know what sounds better.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 07:04:09 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45924596</link><dc:creator>alex_young</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45924596</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45924596</guid></item><item><title>New comment by 3ln00b in "Kubernetes Ingress Nginx is retiring"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;How do you people even keep up with this? I'm going back to cybersecurity after trying DevOps for a year, it's not for me. I miss my sysadmin days, things were simple back then and worked. Maybe I'm just getting old and my cognitive abilities are declining. It seems to me that the current tech scene doesn't reward simple.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 04:19:24 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45923809</link><dc:creator>3ln00b</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45923809</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45923809</guid></item></channel></rss>