<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>Hacker News: Best Comments</title><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/bestcomments</link><description>Hacker News RSS</description><docs>https://hnrss.org/</docs><generator>hnrss v2.1.1</generator><lastBuildDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 01:20:07 +0000</lastBuildDate><ns0:link href="https://hnrss.org/bestcomments" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item><title>New comment by nine_k in "Has the cost of building software dropped 90%?"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Had the cost of building custom software dropped 90%, we would be seeing a flurry of low-cost, decent-quality SaaS offering all over the marketplace, possibly undercutting some established players.&lt;p&gt;From where I sit, right now, this does not seem to be the case.&lt;p&gt;This is as if writing down the code is not the biggest problem, or the biggest time sink, of building software.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 20:15:59 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46197061</link><dc:creator>nine_k</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46197061</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46197061</guid></item><item><title>New comment by ZeroConcerns in "Microsoft has a problem: lack of demand for its AI products"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Well, the major problem Microsoft is facing is that its AI products are not only &lt;i&gt;shoddier than average&lt;/i&gt;, which is nothing new for them in many categories, but that this time the competition can actually easily leapfrog them.&lt;p&gt;Like, I have a 'Copilot' button prominently displayed in my New Outlook on MacOS (the only platform where the app-with-that-designation is sort-of usable), and it's a dropdown menu, and it has... &lt;i&gt;zero&lt;/i&gt; items when expanded.&lt;p&gt;I asked my 'Microsoft 365 Bing Chat AI Bot Powered By ChatGPT&lt;tm&gt;' about that, and it wasn't able to tell me how to make that button &lt;i&gt;actually do something&lt;/i&gt;, ending the conversation with "yeah, that's sort-of a tease, isn't it?"...&lt;p&gt;Oh, well, and I actually &lt;i&gt;also&lt;/i&gt; have a dedicated Copilot button on my new Lenovo laptop powered-by-Windows-11. And, guess what, it does &lt;i&gt;exactly nothing&lt;/i&gt;! I can elect to either assign this button to 'Search', which opens a WebView2 to bing.com (ehhm, yeah, sure, thanks!) or to 'Custom', in which case it informs me that 'nothing' meets the hardware requirements to actually enable that.&lt;p&gt;So, my question to anyone in the Microsoft C-suite: have you &lt;i&gt;ever&lt;/i&gt; tried to, like, actually &lt;i&gt;use&lt;/i&gt;, like &lt;i&gt;anything&lt;/i&gt; that you're selling? Because if you would have, the failings would have been obvious, right? Right??&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 17:40:26 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46195233</link><dc:creator>ZeroConcerns</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46195233</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46195233</guid></item><item><title>New comment by teeray in "Uber is turning data about trips and takeout into insights for marketers"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;If you have the disposable income to pay to remove advertising, you are exactly the market segment advertisers want to reach. They will always be willing to pay to outbid that segment’s own desire to not see ads.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 15:32:20 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46193402</link><dc:creator>teeray</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46193402</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46193402</guid></item><item><title>New comment by reenorap in "I wasted years of my life in crypto"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I worked at a crypto exchange and after I came to the conclusion that 99% of crypto was scams and rugpulls, I sold all my crypto and vowed to have nothing to do with it. It's more of a religion than a financial instrument and absolutely nothing has shown to me that crypto is anything more than a speculative gamble, basically tulips with the religious promise of a better world. The number of employees that lost money on rugpulls while I was there, but "still believed in crypto" was staggering.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 15:28:15 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46193336</link><dc:creator>reenorap</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46193336</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46193336</guid></item><item><title>New comment by dfxm12 in "Uber is turning data about trips and takeout into insights for marketers"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;So many times on this website, people say, "I will pay for the service to get rid of advertising." You pay for this service and rides aren't getting any cheaper. It is naive to think any company isn't finding ways to monetize your behavior, whether you're paying them or not.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 15:27:33 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46193327</link><dc:creator>dfxm12</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46193327</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46193327</guid></item><item><title>New comment by JSR_FDED in "IBM to acquire Confluent"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;IBM have an absolutely stellar record of blowing acquisitions. The highly motivated newly acquired team will be in honeymoon phase for 3 months, and then it slowly dawns on them that they’ve joined an unbelievably rigid organization where things like customer satisfaction and great products don’t matter at all. Then they’ll be in shock and disbelief at the mind boggling Byzantine rules and internal systems they have to use, whose sole purpose is to make sure nobody does anything. Finally, the core IBM sales force will start to make demands on them and will short to ground any vestiges of energy, time, opportunity and motivation they might have left. The good team members will leave and join a  former business partner, or decide to spend more time with the family. They’ll meet often at the beginning to relive the glory days of pre-acquisition and recount times where they went went above and beyond for that important early customer. But then these meetings will become fewer and fewer. Finally they’ll find a way of massaging their resumes to cast the last years as being “at the heart of AI infrastructure”.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 15:03:05 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46192996</link><dc:creator>JSR_FDED</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46192996</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46192996</guid></item><item><title>New comment by keiferski in "The "confident idiot" problem: Why AI needs hard rules, not vibe checks"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;The thing that bothers me the most about LLMs is how they never seem to understand "the flow" of an actual conversation between humans. When I ask a person something, I expect them to give me a short reply which includes another question/asks for details/clarification. A conversation is thus an ongoing "dance" where the questioner and answerer gradually arrive to the same shared meaning.&lt;p&gt;LLMs don't do this. Instead, every question is immediately responded to with extreme confidence with a paragraph or more of text. I know you can minimize this by configuring the settings on your account, but to me it just highlights how it's not operating in a way remotely similar to the human-human one I mentioned above. I constantly find myself saying, "No, I meant [&lt;i&gt;concept&lt;/i&gt;] in this way, not that way," and then getting annoyed at the robot because it's masquerading as a human.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 13:46:02 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46192154</link><dc:creator>keiferski</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46192154</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46192154</guid></item><item><title>New comment by saagarjha in "GitHub Actions has a package manager, and it might be the worst"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I’d appreciate not being called lazy for mentioning a lack of investment on Microsoft’s side to secure their paid and fairly lucrative service that they bought a popular code hosting platform to integrate with.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 10:07:20 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46190532</link><dc:creator>saagarjha</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46190532</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46190532</guid></item><item><title>New comment by phplovesong in "I wasted years of my life in crypto"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;The original promise of crypto was lost a LONG time ago.&lt;p&gt;Instead of being a true rival to FIAT, it became a thing with a toxic-as-hell commumity, fraud, and basically its nothing more than a high risk stock. The risk is NOT only "will this go up or down" but you have a high risk of being robbed, as have happened to millions of people.&lt;p&gt;Maybe there will be a better alternative in the future, but right now bitcoin is not it.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 10:07:11 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46190528</link><dc:creator>phplovesong</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46190528</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46190528</guid></item><item><title>New comment by cryptonym in "I wasted years of my life in crypto"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;In a casino you have
- The gamblers spending a lot on the casino
- The people coming in for the fun and spending little money
- The owners/C-levels
- The operational team&lt;p&gt;Someone from the operational team just learned that business relies only on the first group to be successful.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 09:44:47 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46190342</link><dc:creator>cryptonym</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46190342</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46190342</guid></item><item><title>New comment by saagarjha in "GitHub Actions has a package manager, and it might be the worst"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;What’s more, GitHub has basically stopped maintaining their own actions, pushing people to sketchy forks to do basic things. Their entire ecosystem is basically held up with duct tape and gets very little investment.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 09:08:17 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46190071</link><dc:creator>saagarjha</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46190071</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46190071</guid></item><item><title>New comment by jefftk in "Dollar-stores overcharge customers while promising low prices"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;&gt; Red Baron frozen pizzas, listed on the shelf at $5, rang up at $7.65. Bounty paper towels, shelf price $10.99, rang up at $15.50.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;p&gt;This very rarely happens in MA, because when it does the store has to give you the item for $10 off, including if that makes it free. And they have to post a sign at the register explaining the law, which means when you're invoking it all you need to do is point at the sign.&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.mass.gov/info-details/consumer-pricing-accuracy-information" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://www.mass.gov/info-details/consumer-pricing-accuracy-...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 01:04:10 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46187156</link><dc:creator>jefftk</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46187156</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46187156</guid></item><item><title>New comment by wilsmex in "I failed to recreate the 1996 Space Jam website with Claude"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Well this was interesting.  As someone who was actually building similar website in the late 90's I threw this into the Opus 4.5.  Note the original author is wrong about the original site however:&lt;p&gt;"The Space Jam website is simple: a single HTML page, absolute positioning for every element, and a tiling starfield GIF background.".&lt;p&gt;This is not true, the site is built using tables, not positioning at all, CSS wasn't a thing back then...&lt;p&gt;Here was its one-shot attempt at building the same type of layout (table based) with a screenshot and assets as input:  &lt;a href="https://i.imgur.com/fhdOLwP.png" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://i.imgur.com/fhdOLwP.png&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 07 Dec 2025 23:02:10 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46186253</link><dc:creator>wilsmex</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46186253</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46186253</guid></item><item><title>New comment by regera in "Dollar-stores overcharge customers while promising low prices"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Dollar stores are private equity with a checkout lane.&lt;p&gt;In 2025, Dollar Tree sold Family Dollar to a group of private-equity firms: Brigade Capital Management, Macellum Capital Management and Arkhouse Management Co.&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://corporate.dollartree.com/news-media/press-releases/detail/288/dollar-tree-completes-sale-of-family-dollar-business-to" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://corporate.dollartree.com/news-media/press-releases/d...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;It’s a business model cosplaying as poverty relief while quietly siphoning money from the people least able to lose it. They already run on a thin-staff, high-volume model. That 23% increase is not a glitch. They know their customers can’t drive across town to complain. They know the regulators won’t scale fines to revenue.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 07 Dec 2025 21:07:31 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46185157</link><dc:creator>regera</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46185157</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46185157</guid></item><item><title>New comment by Palmik in "Google Titans architecture, helping AI have long-term memory"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;DeepSeek and other Chinese companies. Not only do they publish research, they also put their resources where their mouth (research) is. They actually use it and prove it through their open models.&lt;p&gt;Most research coming out of big US labs is counter indicative of practical performance. If it worked (too) well in practice, it wouldn't have been published.&lt;p&gt;Some examples from DeepSeek:&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2405.04434" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://arxiv.org/abs/2405.04434&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2502.11089" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://arxiv.org/abs/2502.11089&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 07 Dec 2025 20:33:09 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46184875</link><dc:creator>Palmik</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46184875</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46184875</guid></item><item><title>New comment by yen223 in "Estimates are difficult for developers and product owners"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;The unique thing about estimates in software engineering is that if you do it right, projects should be impossible to estimate!&lt;p&gt;Tasks that are easiest to estimate are tasks that are predictable, and repetitive. If I ask you how long it'll take to add a new database field, and you've added a new database field 100s of times in the past and each time they take 1 day, your estimate for it is going to be very spot-on.&lt;p&gt;But in the software world, predictable and repetitive tasks are also the kinds of tasks that are most easily automated, which means the time it takes to perform those tasks should asymptotically approach 0.&lt;p&gt;But if the predictable tasks take 0 time, how long a project takes will be dominated by the novel, unpredictable parts.&lt;p&gt;That's why software estimates are very hard to do.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 07 Dec 2025 20:01:34 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46184611</link><dc:creator>yen223</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46184611</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46184611</guid></item><item><title>New comment by game_the0ry in "Scala 3 slowed us down?"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I am not a scala fan and do not care for it, but I upvote for the thorough thought process, breakdown, and debugging of the problem. This is how technical blogs should be written. AI aint got shit on this.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 07 Dec 2025 16:38:46 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46182978</link><dc:creator>game_the0ry</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46182978</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46182978</guid></item><item><title>New comment by libraryofbabel in "The programmers who live in Flatland"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Or perhaps, just perhaps, the true higher-dimensional move is realizing that choice of programming language isn’t usually the critical factor in whether a project, system, or business succeeds or fails, and that obsessing over the One True Way is a trap.&lt;p&gt;It might surprise the author to learn that there are many people who:&lt;p&gt;1) Have tried lisp and clojure&lt;p&gt;2) Liked their elegance and expressiveness&lt;p&gt;3) Have read through SICP and done most of the exercises&lt;p&gt;4) Would still choose plain old boring easy-to-read always-second-best Python for 90% of use-cases (and probably Rust for the last 10%) when building a real business in the real world.&lt;p&gt;The article could really benefit from some steel-manning. Remove the cute Flatland metaphor and it is effectively arguing that lisp/clojure haven’t been universally adopted because most programmers haven’t Seen The Light in some sort of epiphany of parentheses and macros. The truth is more nuanced.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 07 Dec 2025 16:34:04 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46182942</link><dc:creator>libraryofbabel</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46182942</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46182942</guid></item><item><title>New comment by CapitalistCartr in "Over fifty new hallucinations in ICLR 2026 submissions"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I'm an industrial electrician. A lot of poor electrical work is visible only to a fellow electrician, and sometimes only another industrial electrician. Bad technical work requires technical inspectors to criticize. Sometimes highly skilled ones.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 07 Dec 2025 15:29:18 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46182385</link><dc:creator>CapitalistCartr</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46182385</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46182385</guid></item><item><title>New comment by hanshenning in "The state of Schleswig-Holstein is consistently relying on open source"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;You're not wrong, but this is actually what they're pursuing; the article just leaves it out.&lt;p&gt;&gt; The goal is not only to save costs, but above all to gain digital sovereignty.&lt;p&gt;&gt; [It's true] that open source is not necessarily cheaper, [..] it requires investment. But the money flows into internal infrastructure, into the further development of Nextcloud, LibreOffice, and other similar systems, instead of proprietary ones.&lt;p&gt;&gt; Schleswig-Holstein pursues an "upstream-only strategy," meaning that developments flow directly back into international projects. The state does not want to maintain its own forks, but rather contribute all improvements directly to the main projects, thereby contributing to development for the benefit of the general public.[1]&lt;p&gt;On a side note, the real key to the project's success is that it's supported by a coalition of the conservative and green parties. They actually value digital sovereignty and longterm cost savings. Contrast that with Bavaria, where the MS lobbyist managed to get them to sign a longterm Office 365 contract…&lt;p&gt;[1]&lt;a href="https://www-heise-de.translate.goog/hintergrund/Interview-Wie-die-OSS-Umstellung-in-Schleswig-Holstein-laeuft-10629991.html?_x_tr_sl=de&amp;_x_tr_tl=en&amp;_x_tr_pto=wapp" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://www-heise-de.translate.goog/hintergrund/Interview-Wi...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 07 Dec 2025 15:28:18 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46182376</link><dc:creator>hanshenning</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46182376</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46182376</guid></item><item><title>New comment by theoldgreybeard in "Over fifty new hallucinations in ICLR 2026 submissions"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;If a carpenter builds a crappy shelf “because” his power tools are not calibrated correctly - that’s a crappy carpenter, not a crappy tool.&lt;p&gt;If a scientist uses an LLM to write a paper with fabricated citations - that’s a crappy scientist.&lt;p&gt;AI is not the problem, laziness and negligence is.  There needs to be serious social consequences to this kind of thing, otherwise we are tacitly endorsing it.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 07 Dec 2025 15:09:30 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46182214</link><dc:creator>theoldgreybeard</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46182214</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46182214</guid></item><item><title>New comment by input_sh in "The state of Schleswig-Holstein is consistently relying on open source"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I &lt;i&gt;hate&lt;/i&gt; when switches like these get advertised first and foremost as some huge cost-cutting measure, further solidifying open source ecosystem as some cheap knock-offs of their commercial alternatives.&lt;p&gt;How about instead you donate the same amount of money you would've paid to Microsoft anyways to fund open source projects you rely on? At least for one year, then drop it down to some arbitrary chosen percentage of that cost. That way you can still advertise it as a cost-cutting measure, and everyone would benefit.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 07 Dec 2025 14:30:11 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46181911</link><dc:creator>input_sh</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46181911</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46181911</guid></item><item><title>New comment by okdood64 in "Google Titans architecture, helping AI have long-term memory"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;From the blog:&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.00663" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.00663&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://arxiv.org/pdf/2504.13173" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://arxiv.org/pdf/2504.13173&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;Is there any other company that's openly publishing their research on AI at this level? Google should get a lot of credit for this.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 07 Dec 2025 14:05:36 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46181759</link><dc:creator>okdood64</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46181759</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46181759</guid></item><item><title>New comment by fsh in "I wasted years of my life in crypto"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;It's an ingenious solution to achieve a "trustless" currency that prevents double-spending without a central authority. Unfortunately, this solves the wrong problem. Spending money usually involves getting a good or service in return, which inherently requires "trust" (as does any human interaction). Your fancy blockchain is not going to help you if you order something with Bitcoin and no package arrives.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 07 Dec 2025 13:55:49 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46181710</link><dc:creator>fsh</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46181710</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46181710</guid></item><item><title>New comment by GnarfGnarf in "The state of Schleswig-Holstein is consistently relying on open source"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I'm a Windows/macOS developer, but I strongly feel that all national governments need to convert to Linux, for strategic sovereignty. I'm sure Microsoft, under orders from the U.S. government, could disable all computers in any country or organization, at the flick of a switch.&lt;p&gt;Imagine how Open Source Software could improve if a consortium of nations put their money and resources into commissioning bug fixes and enhancements, which would be of collective benefit.&lt;p&gt;Apart from a few niche cases, the needs of most government bureaucracies would be well served by currently available OSS word processing, spreadsheet, presentation and graphics software.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 07 Dec 2025 13:48:31 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46181666</link><dc:creator>GnarfGnarf</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46181666</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46181666</guid></item><item><title>New comment by spicyusername in "I wasted years of my life in crypto"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I've never understood the initial arguments about Bitcoin, no matter how many times they've been explained to me.&lt;p&gt;The block chain is, and always was, an extremely inconvenient database. How anyone, especially many intelligent people, thought it was realistic to graft a currency on top of such a unwieldy piece of technology is beyond me. Maybe it goes to show how few people understand economics and anthropology and how dunning-krueger can happen to anyone.&lt;p&gt;Now the uninformed gambling on futuristic sounding hokum? THAT is easy to understand.&lt;p&gt;That being said, I'm sorry the author had to go through this experience, the road of life is often filled with unexpected twists and turns.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 07 Dec 2025 13:28:32 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46181533</link><dc:creator>spicyusername</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46181533</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46181533</guid></item><item><title>New comment by PeterHolzwarth in "The past was not that cute"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;"A woman's work is never done."&lt;p&gt;In our agrarian past, the cultural division of labor at the time said that men worked the field, women ran the home. And that later job was brutal, never-ending, and consumed &lt;i&gt;all&lt;/i&gt; waking hours until the day she died.&lt;p&gt;Men broke their backs in the field, women consumed their lives doing the ceaseless work that never ended, every waking moment. (And occasionally helped out in the field, too).&lt;p&gt;Running a family was a brutal two-person job -- and the kids had to dive in to help out the second they could lift something heavier than a couple pounds.&lt;p&gt;We forget so easily that for the entire history of our species - up until just recently - simply staying alive and somewhat warm and minimally fed was a hundred-hour-a-week job for mom and dad.&lt;p&gt;There are important downsides, but the Green Revolution - and dare I say it, the industrial revolution - was truly transformative for our species.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 07 Dec 2025 04:48:26 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46179223</link><dc:creator>PeterHolzwarth</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46179223</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46179223</guid></item><item><title>New comment by jasongill in "Screenshots from developers: 2002 vs. 2015 (2015)"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I met RMS at the Atlanta Linux Showcase in 1998. In the area with vendor booths in the lobby area of the show, he had laid down a blanket and was sitting in the middle with his legs crossed. He had printed copies of man pages printed and stapled together with covers laid out in front of him.&lt;p&gt;I walked up and introduced myself and said that I was a big fan, appreciated his hard work, etc. He looked at me coldly and just said "so are you going to buy something?" and motioned toward the booklets. I didn't need a printed copy of the `sed` man page so I shrugged and he seemed quite annoyed, turned to his assistant with a notebook computer and started dictating something to them, as almost to make it clear that our interaction was over.&lt;p&gt;I'm not sure what the point of posting this is, but that's my RMS story - it was my first "never meet your heroes" moment, I guess.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 07 Dec 2025 03:33:35 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46178925</link><dc:creator>jasongill</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46178925</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46178925</guid></item><item><title>New comment by thundergolfer in "Using LLMs at Oxide"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;A measured, comprehensive, and sensible take. Not surprising from Bryan. This was a nice line:&lt;p&gt;&gt;  it’s just embarrassing — it’s as if the writer is walking around with their intellectual fly open.&lt;p&gt;I think Oxide didn't include this in the RFD because they exclusively hire senior engineers, but in an organization that contains junior engineers I'd add something specific to help junior engineers understand how they should approach LLM use.&lt;p&gt;Bryan has 30+ years of challenging software (and now hardware) engineering experience. He memorably said that he's worked on and completed a "hard program" (an OS), which he defines as a program you doubt you can actually get working.&lt;p&gt;The way Bryan approaches an LLM is super different to how a 2025 junior engineer does so. That junior engineer possibly hasn't programmed without the tantalizing, even desperately tempting option to be assisted by an LLM.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 07 Dec 2025 01:46:39 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46178458</link><dc:creator>thundergolfer</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46178458</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46178458</guid></item><item><title>New comment by tyushk in "Trains cancelled over fake bridge collapse image"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&gt; A BBC journalist ran the image through an AI chatbot which identified key spots that may have been manipulated.&lt;p&gt;The image is likely AI generated in this case, but this does not seem like the best strategy for finding out if an image is AI generated.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 07 Dec 2025 00:56:25 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46178228</link><dc:creator>tyushk</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46178228</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46178228</guid></item></channel></rss>