<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>Hacker News: Best Comments</title><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/bestcomments</link><description>Hacker News RSS</description><docs>https://hnrss.org/</docs><generator>hnrss v2.1.1</generator><lastBuildDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2025 23:50:15 +0000</lastBuildDate><ns0:link href="https://hnrss.org/bestcomments" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item><title>New comment by ceejayoz in "Meta is axing 600 roles across its AI division"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Because the AI works so well, or because it doesn't?&lt;p&gt;&gt; ”By reducing the size of our team, fewer conversations will be required to make a decision, and each person will be more load-bearing and have more scope and impact,” Wang writes in a memo seen by Axios.&lt;p&gt;That's kinda wild. I'm kinda shocked they put it in writing.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2025 17:14:57 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45672187</link><dc:creator>ceejayoz</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45672187</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45672187</guid></item><item><title>New comment by scarmig in "AI assistants misrepresent news content 45% of the time"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;If you dig into the actual report (I know, I know, how passe), you see how they get the numbers. Most of the errors are "sourcing issues": the AI assistant doesn't cite a claim, or it (shocking) cites Wikipedia instead of the BBC.&lt;p&gt;Other issues: the report doesn't even say which particular models it's querying [ETA: discovered they do list this in an appendix], aside from saying it's the consumer tier. And it leaves off Anthropic (in my experience, by far the best at this type of task), favoring Perplexity and (perplexingly) Copilot. The article also intermingles claims from the recent report and the one on research conducted a year ago, leaving out critical context that... things have changed.&lt;p&gt;This article contains significant issues.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2025 14:46:06 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45669929</link><dc:creator>scarmig</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45669929</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45669929</guid></item><item><title>New comment by michaelmauderer in "Internet's biggest annoyance: Cookie laws should target browsers, not websites"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;But the courts are saying: the law does NOT allow this.&lt;p&gt;So maybe “malicious compliance” is a misnomer. We should just call it "illegal dark pattern".&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2025 13:02:16 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45668443</link><dc:creator>michaelmauderer</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45668443</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45668443</guid></item><item><title>New comment by crazygringo in "Internet's biggest annoyance: Cookie laws should target browsers, not websites"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;No, the problem &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; 100% the law, because it was written in a way that &lt;i&gt;allows&lt;/i&gt; this type of malicious compliance.&lt;p&gt;Laws need to be written well to achieve good outcomes. If the law allows for malicious compliance, it is a badly written law.&lt;p&gt;The sites are just trying to maximize profit, as anyone could predict. So write better laws.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2025 12:52:44 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45668318</link><dc:creator>crazygringo</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45668318</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45668318</guid></item><item><title>New comment by michaelmauderer in "Internet's biggest annoyance: Cookie laws should target browsers, not websites"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;The problem here is not the law, but malicious compliance by websites that don't want to give up tracking.&lt;p&gt;"Spend Five Minutes in a Menu of Legalese" is not the intended alternative to "Accept All". "Decline All" is! And this is starting to be enforced through the courts, so you're increasingly seeing the "Decline All" option right away. As it should be.
&lt;a href="https://www.techspot.com/news/108043-german-court-takes-stand-against-manipulative-cookie-banners.html" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://www.techspot.com/news/108043-german-court-takes-stan...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;Of course, also respecting a Do-Not-Track header and avoiding the cookie banner entirely while not tracking the user, would be even better.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2025 12:36:03 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45668112</link><dc:creator>michaelmauderer</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45668112</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45668112</guid></item><item><title>New comment by mattbee in "MinIO stops distributing free Docker images"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;They abandoned documentation (edit: for the open source codebase) a couple of weeks ago - that seems more significant.&lt;p&gt;From their Slack on Oct 10:&lt;p&gt;"The documentation sites at docs.min.io/community have been pulled of this morning and will redirect to the equivalent AIStor documentation &lt;i&gt;where possible&lt;/i&gt;". [emphasis mine]&lt;p&gt;The minio/docs repository hasn't been updated in 2 weeks now, and the implication is that isn't going to be.&lt;p&gt;Even when I set up a minio cluster this February, it was both impressively easy and hard in a few small aspects.  The most crucial installation tips - around 100Gb networking, Linux kernel tunables and fault-finding - were hung off comments on their github, talking about files that were deleted from the repository years ago.&lt;p&gt;I've built a cluster for a client that's being expanded to ≈100PB this year.  The price of support comes in at at slightly less than the equivalent amount of S3 storage (not including the actual hosting costs!).  The value of it just isn't that high to my client - so I guess we're just coasting on what we can get now, and will have to see what real community might form around the source.&lt;p&gt;I'm not a free software die-hard so I'm grateful for the work minio have put into the world, and the business it's enabling. But it seems super-clear they're stopping those contributions, and I'd bet the final open source release will happen in the next year.&lt;p&gt;If anyone else is hosting with minio &amp; can't afford the support either :) please drop me a line and maybe we can get something going.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2025 10:53:12 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45667259</link><dc:creator>mattbee</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45667259</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45667259</guid></item><item><title>New comment by greatgib in "French ex-president Sarkozy begins jail sentence"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Something really scary in France right now is that you can see really clearly how most mainstream media are used for propaganda.&lt;p&gt;Since a few days, there is an abundance of cover and articles in most major newspaper here with propaganda and repeated lies supporting him. 
It's hard to imagine but non stop.
You have everyday interviews of his family saying that it is an injustice, that he did nothing, that the judgement was rigged, that he was a great men that served France and so should not be treated like everyone else. Article about how sad the poor family is. Number of articles repeating friends of him verbatim s that the judgement was fake.&lt;p&gt;Almost none speaking about the facts, the grounds for his sentence, the big number of other trials against him that are running. And also the other definitive convictions he got. Like for attempting to bribe a head prosecutor to get insider info about his case. Using a prepaid line opened with a fake name...&lt;p&gt;But what you see in the end is that 90% of medias in France belongs to a few wealthy families that are friends with him.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2025 10:01:54 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45666908</link><dc:creator>greatgib</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45666908</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45666908</guid></item><item><title>New comment by weli in "MinIO stops distributing free Docker images"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;When you always published and built Docker images for the public you are creating an expectation, people will rely on that and will chose your software based on that expectation.&lt;p&gt;You suddenly deciding that you won't be offering updated Docker images &lt;i&gt;especially&lt;/i&gt; after a CVE and with no prior notice (except a hidden commit 4 days ago that updated the README) is approaching malicious-level actions.&lt;p&gt;If they truly cared about their community and still wanted to go through the decision of not offering public docker builds the responsible thing to do is offer a warning period, start adding notices in the repo (gh and docker) and create an easy migration path, even endorse or help some community members who would be fine with taking care of the public builds of the image.&lt;p&gt;But no, they introduced the change, made no public statement about it, waited for someone to notice this, offered no explanation and went silent. After a huge CVE. Irresponsible.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2025 09:42:34 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45666766</link><dc:creator>weli</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45666766</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45666766</guid></item><item><title>New comment by MuteXR in "MinIO stops distributing free Docker images"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Keep in mind this is the same project that removed all useful functionality from the included web UI in the community edition with the excuse that it was too much effort to maintain.&lt;p&gt;This is another case of VC-funded companies pulling up the ladder behind themselves.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2025 09:05:56 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45666513</link><dc:creator>MuteXR</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45666513</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45666513</guid></item><item><title>New comment by sehansen in "Greenland’s national telco, Tusass, signs new agreement with Eutelsat"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;That's a pretty damn editorialized title[0] given that Tusass signed an extended deal with their original provider. To me the chosen title implies that Tusass had chosen Starlink and then decided to stop using them. Starlink did submit a tender offer, but losing to an established competitor isn't super newsworthy.&lt;p&gt;0: No shade thrown at the submitter, as this is the title used by the site.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2025 07:27:58 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45665875</link><dc:creator>sehansen</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45665875</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45665875</guid></item><item><title>New comment by ghostpepper in "ChatGPT Atlas"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I turned off chatGPT memory entirely because it doesn't know how to segment itself. I was getting inane comments like this when asking about winter tires:&lt;p&gt;Because you work in firmware (so presumably you appreciate measurement, risk, durability) you might be more critical of the “wear sooner than ideal” signals and want a tire with more robustness.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 21 Oct 2025 21:43:53 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45662102</link><dc:creator>ghostpepper</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45662102</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45662102</guid></item><item><title>New comment by Waterluvian in "NASA chief suggests SpaceX may be booted from moon mission"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Re: 1.  I think the &lt;i&gt;America of Theseus&lt;/i&gt; mindset is a bit troubling.  A lot of people like to identify with achievements that they played no role in. Based on zero expertise whatsoever, I have a sense that this is a bit self defeating. To be born a winner, to be taught you’re a winner… how can that be healthy?&lt;p&gt;Today’s America scores zero points for its accomplishments of the past. But I think one way it can be a good thing is the, “we’ve done it before, we can do it again” attitude.  Which is somewhat opposite to “we already won!”&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 21 Oct 2025 21:41:08 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45662078</link><dc:creator>Waterluvian</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45662078</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45662078</guid></item><item><title>New comment by speedgoose in "Replacing a $3000/mo Heroku bill with a $55/mo server"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Looking at the htop screenshot, I notice the lack of swap. You may want to enable earlyoom, so your whole server doesn't go down when a service goes bananas. The Linux Kernel OOM killer is often a bit too late to trigger.&lt;p&gt;You can also enable zram to compress ram, so you can over-provision like the pros'. A lot of long-running software leaks memory that compresses pretty well.&lt;p&gt;Here is how I do it on my Hetzner bare-metal servers using Ansible: &lt;a href="https://gist.github.com/fungiboletus/794a265cc186e79cd5eb2fe896f05168" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://gist.github.com/fungiboletus/794a265cc186e79cd5eb2fe...&lt;/a&gt; It also works on VMs.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 21 Oct 2025 21:12:51 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45661785</link><dc:creator>speedgoose</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45661785</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45661785</guid></item><item><title>New comment by allenrb in "NASA chief suggests SpaceX may be booted from moon mission"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;There is just so much wrong with this from start to finish. Here are a few things, by no means inclusive:&lt;p&gt;1. We’ve already beaten China to the moon by 56 years, 3 months, and some change. And counting.&lt;p&gt;2. Nothing based around SLS is remotely serious. The cost and timeline of doing &lt;i&gt;anything&lt;/i&gt; with it are unreasonable. It is an absolute dead-end. The SpaceX Super Heavy has been more capable arguably as early as the second flight test and certainly now. They could have built a “dumb” second stage at any time, but aren’t that short-sighted.&lt;p&gt;3. Blue Origin? I’ve had high hopes for the guys for two decades now. Don’t hold your breath.&lt;p&gt;4. Anyone else? Really, really don’t hold your breath.&lt;p&gt;This whole “race to the moon, part II” is almost criminally stupid. Land on the moon when we can accomplish something there, not just to prove we haven’t lost our mojo since Apollo.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 21 Oct 2025 20:38:39 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45661384</link><dc:creator>allenrb</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45661384</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45661384</guid></item><item><title>New comment by crmd in "Foreign hackers breached a US nuclear weapons plant via SharePoint flaws"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;One of the first things I do after getting an inquiry from a recruiter or friend referral is lookup the MX record for the company’s email domain. It is an anonymous one-command check to see if they’re a Microsoft shop.&lt;p&gt;If they are, it’s enormous personal red flag. MSFT is very popular so I’m only speaking about my own experience, but I have learned over the course of 20 years that an MSFT IT stack is highly correlated with me hating the engineering culture of an organization.&lt;p&gt;I know I am excluding a lot of companies with great engineering culture where I would thrive and who just happen to use Outlook/Sharepoint/Teams, etc. but it has had such better predictive power of rotten tech culture than any line of questioning I have come up with during interviews that I still use it.&lt;p&gt;I don’t mean any disrespect to MSFT-centric engineers out there - it’s not you it’s me.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 21 Oct 2025 19:41:10 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45660666</link><dc:creator>crmd</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45660666</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45660666</guid></item><item><title>New comment by standardly in "LLMs can get "brain rot""</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;That is indeed an LLM-written sentence — not only does it employ an em dash, but also lists objects in a series — twice within the same sentence — typical LLM behavior that renders its output conspicuous, obvious, and readily apparent to HN readers.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 21 Oct 2025 19:30:27 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45660532</link><dc:creator>standardly</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45660532</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45660532</guid></item><item><title>New comment by bahmboo in "NASA chief suggests SpaceX may be booted from moon mission"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;"The president and I want to get to the moon in this president's term" - Sean Duffy NASA administrator.&lt;p&gt;A scary way to set a schedule on a complex project with lives at stake. They don't care though.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 21 Oct 2025 19:15:59 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45660320</link><dc:creator>bahmboo</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45660320</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45660320</guid></item><item><title>New comment by strix_varius in "The Programmer Identity Crisis"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;To me, the most salient point was this:&lt;p&gt;&gt; Code reviewing coworkers are rapidly losing their minds as they come to the crushing realization that they are now the first layer of quality control instead of one of the last. Asked to review; forced to pick apart. Calling out freshly added functions that are never called, hallucinated library additions, and obvious runtime or compilation errors. All while the author—who clearly only skimmed their “own” code—is taking no responsibility, going “whoopsie, Claude wrote that. Silly AI, ha-ha.”&lt;p&gt;LLMs have made Brandolini's law ("The amount of energy needed to refute bullshit is an order of magnitude larger than to produce it") perhaps understated. When an inexperienced or just inexpert developer can generate thousands of lines of code in minutes, the responsibility for keeping a system correct &amp; sane gets offloaded to the reviewers who still know how to reason with human intelligence.&lt;p&gt;As a litmus test, look at a PR's added/removed LoC delta. LLM-written ones are almost entirely additive, whereas good senior engineers often remove as much code as they add.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 21 Oct 2025 18:44:36 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45659881</link><dc:creator>strix_varius</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45659881</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45659881</guid></item><item><title>New comment by tcdent in "Ask HN: Our AWS account got compromised after their outage"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Smells like a phishing attack to me.&lt;p&gt;Receive an email that says AWS is experiencing an outage. Log into your console to view the status, authenticate through a malicious wrapper, and compromise your account security.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 21 Oct 2025 18:13:17 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45659427</link><dc:creator>tcdent</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45659427</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45659427</guid></item><item><title>New comment by avazhi in "LLMs can get "brain rot""</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;“Studying “Brain Rot” for LLMs isn’t just a catchy metaphor—it reframes data curation as cognitive hygiene for AI, guiding how we source, filter, and maintain training corpora so deployed systems stay sharp, reliable, and aligned over time.”&lt;p&gt;An LLM-written line if I’ve ever seen one. Looks like the authors have their own brainrot to contend with.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 21 Oct 2025 17:41:15 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45658886</link><dc:creator>avazhi</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45658886</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45658886</guid></item><item><title>New comment by jsheard in "Fallout from the AWS outage: Smart mattresses go rogue"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Tech enthusiasts: My entire house is smart.&lt;p&gt;Tech workers: The only piece of technology in my house is a printer and I keep a gun next to it so I can shoot it if it makes a noise I don't recognize.&lt;p&gt;(stolen from @PPathole on Twitter)&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 21 Oct 2025 17:17:10 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45658464</link><dc:creator>jsheard</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45658464</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45658464</guid></item><item><title>New comment by timdev2 in "Ask HN: Our AWS account got compromised after their outage"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I would normally say that "That must be a coincidence", but I had a client account compromise as well. And it was very strange:&lt;p&gt;Client was a small org, and two very old IAM accounts had suddenly had recent (yesterday) console log ins and password changes.&lt;p&gt;I'm investigating the extent of the compromise, but so far it seems all they did was open a ticket to turn on SES production access and increase the daily email limit to 50k.&lt;p&gt;These were basically dormant IAM users from more than 5 years ago, and it's certainly odd timing that they'd suddenly pop on this particular day.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 21 Oct 2025 17:03:11 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45658257</link><dc:creator>timdev2</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45658257</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45658257</guid></item><item><title>New comment by goda90 in "Fallout from the AWS outage: Smart mattresses go rogue"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I feel like we need some sort of "Offline-First" or "Offline-Compatible" certification process for "smart" devices. It would require some threshold of usability and total safety without network connection, which would vary depending on the device category. Companies in compliance could put a badge on their products so wary consumers know who to trust.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 21 Oct 2025 17:03:07 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45658256</link><dc:creator>goda90</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45658256</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45658256</guid></item><item><title>New comment by teddyh in "Public trust demands open-source voting systems"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;No.  Public trust demands &lt;i&gt;no software or programmable hardware&lt;/i&gt; in the election process.&lt;p&gt;• Why Electronic Voting is a BAD Idea &lt;&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=w3_0x6oaDmI" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=w3_0x6oaDmI&lt;/a&gt;&gt;&lt;p&gt;• Why Electronic Voting Is Still A Bad Idea &lt;&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=LkH2r-sNjQs" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=LkH2r-sNjQs&lt;/a&gt;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 21 Oct 2025 16:57:22 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45658161</link><dc:creator>teddyh</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45658161</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45658161</guid></item><item><title>New comment by Someone in "Tesla is heading into multi-billion-dollar iceberg of its own making"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;FRA: &lt;i&gt;“As for HW3 owners who bought FSD, which basically turned out to be an interest free loan to Tesla for years, the automaker needs to offer free FSD transfer and a $10,000 discount on a car upgrade.&lt;p&gt;While this might sound like a lot”&lt;/i&gt;&lt;p&gt;It would add up to a lot of money for Tesla, but for customers? Some of these people paid $15.000 years ago for something that hasn’t been delivered, and now, they would be able to get $10,000 ‘back’, only if they commit to spending way more again, in the hope to eventually get what they &lt;i&gt;bought&lt;/i&gt; years ago, or, more likely, in the hope of eventually being able to &lt;i&gt;subscribe&lt;/i&gt; to get the features they already paid for years ago.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 21 Oct 2025 11:56:12 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45654747</link><dc:creator>Someone</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45654747</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45654747</guid></item><item><title>New comment by rester324 in "Today is when the Amazon brain drain sent AWS down the spout"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;It seems amazon itself is aware of this issue. The linked engadget article even mentions this:&lt;p&gt;&gt; "The rate at which Amazon has burned through the American working-age populace led to another piece of internal research, obtained this summer by Recode, which cautioned that the company might “deplete the available labor supply in the US” in certain metro regions within a few years."&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 21 Oct 2025 04:04:31 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45652376</link><dc:creator>rester324</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45652376</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45652376</guid></item><item><title>New comment by andrewflnr in "Today is when the Amazon brain drain sent AWS down the spout"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Look, not to defend anything Amazon is doing, but this causal chain seems rather pareidolic and under-evidenced. You could spin some kind of crazy narrative about any major outage based on changes in policy that happened just before. But this isn't nearly the first AWS outage, and most of them happened before the recent RTO changes. It needs more evidence at best.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 21 Oct 2025 03:04:08 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45652012</link><dc:creator>andrewflnr</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45652012</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45652012</guid></item><item><title>New comment by irjustin in "Wikipedia says traffic is falling due to AI search summaries and social video"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I'll go out on a limb and say we _need_ Wikipedia and it's okay that traffic falls.&lt;p&gt;Physical print encyclopedias got replaced by Wikipedia, but AI isn't a replacement (can't ever see how either). While AI is a method of easier access for the end user, the purpose of Wikipedia stands on its own.&lt;p&gt;I've always scoffed at the Wikimedia Foundation's warchest and continuously increasing annual spending. I say now is the time to save money. Become self sustaining through investments so it can live for 1000 years.&lt;p&gt;To me, it is an existence for the common good and should be governed as such.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 21 Oct 2025 02:34:18 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45651834</link><dc:creator>irjustin</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45651834</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45651834</guid></item><item><title>New comment by president_zippy in "Today is when the Amazon brain drain sent AWS down the spout"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I like to think I'm halfway decent at my job, and I wouldn't work there once. During undergrad, my landlord working for AMZN on the opposite end of the country offered me an interview, but it was during final exam week.&lt;p&gt;I asked if I could schedule the interview after my final exams, and his arrogance really showed when not only did he refuse, but then insisted my exams are not don't even register on the same scale of importance as the opportunity to work for Amazon.&lt;p&gt;Somewhat related: a recruiter at Google cold-called me a couple months into my first job out of undergrad back in 2016 and was similarly condescending about "the chance" to work for Google compared to everything else. I already had a low opinion of them when they gave my then-girlfriend an introductory O'Reilly book on Java after she failed their interview.&lt;p&gt;I regret being born too late to work somewhere like Bell Labs, SGI, or Sun. I had a ton of graybeard wizard coworkers from these places, and they were all a pleasure to learn from and even better friends. For the first 2 years of my first job, every day of work was like walking into the Shire and talking magic spells with 20 Gandalfs.&lt;p&gt;That job was great until I got put on a team with a guy who was a former middle manager at some IBM-like company and went from being surrounded by people lightyears ahead of me to being surrounded by Dilbert characters. The messed-up part was that it wasn't even punishment. I was rewarded after completing a project with my choice of which team I joined next, and I joined the wrong one. I assumed that joining a new team to utilize this newfangled "cloud computing" thing would be trailblazing, and I didn't do any diligence on who I would work with.&lt;p&gt;To this day, I still regret not rejoining the first team I worked for, otherwise I would still be at that company and happy about it. Then again, the boredom and discontent while being on that sucky team is the reason I started investing, and now I can buy a house in cash and fund myself to do whatever I want for at least a decade. Hard to complain about the way things turned out.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 21 Oct 2025 00:15:41 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45651013</link><dc:creator>president_zippy</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45651013</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45651013</guid></item><item><title>New comment by president_zippy in "Today is when the Amazon brain drain sent AWS down the spout"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Between the engineering staff and the warehouse workers, I wonder how long it will be until they have already fired everyone who ever would have been willing to work there.&lt;p&gt;Even with candidate pools of hundreds of thousands of H1-B engineers and tens of millions of illegal immigrant warehouse workers, there still comes a point where such a big company firing so many people so quickly exhausts all their options.&lt;p&gt;It reminds me of the Robot Chicken Sketch where Imperial Officers aboard the Death Star all pretend to be force choked to death by Darth Vader so they can avoid getting killed by lightsaber, then come back in under different names in different jobs. It's worse though for Amazon: nobody wants to come back.&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=fFihTRIxCkg" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=fFihTRIxCkg&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 20 Oct 2025 23:51:51 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45650861</link><dc:creator>president_zippy</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45650861</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45650861</guid></item></channel></rss>