<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>Hacker News: Best Comments</title><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/bestcomments</link><description>Hacker News RSS</description><docs>https://hnrss.org/</docs><generator>hnrss v2.1.1</generator><lastBuildDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 00:31:36 +0000</lastBuildDate><ns0:link href="https://hnrss.org/bestcomments" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item><title>New comment by falcor84 in "Gemini 3"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I love it that there's a "Read AI-generated summary" button on their post about their new AI.&lt;p&gt;I can only expect that the next step is something like "Have your AI read our AI's auto-generated summary", and so forth until we are all the way at Douglas Adams's Electric Monk:&lt;p&gt;&gt; The Electric Monk was a labour-saving device, like a dishwasher or a video recorder. Dishwashers washed tedious dishes for you, thus saving you the bother of washing them yourself; video recorders watched tedious television for you, thus saving you the bother of looking at it yourself. Electric Monks believed things for you, thus saving you what was becoming an increasingly onerous task, that of believing all the things the world expected you to believe.&lt;p&gt;- from "Dirk Gently's Holistic Detective Agency"&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 20:55:34 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45971919</link><dc:creator>falcor84</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45971919</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45971919</guid></item><item><title>New comment by throwaway13337 in "Google Antigravity"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I gave it a fair shot.&lt;p&gt;It is a vs code fork. There were some UI glitches. Some usability was better. Cursor has some real annoying usability issues - like their previous/next code change never going away and no way to disable it. Design of this one looks more polished and less muddy.&lt;p&gt;I was working on a project and just continued with it. It was easy because they import setting from cursor. Feels like the browser wars.&lt;p&gt;Anyway, I figured it was the only way to use gemini 3 so I got started. A fast model that doesn't look for much context. Could be a preprompt issue. But you have to prod it do stuff - no ambition and a kinda offputting atitude like 2.5.&lt;p&gt;But hey - a smarter, less context rich Cursor composer model. And that's a complement because the latest composer is a hidden gem. Gemini has potential.&lt;p&gt;So I start using it for my project and after about 20 mins - oh, no. Out of credits.&lt;p&gt;What can I do? Is there a buy a plan button? No? Just use a different model?&lt;p&gt;What's the strategy here? If I am into your IDE and your LLM, how do I actually use it? I can't pay for it and it has 20 minutes of use.&lt;p&gt;I switched back to cursor. And you know? it had gemini 3 pro. Likely a less hobbled version. Day one. Seems like a mistake in the eyes of the big evil companies but I'll take it.&lt;p&gt;Real developers want to pay real money for real useful things.&lt;p&gt;Google needs to not set themselves up for failure with every product release.&lt;p&gt;If you release a product, let those who actually want to use it have a path to do so.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 19:53:00 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45971152</link><dc:creator>throwaway13337</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45971152</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45971152</guid></item><item><title>New comment by lairv in "Gemini 3"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Out of curiosity, I gave it the latest project euler problem published on 11/16/2025, very likely out of the training data&lt;p&gt;Gemini thought for 5m10s before giving me a python snippet that produced the correct answer. The leaderboard says that the 3 fastest human to solve this problem took 14min, 20min and 1h14min respectively&lt;p&gt;Even thought I expect this sort of problem to very much be in the distribution of what the model has been RL-tuned to do, it's wild that frontier model can now solve in minutes what would take me days&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 17:37:15 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45969422</link><dc:creator>lairv</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45969422</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45969422</guid></item><item><title>New comment by kUdtiHaEX in "Google Antigravity"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;2020: every day a new JS framework is announced&lt;p&gt;2024: every day a new Chrome fork browser is announced&lt;p&gt;2025: every day a new AI IDE vscode fork is announced&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 16:52:45 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45968798</link><dc:creator>kUdtiHaEX</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45968798</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45968798</guid></item><item><title>New comment by modeless in "Google Antigravity"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Thank you for saying what this entire blog post doesn't. It's actually disrespectful of Google to launch this without even a mention of the fact that it is based on VSCode.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 16:42:09 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45968618</link><dc:creator>modeless</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45968618</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45968618</guid></item><item><title>New comment by nateb2022 in "Google Antigravity"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I went ahead and downloaded it, it looks to be a VSCode fork very similar to Cursor, with support for the following models:&lt;p&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;  - Gemini 3 Pro (High)
  - Gemini 3 Pro (Low)
  - Claude Sonnet 4.5
  - Claude Sonnet 4.5 (Thinking)
  - GPT-OSS 120B (Medium)&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 16:30:36 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45968432</link><dc:creator>nateb2022</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45968432</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45968432</guid></item><item><title>New comment by aavshr in "Cloudflare Global Network experiencing issues"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&gt; In short, a latent bug in a service underpinning our bot mitigation capability started to crash after a routine configuration change we made. That cascaded into a broad degradation to our network and other services. This was not an attack.&lt;p&gt;From the CTO, Source: &lt;a href="https://x.com/dok2001/status/1990791419653484646" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://x.com/dok2001/status/1990791419653484646&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 16:14:12 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45968164</link><dc:creator>aavshr</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45968164</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45968164</guid></item><item><title>New comment by njarboe in "Nearly all UK drivers say headlights are too bright"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;One of the main reasons people want/need brighter headlights is that there is much more light inside the car from screens. These don't let your eyes adjust to the dark properly. Older cars had dim green lighting for the gauges and even had a knob to adjust the brightness up and down. You could create a very dim interior instead of the huge amount of white light you get with modern cars and the multiple screens.&lt;p&gt;I'm happy my Tesla does a decent job of having the screen be quite dark at night but the headlights are quite bad with the horizontal cutoff style that only lights the first few feet of horizontal ahead of the car. I need to see those deer and elk on the side of the road, damn it.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 15:11:13 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45967241</link><dc:creator>njarboe</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45967241</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45967241</guid></item><item><title>New comment by throwaway150 in "Do not put your site behind Cloudflare if you don't need to"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&gt; For your small blog with one hundred visitors per month, it's probably the same: "no one will burn their DDoS capabilities on you!"&lt;p&gt;If this is their core argument for not using CDN, then this post sounds like a terribly bad advice. Hopes and prayers do not make a valid security strategy. Appropriate controls and defenses do. The author seems to be completely missing that it takes only a few bucks to buy DDoS as a service. Sometimes people do DDoS your small blog because some random stranger didn't like something you said somewhere online. Speaking from experience. Very much the reason I'm posting this with a throwaway account. If your website receives DDoS, your hosts will take down your server. Nobody wants to be in this situation even if for a personal, small blog.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 14:36:12 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45966683</link><dc:creator>throwaway150</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45966683</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45966683</guid></item><item><title>New comment by abelanger in "Cloudflare Global Network experiencing issues"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;If anyone needs commands for turning off the CF proxy for their domains and happens to have a Cloudflare API token.&lt;p&gt;First you can grab the zone ID via:&lt;p&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;    curl -X GET "https://api.cloudflare.com/client/v4/zones" -H "Authorization: Bearer $API_TOKEN" -H "Content-Type: application/json" | jq -r '.result[] | "\(.id) \(.name)"'
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
And a list of DNS records using:&lt;p&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;    curl -X GET "https://api.cloudflare.com/client/v4/zones/$ZONE_ID/dns_records" -H "Authorization: Bearer $API_TOKEN" -H "Content-Type: application/json"
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
Each DNS record will have an ID associated. Finally patch the relevant records:&lt;p&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;    curl -X PATCH "https://api.cloudflare.com/client/v4/zones/$ZONE_ID/dns_records/$RECORD_ID" -H "Authorization: Bearer $API_TOKEN" -H "Content-Type: application/json" --data '{"proxied":false}'
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
Copying from a sibling comment - some warnings:&lt;p&gt;- SSL/TLS: You will likely lose your Cloudflare-provided SSL certificate. Your site will only work if your origin server has its own valid certificate.&lt;p&gt;- Security &amp; Performance: You will lose the performance benefits (caching, minification, global edge network) and security protections (DDoS mitigation, WAF) that Cloudflare provides.&lt;p&gt;- This will also reveal your backend internal IP addresses. Anyone can find permanent logs of public IP addresses used by even obscure domain names, so potential adversaries don't necessarily have to be paying attention at the exact right time to find it.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 13:57:53 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45966041</link><dc:creator>abelanger</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45966041</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45966041</guid></item><item><title>New comment by afavour in "Cloudflare Global Network experiencing issues"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Because no one cares enough, including users.&lt;p&gt;Oddly this centralization allows a complete deferral of blame without you even doing anything: if you’re down, that’s bad. But if you’re down, Spotify is down, social media is down… then “the internet is broken” and you don’t look so bad.&lt;p&gt;It also reduces your incentive to change, if “the internet is down” people will put down their device and do something else. Even if your web site is up they’ll assume it isn’t.&lt;p&gt;I’m not saying this is a good thing but I’m simply being realistic about why we ended up where we are.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 13:43:53 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45965824</link><dc:creator>afavour</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45965824</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45965824</guid></item><item><title>New comment by arbuge in "Cloudflare Global Network experiencing issues"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Tell him it's worse than he thinks. He obviously brought the entire Cloudflare system down.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 13:15:20 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45965344</link><dc:creator>arbuge</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45965344</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45965344</guid></item><item><title>New comment by lordofgibbons in "Cloudflare Global Network experiencing issues"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;How did we get to a place where either Cloudflare or AWS having an outage means a large part of the web going down? This centralization is very worrying.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 13:12:53 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45965293</link><dc:creator>lordofgibbons</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45965293</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45965293</guid></item><item><title>New comment by rollulus in "Cloudflare Global Network experiencing issues"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Classic. I see issues. Vendor’s status page is all green. Go to HN to find the confirmation. Applies to AWS, GH, everyone.&lt;p&gt;Edit: beautiful, this decentralised design of the internet.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 12:07:55 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45964342</link><dc:creator>rollulus</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45964342</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45964342</guid></item><item><title>New comment by entropoem in "Cloudflare Global Network experiencing issues"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Everyone laughs when AWS collapses, everyone is silent when Cloudflare collapses. Why? Because the place to laugh has collapsed.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 11:48:22 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45963935</link><dc:creator>entropoem</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45963935</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45963935</guid></item><item><title>New comment by jpmonette in "Cloudflare Global Network experiencing issues"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;phewphoria&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 11:44:14 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45963886</link><dc:creator>jpmonette</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45963886</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45963886</guid></item><item><title>New comment by gwd in "Cloudflare Global Network experiencing issues"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I do appreciate the visual "mea culpa":&lt;p&gt;Your browser: Working&lt;p&gt;Host:  Working&lt;p&gt;Cloudflare: Error&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 11:44:04 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45963883</link><dc:creator>gwd</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45963883</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45963883</guid></item><item><title>New comment by itzjacki in "Cloudflare Global Network experiencing issues"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;A colleague of mine just came bursting through my office door in a panic, thinking he brought our site down since this happened just as he made some changes to our Cloudflare config. He was pretty relieved to see this post.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 11:37:47 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45963808</link><dc:creator>itzjacki</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45963808</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45963808</guid></item><item><title>New comment by powerclue in "How many video games include a marriage proposal? At least one"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;That's me! I made that 17 years ago, still happily married. Took me like two weeks of full time tinkering. It involved a lot of trial and error messing with a hex editor.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 06:54:42 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45962129</link><dc:creator>powerclue</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45962129</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45962129</guid></item><item><title>New comment by luke727 in "Windows 11 adds AI agent that runs in background with access to personal folders"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&gt; Office products are bastardized with copilot buttons everywhere.&lt;p&gt;They put copilot in notepad. NOTEPAD.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 05:44:38 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45961771</link><dc:creator>luke727</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45961771</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45961771</guid></item><item><title>New comment by ChicagoDave in "Windows 11 adds AI agent that runs in background with access to personal folders"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Microsoft has gone full-blown evil corporation again. No customer validation on any of the AI cruft. No full OPT OUT. Office products are bastardized with copilot buttons everywhere.&lt;p&gt;I've been a Windows user from day one and I now see a future without it. Satya had been a bright spot in Microsoft, but this blind lust for AI, especially in bed with Altman who is pure con artist, is unforgivable.&lt;p&gt;Some of the investment sells recently are starting to look like the beginning of the end for OpenAI. That will have a wide range impact on everything.&lt;p&gt;I use Claude for coding (and mostly in WSL). OpenAI enabled its users to have a sext conversation.&lt;p&gt;Seriously. And Satya just keeps on at full speed.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 04:50:06 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45961517</link><dc:creator>ChicagoDave</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45961517</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45961517</guid></item><item><title>New comment by astrocat in "How many video games include a marriage proposal? At least one"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;The heart-warming gem:&lt;p&gt;&gt; I sent a note about these Easter eggs to Scott Corley [the game's developer]. He said that he had recently pulled out the game to show the marriage proposal to his son. But he’d forgotten the code and couldn’t make it work! He and Melissa did indeed live happily ever after.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 04:19:38 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45961344</link><dc:creator>astrocat</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45961344</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45961344</guid></item><item><title>New comment by caymanjim in "Raccoons are showing early signs of domestication"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;They're pretty great pets. We had one for a while when I was a kid. Its mom got run over and we nursed it and raised it for a few months. Instinctively used the same litter box as the cats. Hung out on the couch sitting on my shoulder watching TV. Friendly and playful. Would follow people around and play with toys.&lt;p&gt;The biggest challenge is that they basically have hands. He would climb up the kitchen cabinets, grab a box of cereal, open it up and sit there eating out of it like a toddler.&lt;p&gt;We only had him for a few months before reintroducing him to the woods behind the house. I've wanted a pet raccoon again ever since.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 02:41:44 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45960821</link><dc:creator>caymanjim</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45960821</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45960821</guid></item><item><title>New comment by everdrive in "Windows 11 adds AI agent that runs in background with access to personal folders"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;It's an agentic OS now. It acts as an agent on behalf of Microsoft and its business partners, and against your interests.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 00:27:08 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45960047</link><dc:creator>everdrive</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45960047</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45960047</guid></item><item><title>New comment by etangent in "My stages of learning to be a socially normal person"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&gt; a lot of the points felt more like learning how to charm, manipulate, and game social interactions.&lt;p&gt;A lot of stuff "normal" people do is charm, manipulate, and game social interactions. Except because they are not conscious about it, we give them a pass. One of the characteristics of autistic-spectrum individuals is that they must make a conscious effort to achieve goals that are achieved unconsciously by most of us. If we prevent such individuals from learning all that rarely-written-down stuff consciously because it seems "distasteful" to us, then we are disadvantaging such individuals socially.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 21:16:10 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45958403</link><dc:creator>etangent</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45958403</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45958403</guid></item><item><title>New comment by baklavaEmperor in "Israeli-founded app preloaded on Samsung phones is attracting controversy"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;What’s striking is how often these ‘small’ surveillance tech stories trace back to the same state-aligned ecosystem. When Israel does it, it’s treated as a complex security issue. When another ‘bad’ country does the same thing, we immediately call it espionage. And almost on cue, the discussion drifts anywhere except the uncomfortable fact that it’s the same ecosystem from the same country showing up again.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 20:30:54 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45957934</link><dc:creator>baklavaEmperor</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45957934</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45957934</guid></item><item><title>New comment by Aurornis in "My stages of learning to be a socially normal person"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;This post wasn't what I was expecting from the "socially normal" title. While there is a lot of self-reflection and growth in this piece, a lot of the points felt more like learning how to charm, manipulate, and game social interactions.&lt;p&gt;Look at the first two subheadings:&lt;p&gt;&gt; 1: Connecting with people is about being a dazzling person&lt;p&gt;&gt; 2: Connecting with people is about playing their game&lt;p&gt;The post felt like a rollercoaster between using tricks to charm and manipulate, and periods of genuinely trying to learn how to be friends with people.&lt;p&gt;I don't want to disparage the author as this is a personal journey piece and I appreciate them sharing it. However this did leave me slightly uneasy, almost calling back to earlier days of the internet when advice about "social skills" often meant reductively thinking about other people, assuming you can mind-read them to deconstruct their mindset (the section about identifying people who feel underpraised, insecure, nervous,) and then leverage that to charm them (referred to as "dancing to the music" in this post).&lt;p&gt;Maybe the takeaway I'd try to give is to read this as an interesting peek into someone's mind, but not necessarily great advice for anyone else's situation or a healthy way to view relationships.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 20:24:50 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45957863</link><dc:creator>Aurornis</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45957863</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45957863</guid></item><item><title>New comment by hpdigidrifter in "Why don't people return their shopping carts?"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I assume it's generally unbecoming to reference 4chan posts for an academic but surprised the Shopping Cart theory didn't get a mention given how close it was to the subject matter.&lt;p&gt;&gt;“The shopping cart is the ultimate litmus test for whether a person is capable of self-governing. To return the shopping cart is an easy, convenient task and one we all recognize as the correct, appropriate thing to do. To return the shopping cart is objectively right. There are no situations other than dire emergencies in which a person is not able to return their cart. Simultaneously, it is not illegal to abandon your shopping cart. Therefore, the shopping cart presents itself as the apex example of whether a person will do what is right without being forced to do it.”&lt;p&gt;&gt;“No one will punish you for not returning the shopping cart, no one will fine you, or kill you for not returning the shopping cart. You gain nothing by returning the shopping cart. You must return the shopping cart out of the goodness of your own heart. You must return the shopping cart because it is the right thing to do. Because it is correct. The Shopping Cart Theory, therefore, is a great litmus test on whether a person is a good or bad member of society.”&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 18:45:54 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45956589</link><dc:creator>hpdigidrifter</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45956589</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45956589</guid></item><item><title>New comment by nwellnhof in "Google is killing the open web, part 2"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Removing XSLT from browsers was long overdue and I'm saying that as ex-maintainer of libxslt who probably triggered (not caused) this removal. What's more interesting is that Chromium plans to switch to a Rust-based XML parser. Currently, they seem to favor xml-rs which only implements a subset of XML. So apparently, Google is willing to remove standards-compliant XML support as well. This is a lot more concerning.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 16:33:27 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45955183</link><dc:creator>nwellnhof</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45955183</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45955183</guid></item><item><title>New comment by AlbertoGP in "Britney Spears' Guide to Semiconductor Physics (2000)"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Around the time this website was made, I was building an application for a big company in Spain that was to run as a Java applet and required the code to be signed.&lt;p&gt;They did not yet have their own certificates so I had to make my own CA during testing and sign the code, and I wanted to make sure that they did not forget to switch to their certificates later, so instead of signing the code with my name which some bureaucrat might decide to not bother changing, the code was signed by Britney Spears.&lt;p&gt;They noticed it, got the joke and made sure to switch certificates for the release. Everything went well thanks to Britney.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 00:38:11 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45949868</link><dc:creator>AlbertoGP</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45949868</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45949868</guid></item></channel></rss>