<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>Hacker News: Best Comments</title><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/bestcomments</link><description>Hacker News RSS</description><docs>https://hnrss.org/</docs><generator>hnrss v2.1.1</generator><lastBuildDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 01:41:52 +0000</lastBuildDate><ns0:link href="https://hnrss.org/bestcomments" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item><title>New comment by yen223 in "Estimates are difficult for developers and product owners"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;The unique thing about estimates in software engineering is that if you do it right, projects should be impossible to estimate!&lt;p&gt;Tasks that are easiest to estimate are tasks that are predictable, and repetitive. If I ask you how long it'll take to add a new database field, and you've added a new database field 100s of times in the past and each time they take 1 day, your estimate for it is going to be very spot-on.&lt;p&gt;But in the software world, predictable and repetitive tasks are also the kinds of tasks that are most easily automated, which means the time it takes to perform those tasks should asymptotically approach 0.&lt;p&gt;But if the predictable tasks take 0 time, how long a project takes will be dominated by the novel, unpredictable parts.&lt;p&gt;That's why software estimates are very hard to do.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 07 Dec 2025 20:01:34 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46184611</link><dc:creator>yen223</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46184611</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46184611</guid></item><item><title>New comment by game_the0ry in "Scala 3 slowed us down?"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I am not a scala fan and do not care for it, but I upvote for the thorough thought process, breakdown, and debugging of the problem. This is how technical blogs should be written. AI aint got shit on this.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 07 Dec 2025 16:38:46 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46182978</link><dc:creator>game_the0ry</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46182978</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46182978</guid></item><item><title>New comment by libraryofbabel in "The programmers who live in Flatland"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Or perhaps, just perhaps, the true higher-dimensional move is realizing that choice of programming language isn’t usually the critical factor in whether a project, system, or business succeeds or fails, and that obsessing over the One True Way is a trap.&lt;p&gt;It might surprise the author to learn that there are many people who:&lt;p&gt;1) Have tried lisp and clojure&lt;p&gt;2) Liked their elegance and expressiveness&lt;p&gt;3) Have read through SICP and done most of the exercises&lt;p&gt;4) Would still choose plain old boring easy-to-read always-second-best Python for 90% of use-cases (and probably Rust for the last 10%) when building a real business in the real world.&lt;p&gt;The article could really benefit from some steel-manning. Remove the cute Flatland metaphor and it is effectively arguing that lisp/clojure haven’t been universally adopted because most programmers haven’t Seen The Light in some sort of epiphany of parentheses and macros. The truth is more nuanced.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 07 Dec 2025 16:34:04 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46182942</link><dc:creator>libraryofbabel</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46182942</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46182942</guid></item><item><title>New comment by CapitalistCartr in "Over fifty new hallucinations in ICLR 2026 submissions"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I'm an industrial electrician. A lot of poor electrical work is visible only to a fellow electrician, and sometimes only another industrial electrician. Bad technical work requires technical inspectors to criticize. Sometimes highly skilled ones.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 07 Dec 2025 15:29:18 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46182385</link><dc:creator>CapitalistCartr</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46182385</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46182385</guid></item><item><title>New comment by hanshenning in "The state of Schleswig-Holstein is consistently relying on open source"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;You're not wrong, but this is actually what they're pursuing; the article just leaves it out.&lt;p&gt;&gt; The goal is not only to save costs, but above all to gain digital sovereignty.&lt;p&gt;&gt; [It's true] that open source is not necessarily cheaper, [..] it requires investment. But the money flows into internal infrastructure, into the further development of Nextcloud, LibreOffice, and other similar systems, instead of proprietary ones.&lt;p&gt;&gt; Schleswig-Holstein pursues an "upstream-only strategy," meaning that developments flow directly back into international projects. The state does not want to maintain its own forks, but rather contribute all improvements directly to the main projects, thereby contributing to development for the benefit of the general public.[1]&lt;p&gt;On a side note, the real key to the project's success is that it's supported by a coalition of the conservative and green parties. They actually value digital sovereignty and longterm cost savings. Contrast that with Bavaria, where the MS lobbyist managed to get them to sign a longterm Office 365 contract…&lt;p&gt;[1]&lt;a href="https://www-heise-de.translate.goog/hintergrund/Interview-Wie-die-OSS-Umstellung-in-Schleswig-Holstein-laeuft-10629991.html?_x_tr_sl=de&amp;_x_tr_tl=en&amp;_x_tr_pto=wapp" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://www-heise-de.translate.goog/hintergrund/Interview-Wi...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 07 Dec 2025 15:28:18 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46182376</link><dc:creator>hanshenning</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46182376</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46182376</guid></item><item><title>New comment by theoldgreybeard in "Over fifty new hallucinations in ICLR 2026 submissions"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;If a carpenter builds a crappy shelf “because” his power tools are not calibrated correctly - that’s a crappy carpenter, not a crappy tool.&lt;p&gt;If a scientist uses an LLM to write a paper with fabricated citations - that’s a crappy scientist.&lt;p&gt;AI is not the problem, laziness and negligence is.  There needs to be serious social consequences to this kind of thing, otherwise we are tacitly endorsing it.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 07 Dec 2025 15:09:30 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46182214</link><dc:creator>theoldgreybeard</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46182214</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46182214</guid></item><item><title>New comment by input_sh in "The state of Schleswig-Holstein is consistently relying on open source"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I &lt;i&gt;hate&lt;/i&gt; when switches like these get advertised first and foremost as some huge cost-cutting measure, further solidifying open source ecosystem as some cheap knock-offs of their commercial alternatives.&lt;p&gt;How about instead you donate the same amount of money you would've paid to Microsoft anyways to fund open source projects you rely on? At least for one year, then drop it down to some arbitrary chosen percentage of that cost. That way you can still advertise it as a cost-cutting measure, and everyone would benefit.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 07 Dec 2025 14:30:11 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46181911</link><dc:creator>input_sh</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46181911</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46181911</guid></item><item><title>New comment by okdood64 in "Google Titans architecture, helping AI have long-term memory"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;From the blog:&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.00663" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.00663&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://arxiv.org/pdf/2504.13173" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://arxiv.org/pdf/2504.13173&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;Is there any other company that's openly publishing their research on AI at this level? Google should get a lot of credit for this.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 07 Dec 2025 14:05:36 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46181759</link><dc:creator>okdood64</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46181759</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46181759</guid></item><item><title>New comment by GnarfGnarf in "The state of Schleswig-Holstein is consistently relying on open source"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I'm a Windows/macOS developer, but I strongly feel that all national governments need to convert to Linux, for strategic sovereignty. I'm sure Microsoft, under orders from the U.S. government, could disable all computers in any country or organization, at the flick of a switch.&lt;p&gt;Imagine how Open Source Software could improve if a consortium of nations put their money and resources into commissioning bug fixes and enhancements, which would be of collective benefit.&lt;p&gt;Apart from a few niche cases, the needs of most government bureaucracies would be well served by currently available OSS word processing, spreadsheet, presentation and graphics software.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 07 Dec 2025 13:48:31 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46181666</link><dc:creator>GnarfGnarf</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46181666</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46181666</guid></item><item><title>New comment by sedatk in "Kilauea erupts, destroying webcam [video]"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I was there today. We happened to notice the smoke over Kilauea while driving to Hilo, then checked out USGS cams, and immediately drove there and spent the next 7 hours getting mesmerized.&lt;p&gt;As my first eruption encounter,  I didn’t expect to experience several things like the heat even from a long distance, enough to keep me warm in my shorts at 60F, and the loud rumble, like a giant waterfall. The flow of lava was way faster than I expected too, almost like oil.&lt;p&gt;Mind blown.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 07 Dec 2025 09:48:59 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46180489</link><dc:creator>sedatk</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46180489</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46180489</guid></item><item><title>New comment by PeterHolzwarth in "The past was not that cute"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;"A woman's work is never done."&lt;p&gt;In our agrarian past, the cultural division of labor at the time said that men worked the field, women ran the home. And that later job was brutal, never-ending, and consumed &lt;i&gt;all&lt;/i&gt; waking hours until the day she died.&lt;p&gt;Men broke their backs in the field, women consumed their lives doing the ceaseless work that never ended, every waking moment. (And occasionally helped out in the field, too).&lt;p&gt;Running a family was a brutal two-person job -- and the kids had to dive in to help out the second they could lift something heavier than a couple pounds.&lt;p&gt;We forget so easily that for the entire history of our species - up until just recently - simply staying alive and somewhat warm and minimally fed was a hundred-hour-a-week job for mom and dad.&lt;p&gt;There are important downsides, but the Green Revolution - and dare I say it, the industrial revolution - was truly transformative for our species.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 07 Dec 2025 04:48:26 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46179223</link><dc:creator>PeterHolzwarth</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46179223</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46179223</guid></item><item><title>New comment by jasongill in "Screenshots from developers: 2002 vs. 2015 (2015)"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I met RMS at the Atlanta Linux Showcase in 1998. In the area with vendor booths in the lobby area of the show, he had laid down a blanket and was sitting in the middle with his legs crossed. He had printed copies of man pages printed and stapled together with covers laid out in front of him.&lt;p&gt;I walked up and introduced myself and said that I was a big fan, appreciated his hard work, etc. He looked at me coldly and just said "so are you going to buy something?" and motioned toward the booklets. I didn't need a printed copy of the `sed` man page so I shrugged and he seemed quite annoyed, turned to his assistant with a notebook computer and started dictating something to them, as almost to make it clear that our interaction was over.&lt;p&gt;I'm not sure what the point of posting this is, but that's my RMS story - it was my first "never meet your heroes" moment, I guess.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 07 Dec 2025 03:33:35 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46178925</link><dc:creator>jasongill</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46178925</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46178925</guid></item><item><title>New comment by ChrisMarshallNY in "Trains cancelled over fake bridge collapse image"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I think we’re just getting started, with fake images and videos.&lt;p&gt;I suspect that people will be killed, because of outrage over fake stuff. Before the Ukraine invasion, some of the folks in Donbas made a fake bomb, complete with corpses from a morgue (with autopsy scars)[0]. That didn’t require any AI at all.&lt;p&gt;We can expect videos of unpopular minorities, doing horrible things, politicians saying stuff they never said, and evidence submitted to trial, that was completely made from whole cloth.&lt;p&gt;It’s gonna suck.&lt;p&gt;[0] &lt;a href="https://www.bellingcat.com/news/2022/02/28/exploiting-cadavers-and-faked-ieds-experts-debunk-staged-pre-war-provocation-in-the-donbas/" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://www.bellingcat.com/news/2022/02/28/exploiting-cadave...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 07 Dec 2025 02:55:44 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46178756</link><dc:creator>ChrisMarshallNY</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46178756</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46178756</guid></item><item><title>New comment by lukasb in "Using LLMs at Oxide"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;One difference is that clichéd prose is bad and clichéd code is generally good.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 07 Dec 2025 02:25:55 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46178642</link><dc:creator>lukasb</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46178642</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46178642</guid></item><item><title>New comment by thundergolfer in "Using LLMs at Oxide"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;A measured, comprehensive, and sensible take. Not surprising from Bryan. This was a nice line:&lt;p&gt;&gt;  it’s just embarrassing — it’s as if the writer is walking around with their intellectual fly open.&lt;p&gt;I think Oxide didn't include this in the RFD because they exclusively hire senior engineers, but in an organization that contains junior engineers I'd add something specific to help junior engineers understand how they should approach LLM use.&lt;p&gt;Bryan has 30+ years of challenging software (and now hardware) engineering experience. He memorably said that he's worked on and completed a "hard program" (an OS), which he defines as a program you doubt you can actually get working.&lt;p&gt;The way Bryan approaches an LLM is super different to how a 2025 junior engineer does so. That junior engineer possibly hasn't programmed without the tantalizing, even desperately tempting option to be assisted by an LLM.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 07 Dec 2025 01:46:39 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46178458</link><dc:creator>thundergolfer</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46178458</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46178458</guid></item><item><title>New comment by tyushk in "Trains cancelled over fake bridge collapse image"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&gt; A BBC journalist ran the image through an AI chatbot which identified key spots that may have been manipulated.&lt;p&gt;The image is likely AI generated in this case, but this does not seem like the best strategy for finding out if an image is AI generated.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 07 Dec 2025 00:56:25 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46178228</link><dc:creator>tyushk</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46178228</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46178228</guid></item><item><title>New comment by delichon in "The past was not that cute"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Back in 2025 before cheap bots, our grandparents endured lives of servitude. They spent an enormous amount of time doing simple chores like folding clothes, driving, programming, washing and dusting, grooming themselves. They had to walk their own dogs and play with their own children. They sometimes even had to cook their own food, directly over fire. "Hygiene" was a primitive joke. A full day's work usually wasn't even enough to buy a single new car. &lt;i&gt;They&lt;/i&gt; wrote checks to the &lt;i&gt;government&lt;/i&gt;, rather than the other way around. Life was brutal, desperate and short.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 06 Dec 2025 23:38:14 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46177641</link><dc:creator>delichon</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46177641</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46177641</guid></item><item><title>New comment by jordanb in "Perl's decline was cultural"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I always found the Perl "community" to be really off-putting with all the monk and wizard nonsense. Then there was the whole one-liner thing that was all about being clever and obscure. Everything about Python came off as being much more serious and &lt;i&gt;normal&lt;/i&gt; for a young nerd who wasn't a theater kid.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 06 Dec 2025 18:16:28 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46175337</link><dc:creator>jordanb</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46175337</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46175337</guid></item><item><title>New comment by axelthegerman in "GrapheneOS is the only Android OS providing full security patches"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Oh that's one of the best news in the smartphone world in a long time.&lt;p&gt;It's impossible to escape the Apple/Google duopoly but at least GrapheneOS makes the most out of Android regarding privacy.&lt;p&gt;I still wish we could get some kind of low resource, stable and mature Android clone instead of Google needlessly increasing complexity but this will over time break app compatibility (Google will make sure of it)&lt;p&gt;Edit: I do think Pixel devices used to be one of the best but still I'd like to choose my hardware and software separately interoperating via standards&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 06 Dec 2025 17:51:00 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46175172</link><dc:creator>axelthegerman</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46175172</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46175172</guid></item><item><title>New comment by walterbell in "GrapheneOS is the only Android OS providing full security patches"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://tbot.substack.com/p/grapheneos-new-oem-partnership" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://tbot.substack.com/p/grapheneos-new-oem-partnership&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;&gt; GrapheneOS has officially confirmed a major new hardware partnership—one that marks the end of its long-standing Pixel exclusivity. According to the team, work with a major Android OEM began in June and is now moving toward the development of a next-generation smartphone built to meet GrapheneOS’ strict privacy and security standards.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 06 Dec 2025 16:46:13 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46174679</link><dc:creator>walterbell</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46174679</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46174679</guid></item><item><title>New comment by tayiorrobinson in "How I discovered a hidden microphone on a Chinese NanoKVM"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;To be fair, the microphone _is_ listed on the specsheet of the LicheeRV Nano&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://wiki.sipeed.com/hardware/en/lichee/RV_Nano/1_intro.html" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://wiki.sipeed.com/hardware/en/lichee/RV_Nano/1_intro.h...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;I assume they didn't intend to put a  mic on the KVM product, but they wanted to make a KVM product, already had this SBC product, which reusing their existing stock of helped keep cost low.&lt;p&gt;Should they have been more up front about it it? Sure, and it's not great that they had a bunch of security issues in the FW anyway, so not exactly great, but "hidden microphone in a Chinese KVM" lets the mind wander&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 06 Dec 2025 14:54:59 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46173784</link><dc:creator>tayiorrobinson</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46173784</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46173784</guid></item><item><title>New comment by cracki in "Schizophrenia sufferer mistakes smart fridge ad for psychotic episode"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Time to ban all adverts everywhere. I'm not the only one who is fed up with ads.&lt;p&gt;I don't see ads, thanks to ad blocking tech in browsers and smartphones. Any time that happens to fail and I get to endure an ad, I am amazed that regular people without ad blocking tech can endure this onslaught.&lt;p&gt;The time to negotiate a "middle ground" is long past. Let's not even entertain that idea.&lt;p&gt;An acceptable middle ground could have been designated areas for ads, which you have to seek out to see them. Think of the Yellow Pages.&lt;p&gt;Ad companies need to be reined in. They cannot control themselves. They are lobbying against all limits and controls. The only solution is to eradicate ads entirely and to make sure that anyone who gets that idea will never get it again.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 06 Dec 2025 11:27:55 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46172492</link><dc:creator>cracki</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46172492</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46172492</guid></item><item><title>New comment by hebejebelus in "Wolfram Compute Services"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Man, I miss Wolfram Language. Once you've twisted your brain a little to grok its usage, it's such an incredibly high-value tool, especially for exploration and prototyping. I saw it more as a do-anything software tool for researchers rather than as a language aimed at programmers, so I put on a researcher hat and tried to forget everything I knew as a professional programmer, and had a few memorable seasons with it around 2016-2020. I remember calculating precisely which days of the year would cause the sunlight to pass through a window and some glass blocks in an internal wall, creating a beautiful light show indoors. It only took a couple of minutes to get a nice animated visualisation and a calendar.&lt;p&gt;Nowadays I'd probably just ask Claude to figure it out for me, but pre LLMs, WL was the highest value tool for thought in my toolbox.&lt;p&gt;(Edit: and they actually offer perpetual licenses!)&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 06 Dec 2025 09:34:25 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46171939</link><dc:creator>hebejebelus</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46171939</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46171939</guid></item><item><title>New comment by xioxox in "Schizophrenia sufferer mistakes smart fridge ad for psychotic episode"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Although adverts on the fridge are absolutely terrible, is this genuine? Here's a reddit post some time before that suggesting the scenario: &lt;a href="https://old.reddit.com/r/assholedesign/comments/1ow6cpu/apparently_my_samsung_fridge_has_ads_now/nonrm5s/" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://old.reddit.com/r/assholedesign/comments/1ow6cpu/appa...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 06 Dec 2025 09:18:04 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46171868</link><dc:creator>xioxox</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46171868</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46171868</guid></item><item><title>New comment by jamesbelchamber in "Schizophrenia sufferer mistakes smart fridge ad for psychotic episode"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;We really need some legislation that outlaws this sort of control over devices we buy.&lt;p&gt;If someone wants to install an advert app on their fridge (I assume in exchange for money) then fair enough.&lt;p&gt;If I buy a tv I shouldn't just have to accept that, now or in the future, the manufacturer will sell advertising on it.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 06 Dec 2025 08:22:48 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46171608</link><dc:creator>jamesbelchamber</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46171608</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46171608</guid></item><item><title>New comment by brendangregg in "Leaving Intel"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I like to measure things. In real life and on computers. But I also have a couple of work reasons for it:&lt;p&gt;As a remote worker, I'm under extra pressure to prove that remoteness works.&lt;p&gt;As a senior employee, I'm also under pressure to regularly report where my time is spent.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 06 Dec 2025 05:11:04 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46170913</link><dc:creator>brendangregg</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46170913</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46170913</guid></item><item><title>New comment by WD-42 in "Self-hosting my photos with Immich"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Self hosting used to mean conceding on something. I can honestly say Immich is better in every way than Google Photos or whatever Apple calls it. The only thing is having to set it up yourself.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 06 Dec 2025 03:02:17 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46170203</link><dc:creator>WD-42</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46170203</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46170203</guid></item><item><title>New comment by randycupertino in "YouTube caught making AI-edits to videos and adding misleading AI summaries"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;A makeup influencer I follow noticed youtube and instagram are automatically adding filters to his face without permission to his videos.  If his content was about lip makeup they make his lips enormous and if it was about eye makeup the filters make his eyes gigantic.  They're having AI detecting the type of content and automatically applying filters.&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.instagram.com/reel/DO9MwTHCoR_/?igsh=MTZybml2NDBwbmhxMw%3D%3D" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://www.instagram.com/reel/DO9MwTHCoR_/?igsh=MTZybml2NDB...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;The screenshots/videos of them doing it are pretty wild, and insane they are editing creators' uploads without consent!&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 06 Dec 2025 02:22:14 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46169968</link><dc:creator>randycupertino</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46169968</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46169968</guid></item><item><title>New comment by gyomu in "Leaving Intel"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&gt; "I also supported cloud computing, participating in 110 customer meetings, and created a company-wide strategy to win back the cloud with 33 specific recommendations, in collaboration with others across 6 organizations."&lt;p&gt;Man people keep count of this stuff?! Maybe I should too, it does make flexing easier.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 06 Dec 2025 01:47:51 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46169774</link><dc:creator>gyomu</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46169774</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46169774</guid></item><item><title>New comment by mlsu in "Sam Altman’s DRAM Deal"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Moves like this should be illegal.&lt;p&gt;It's becoming increasingly clear that OpenAI is going to get lapped by Google on technical merits. So this is the "code red" solution? Supply shenanigans?&lt;p&gt;They are getting beat in the developer market by Anthropic. And getting beat on fundamental tech by Google. This is a company whose ostensible mission is to "benefit all of humanity" ...&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 06 Dec 2025 01:02:57 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46169474</link><dc:creator>mlsu</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46169474</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46169474</guid></item></channel></rss>