<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>Hacker News: Best Comments</title><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/bestcomments</link><description>Hacker News RSS</description><docs>https://hnrss.org/</docs><generator>hnrss v2.1.1</generator><lastBuildDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 02:23:52 +0000</lastBuildDate><ns0:link href="https://hnrss.org/bestcomments" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item><title>New comment by input_sh in "France dumps Zoom and Teams as Europe seeks digital autonomy from the US"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Worth pointing out: France is not &lt;i&gt;adopting&lt;/i&gt; existing open source software, they're building their own software and releasing it under the MIT licence. Most of it (or all of it?) is Django backend + React frontend (using a custom-built UI kit).&lt;p&gt;Home page for the entire suite (in French) with some screenshots: &lt;a href="https://lasuite.numerique.gouv.fr/" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://lasuite.numerique.gouv.fr/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;Code bases are on GitHub and they use English there: &lt;a href="https://github.com/suitenumerique/" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://github.com/suitenumerique/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dev handbook (in English): &lt;a href="https://suitenumerique.gitbook.io/handbook" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://suitenumerique.gitbook.io/handbook&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;Not French and I can't say I personally tried deploying any of them, but I've been admiring their efforts from afar for a while now.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2026 19:18:53 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46875837</link><dc:creator>input_sh</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46875837</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46875837</guid></item><item><title>New comment by cedws in "Qwen3-Coder-Next"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I kind of lost interest in local models. Then Anthropic started saying I’m not allowed to use my Claude Code subscription with my preferred tools and it reminded me why we need to support open tools and models. I’ve cancelled my CC subscription, I’m not paying to support anticompetitive behaviour.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2026 17:05:08 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46873708</link><dc:creator>cedws</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46873708</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46873708</guid></item><item><title>New comment by breakyerself in "Banning lead in gas worked. The proof is in our hair"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Almost every environmental regulation has come after it was already shown that there was some harm that needed to be mitigated.&lt;p&gt;The worst environmental crisis in human history is going largely unchecked. I find it hard to take seriously any argument that environmental regulation has gone too far as opposed to not nearly far enough.&lt;p&gt;If there's a specific regulation that can be shown to be doing more harm than good I'm cool with revisiting anything, but the common sense wisdom around environmental regulation has been corrupted by corporate public relations campaigns.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2026 15:48:39 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46872493</link><dc:creator>breakyerself</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46872493</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46872493</guid></item><item><title>New comment by iainmerrick in "Agent Skills"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;This stuff smells like maybe the bitter lesson isn't fully appreciated.&lt;p&gt;You might as well just write instructions in English in any old format, as long as it's comprehensible. Exactly as you'd do for human readers! Nothing has really changed about what constitutes good documentation. &lt;i&gt;(Edit to add: my parochialism is showing there, it doesn't have to be English)&lt;/i&gt;&lt;p&gt;Is any of this standardization really needed? Who does it benefit, except the people who enjoy writing specs and establishing standards like this? If it really is a productivity win, it ought to be possible to run a comparison study and prove it. Even then, it might not be worthwhile in the longer run.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2026 15:09:04 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46871907</link><dc:creator>iainmerrick</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46871907</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46871907</guid></item><item><title>New comment by bgnn in "xAI joins SpaceX"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;The real reason is, Elon has SpaceX and xAI. He can create an illusion of synergy and orders of magnitude advancements to boost the market cap and pocket all the money. He realized long time ago you don't need to deliver to play the market cap game, in fact it's better if you are selling a story far in the future rather than a something you can deliver now.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2026 07:54:14 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46867905</link><dc:creator>bgnn</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46867905</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46867905</guid></item><item><title>New comment by igorramazanov in "Court orders restart of all US offshore wind power construction"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;If a country changes course every four years, how can the success of a long-term project be ensured?&lt;p&gt;And what of its negotiating credibility? How can the other side trust that an agreement will hold in the future?&lt;p&gt;This is not a critique, but a genuine curiosity, because there's an obvious drawback with a system with opposing world views.&lt;p&gt;Unless, of course, something still unites them in the first place, with acceptable disparity on each side turning it into an advantage of flexibility and adaptability while keeping the focus on long-term ideas and plans.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2026 03:37:02 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46866145</link><dc:creator>igorramazanov</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46866145</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46866145</guid></item><item><title>New comment by caseysoftware in "The TSA's New $45 Fee to Fly Without ID Is Illegal"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&gt; &lt;i&gt;So it was never about security at all then, was it?&lt;/i&gt;&lt;p&gt;Never was.&lt;p&gt;I flew every other week prior to covid and haven't once been through the scanners. For the first ~6 years, I opted out and got pat down over and over again.&lt;p&gt;Then I realized I could even skip that.&lt;p&gt;Now at the checkpoint, I stand at the metal detector. When they wave me to the scanner, I say "I can't raise my arms over my head." They wave me through the metal detector, swab my hands, and I'm done. I usually make it through before my bags.&lt;p&gt;Sometimes, a TSA moron asks "why not?" and I simply say "are you asking me to share my personal healthcare information out loud in front of a bunch of strangers? Are you a medical professional?" and they back down.&lt;p&gt;Other times, they've asked "can you raise them at least this high?" and kind of motion. I ask "are you asking me to potentially injure myself for your curiosity? are you going to pay for any injuries or pain I suffer?"&lt;p&gt;The TSA was NEVER about security. It was designed as a jobs program and make it look like we were doing something for security.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2026 01:16:05 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46864953</link><dc:creator>caseysoftware</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46864953</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46864953</guid></item><item><title>New comment by rainsford in "xAI joins SpaceX"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;We also shouldn't overlook the fact that the proposal entirely glosses over the implication of the alternative benefits we might realize if humanity achieved the incredible engineering and technical capacity necessary to make this version of space AI happen.&lt;p&gt;Think about it.  Elon conjures up a vision of the future where we've managed to increase our solar cell manufacturing capacity by two whole orders of magnitude and have the space launch capability for all of it along with tons and tons of other stuff and the best he comes up with is...GPUs in orbit?&lt;p&gt;This is essentially the superhero gadget technology problem, where comic books and movies gloss over the the civilization changing implications of some technology the hero invents to punch bad guys harder.  Don't get me wrong, the idea of orbiting data centers is kind of cool if we can pull it off.  But being &lt;i&gt;able&lt;/i&gt; to pull if off implies an ability to do a lot more interesting things.  The problem is that this is both wildly overambitious and somehow incredibly myopic at the same time.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2026 00:24:23 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46864455</link><dc:creator>rainsford</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46864455</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46864455</guid></item><item><title>New comment by crystal_revenge in "xAI joins SpaceX"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Because this move is entirely financial engineering to hide losses just like the roll up of X in to xAI.&lt;p&gt;None of this has anything to do with business or innovation. Do you not immediately see that? Most of my friends reaction to this news was that this is so obvious it's almost funny (or actually it &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; funny, since most were laughing as they read the headline).&lt;p&gt;I'm curious how you could &lt;i&gt;not&lt;/i&gt; understand the relevance of the quote unless you were aggressively trying to not understanding it.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 23:58:09 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46864179</link><dc:creator>crystal_revenge</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46864179</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46864179</guid></item><item><title>New comment by n_u in "xAI joins SpaceX"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;A former NASA engineer with a PhD in space electronics who later worked at Google for 10 years wrote an article about why datacenters in space are very technically challenging:&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://taranis.ie/datacenters-in-space-are-a-terrible-horrible-no-good-idea/" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://taranis.ie/datacenters-in-space-are-a-terrible-horri...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;I don't have any specialized knowledge of the physics but I saw an article suggesting the real reason for the push to build them in space is to hedge against political pushback preventing construction on Earth.&lt;p&gt;I can't find the original article but here is one about datacenter pushback:&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/opinion/articles/2025-08-20/ai-and-crypto-data-centers-are-nimbys-new-target" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://www.bloomberg.com/opinion/articles/2025-08-20/ai-and...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;But even if political pushback on Earth is the real reason, it still seems datacenters in space are extremely technically challenging/impossible to build.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 23:40:58 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46863941</link><dc:creator>n_u</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46863941</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46863941</guid></item><item><title>New comment by paxys in "The TSA's New $45 Fee to Fly Without ID Is Illegal"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;It's hilarious how transparent a money grab this entire thing is.&lt;p&gt;"You need to show a Real ID for security, otherwise how do we know you won't hijack the plane?"&lt;p&gt;"Well I don't have a Real ID."&lt;p&gt;"Ok then, give us $45 and you can go through."&lt;p&gt;So it was never about security at all then, was it?&lt;p&gt;And don't get me started with all the paid express security lanes. Because of course only poor people can weaponize shoes and laptops.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 23:40:20 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46863932</link><dc:creator>paxys</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46863932</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46863932</guid></item><item><title>New comment by eduardogarza in "xAI joins SpaceX"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;From the Big Short (movie)&lt;p&gt;Jared Vennett (narration):
"In the years that followed, hundreds of bankers and rating agency's executives went to jail. The SEC was completely overhauled, and Congress had no choice but to break up the big banks and regulate the mortgage and derivatives industries."&lt;p&gt;"Just kidding. Banks took the money the American people gave them, and they used it to pay themselves huge bonuses, and lobby the Congress to kill big reform. And then they blamed immigrants and poor people, and this time even teachers."&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 23:31:30 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46863811</link><dc:creator>eduardogarza</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46863811</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46863811</guid></item><item><title>New comment by softwaredoug in "Court orders restart of all US offshore wind power construction"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;If these projects ultimately end up canceled they’ll be the largest “mostly done” infrastructure projects to be cancelled. A huge waste. And a monument to US incompetency.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 23:22:12 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46863690</link><dc:creator>softwaredoug</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46863690</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46863690</guid></item><item><title>New comment by AndyKelley in "Zig Libc"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;The very same day I sat at home writing this devlog like a coward, less than five miles away, armed forces who are in my city against the will of our elected officials shot tear gas, unprovoked, at peaceful protestors, including my wife.&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.kptv.com/2026/01/31/live-labor-unions-rally-march-portland-ice-facility-protest/" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://www.kptv.com/2026/01/31/live-labor-unions-rally-marc...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;This isn't some hypothetical political agenda I'm using my platform to push. There's a nonzero chance I go out there next weekend to peacefully protest, and get shot like Alex Pretti.&lt;p&gt;Needless to say, if I get shot by ICE, it's not good for the Zig project. And they've brought the battle to my doorstep, almost literally.&lt;p&gt;Abolish ICE.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 23:20:17 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46863669</link><dc:creator>AndyKelley</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46863669</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46863669</guid></item><item><title>New comment by darth_avocado in "xAI joins SpaceX"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;He buys twitter at an inflated valuation. Runs it to the ground to a much lower valuation of $9B. [1] Then, his company Xai buys Twitter at a $33B, inflating the valuation up. Then SpaceX merges with Xai for no particular reason, but is expected to IPO at a $1T+ in the upcoming years. [3]&lt;p&gt;I’m not that smart, but if I were, I would be thinking this is an extended way to move the losses from the Twitter purchase on to the public markets.&lt;p&gt;[1] &lt;a href="https://www.axios.com/2023/12/31/elon-musks-x-fidelity-valuation-cut" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://www.axios.com/2023/12/31/elon-musks-x-fidelity-valua...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;[2] &lt;a href="https://www.reuters.com/markets/deals/musks-xai-buys-social-media-platform-x-45-billion-2025-03-28/" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://www.reuters.com/markets/deals/musks-xai-buys-social-...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;[3] &lt;a href="https://www.cnbc.com/amp/2026/02/02/elon-musk-spacex-xai-ipo.html" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://www.cnbc.com/amp/2026/02/02/elon-musk-spacex-xai-ipo...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 22:37:08 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46862979</link><dc:creator>darth_avocado</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46862979</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46862979</guid></item><item><title>New comment by paxys in "xAI joins SpaceX"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Just a neat bit of financial engineering. You can tell because Elon picked SpaceX instead of Tesla – which would have actually made sense at some level (Optimus Robots + AI). But Tesla is public and so he'd need to follow laws and reporting requirements.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 22:23:42 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46862731</link><dc:creator>paxys</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46862731</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46862731</guid></item><item><title>New comment by senko in "xAI joins SpaceX"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;As a SpaceX fan, I am saddened by this news.&lt;p&gt;The only reason for xAI to join SpaceX is to offload Elon's Twitter debt in the upcoming IPO.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 22:22:17 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46862710</link><dc:creator>senko</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46862710</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46862710</guid></item><item><title>New comment by alangibson in "xAI joins SpaceX"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Either this is a straight up con, or Musk found a glitch in physics. It's extremely difficult to keep things cold in space.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 22:13:48 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46862572</link><dc:creator>alangibson</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46862572</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46862572</guid></item><item><title>New comment by rybosworld in "xAI joins SpaceX"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&gt; The basic math is that launching a million tons per year of satellites generating 100 kW of compute power per ton would add 100 gigawatts of AI compute capacity annually, with no ongoing operational or maintenance needs. Ultimately, there is a path to launching 1 TW/year from Earth.&lt;p&gt;&gt; My estimate is that within 2 to 3 years, the lowest cost way to generate AI compute will be in space.&lt;p&gt;This is so obviously false. For one thing, in what fantasy world would the ongoing operational and maintenance needs be 0?&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 22:10:52 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46862510</link><dc:creator>rybosworld</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46862510</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46862510</guid></item><item><title>New comment by Buttons840 in "xAI joins SpaceX"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;SpaceX is too big to fail. It's important for national security.&lt;p&gt;I wonder if Elon wants to tangle all his businesses into SpaceX so they are all kept afloat by SpaceX's importance.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 22:07:23 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46862456</link><dc:creator>Buttons840</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46862456</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46862456</guid></item><item><title>New comment by gok in "xAI joins SpaceX"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&gt; it is possible to put 500 to 1000 TW/year of AI satellites into deep space, meaningfully ascend the Kardashev scale and harness a non-trivial percentage of the Sun’s power&lt;p&gt;We currently make around 1 TW of photovoltaic cells per year, globally. The proposal here is to launch that much to space every 9 hours, complete with attached computers, continuously, from the moon.&lt;p&gt;edit: Also, this would capture a very trivial percentage of the Sun's power. A few trillionths per year.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 22:06:22 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46862435</link><dc:creator>gok</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46862435</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46862435</guid></item><item><title>New comment by OlympicMarmoto in "The Codex App"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;It is baffling how these AI companies, with billions of dollars, cannot build native applications, even with the help of AI. From a UI perspective, these are mostly just chat apps, which are not particularly difficult to code from scratch. Before the usual excuses come about how it is impossible to build a custom UI, consider software that is orders of magnitude more complex, such as raddbg, 10x, Superluminal, Blender, Godot, Unity, and UE5, or any video game with a UI. On top of that, programs like Claude Cowork or Codex should, by design, integrate as deeply with the OS as possible. This requires calling native APIs (e.g., Win32), which is not feasible from Electron.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 21:31:37 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46861884</link><dc:creator>OlympicMarmoto</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46861884</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46861884</guid></item><item><title>New comment by OsamaJaber in "Todd C. Miller – Sudo maintainer for over 30 years"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;30+ years maintaining one of the most critical pieces of infrastructure on nearly every Linux and Unix system, and he's currently looking for a sponsor to fund continued development. Every company running sudo in production owes this man. Someone should fix that&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 18:16:13 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46859228</link><dc:creator>OsamaJaber</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46859228</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46859228</guid></item><item><title>New comment by marssaxman in "Claude Code is suddenly everywhere inside Microsoft"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&gt; Microsoft really needs to get a better handle with the naming conventions.&lt;p&gt;They really won't, though; Microsoft just &lt;i&gt;does&lt;/i&gt; this kind of thing, over and over and over. Before everything was named "365", it was all "One", before that it was "Live"... 20 years ago, everything was called ".NET" whether it had anything to do with the Internet or not. Back in the '90s they went crazy for a while calling everything "Active".&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 17:47:25 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46858855</link><dc:creator>marssaxman</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46858855</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46858855</guid></item><item><title>New comment by jFriedensreich in "Waymo seeking about $16B near $110B valuation"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;No product had such a fast transition from novelty to "omg i never want to interact with a human again". I feel about 100% less stressed and happier using a waymo or riding motorbike or bicycle next to a waymo than with human drivers. I hope this next phase will bring availability and prices down. We need this in europe.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 16:04:07 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46857536</link><dc:creator>jFriedensreich</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46857536</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46857536</guid></item><item><title>New comment by kemotep in "Claude Code is suddenly everywhere inside Microsoft"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Microsoft really needs to get a better handle with the naming conventions.&lt;p&gt;There is Microsoft Copilot, which replaced Bing Chat, Cortana and uses OpenAI’s GPT-4 and 5 models.&lt;p&gt;There is Github Copilot, the coding autocomplete tool.&lt;p&gt;There is Microsoft 365 Copilot, what they now call Office with built in GenAI stuff.&lt;p&gt;There is also a Copilot cli that lets you use whatever agent/model backend you want too?&lt;p&gt;Everything is Copilot. Laptops sell with Copilot buttons now.&lt;p&gt;It is not immediately clear what version of Copilot someone is talking about. 99% of my experience is with the Office and it 100% fails to do the thing it was advertised to do 2 years ago when work initially got the subscription. Point it a SharePoint/OneDrive location, a handful of excel spreadsheets and pdfs/word docs and tell it to make a PowerPoint presentation based on that information.&lt;p&gt;It cannot do this. It will spit out nonsense. You have to hold it by the hand tell it everything to do step by step to the point that making the PowerPoint presentation yourself is significantly faster because you don’t have to type out a bunch of prompts and edit it’s garbage output.&lt;p&gt;And now it’s clear they aren’t even dogfooding their own LLM products so why should anyone pay for Copilot?&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 15:31:05 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46857117</link><dc:creator>kemotep</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46857117</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46857117</guid></item><item><title>New comment by tylerchilds in "Claude Code is suddenly everywhere inside Microsoft"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;This is funny because everyone’s AI strategy should have been&lt;p&gt;“What do we actually need to be productive?”&lt;p&gt;Which is how Anthropic pulled ahead of Microsoft, that prioritized&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;checks notes&lt;/i&gt;&lt;p&gt;Taking screenshots of every windows user’s desktop every few seconds. For productivity.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 15:28:28 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46857092</link><dc:creator>tylerchilds</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46857092</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46857092</guid></item><item><title>New comment by PunchyHamster in "Two kinds of AI users are emerging"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I'd argue 2 types of users are&lt;p&gt;* People using it as a tool, aware of its limitations and treating it basically as  intern/boring task executor (whether its some code boilerplate, or pooping out/shortening some corporate email), or as tool to give themselves summary of topic they can then bite into deeper.&lt;p&gt;* People outsourcing thinking and entire skillset to it - they usually have very little clue in the topic, are interested only in results, and are not interested in knowing more about the topic or honing their skills in the topic&lt;p&gt;The second group is one that thinks talking to a chatbot will replace senior developer&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 08:27:01 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46853721</link><dc:creator>PunchyHamster</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46853721</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46853721</guid></item><item><title>New comment by ryandrake in "Notepad++ hijacked by state-sponsored actors"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Similar comments also come up in the [now regular] "I don't want to see political articles on HN" threads, and I think the response is similar: Asking for "no politics" is itself a strong political view: One in support/service of whatever the current status quo is. Trying to set oneself apart from (or above) politics is itself political. If you're lucky enough to be one of the fortunate people on earth who are not under attack by political forces or who benefit from status quo politics, I'd encourage you to simply reflect on that good luck and try to ignore the "politics" that others are deeply affected by and care about.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 02:49:36 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46851842</link><dc:creator>ryandrake</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46851842</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46851842</guid></item><item><title>New comment by danpalmer in "Two kinds of AI users are emerging"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I've noticed a huge gap between AI use on greenfield projects and brownfield projects. The first day of working on a greenfield project I can accomplish a week of work. But the second day I can accomplish a few days of work. By the end of the first week I'm getting a 20% productivity gain.&lt;p&gt;I think AI is just allowing everyone to speed-run the innovator's dilemma. Anyone can create a small version of anything, while big orgs will struggle to move quickly as before.&lt;p&gt;The interesting bit is going to be whether we see AI being used in maturing those small systems into big complex ones that account for the edge cases, meet all the requirements, scale as needed, etc. That's hard for humans to do, and particularly while still moving. I've not see any of this from AI yet outside of either a) very directed small changes to large complex systems, or b) plugins/extensions/etc along a well define set of rails.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 01:44:03 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46851425</link><dc:creator>danpalmer</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46851425</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46851425</guid></item></channel></rss>