<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>Hacker News: Best Comments</title><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/bestcomments</link><description>Hacker News RSS</description><docs>https://hnrss.org/</docs><generator>hnrss v2.1.1</generator><lastBuildDate>Wed, 03 Sep 2025 23:46:01 +0000</lastBuildDate><ns0:link href="https://hnrss.org/bestcomments" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item><title>New comment by jelder in "Airbus B612 Cockpit Font"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;What it actually looks like: &lt;a href="https://fonts.google.com/specimen/B612" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://fonts.google.com/specimen/B612&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 03 Sep 2025 15:07:27 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45116692</link><dc:creator>jelder</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45116692</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45116692</guid></item><item><title>New comment by goalieca in "MIT Study Finds AI Use Reprograms the Brain, Leading to Cognitive Decline"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Anecdote here, but when I was in grad school, I was talking to a PhD student i respected a lot. Whenever he read a paper, he would try to write the code out and get it working. I would take a couple of months but he could whip it up in a few days. He explained to me that it was just practice and the more you practice the better you become. He not only coded things quickly, he started analyzing papers quicker too and became really good at synthesizing ideas, knowing what worked and didn't, and built up a phenomenal intuition.&lt;p&gt;These days, I'm fairly senior and don't touch code much anymore but I find it really really instructive to get my hands dirty and struggle through new code and ideas. I think the "just tweak the prompts bro" people are missing out on learning.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 03 Sep 2025 13:57:28 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45115887</link><dc:creator>goalieca</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45115887</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45115887</guid></item><item><title>New comment by ot in "%CPU utilization is a lie"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Utilization is not a lie, it is a measurement of a well-defined quantity, but people make assumptions to extrapolate capacity models from it, and that is where reality diverges from expectations.&lt;p&gt;Hyperthreading (SMT) and Turbo (clock scaling) are only a part of the variables causing non-linearity, there are a number of other resources that are shared across cores and "run out" as load increases, like memory bandwidth, interconnect capacity, processor caches. Some bottlenecks might come even from the software, like spinlocks, which have non-linear impact on utilization.&lt;p&gt;Furthermore, most CPU utilization metrics average over very long windows, from several seconds to a minute, but what really matters for the performance of a latency-sensitive server happens in the time-scale of tens to hundreds of milliseconds, and a multi-second average will not distinguish a bursty behavior from a smooth one. The latter has likely much more capacity to scale up.&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, the suggested approach is not that accurate either, because it hinges on two inherently unstable concepts&lt;p&gt;&gt; Benchmark how much work your server can do before having errors or unacceptable latency.&lt;p&gt;The measurement of this is extremely noisy, as you want to detect the point where the server starts becoming unstable. Even if you look at a very simple queueing theory model, the derivatives close to saturation explode, so any nondeterministic noise is extremely amplified.&lt;p&gt;&gt; Report how much work your server is currently doing.&lt;p&gt;There is rarely a stable definition of "work". Is it RPS? Request cost can vary even throughout the day. Is it instructions? Same, the typical IPC can vary.&lt;p&gt;Ultimately, the confidence intervals you get from the load testing approach might be as large as what you can get from building an empirical model from utilization measurement, as long as you measure your utilization correctly.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 03 Sep 2025 00:49:21 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45111036</link><dc:creator>ot</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45111036</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45111036</guid></item><item><title>New comment by supernova87a in "Google can keep its Chrome browser but will be barred from exclusive contracts"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;By the way, a pet peeve of mine right now is that reporters covering court cases (and we have so many of public interest lately) never seem to simply paste the link to the online PDF decision/ruling for us all to read, right in the story.  (and another user here kindly did that for us below: &lt;a href="https://storage.courtlistener.com/recap/gov.uscourts.dcd.223205/gov.uscourts.dcd.223205.1436.0_1.pdf" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://storage.courtlistener.com/recap/gov.uscourts.dcd.223...&lt;/a&gt; )&lt;p&gt;It seems such a simple step (they must have been using the ruling PDF to write the story) yet why is it always such a hassle for them to feel that they should link the original content?  I would rather be able to see the probably dozens of pages ruling with the full details rather than hear it secondhand from a reporter at this point.  It feels like they want to be the gatekeepers of information, and poor ones at that.&lt;p&gt;I think it should be adopted as standard journalistic practice in fact -- reporting on court rulings must come with the PDF.&lt;p&gt;Aside from that, it will be interesting to see on what grounds the judge decided that this particular data sharing remedy was the solution. Can anyone now simply claim they're a competitor and get access to Google's tons of data?&lt;p&gt;I am not too familiar with antitrust precedent, but to what extent does the judge rule on how specific the data sharing need to be (what types of data, for what time span, how anonymized, etc. etc.) or appoint a special master?   Why is that up to the judge versus the FTC or whoever to propose?&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 02 Sep 2025 21:30:17 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45109304</link><dc:creator>supernova87a</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45109304</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45109304</guid></item><item><title>New comment by fidotron in "Google can keep its Chrome browser but will be barred from exclusive contracts"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;This is an astonishing victory for Google, they must be very happy about it.&lt;p&gt;They get basically everything they want (keeping it all in the tent), plus a negotiating position on search deals where they can refuse something because they can't do it now.&lt;p&gt;Quite why the judge is so concerned about the rise of AI factoring in here is beyond me. It's fundamentally an anticompetitive decision.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 02 Sep 2025 21:05:17 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45109040</link><dc:creator>fidotron</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45109040</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45109040</guid></item><item><title>New comment by shayway in "Amazon must face US nationwide class action over third-party sales"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&gt; Amazon argued that the class was too large to be manageable&lt;p&gt;Sorry, we've wronged too many people to be held accountable! What a wild argument.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 02 Sep 2025 20:16:45 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45108426</link><dc:creator>shayway</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45108426</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45108426</guid></item><item><title>New comment by AlexandrB in "Anthropic raises $13B Series F"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;The whole LLM era is horrible. All the innovation is coming "top-down" from very well funded companies - many of them tech incumbents, so you &lt;i&gt;know&lt;/i&gt; the monetization is going to be awful. Since the models are expensive to run it's all subscription priced and has to run in the cloud where the user has no control. The hype is insane, and so usage is being pushed by C-suite folks who have no idea whether it's actually benefiting someone "on the ground" and decisions around &lt;i&gt;which&lt;/i&gt; AI to use are often being made on the basis of existing vendor relationships. Basically it's the culmination of all the worst tech trends of the last 10 years.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 02 Sep 2025 18:38:54 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45107239</link><dc:creator>AlexandrB</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45107239</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45107239</guid></item><item><title>New comment by Bukhmanizer in "We already live in social credit, we just don't call it that"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;The issue is that American media/discourse paints a very distorted view of what life under authoritarian rule is like. The truth is in many countries, unless you’re some kind of minority, politically active, or in legal trouble, day-to-day life is mostly similar to life in the west. But people don’t want to hear that, because we want to feel &lt;i&gt;better&lt;/i&gt; than them. Like we wouldn’t tolerate that kind of life.&lt;p&gt;Of course the most frustrating part about that is as the US and other western countries start sliding into authoritarianism, people deny it because they don’t &lt;i&gt;feel&lt;/i&gt; like it’s authoritarian.&lt;p&gt;Edit: To clarify, I don’t think life is exactly the same - just that the consequences of authoritarianism are much more insidious than they’re portrayed.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 02 Sep 2025 18:26:09 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45107075</link><dc:creator>Bukhmanizer</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45107075</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45107075</guid></item><item><title>New comment by atomicnumber3 in "Python has had async for 10 years – why isn't it more popular?"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;The author gets close to what I think the root problem is, but doesn't call it out.&lt;p&gt;The truth is that in python, async was too little, too late. By the time it was introduced, most people who actually needed to do lots of io concurrently had their own workarounds (forking, etc) and people who didn't actually need it had found out how to get by without it (multiprocessing etc).&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile, go showed us what good green threads can look like. Then java did it too. Meanwhile, js had better async support the whole time. But all it did was show us that async code just plain sucks compared to green thread code that can just block, instead of having to do the async dances.&lt;p&gt;So, why engage with it when you already had good solutions?&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 02 Sep 2025 17:41:21 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45106455</link><dc:creator>atomicnumber3</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45106455</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45106455</guid></item><item><title>New comment by Y_Y in "The staff ate it later"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&gt; Then Pharaoh also called for the wise men and the sorcerers, and they also, the magicians of Egypt, did the same with their secret arts. For each one threw down his staff and they turned into serpents. But Aaron’s staff swallowed up their staffs.&lt;p&gt;- Exodus 7:1-12 (NIV)&lt;p&gt;Many moons ago I had a girlfriend who worked on an nationally broadcast afternoon show where they often had guest chefs demonstrating dishes, so I would come home from my thankless PhD work to eat Michelin-starred food from a lunchbox. Overall not so bad.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 02 Sep 2025 17:00:12 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45105801</link><dc:creator>Y_Y</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45105801</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45105801</guid></item><item><title>New comment by llamasushi in "Anthropic raises $13B Series F"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;The compute moat is getting absolutely insane. We're basically at the point where you need a small country's GDP just to stay in the game for one more generation of models.&lt;p&gt;What gets me is that this isn't even a software moat anymore - it's literally just whoever can get their hands on enough GPUs and power infrastructure. TSMC and the power companies are the real kingmakers here. You can have all the talent in the world but if you can't get 100k H100s and a dedicated power plant, you're out.&lt;p&gt;Wonder how much of this $13B is just prepaying for compute vs actual opex. If it's mostly compute, we're watching something weird happen - like the privatization of Manhattan Project-scale infrastructure. Except instead of enriching uranium we're computing gradient descents lol&lt;p&gt;The wildest part is we might look back at this as cheap. GPT-4 training was what, $100M? GPT-5/Opus-4 class probably $1B+? At this rate GPT-7 will need its own sovereign wealth fund&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 02 Sep 2025 16:29:33 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45105325</link><dc:creator>llamasushi</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45105325</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45105325</guid></item><item><title>New comment by Centigonal in "You don't want to hire "the best engineers""</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;There is no such thing as "the best engineers." Some engineers are definitely better than others, but once you pass the bar of "really smart, great work ethic," the tech tree diverges pretty dramatically.&lt;p&gt;Some engineers (like Notch) are amazing at quickly putting out vast quantities of mediocre code, prototyping ideas, maintaining a clear product vision, and bringing something into reality quickly. Other engineers (like John Carmack) are great at generating well-founded opinions and finding clever solutions to difficult issues. Some engineers (like Bill Atkinson) worked mostly remotely and developed amazing technology, while other engineers (like Joel Spolsky) insisted on in-office and built a best-in-class mentorship organization.&lt;p&gt;While hiring people with exceptional talent is a step-change when it comes to any organization's ability to accomplish its goals, there is no one metric for "best." Much better to identify the specific skills for which you need exceptional talent, and to create a hiring funnel that identifies people who excel in that dimension.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 02 Sep 2025 15:31:14 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45104389</link><dc:creator>Centigonal</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45104389</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45104389</guid></item><item><title>New comment by YuukiRey in "Next.js is infuriating"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I 100% agree. I've ran into the same issues, and I would never use Next.js for anything, and I will encourage every team at work to use something else.&lt;p&gt;In general Next.js has so many layers of abstraction that 99.9999% of projects don't need. And the ones that do are probably better off building a bespoke solution from lower level parts.&lt;p&gt;Next.js is easily the worst technology I've ever used.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 02 Sep 2025 10:04:35 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45101009</link><dc:creator>YuukiRey</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45101009</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45101009</guid></item><item><title>New comment by shawabawa3 in "We should have the ability to run any code we want on hardware we own"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&gt; If you decide you don't want a relationship with either of those companies you will be extremely disadvantaged.&lt;p&gt;Even more worrying is the inverse of this - if Google and/or Apple decide for whatever reason they don't want a relationship with you (aka they ban you for no reason) - you are completely screwed&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2025 13:15:52 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45092481</link><dc:creator>shawabawa3</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45092481</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45092481</guid></item><item><title>New comment by kristov in "We should have the ability to run any code we want on hardware we own"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I think the conversation needs to change from "can't run software of our choice" to "can't participate in society without an apple or google account". I have been living with a de-googled android phone for a number of years, and it is getting harder and harder, while at the same time operating without certain "apps" is becoming more difficult.&lt;p&gt;For example, by bank (abn amro) still allows online banking on desktop via a physical auth device, but they are actively pushing for login only via their app. I called their support line for a lost card, and had to go through to second level support because I didn't have the app. If they get their way, eventually an apple or google account will be mandatory to have a bank account with them.&lt;p&gt;My kid goes to a school that outsourced all communication via an app. They have a web version, but it's barely usable. The app doesn't run without certain google libs installed. Again, to participate in school communication about my kid effectively requires an apple or google account.&lt;p&gt;I feel like the conversation we should be having is that we are sleepwalking into a world where to participate in society you must have an account with either apple or google. If you decide you don't want a relationship with either of those companies you will be extremely disadvantaged.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2025 13:05:38 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45092413</link><dc:creator>kristov</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45092413</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45092413</guid></item><item><title>New comment by zmmmmm in "We should have the ability to run any code we want on hardware we own"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&gt; In this context this would mean having the ability and documentation to build or install alternative operating systems on this hardware&lt;p&gt;It doesn't work. Everything from banks to Netflix and others are slowly edging out anything where they can't fully verify the chain of control to an entity they can have a legal or contractual relationship with. To be clear, this is fundamental, not incidental. You can't run your own operating system because it's not in Netflix's financial interest for you to do so. Or your banks, or your government. They all benefit from you not having control, so you can't.&lt;p&gt;This is why it's so important to defend the real principles here not just the technical artefacts of them. Netflix shouldn't be able to insist on a particular type of DRM for me to receive their service. Governments shouldn't be able to prevent me from end to end encrypting things. I should be able to opt into all this if I want more security, but it can't be mandatory. However all of these things are not technical, they are principles and rights that we have to argue for.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2025 02:51:16 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45088995</link><dc:creator>zmmmmm</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45088995</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45088995</guid></item><item><title>New comment by m463 in "Is it possible to allow sideloading and keep users safe?"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;"sideloading" connotates something that is negative.&lt;p&gt;On systems before apple's locked-down iphone, it was just called "installing".&lt;p&gt;The PC revolution started with people just inserting their software into the comptuer and running it.  You didn't have to ask the computer manufacturer or the OS vendor permission to do it.&lt;p&gt;And note that apple doesn't allow you to protect yourself.  You cannot install a firewall and block arbitrary software on your phone.  For example, you can not block apple telemetry.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 31 Aug 2025 05:39:19 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45080628</link><dc:creator>m463</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45080628</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45080628</guid></item><item><title>New comment by lazarus01 in "Six months into tariffs, businesses have no idea how to price anything"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;In NYC, for the first 6 months of 2025, 994 new private sector jobs were created [1].  During the same period last year, there were 66,000 new jobs created.&lt;p&gt;Higher cost of doing business from tariffs has frozen hiring.  With a frozen job market, there’s less revenue coming in.&lt;p&gt;NYC is a leading indicator for the rest of the country.&lt;p&gt;[1] &lt;a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2025/08/13/nyregion/nyc-jobs.html" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://www.nytimes.com/2025/08/13/nyregion/nyc-jobs.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 30 Aug 2025 22:32:14 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45078568</link><dc:creator>lazarus01</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45078568</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45078568</guid></item><item><title>New comment by michael1999 in "FBI cyber cop: Salt Typhoon pwned 'nearly every American'"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;The security community warned that making Lawful Access easy and automated would guarantee that bad people would penetrate the network.&lt;p&gt;And now we have China using CALEA-crippled systems to slurp up the entire USA network.  Exactly as predicted.&lt;p&gt;And this - "outside of the norms of what we see in the espionage space" - LOL.  ROTFL even.  The NSA tapped Google's backbone!  Have we forgotten Room 641A? MAINWAY? Poindexter and TIA?  Palantir?&lt;p&gt;The NSA used to play defence and offence, and has gone full-offence for a generation.  Did anyone really believe that only the USA could play offence?&lt;p&gt;Morons.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 30 Aug 2025 15:52:28 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45075658</link><dc:creator>michael1999</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45075658</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45075658</guid></item><item><title>New comment by sodapopcan in "Do the simplest thing that could possibly work"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;This is the classic misunderstanding where software engineers can't seem to communicate well with each other.&lt;p&gt;We can even just look at the title here: Do the simplest thing POSSIBLE.&lt;p&gt;You can't escape complexity when a problem is complex.  You could certainly still complicate it even more than necessary, though.  Nowhere in this article is it saying you can avoid complexity altogether, but that many of us tend to over-complicate problems for no good reason.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 29 Aug 2025 22:30:05 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45070127</link><dc:creator>sodapopcan</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45070127</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45070127</guid></item><item><title>New comment by codingwagie in "Do the simplest thing that could possibly work"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I think this works in simple domains. After working in big tech for a while, I am still shocked by the required complexity. Even the simplest business problem may take a year to solve, and constantly break due to the astounding number of edge cases and scale.&lt;p&gt;Anyone proclaiming simplicity just hasnt worked at scale. Even rewrites that have a decade old code base to be inspired from, often fail due to the sheer amount of things to consider.&lt;p&gt;A classic, Chesterton's Fence:&lt;p&gt;"There exists in such a case a certain institution or law; let us say, for the sake of simplicity, a fence or gate erected across a road. The more modern type of reformer goes gaily up to it and says, “I don’t see the use of this; let us clear it away.” To which the more intelligent type of reformer will do well to answer: “If you don’t see the use of it, I certainly won’t let you clear it away. Go away and think. Then, when you can come back and tell me that you do see the use of it, I may allow you to destroy it.”"&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 29 Aug 2025 20:39:02 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45069135</link><dc:creator>codingwagie</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45069135</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45069135</guid></item><item><title>New comment by NitpickLawyer in "Grok Code Fast 1"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Tested this yesterday with Cline. It's fast, works well with agentic flows, and produces decent code. No idea why this thread is so negative (also got flagged while I was typing this?) but it's a decent model. I'd say it's at or above gpt5-mini level, which is awesome in my book (I've been maining gpt5-mini for a few weeks now, does the job on a budget).&lt;p&gt;Things I noted:&lt;p&gt;- It's fast. I tested it in EU tz, so ymmv&lt;p&gt;- It does agentic in an interesting way. Instead of editing a file whole or in many places, it does many small passes.&lt;p&gt;- Had a feature take ~110k tokens (parsing html w/ bs4). Still finished the task. Didn't notice any problems at high context.&lt;p&gt;- When things didn't work first try, it created a &lt;i&gt;new&lt;/i&gt; file to test, did all the mocking / testing there, and then once it worked edited the main module file. Nice. GPT5-mini would often times edit working files, and then get confused and fail the task.&lt;p&gt;All in all, not bad. At the price point it's at, I could see it as a daily driver. Even agentic stuff w/ opus + gpt5 high as planners and this thing as an implementer. It's fast enough that it might be worth setting it up in parallel and basically replicate pass@x from research.&lt;p&gt;IMO it's good to have options at every level. Having many providers fight for the market is good, it keeps them on their toes, and brings prices down. GPT5-mini is at 2$/MTok, this is at 1.5$/MTok. This is basically "free", in the great scheme of things. I ndon't get the negativity.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 29 Aug 2025 16:20:12 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45066063</link><dc:creator>NitpickLawyer</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45066063</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45066063</guid></item><item><title>New comment by jp57 in "Flunking my Anthropic interview again"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;One great piece of advice an informal mentor gave me long ago is that &lt;i&gt;there is no information in a rejection&lt;/i&gt;.&lt;p&gt;That is to say that you cannot draw any conclusions about yourself or your interviewing technique or your skills or anything from the single &lt;i&gt;accept==0&lt;/i&gt; bit that you typically get back.  There are so many reasons that a candidate might get rejected that have nothing to do with one's individual performance in the interview or application process.&lt;p&gt;Having been on the hiring side of the interview table now many more times than on the seeking side, I can say that this is totally true.&lt;p&gt;One of the biggest misconceptions I see from job seekers, especially younger ones, is to equate a job interview to a test at school, assuming that there is some objective bar and if you pass it then you &lt;i&gt;must&lt;/i&gt; be hired.  It's simply not true.  Frequently more than one good applicant applies for a single open role, and the hiring team has to choose among them.   In that case, you could "pass" and still not get the job and the only reason is that the hiring team liked someone else better.&lt;p&gt;I can only think of one instance where we had two great candidates for one role and management found a way to open another role so we could hire both.  In a few other cases, we had people whom we liked but didn't choose and we forwarded their resumes to other teams who had open roles we thought would fit, but most of the time it's just, "sorry."&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 29 Aug 2025 15:22:01 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45065311</link><dc:creator>jp57</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45065311</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45065311</guid></item><item><title>New comment by nomilk in "Some users have noticed settings that let Meta analyze and retain phone photos"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;IMO Apple should provide the user with audit logs of which photos/videos were accessed by each app. It might be a long list but it alleviates doubt and would put huge pressure on reputable developers to ensure they don’t get caught doing things the user wouldn’t have expected (even if the user technically allowed it).&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 29 Aug 2025 12:37:58 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45063289</link><dc:creator>nomilk</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45063289</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45063289</guid></item><item><title>New comment by metaphor in "Tesla said it didn't have key data in a fatal crash, then a hacker found it"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&gt; &lt;i&gt;Immediately after the wreck at 9:14 p.m. on April 25, 2019, the crucial data detailing how it unfolded was automatically uploaded to the company’s servers and stored in a vast central database, according to court documents. Tesla’s headquarters soon sent an automated message back to the car confirming that it had received the collision snapshot.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;p&gt;&gt; &lt;i&gt;Moments later, court records show, the data was just as automatically “unlinked” from the 2019 Tesla Model S at the scene, meaning the local copy was marked for deletion, a standard practice for Teslas in such incidents, according to court testimony.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;p&gt;Wow...just wow.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 29 Aug 2025 12:25:22 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45063162</link><dc:creator>metaphor</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45063162</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45063162</guid></item><item><title>New comment by bdd8f1df777b in "Ask HN: The government of my country blocked VPN access. What should I use?"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;If you need to bypass censorship, you'll need a tool specifically designed for anti-censorship, rather than any one repurposed for that.&lt;p&gt;Since China has the most advanced network censorship, the Chinese have also invented the most advanced anti-censorship tools.&lt;p&gt;The first generation is shadowsocks. It basically encrypts the traffic from the beginning without any handshakes, so DPI cannot find out its nature. This is very simple and fast and should suffice in most places.&lt;p&gt;The second generation is the Trojan protocol. The lack of a handshake in shadowsocks is also a distinguishing feature that may alert the censor and the censor can decide to block shadowsocks traffic based on suspicions alone. Trojan instead tries to blend in the vast amount of HTTPS traffic over the Internet by pretending to be a normal Web server protected by HTTPS.&lt;p&gt;After Trojan, a plethora of protocol based on TLS camouflaging have been invented.&lt;p&gt;1. Add padding to avoid the TLS-in-TLS traffic characteristics in the original Trojan protocol. Protocols: XTLS-VLESS-VISION.&lt;p&gt;2. Use QUIC instead of TCP+TLS for better performance (very visible if your latency to your tunnel server is high). Protocols: Hysteria2 and TUIC.&lt;p&gt;3. Multiplex multiple proxy sessions in one TCP connection. Protocols: h2mux, smux, yamux.&lt;p&gt;4. Steal other websites' certificates. Protocols: ShadowTLS, ShadowQUIC, XTLS-REALITY.&lt;p&gt;Oh, and there is masking UDP traffic as ICMP traffic or TCP traffic to bypass ISP's QoS if you are proxying traffic through QUIC. Example: phantun.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 29 Aug 2025 09:00:28 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45061811</link><dc:creator>bdd8f1df777b</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45061811</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45061811</guid></item><item><title>New comment by tecleandor in "The Synology End Game"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Not only that, but their security situation is terrible. Their OS is full of EOL'ed stuff.&lt;p&gt;On products you can buy TODAY, you find:&lt;p&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;  - Their Btrfs filesystem is a fork of a very old branch and doesn't have modern patches
  - A custom, non standard, self built, ACL system for the filesystem
  - Kernel 4.4
  - PHP 7.4 (requirement for their Hyperbackup app)
  - smbd 4.15
  - PostgreSQL 11.11
  - smbd 8.2p1
  - Redis 6.2.8
  - ...
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
They claim it's OK because they've backported all security fixes to their versions. I don't believe them. The (theoretical) huge effort needed for doing that would allow them to grow a way better product.&lt;p&gt;And it's not only about security, but about features (well, some are security features too). We're missing new kernel features (network hardware offload, security, wireguard...), filesystem (btrfs features, performance and error patches...), file servers (new features and compatibility, as Parallel NFS or Multichannel CIFS/SMB), and so on...&lt;p&gt;I think they got stuck on 4.4 because of their btrfs fork, and now they're too deep on their own hole.&lt;p&gt;Also, their backend is a mess. A bunch of different apps developed on different ways that mostly don't talk to each other. They sometimes overlap with each other and have very essential features that don't work and don't plan to fix. Meanwhile, they're busy releasing AI stuff features for the "Office" app.&lt;p&gt;Edit note: For myself and some business stuff, I have a bunch of TrueNAS deployments, from a small Jonsbo box for my home, to a +16 disk rack server. This was for a client that wanted to migrate from another Synology they had on loan, and I didn't want to push a server on them, as they're a bit far away from me, and I wanted it to be serviceable by anyone. I regret it.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 29 Aug 2025 08:44:57 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45061701</link><dc:creator>tecleandor</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45061701</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45061701</guid></item><item><title>New comment by codeflo in "The Synology End Game"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;The year is 2025. Delivering a good product is not considered profitable enough anymore. If a company or product is beloved by customers then that means it doesn't squeeze them to the max. This is clearly money left on the table that someone will sooner or later extract. High-end brands are not exempt from this.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 29 Aug 2025 08:13:56 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45061494</link><dc:creator>codeflo</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45061494</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45061494</guid></item><item><title>New comment by mitchellh in "My startup banking story (2023)"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Funny to see this pop up again (I'm the author). The year is now 2025 and I still use Chase as a personal bank and I'm now discovering new funny banking behaviors. I'll use this as a chance to share. :)&lt;p&gt;My company had an exit, I did well financially. This is not a secret. I'm extremely privileged and thankful for it. But as a result of this, I've used a private bank (or mix) for a number of years to store the vast majority of my financial assets (over 99.99% of all assets, I just did the math). An unfortunate property of private banks is they make it hard to do retail-like banking behaviors: depositing a quick check, pulling cash from an ATM, but ironically most importantly Zelle.&lt;p&gt;As such, I've kept my Chase personal accounts and use them as my retail bank: there are Chase branches everywhere, its easy to get to an ATM, and they give me easy access to Zelle! I didn't choose Chase specifically, I've just always used Chase for personal banking since I was in high school so I just kept using them for this.&lt;p&gt;Anyways, I tend to use my Chase account to pay a bunch of bills, just because it's more convenient (Zelle!). I have 3 active home construction projects, plus pay my CC, plus pretty much all other typical expenses (utilities, car payments, insurance, etc.). But I float the money in/out of the account as necessary to cover these. We do accounting of all these expenses at the private bank side, so its all tracked, but it settles within the last 24-48 hours via Chase.&lt;p&gt;Otherwise, I keep my Chase balance no more than a few thousand dollars.&lt;p&gt;This really wigs out automated systems at Chase. I get phone calls all the time (like, literally multiple times per week) saying "we noticed a large transfer into your account, we can help!" And I cheekily respond "refresh, it's back to zero!" And they're just confused. To be fair, I've explained the situation in detail to multiple people multiple times but it isn't clicking, so they keep calling me.&lt;p&gt;I now ignore the phone calls. Hope I don't regret that later lol.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 28 Aug 2025 20:51:57 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45056901</link><dc:creator>mitchellh</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45056901</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45056901</guid></item><item><title>New comment by _verandaguy in "Ask HN: The government of my country blocked VPN access. What should I use?"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Hello! I've got experience working on censorship circumvention for a major VPN provider (in the early 2020s).&lt;p&gt;- First things first, you have to get your hands on actual VPN software and configs. Many providers who are aware of VPN censorship and cater to these locales distribute their VPNs through hard-to-block channels and in obfuscated packages. S3 is a popular option but by no means the only one, and some VPN providers partner with local orgs who can figure out the safest and most efficient ways to distribute a VPN package in countries at risk of censorship or undergoing censorship.&lt;p&gt;- Once you've got the software, you should try to use it with an obfuscation layer.&lt;p&gt;Obfs4proxy is a popular tool here, and relies on a pre-shared key to make traffic look like nothing special. IIRC it also hides the VPN handshake. This isn't a perfectly secure model, but it's good enough to defeat most DPI setups.&lt;p&gt;Another option is Shapeshifter, from Operator (&lt;a href="https://github.com/OperatorFoundation" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://github.com/OperatorFoundation&lt;/a&gt;). Or, in general, anything that uses pluggable transports. While it's a niche technology, it's quite useful in your case.&lt;p&gt;In both cases, the VPN provider must provide support for these protocols.&lt;p&gt;- The toughest step long term is not getting caught using a VPN. By its nature, long-term statistical analysis will often reveal a VPN connection regardless of obfuscation and masking (and this approach can be cheaper to support than DPI by a state actor). I don't know the situation on the ground in Indonesia, so I won't speculate about what the best way to avoid this would be, long-term.&lt;p&gt;I will endorse Mullvad as a trustworthy and technically competent VPN provider in this niche (n.b., I do not work for them, nor have I worked for them; they were a competitor to my employer and we always respected their approach to the space).&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 28 Aug 2025 18:48:36 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45055604</link><dc:creator>_verandaguy</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45055604</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45055604</guid></item></channel></rss>