<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>Hacker News: Best Comments</title><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/bestcomments</link><description>Hacker News RSS</description><docs>https://hnrss.org/</docs><generator>hnrss v2.1.1</generator><lastBuildDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 00:24:36 +0000</lastBuildDate><ns0:link href="https://hnrss.org/bestcomments" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item><title>New comment by cweagans in "Fix macOS 26 (Tahoe) exaggerated rounded corners"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Your GitHub repo and the associated medium article do a great job of describing the problem and the solution that you settled on. I don’t understand why you didn’t include a screenshot of what this looks like though. The suitability of your tool depends on what it looks like.&lt;p&gt;Please, always include screenshots in open source projects that are aesthetic in nature.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 20:35:19 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46684148</link><dc:creator>cweagans</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46684148</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46684148</guid></item><item><title>New comment by qntty in "Letter from a Birmingham Jail (1963)"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&gt; Sometimes a law is just on its face and unjust in its application. For instance, I have been arrested on a charge of parading without a permit. Now, there is nothing wrong in having an ordinance which requires a permit for a parade. But such an ordinance becomes unjust when it is used to maintain segregation and to deny citizens the First-Amendment privilege of peaceful assembly and protest.&lt;p&gt;&gt; I hope you are able to see the distinction I am trying to point out. In no sense do I advocate evading or defying the law, as would the rabid segregationist. That would lead to anarchy. One who breaks an unjust law must do so openly, lovingly, and with a willingness to accept the penalty. I submit that an individual who breaks a law that conscience tells him is unjust, and who willingly accepts the penalty of imprisonment in order to arouse the conscience of the community over its injustice, is in reality expressing the highest respect for law.&lt;p&gt;I always have to go back to read this part again because I feel like it's so unexpected. You don't really hear anyone saying quite the same thing today.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 19:32:50 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46683399</link><dc:creator>qntty</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46683399</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46683399</guid></item><item><title>New comment by atonse in "Apple testing new App Store design that blurs the line between ads and results"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;More and more evidence that the a-holes with spreadsheets are taking over at Apple and they’re completely devoid of any ideas on the software side.&lt;p&gt;I heard someone randomly say that they should replace Tim Cook with Scott Forstall. I chuckled at the idea but this might be a great idea.&lt;p&gt;Apple is having its Ballmer moment. Google did too before AI lit the fire under their feet.&lt;p&gt;Who is going to be Apple’s next Nadella? Steve Jobs was the original.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 17:00:52 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46681411</link><dc:creator>atonse</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46681411</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46681411</guid></item><item><title>New comment by bartread in "American importers and consumers bear the cost of 2025 tariffs: analysis"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I'm glad they've done the work here and put a figure on it - the impact absolutely needed to be quantified - but I also have to say... to the surprise of absolutely no-one with even the most basic grasp of how economies function.&lt;p&gt;People, lots of people, lots of people who have a really deep understanding of national and global economics (unlike me), have been warning about this since talk of tariffs became common currency a year ago.&lt;p&gt;I wouldn't like to comment on HN's political leanings in the round and, obviously, there are a large portion of non-US readers/commenters on the site (including me), but will say this: there are a portion of you who voted for this. Exactly this.&lt;p&gt;What were you thinking? What was going through your heads? I'm genuinely curious.&lt;p&gt;EDIT: Wow... well, having asked the question, it looks like I now have a &lt;i&gt;lot&lt;/i&gt; of answers and perspectives to read. Thank you all for taking the time to comment.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 16:12:22 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46680616</link><dc:creator>bartread</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46680616</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46680616</guid></item><item><title>New comment by modeless in "A decentralized peer-to-peer messaging application that operates over Bluetooth"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;It's criminal that cell phones are bristling with incredibly advanced radio technology and yet they are by law not allowed to communicate directly with each other over a distance of more than a couple hundred meters without assistance from a licensed and centrally controlled base station. Meanwhile a $10 walkie talkie using primitive stone-age radio technology can go many miles with zero infrastructure, but by law is not allowed to be used for data transmission. This is a choice our governments have made, not something inherent to the technology.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 15:38:49 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46680154</link><dc:creator>modeless</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46680154</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46680154</guid></item><item><title>New comment by al_borland in "Amazon is ending all inventory commingling as of March 31, 2026"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;It’s about time. I’ve been going out of my way to not buy from Amazon, especially on items that are often counterfeit, or where a counterfeit item would cause real issues.&lt;p&gt;Just a couple days ago I was planning to buy some supplements, which Amazon had. I went to the actual website of the company and bought from them, because the idea of getting a knock off was a bit scary. To my dismay, I received an Amazon shipping notice after making the purchase outside of Amazon. This brought back my skepticism. I’m still waiting for the package to arrive and will end up inspecting it closely.&lt;p&gt;A few months ago I bought some headphones from Amazon, because the official site was out of stock on the color I wanted. I ended up going on YouTube and finding a video on how to spot authentic pairs vs counterfeit ones to make sure I got the real thing.&lt;p&gt;This all stemmed from when I bought a water bottle, and the reviews mentioned this commingling issue and how to spot authentic real one vs a fake. I double checked that I was buying from the company’s listing and not one of the other sellers on the item. I received a counterfeit one. Thankfully this review tipped me off. I lost a significant amount of trust in Amazon that day. A random bottle isn’t something I even thought I needed to worry about counterfeit version for.&lt;p&gt;Amazon has a long way to go to rebuild trust with me. This is a step in the right direction. The fact that it took this long is pretty sad. Amazon is the only mainstream store where I’ve ever had to question if I was buying legitimate goods or not.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 13:20:03 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46678672</link><dc:creator>al_borland</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46678672</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46678672</guid></item><item><title>New comment by amiga386 in "Radboud University selects Fairphone as standard smartphone for employees"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I bought a Fairphone 3, released in 2019.&lt;p&gt;The charging port wore out. I bought another one in 2023. They still sell that part today. &lt;a href="https://shop.fairphone.com/shop/fairphone-3-bottom-module-37" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://shop.fairphone.com/shop/fairphone-3-bottom-module-37&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;In fact, I see they still sell parts (the screen, at least) for the Fairphone 2, released in 2015. First-party parts 10 years later, what a concept! &lt;a href="https://shop.fairphone.com/spare-parts" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://shop.fairphone.com/spare-parts&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;I don't know your friend's scenario, but this was mine.&lt;p&gt;It's not an either-or, like "either buy first-party parts for a Fairphone OR buy a second-hand Samsung". You can buy a second-hand Fairphone too. It would be nice if you got first-party parts for Samsungs, years after they're released.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 10:57:15 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46677522</link><dc:creator>amiga386</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46677522</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46677522</guid></item><item><title>New comment by Antibabelic in "Wikipedia: WikiProject AI Cleanup"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I found the page Wikipedia:Signs of AI Writing[1] very interesting and informative. It goes into a lot more detail than the typical "em-dashes" heuristic.&lt;p&gt;[1]: &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Wikipedia:Signs_of_AI_writing" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Wikipedia:Signs_of_AI_writing&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 10:46:11 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46677431</link><dc:creator>Antibabelic</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46677431</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46677431</guid></item><item><title>New comment by nicois in "A decentralized peer-to-peer messaging application that operates over Bluetooth"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;One missing feature: deferred message propagation. As far as I understand, while messages will be rebroadcast until a TTL is exhausted, there is no mechanism to retain in-transit messages and retransmit them to future peers. While this adds overheads, it's table stakes for real-life usage.&lt;p&gt;You should be able to write a message and not rely on the recipient being available when you press send. You should also be able to run nodes to cache messages for longer, and opt in to holding messages for a greater time period. This would among other things allow couriers between disjoint groups of users.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 08:48:05 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46676451</link><dc:creator>nicois</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46676451</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46676451</guid></item><item><title>New comment by vim-guru in "Show HN: I quit coding years ago. AI brought me back"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I'm at the opposite end. I feel AI is sucking all the joy out of the profession. Might pivot away and perhaps live a simpler life. Only problem is that I really need the paycheck :(&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 08:38:39 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46676382</link><dc:creator>vim-guru</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46676382</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46676382</guid></item><item><title>New comment by seiferteric in "Dead Internet Theory"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;My parents were tricked the other day by a fake youtube video of "racist cop" doing something bad and getting outraged by it. I watch part of the video and even though it felt off I couldn't immediately tell for sure if it was fake or not. Nevertheless I googled the names and details and found nothing but repostings of the video. Then I looked at the youtube channel info and there it said it uses AI for "some" of the videos to recreate "real" events. I really doubt that.. it all looks fake. I am just worried about how much divisiveness this kind of stuff will create all so someone can profit off of youtube ads.. it's sad.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 02:40:26 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46674496</link><dc:creator>seiferteric</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46674496</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46674496</guid></item><item><title>New comment by jadenpeterson in "Texas police invested in phone-tracking software and won’t say how it’s used"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Why are they comfortable saying this?&lt;p&gt;&gt; Generally, Boyd said his office uses the software to find “avenues for obtaining probable cause” or “to verify reasonable suspicion that you already have”—not as a basis by itself to make arrests.&lt;p&gt;As if that's not a massive violation of our rights in and of itself. This is my fundamental problem with the internet. As much as stories like these gain traction, as many millions of redditors protest these increasingly common stories (for example, the suspicious nature of Luigi Mangione being 'reported' in that McDonalds), nothing will change.&lt;p&gt;Perhaps this is the part of the criminal justice system I am most suspect of. Is this what happens in a country with less regulation?&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 18 Jan 2026 21:50:49 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46672499</link><dc:creator>jadenpeterson</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46672499</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46672499</guid></item><item><title>New comment by klondike_klive in "Gaussian Splatting – A$AP Rocky "Helicopter" music video"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;You... you must have been quite some 5 year old.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 18 Jan 2026 21:02:02 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46672121</link><dc:creator>klondike_klive</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46672121</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46672121</guid></item><item><title>New comment by antirez in "Flux 2 Klein pure C inference"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Something that may be interesting for the reader of this thread: this project was possible only once I started to tell Opus that it &lt;i&gt;needed&lt;/i&gt; to take a file with all the implementation notes, and also accumulating all the things we discovered during the development process. And also, the file had clear instructions to be taken updated, and to be processed ASAP after context compaction. This kinda enabled Opus to do such a big coding task in a reasonable amount of time without loosing track. Check the file IMPLEMENTATION_NOTES.md in the GitHub repo for more info.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 18 Jan 2026 19:25:18 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46671233</link><dc:creator>antirez</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46671233</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46671233</guid></item><item><title>New comment by darhodester in "Gaussian Splatting – A$AP Rocky "Helicopter" music video"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Hi,&lt;p&gt;I'm David Rhodes, Co-founder of CG Nomads, developer of GSOPs (Gaussian Splatting Operators) for SideFX Houdini. GSOPs was used in combination with OTOY OctaneRender to produce this music video.&lt;p&gt;If you're interested in the technology and its capabilities, learn more at &lt;a href="https://www.cgnomads.com/" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://www.cgnomads.com/&lt;/a&gt; or AMA.&lt;p&gt;Try GSOPs yourself: &lt;a href="https://github.com/cgnomads/GSOPs" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://github.com/cgnomads/GSOPs&lt;/a&gt; (example content included).&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 18 Jan 2026 19:14:06 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46671123</link><dc:creator>darhodester</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46671123</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46671123</guid></item><item><title>New comment by nodra in "Gaussian Splatting – A$AP Rocky "Helicopter" music video"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Never did I think I would ever see anything close to related to A$AP on HN. I love this place.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 18 Jan 2026 18:12:16 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46670420</link><dc:creator>nodra</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46670420</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46670420</guid></item><item><title>New comment by EastLondonCoder in "Statement by Denmark, Finland, France, Germany, the Netherlands,Norway,Sweden,UK"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;This isn’t really about Greenland’s strategic value; it’s about the category error. You can trade goods, sign treaties, and negotiate basing rights. You can’t “buy” a people or their sovereignty especially when they don’t consent. That’s why Europe responds with process and principle: normalize coercion-as-bargaining among allies and you’re reviving a pre-1945 model of politics Europe built institutions to prevent.&lt;p&gt;It’s also lose-lose for the US. There isn’t a positive outcome. If it’s dropped, the damage is “just” reputational and partly repairable. If it’s pursued: tariffs, threats, coercion. It burns trust inside NATO, accelerates European strategic decoupling, and hands a propaganda gift to every US adversary. A forced takeover would be a catastrophic own-goal: legitimacy crisis, sanctions/retaliation, and a long-term security headache the US doesn’t need.&lt;p&gt;And the deeper issue is credibility. The dollar’s reserve status and US financial leverage rest on the assumption that the US is broadly predictable and rule-bound. When you start treating allies like extractive targets, you’re not “winning” you’re encouraging everyone to build workarounds. Part of the postwar setup was that Europe outsourced a lot of hard security while the US underwrote the system; if the US turns that security guarantee into leverage against allies, you should expect Europe to reprice the relationship and invest accordingly.&lt;p&gt;The least-bad outcome is a face-saving off-ramp and dropping the whole line of inquiry. Nothing good comes from keeping it on the table.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 18 Jan 2026 17:25:40 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46669850</link><dc:creator>EastLondonCoder</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46669850</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46669850</guid></item><item><title>New comment by huhkerrf in "The Nobel Prize and the Laureate Are Inseparable"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;It's such a joke that we're even having to discuss this. Has there ever been such a thin-skinned, self-absorbed leader of a major power before? Even his biggest fans have to admit, if only to themselves, that he acts like a toddler.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 18 Jan 2026 17:21:52 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46669810</link><dc:creator>huhkerrf</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46669810</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46669810</guid></item><item><title>New comment by bad_haircut72 in "The Nobel Prize and the Laureate Are Inseparable"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;They can say whatever they want but Usain Bolt gave me his gold medal so now Im the fastest 100m runner in the world&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 18 Jan 2026 17:21:45 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46669808</link><dc:creator>bad_haircut72</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46669808</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46669808</guid></item><item><title>New comment by csense in "Predicting OpenAI's ad strategy"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Advertising spend being too high is a symptom of a supply glut.  Too many products in the marketplace, not enough consumers to buy them.&lt;p&gt;In a different world where there are higher wages, more people would have more spending power.  Then companies wouldn't have to spend as many dollars on advertising, which they could split between higher wages, higher margins and lower prices.&lt;p&gt;Alas, the short-term single-firm directional incentive for company decision makers in that world leads to marginal prioritization of higher margins.  The loss of wages leads to loss of consumer spending power but it's spread across the economy.  But every firm has the same incentive so they all do the same thing, and the good thing gets ruined.&lt;p&gt;This line of thinking leads to a Georgist-ish conclusion:  The class conflict &lt;i&gt;shouldn't&lt;/i&gt; be between workers and employers.  They should be allies; the real cause of nobody being able to afford anything is rent extractors.  (Writing in the 1800's, George [1] was most concerned about land rents; but the advertising monopoly of Google / Meta may be another form of extractive rent with similar characteristics.)&lt;p&gt;Maybe Henry Ford was on to something when he shocked the world by paying his employees enough to afford the product they were making (more than doubling many workers' wages)...&lt;p&gt;[1] &lt;a href="https://www.astralcodexten.com/p/your-book-review-progress-and-poverty" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://www.astralcodexten.com/p/your-book-review-progress-a...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 18 Jan 2026 16:56:56 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46669491</link><dc:creator>csense</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46669491</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46669491</guid></item><item><title>New comment by jesse__ in "Command-line Tools can be 235x Faster than your Hadoop Cluster (2014)"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I've done a handful of interviews recently where the 'scaling' problem involves something that comfortably fits on one machine.  The funniest one was ingesting something like 1gb of json &lt;i&gt;per day&lt;/i&gt;.  I explained, from first principals, how it fits, and received feedback along the lines of "our engineers agreed with your technical assessment, but that's not the answer we wanted, so we're going to pass".  I've had this experience a good handful of times.&lt;p&gt;I think a lot of people don't realize machines come with TBs of RAM and hundreds of physical cores.  One machine is fucking huge these days.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 18 Jan 2026 16:40:39 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46669253</link><dc:creator>jesse__</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46669253</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46669253</guid></item><item><title>New comment by bearjaws in "Predicting OpenAI's ad strategy"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;There is something to be said about the state of advertising.&lt;p&gt;Increasingly it seems you must go to the almighty Google or Meta in order to launch any business.&lt;p&gt;We're looking to expand into a new business line and have out grown our pharmacy capacity.&lt;p&gt;The new business line will cost about $2M in software dev, and $3M for the new facility. The advertising budget? $40,000,000 (annual).&lt;p&gt;We can build 10 robotic pharmacies (~10 staff per 4000 fills daily, each) for the price of just the advertising.&lt;p&gt;Increasingly we wonder why America doesn't build more and here is why. You are going to give all your revenue to two platforms. Unless you operate in a business line with 50% margin you are screwed.&lt;p&gt;I don't know what the solution is, but its clear that the platforms are figuring out how much margin everyone has and slowly eroding it. Somewhere between 8-15% of the cost of all products we purchase is advertising spend.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 18 Jan 2026 15:15:37 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46668449</link><dc:creator>bearjaws</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46668449</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46668449</guid></item><item><title>New comment by lordnacho in "Software engineers can no longer neglect their soft skills"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I don't think it has ever been the case that you could neglect soft skills. You will hear this over and over, in every area of every business: people become successful by adjusting their behaviour to what works for the business. Sometimes this is called being a slick politician, sometimes it is called avoiding getting bogged down in politics.&lt;p&gt;But it's never been the case that a dev could just focus on technical things and not spend any time figuring out the context they are working in, and behaving accordingly.&lt;p&gt;My first day of work, this is what my boss said to me: "Look at this trading floor. There's screens everywhere, everything is numbers. Deltas, gammas, vegas. Everything is calculated by computers. But don't forget, every business is a people business!"&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 18 Jan 2026 14:51:57 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46668224</link><dc:creator>lordnacho</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46668224</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46668224</guid></item><item><title>New comment by MontyCarloHall in "Predicting OpenAI's ad strategy"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I think ads will inevitably roll out across all tiers, even the expensive paid ones. Ad revenue isn't uniformly distributed across users, but rather heavily skewed towards the wealthiest users, exactly the users most able to purchase an ad-free experience. The users paying $20 or $200/month for premium tiers of ChatGPT are precisely the ones you don't want to exclude from generating ad revenue.&lt;p&gt;Google realized this a long time ago; there is no ad-free paid version of Google Search.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 18 Jan 2026 14:41:36 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46668134</link><dc:creator>MontyCarloHall</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46668134</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46668134</guid></item><item><title>New comment by MarginalGainz in "Command-line Tools can be 235x Faster than your Hadoop Cluster (2014)"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;The saddest part about this article being from 2014 is that the situation has arguably gotten worse.&lt;p&gt;We now have even more layers of abstraction (Airflow, dbt, Snowflake) applied to datasets that often fit entirely in RAM.&lt;p&gt;I've seen startups burning $5k/mo on distributed compute clusters to process &lt;10GB of daily logs, purely because setting up a 'Modern Data Stack' is what gets you promoted, while writing a robust bash script is seen as 'unscalable' or 'hacky'. The incentives are misaligned with efficiency.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 18 Jan 2026 11:59:43 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46667098</link><dc:creator>MarginalGainz</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46667098</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46667098</guid></item><item><title>New comment by karim79 in "jQuery 4"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Still one of my favourite libs on the whole planet. I will always love jQuery. It is responsible for my career in (real) companies.&lt;p&gt;Live on jQuery! Go forth and multiply!&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 18 Jan 2026 05:54:07 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46665162</link><dc:creator>karim79</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46665162</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46665162</guid></item><item><title>New comment by xeeeeeeeeeeenu in "Erdos 281 solved with ChatGPT 5.2 Pro"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&gt; no prior solutions found.&lt;p&gt;This is no longer true, a prior solution has just been found[1], so the LLM proof has been moved to the Section 2 of Terence Tao's wiki[2].&lt;p&gt;[1] - &lt;a href="https://www.erdosproblems.com/forum/thread/281#post-3325" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://www.erdosproblems.com/forum/thread/281#post-3325&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;[2] - &lt;a href="https://github.com/teorth/erdosproblems/wiki/AI-contributions-to-Erd%C5%91s-problems#2-fully-ai-generated-solutions-to-problems-for-which-subsequent-literature-review-found-full-or-partial-solutions" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://github.com/teorth/erdosproblems/wiki/AI-contribution...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 18 Jan 2026 05:15:14 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46664976</link><dc:creator>xeeeeeeeeeeenu</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46664976</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46664976</guid></item><item><title>New comment by davnicwil in "The recurring dream of replacing developers"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;In the end, I think the dream underneath this dream is about being able to manifest things into reality without having to get into the details.&lt;p&gt;The details are what stops it from working in every form it's
been tried.&lt;p&gt;You cannot escape the details. You must engage with them and solve them directly, meticulously. It's messy, it's extremely complicated and it's just plain hard.&lt;p&gt;There is no level of abstraction that saves you from this, because the last level is simply things happening in the world in the way you want them to, and it's really really complicated to engineer that to happen.&lt;p&gt;I think this is evident by looking at the extreme case. There are plenty of companies with software engineers who truly can turn instructions articulated in plain language into software. But you see lots of these not being successful for the simple reason that those providing the instructions are not sufficiently engaged with the detail, or have the detail wrong. Conversely, for the most successful companies the opposite is true.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 18 Jan 2026 02:33:10 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46664302</link><dc:creator>davnicwil</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46664302</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46664302</guid></item><item><title>New comment by danpalmer in "If you put Apple icons in reverse it looks like someone getting good at design"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;It looks like someone getting good at illustration. Older icons are far better illustrations. However icon design is not just about illustration, it's about clarity and affordances. Icons don't exist in isolation like an illustration, they exist alongside the rest of the UX and other app icons, and being recognisable is important.&lt;p&gt;All that to say, the sweet pot was likely somewhere in the middle of this timeline. The earliest icons aren't recognisable enough as they're too illustrative. The later icons aren't recognisable enough because they're too basic. The middle are pretty, clear from colour, clear from shape, well branded.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 18 Jan 2026 01:00:31 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46663780</link><dc:creator>danpalmer</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46663780</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46663780</guid></item><item><title>New comment by Esophagus4 in "Raising money fucked me up"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&gt; It's much more comfortable to be the person that "could be X" than to be the person that tries to actually do it.&lt;p&gt;Brilliant insight.&lt;p&gt;Reminds of me this, from Theodore Roosevelt's Citizenship in a Republic:&lt;p&gt;&gt; It is not the critic who counts; not the man who points out how the strong man stumbles, or where the doer of deeds could have done them better. The credit belongs to the man who is actually in the arena, whose face is marred by dust and sweat and blood; who strives valiantly; who errs, who comes short again and again, because there is no effort without error and shortcoming; but who does actually strive to do the deeds; who knows great enthusiasms, the great devotions; who spends himself in a worthy cause; who at the best knows in the end the triumph of high achievement, and who at the worst, if he fails, at least fails while daring greatly, so that his place shall never be with those cold and timid souls who neither know victory nor defeat.&lt;p&gt;Good luck, and go get 'em.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 18 Jan 2026 00:51:04 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46663737</link><dc:creator>Esophagus4</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46663737</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46663737</guid></item></channel></rss>