<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>Hacker News: Best Comments</title><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/bestcomments</link><description>Hacker News RSS</description><docs>https://hnrss.org/</docs><generator>hnrss v2.1.1</generator><lastBuildDate>Sun, 21 Sep 2025 00:21:29 +0000</lastBuildDate><ns0:link href="https://hnrss.org/bestcomments" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item><title>New comment by roughly in "Trump to impose $100k fee for H-1B worker visas, White House says"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I think there’s plenty of interesting debates to be had about immigration policy and its effects on the labor market, but one thing worth noting here is that the primary problem that damn near every other country on earth has isn’t immigration, it’s brain drain.&lt;p&gt;A core strategic strength of the US over the last century has been that everyone with any talent wants to come here to work, and by and large we’ve let them do so. You can argue how well that’s worked out for us - having worked with a great many extremely talented H1bs in an industry largely built by immigrants, I’d consider it pretty positive - but it damn sure hasn’t worked out well for the countries those talented folks came from.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 20:40:08 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45306289</link><dc:creator>roughly</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45306289</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45306289</guid></item><item><title>New comment by fasbiner in "Slack has raised our charges by $195k per year"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;It's not a mistake that you're only reachable when your bad business practices are so heinous they go viral. You are an executive at a company that saves money by not offering customer support except when there's bad PR or a lawsuit.&lt;p&gt;Are you going to be fixing that your billing system is not human-reachable, or are you just going to be fixing this one incident while leaving the broken system as-is for everyone who didn't go viral?&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2025 17:56:43 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45292816</link><dc:creator>fasbiner</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45292816</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45292816</guid></item><item><title>New comment by evanjrowley in "Nvidia buys $5B in Intel"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Nvidia's stake in Intel could have terrible consequences. First, it is in Nvidia's interest to kill Intel's Arc graphics, and that would be very bad because it is the only thing brighing GPU prices down for consumers. Second, the death of Intel graphics / Arc would be extremely bad for Linux, because Intel's approach to GPU drivers is the best for compatibility, wheras Nvidia is actively hostile to drivers on Linux. Third, Intel is the only company marketing consumer-grade graphics virtualization (SR-IOV), and the loss of that would make Nvidia's enterprise chips the only game in town, meaning the average consumer gets less performance, less flexibility, and less security on their computers.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2025 16:22:10 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45291556</link><dc:creator>evanjrowley</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45291556</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45291556</guid></item><item><title>New comment by sirwhinesalot in "KDE is now my favorite desktop"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;We now live in a world where KDE looks nicer, more professional, and more consistent than the latest macOS. I don't know how that happened, and KDE isn't even particularly nice looking, but here we are.&lt;p&gt;For many years now KDE has focused on polish, bug fixing and "nice-to-have" improvements rather than major redesigns, and it paid off.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2025 13:47:40 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45289648</link><dc:creator>sirwhinesalot</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45289648</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45289648</guid></item><item><title>New comment by actionfromafar in "Slack has raised our charges by $195k per year"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Thousands of teen coders now hate Salesforce in &lt;i&gt;advance&lt;/i&gt;. This is very shortsighted.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2025 08:43:39 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45287173</link><dc:creator>actionfromafar</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45287173</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45287173</guid></item><item><title>New comment by solid_fuel in "Meta Ray-Ban Display"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Meta locked two games I already paid for - Blade &amp; Sorcery VR and Beat Saber - behind account verification on the Quest 2.  I already bought both of these, played them for a while, but now it won't let me use the headset without "verifying" my facebook account by sending them a photograph of my drivers license.  Neither of these games are online, neither allow me to interact with other users in any way.&lt;p&gt;I will never buy a Meta product again, the brand reputation is lower than dirt to me.  Even ignoring all the other awful things Meta does, they have no reason to require a verified account to play two local-only games that I already paid for.  No matter how cool glasses like these may look, I have no trust that the brand will not suddenly demand more money or information from me to continue using a product I have already purchased.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2025 04:21:18 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45285351</link><dc:creator>solid_fuel</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45285351</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45285351</guid></item><item><title>New comment by casq in "Slack has raised our charges by $195k per year"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Hi, I’m Christina, cofounder of Hack Club. We just announced this news to our community, and this post is from one of the teenagers in Hack Club.  It’s an accurate description of what’s happened, and we’re grateful to them for posting. Slack changed the terms of a special deal we were given last year to charge us for staff and volunteers (not for every teenager coding), and we built programs around that special rate. Then this spring they changed the terms to every single user without telling us or sending a new contract, and then ignored our outreach and delayed us and told us to ignore the bill and not to pay as late as Aug 29&lt;p&gt;Then, suddenly, they called us 2 days ago and said they are going to de-activate the Hack Club Slack, including all message history from 11 years, unless we pay them $50,000 USD this week and $200,000 USD/year moving forward (plus additional annual fees for new accounts, including inactive ones)&lt;p&gt;For anyone reading this, we would really appreciate any way to contact people at Salesforce to discuss time to migrate because deactivating us in 5 days destroys all the work of thousands of teen coders at Hack Club and alum unnecessarily. We are not asking for anything for free. This was an underhanded process by the sales team to raise our rate exorbitantly from a qualified educational 501(c)(3) charity serving young developers or destroy all their projects, DMs and work forever. If Salesforce’s goals have changed- ok. Give us a reasonable amount of time to migrate- and don’t club us over the head like this. We have had an 11 year great relationship with Slack- and have introduced the company to many many future engineers and founders. My email if you can help us: christina@hackclub.com&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2025 04:09:47 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45285280</link><dc:creator>casq</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45285280</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45285280</guid></item><item><title>New comment by SchemaLoad in "Meta Ray-Ban Display"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&gt;Meta Ray-Ban Display glasses are designed to help you look up and stay present. With a quick glance at the in-lens display, you can accomplish everyday tasks—like checking messages, previewing photos, and collaborating with visual Meta AI prompts&lt;p&gt;Can you imagine trying to talk to someone face to face, but they are giving you a blank stare as random notifications and tiktok videos are being beamed inbetween their eyeballs and you.&lt;p&gt;Meta seems like one of the few large tech companies where if the whole company vanished, the world would be purely a better place.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2025 02:01:48 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45284135</link><dc:creator>SchemaLoad</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45284135</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45284135</guid></item><item><title>New comment by JKCalhoun in "Meta Ray-Ban Display"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;They have a brand problem. Absolutely no way I buy anything from Meta.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2025 02:01:08 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45284125</link><dc:creator>JKCalhoun</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45284125</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45284125</guid></item><item><title>New comment by tedggh in "Things you can do with a Software Defined Radio (2024)"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I got a walkie talkie set as a Christmas present when I was 8. Which was kind of an evil thing to do given I had no siblings or friends to play with. One day I turned one set on and listened for a while and I thought I heard someone talking behind all the static noise. So I said something and was shocked to hear the voice talking back to me. Fast forward a few decades, next week is my wedding and that voice on the other side of the radio is my best man.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2025 15:39:29 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45263749</link><dc:creator>tedggh</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45263749</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45263749</guid></item><item><title>New comment by snowwrestler in "I feel Apple has lost its alignment with me and other long-time customers"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&gt; it’s a company that I feel has lost its alignment with me and other long-time Apple users and customers.&lt;p&gt;When OS X debuted there was a daytime radio talk show in my area called “The Computer Guys.” They capably covered all sorts of computing topics, but were clearly long-time Apple dudes. And they spent weeks complaining about what a disaster OS X was. The Dock was useless and violated Apple’s HIG. The Finder made all the same mistakes as Windows did. And a text terminal? Like DOS?? Who the hell is ever going to want to use that on a Mac?&lt;p&gt;Going even farther back, it was long-time dedicated Apple users who booed when Jobs announced the deal with Microsoft.&lt;p&gt;Being a long-time dedicated Apple user is a shitty job. You don’t get paid, have no input, and are constantly disappointed. And Apple does not care about you.&lt;p&gt;I strongly suggest people should throw this notion away. It does not matter how long you’ve bought from a big company, they owe you nothing. If the latest product seems good, buy it. If not, don’t. Any more emotional investment than that is going to cause pointless unhappiness.&lt;p&gt;Save your customer loyalty energy for businesses where you can actually establish a connection, like a restaurant you like, or a local handyman.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2025 03:06:03 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45257631</link><dc:creator>snowwrestler</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45257631</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45257631</guid></item><item><title>New comment by jeffparsons in "Linux phones are more important now than ever"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;My Android phone prevents me from taking screenshots if an app author doesn't want me to.&lt;p&gt;My Android phone prevents me from recording phone calls at the request of my carrier, even though it's totally legal for me to do so in my jurisdiction.&lt;p&gt;I'm not loving where this is all going.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2025 01:32:45 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45257000</link><dc:creator>jeffparsons</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45257000</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45257000</guid></item><item><title>New comment by smcleod in "macOS Tahoe"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I've been running it since the RC and am currently in the process of uninstalling it. The new UI is so incredibly ugly I honestly cannot understand how they thought it was acceptable to even released as a beta let alone an RC and now release.&lt;p&gt;There's SO much padding and wasted screen real estate, disjointed looking floating inner panels, window corners that are so rounded you see gaps in full screen apps, inconsistencies everywhere and - well, I could go on.&lt;p&gt;Basically the vibe I get from it is that they think their users are dumb - they won't care about things like this and that they want everything to look like a preschoolers tablet.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 15 Sep 2025 20:39:14 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45254627</link><dc:creator>smcleod</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45254627</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45254627</guid></item><item><title>New comment by electric_muse in "The treasury is expanding the Patriot Act to attack Bitcoin self custody"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;[flagged]&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 12 Sep 2025 12:58:29 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45221631</link><dc:creator>electric_muse</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45221631</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45221631</guid></item><item><title>New comment by csours in "Charlie Kirk killed at event in Utah"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;History books can tell you facts that happened, but they can never truly tell you how it feels.&lt;p&gt;I feel we're riding a knife's edge and there's a hurricane brewing in the gulf of absurdity.&lt;p&gt;====&lt;p&gt;Incidentally, I feel like this is why it is so hard to actually learn from history. You can read about the 1918 'Spanish' Flu, but you think "we're smarter now". etc.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 10 Sep 2025 20:48:54 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45203460</link><dc:creator>csours</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45203460</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45203460</guid></item><item><title>New comment by dang in "Charlie Kirk killed at event in Utah"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;All: if you can't respond in a non-violent way, please don't post until you can.&lt;p&gt;By non-violent I mean not celebrating violence nor excusing it, but also more than that: I mean metabolizing the violence you feel in yourself, until you no longer have a need to express it aggressively.&lt;p&gt;The feelings we all have about violence are strong and fully human and I'm not judging them. I believe it's our responsibility to each carry our own share of these feelings, rather than firing them at others, including in the petty forms that aggression takes on an internet forum.&lt;p&gt;If you don't share that belief, that's fine, but we do need you to follow the site guidelines when commenting here, and they certainly cover the above request. So if you're going to comment, please make sure you're familiar with and following them: &lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/newsguidelines.html"&gt;https://news.ycombinator.com/newsguidelines.html&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 10 Sep 2025 20:48:37 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45203452</link><dc:creator>dang</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45203452</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45203452</guid></item><item><title>New comment by tenarchits in "US High school students' scores fall in reading and math"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Most of the comments are focused on the supply of education.  But I don't think the supply side is the problem, irrespective of teachers and high schools.  There is more and cheaper education available than ever before.  Nearly every highschooler has more access to learning that kings and emperors would have fought wars for less than 200 years ago.  However,the United States, particularly in the last 50 years, seems to have fostered a culture averse to education.  I believe the years long decline in test scores is a symptom of that cultural shift.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 09 Sep 2025 22:58:45 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45190602</link><dc:creator>tenarchits</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45190602</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45190602</guid></item><item><title>New comment by sandbags in "How can England possibly be running out of water?"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;As the article mentions, privatised water companies have built no new reservoir capacity and relied on drawing from rivers and other sources.&lt;p&gt;What the article doesn’t mention is that pre-privatisation a new reservoir was built every year up to about 1960 and then every few years until privatisation in 1992.&lt;p&gt;So we are about 30 years behind in adding capacity to the system. This combined with the inadequate levels of investment in the system leading to enormous wastage, is the answer.&lt;p&gt;Water should never have been privatised. At least not without a framework for a national strategy for water. I suspect that wasn’t done because it would have made water companies and unattractive source of profit.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 09 Sep 2025 06:53:16 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45178404</link><dc:creator>sandbags</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45178404</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45178404</guid></item><item><title>New comment by ksynwa in "No adblocker detected"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I am extremely insulated from ads online and have been for about a decade. Once in a while I have to browse on a device that does not have an ad blocker or most of the times does not even let you install one. Seeing a website that is SEoptimised and heavily ad supported feels like walking into a crack den. That this is the normal experience for the vast majority of users is sad.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 09 Sep 2025 04:23:39 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45177377</link><dc:creator>ksynwa</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45177377</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45177377</guid></item><item><title>New comment by junon in "NPM debug and chalk packages compromised"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Hi, yep I got pwned. Sorry everyone, very embarrassing.&lt;p&gt;More info:&lt;p&gt;- &lt;a href="https://github.com/chalk/chalk/issues/656" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://github.com/chalk/chalk/issues/656&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;- &lt;a href="https://github.com/debug-js/debug/issues/1005#issuecomment-3266885191" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://github.com/debug-js/debug/issues/1005#issuecomment-3...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;Affected packages (at least the ones I know of):&lt;p&gt;- ansi-styles@6.2.2&lt;p&gt;- debug@4.4.2 (appears to have been yanked as of 8 Sep 18:09 CEST)&lt;p&gt;- chalk@5.6.1&lt;p&gt;- supports-color@10.2.1&lt;p&gt;- strip-ansi@7.1.1&lt;p&gt;- ansi-regex@6.2.1&lt;p&gt;- wrap-ansi@9.0.1&lt;p&gt;- color-convert@3.1.1&lt;p&gt;- color-name@2.0.1&lt;p&gt;- is-arrayish@0.3.3&lt;p&gt;- slice-ansi@7.1.1&lt;p&gt;- color@5.0.1&lt;p&gt;- color-string@2.1.1&lt;p&gt;- simple-swizzle@0.2.3&lt;p&gt;- supports-hyperlinks@4.1.1&lt;p&gt;- has-ansi@6.0.1&lt;p&gt;- chalk-template@1.1.1&lt;p&gt;- backslash@0.2.1&lt;p&gt;It looks and feels a bit like a targeted attack.&lt;p&gt;Will try to keep this comment updated as long as I can before the edit expires.&lt;p&gt;---&lt;p&gt;Chalk has been published over. The others remain compromised (8 Sep 17:50 CEST).&lt;p&gt;NPM has yet to get back to me. My NPM account is entirely unreachable; forgot password system does not work. I have no recourse right now but to wait.&lt;p&gt;Email came from support at npmjs dot help.&lt;p&gt;Looked legitimate at first glance. Not making excuses, just had a long week and a panicky morning and was just trying to knock something off my list of to-dos. Made the mistake of clicking the link instead of going directly to the site like I normally would (since I was mobile).&lt;p&gt;Just NPM is affected. Updates to be posted to the `/debug-js` link above.&lt;p&gt;Again, I'm so sorry.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 08 Sep 2025 15:49:01 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45169794</link><dc:creator>junon</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45169794</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45169794</guid></item><item><title>New comment by lionturtle in "14 Killed in anti-government protests in Nepal"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;It was absolutely not just social media ban, it was mostly youth protesting against the corrupt government and unfairness, social media ban was one element that was against the freedom of speech, but it was right around the time where everyone was documenting the rich politicians, their business connections and their families that have been living lavishly and just inheriting the election seats from generation to generation and spinning beurocracy to their sides.&lt;p&gt;I was there a few hours ago. It was a class struggle, but it was bound to be spun up as "kids don't get facebook and throw tantrum".&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 08 Sep 2025 11:52:15 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45167176</link><dc:creator>lionturtle</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45167176</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45167176</guid></item><item><title>New comment by Aurornis in "996"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;When founders put 996 in their job descriptions or Tweet about their 996 culture it’s a helpful signal to avoid that company.&lt;p&gt;The only time I’d actually consider crazy schedules was if &lt;i&gt;I&lt;/i&gt; was the founder with a huge equity stake and a once in a lifetime opportunity that would benefit from a short period of 996.&lt;p&gt;For average employees? Absolutely not. If someone wants extraordinary hours they need to be providing extraordinary compensation. Pay me a couple million per year and I’ll do it for a while (though not appropriate for everyone). Pay me the same as the other job opportunities? Absolutely no way I’m going to 996.&lt;p&gt;In my experience, the 996 teams aren’t actually cranking out more work. They’re just working odd hours, doing a little work on the weekends to say they worked the weekend, and they spend a lot of time relaxing at the office because they’re always there.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 06 Sep 2025 14:29:34 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45149578</link><dc:creator>Aurornis</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45149578</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45149578</guid></item><item><title>New comment by aeon_ai in "Anthropic agrees to pay $1.5B to settle lawsuit with book authors"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;To be very clear on this point - this is not related to model training.&lt;p&gt;It’s important in the fair use assessment to understand that the training itself is fair use, but the &lt;i&gt;pirating of the books&lt;/i&gt; is the issue at hand here, and is what Anthropic “whoopsied” into in acquiring the training data.&lt;p&gt;Buying used copies of books, scanning them, and training on it is fine.&lt;p&gt;Rainbows End was prescient in many ways.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 05 Sep 2025 20:46:01 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45143392</link><dc:creator>aeon_ai</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45143392</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45143392</guid></item><item><title>New comment by dperfect in "Stripe Launches L1 Blockchain: Tempo"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;It sounds great, but every time I see this argument, I end up going down the rabbit hole of actually studying how stablecoins operate. And every time, I come to the same conclusion: they &lt;i&gt;always&lt;/i&gt; rely on trust in an off-chain oracle or custodian. At that point, a shared ledger implemented with traditional databases / protocols would be faster, easier, and more transparent.&lt;p&gt;Bitcoin (and possibly a few others) is one of the few uses of blockchain that actually makes sense. The blockchain serves the currency, and the currency serves the blockchain. The blockchain exists to provide consensus without needing to trust any off-chain entity, but the blockchain relies on computing infrastructure that has real-world costs. The scarcity of Bitcoin (the currency) and arguably-fictitious reward for participation in mining is the incentive for people in the real world to contribute resources required for the blockchain to function.&lt;p&gt;Any real-world value given to Bitcoin is secondary and &lt;i&gt;only&lt;/i&gt; a result of the fact that (1) mining infrastructure has a cost, and (2) people who understand the system have realized that, unlike fiat, stablecoins, or 1000 other crypto products, Bitcoin has no reliance on trusted, off-chain entities who could manipulate it.&lt;p&gt;You trust your stablecoin's issuer that they hold enough fiat in reserve to match the coin? You might as well trust your bank, but while you're at it, remind them that they don't &lt;i&gt;have&lt;/i&gt; to take days to process a transaction - they &lt;i&gt;could&lt;/i&gt; process transactions as fast as (actually &lt;i&gt;faster&lt;/i&gt; than) a blockchain. But I imagine most banks would point to regulation as a reason for the delays, and they might be right.&lt;p&gt;So what are stablecoins really trying to do? Circumvent regulation? Implement something the banks just aren't willing to do themselves?&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 04 Sep 2025 20:18:38 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45131781</link><dc:creator>dperfect</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45131781</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45131781</guid></item><item><title>New comment by pc in "Stripe Launches L1 Blockchain: Tempo"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;There are lots of crypto skeptics on HN (and we ourselves were disappointed with crypto's payments utility for much of the past decade), so it might be interesting to share what changed our mind over the past couple of years: we started to notice a lot of real-world businesses finding utility in stablecoins. For example, Bridge (a stablecoin orchestration platform that Stripe acquired) is used by SpaceX for managing money in long-tail markets. Another big customer, DolarApp, is providing banking services to customers in Latin America. We're currently adding stablecoin functionality to the Stripe dashboard, and the first user is an Argentinian bike importer that finds transacting with their suppliers to be challenging.&lt;p&gt;Importantly, none of these businesses are using crypto because &lt;i&gt;it's crypto&lt;/i&gt; or for any speculative benefit. They're performing real-world financial activity, and they've found that crypto (via stablecoins) is easier/faster/better than the status quo ante.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 04 Sep 2025 17:08:57 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45129554</link><dc:creator>pc</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45129554</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45129554</guid></item><item><title>New comment by some-guy in "Where's the shovelware? Why AI coding claims don't add up"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;These claims wouldn't matter if the topic weren't so deadly serious. Tech leaders everywhere are buying into the FOMO, convinced their competitors are getting massive gains they're missing out on. This drives them to rebrand as AI-First companies, justify layoffs with newfound productivity narratives, and lowball developer salaries under the assumption that AI has fundamentally changed the value equation.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;p&gt;This is my biggest problem right now. The types of problems I'm trying to solve at work require careful planning and execution, and AI has not been helpful for it in the slightest. My manager told me that the time to deliver my latest project was cut to 20% of the original estimate because we are "an AI-first company". The mass hysteria among SVPs and PMs is absolutely insane right now, I've never seen anything like it.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 03 Sep 2025 22:07:34 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45120908</link><dc:creator>some-guy</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45120908</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45120908</guid></item><item><title>New comment by supernova87a in "Google can keep its Chrome browser but will be barred from exclusive contracts"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;By the way, a pet peeve of mine right now is that reporters covering court cases (and we have so many of public interest lately) never seem to simply paste the link to the online PDF decision/ruling for us all to read, right in the story.  (and another user here kindly did that for us below: &lt;a href="https://storage.courtlistener.com/recap/gov.uscourts.dcd.223205/gov.uscourts.dcd.223205.1436.0_1.pdf" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://storage.courtlistener.com/recap/gov.uscourts.dcd.223...&lt;/a&gt; )&lt;p&gt;It seems such a simple step (they must have been using the ruling PDF to write the story) yet why is it always such a hassle for them to feel that they should link the original content?  I would rather be able to see the probably dozens of pages ruling with the full details rather than hear it secondhand from a reporter at this point.  It feels like they want to be the gatekeepers of information, and poor ones at that.&lt;p&gt;I think it should be adopted as standard journalistic practice in fact -- reporting on court rulings must come with the PDF.&lt;p&gt;Aside from that, it will be interesting to see on what grounds the judge decided that this particular data sharing remedy was the solution. Can anyone now simply claim they're a competitor and get access to Google's tons of data?&lt;p&gt;I am not too familiar with antitrust precedent, but to what extent does the judge rule on how specific the data sharing need to be (what types of data, for what time span, how anonymized, etc. etc.) or appoint a special master?   Why is that up to the judge versus the FTC or whoever to propose?&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 02 Sep 2025 21:30:17 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45109304</link><dc:creator>supernova87a</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45109304</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45109304</guid></item><item><title>New comment by Bukhmanizer in "We already live in social credit, we just don't call it that"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;The issue is that American media/discourse paints a very distorted view of what life under authoritarian rule is like. The truth is in many countries, unless you’re some kind of minority, politically active, or in legal trouble, day-to-day life is mostly similar to life in the west. But people don’t want to hear that, because we want to feel &lt;i&gt;better&lt;/i&gt; than them. Like we wouldn’t tolerate that kind of life.&lt;p&gt;Of course the most frustrating part about that is as the US and other western countries start sliding into authoritarianism, people deny it because they don’t &lt;i&gt;feel&lt;/i&gt; like it’s authoritarian.&lt;p&gt;Edit: To clarify, I don’t think life is exactly the same - just that the consequences of authoritarianism are much more insidious than they’re portrayed.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 02 Sep 2025 18:26:09 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45107075</link><dc:creator>Bukhmanizer</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45107075</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45107075</guid></item><item><title>New comment by kristov in "We should have the ability to run any code we want on hardware we own"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I think the conversation needs to change from "can't run software of our choice" to "can't participate in society without an apple or google account". I have been living with a de-googled android phone for a number of years, and it is getting harder and harder, while at the same time operating without certain "apps" is becoming more difficult.&lt;p&gt;For example, by bank (abn amro) still allows online banking on desktop via a physical auth device, but they are actively pushing for login only via their app. I called their support line for a lost card, and had to go through to second level support because I didn't have the app. If they get their way, eventually an apple or google account will be mandatory to have a bank account with them.&lt;p&gt;My kid goes to a school that outsourced all communication via an app. They have a web version, but it's barely usable. The app doesn't run without certain google libs installed. Again, to participate in school communication about my kid effectively requires an apple or google account.&lt;p&gt;I feel like the conversation we should be having is that we are sleepwalking into a world where to participate in society you must have an account with either apple or google. If you decide you don't want a relationship with either of those companies you will be extremely disadvantaged.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2025 13:05:38 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45092413</link><dc:creator>kristov</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45092413</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45092413</guid></item><item><title>New comment by zmmmmm in "We should have the ability to run any code we want on hardware we own"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&gt; In this context this would mean having the ability and documentation to build or install alternative operating systems on this hardware&lt;p&gt;It doesn't work. Everything from banks to Netflix and others are slowly edging out anything where they can't fully verify the chain of control to an entity they can have a legal or contractual relationship with. To be clear, this is fundamental, not incidental. You can't run your own operating system because it's not in Netflix's financial interest for you to do so. Or your banks, or your government. They all benefit from you not having control, so you can't.&lt;p&gt;This is why it's so important to defend the real principles here not just the technical artefacts of them. Netflix shouldn't be able to insist on a particular type of DRM for me to receive their service. Governments shouldn't be able to prevent me from end to end encrypting things. I should be able to opt into all this if I want more security, but it can't be mandatory. However all of these things are not technical, they are principles and rights that we have to argue for.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2025 02:51:16 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45088995</link><dc:creator>zmmmmm</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45088995</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45088995</guid></item></channel></rss>