<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>Hacker News: Best Comments</title><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/bestcomments</link><description>Hacker News RSS</description><docs>https://hnrss.org/</docs><generator>hnrss v2.1.1</generator><lastBuildDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 00:27:49 +0000</lastBuildDate><ns0:link href="https://hnrss.org/bestcomments" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item><title>New comment by klondike_klive in "Gaussian Splatting – A$AP Rocky "Helicopter" music video"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;You... you must have been quite some 5 year old.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 18 Jan 2026 21:02:02 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46672121</link><dc:creator>klondike_klive</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46672121</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46672121</guid></item><item><title>New comment by darhodester in "Gaussian Splatting – A$AP Rocky "Helicopter" music video"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Hi,&lt;p&gt;I'm David Rhodes, Co-founder of CG Nomads, developer of GSOPs (Gaussian Splatting Operators) for SideFX Houdini. GSOPs was used in combination with OTOY OctaneRender to produce this music video.&lt;p&gt;If you're interested in the technology and its capabilities, learn more at &lt;a href="https://www.cgnomads.com/" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://www.cgnomads.com/&lt;/a&gt; or AMA.&lt;p&gt;Try GSOPs yourself: &lt;a href="https://github.com/cgnomads/GSOPs" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://github.com/cgnomads/GSOPs&lt;/a&gt; (example content included).&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 18 Jan 2026 19:14:06 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46671123</link><dc:creator>darhodester</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46671123</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46671123</guid></item><item><title>New comment by nodra in "Gaussian Splatting – A$AP Rocky "Helicopter" music video"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Never did I think I would ever see anything close to related to A$AP on HN. I love this place.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 18 Jan 2026 18:12:16 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46670420</link><dc:creator>nodra</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46670420</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46670420</guid></item><item><title>New comment by EastLondonCoder in "Statement by Denmark, Finland, France, Germany, the Netherlands,Norway,Sweden,UK"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;This isn’t really about Greenland’s strategic value; it’s about the category error. You can trade goods, sign treaties, and negotiate basing rights. You can’t “buy” a people or their sovereignty especially when they don’t consent. That’s why Europe responds with process and principle: normalize coercion-as-bargaining among allies and you’re reviving a pre-1945 model of politics Europe built institutions to prevent.&lt;p&gt;It’s also lose-lose for the US. There isn’t a positive outcome. If it’s dropped, the damage is “just” reputational and partly repairable. If it’s pursued: tariffs, threats, coercion. It burns trust inside NATO, accelerates European strategic decoupling, and hands a propaganda gift to every US adversary. A forced takeover would be a catastrophic own-goal: legitimacy crisis, sanctions/retaliation, and a long-term security headache the US doesn’t need.&lt;p&gt;And the deeper issue is credibility. The dollar’s reserve status and US financial leverage rest on the assumption that the US is broadly predictable and rule-bound. When you start treating allies like extractive targets, you’re not “winning” you’re encouraging everyone to build workarounds. Part of the postwar setup was that Europe outsourced a lot of hard security while the US underwrote the system; if the US turns that security guarantee into leverage against allies, you should expect Europe to reprice the relationship and invest accordingly.&lt;p&gt;The least-bad outcome is a face-saving off-ramp and dropping the whole line of inquiry. Nothing good comes from keeping it on the table.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 18 Jan 2026 17:25:40 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46669850</link><dc:creator>EastLondonCoder</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46669850</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46669850</guid></item><item><title>New comment by huhkerrf in "The Nobel Prize and the Laureate Are Inseparable"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;It's such a joke that we're even having to discuss this. Has there ever been such a thin-skinned, self-absorbed leader of a major power before? Even his biggest fans have to admit, if only to themselves, that he acts like a toddler.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 18 Jan 2026 17:21:52 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46669810</link><dc:creator>huhkerrf</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46669810</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46669810</guid></item><item><title>New comment by bad_haircut72 in "The Nobel Prize and the Laureate Are Inseparable"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;They can say whatever they want but Usain Bolt gave me his gold medal so now Im the fastest 100m runner in the world&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 18 Jan 2026 17:21:45 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46669808</link><dc:creator>bad_haircut72</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46669808</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46669808</guid></item><item><title>New comment by csense in "Predicting OpenAI's ad strategy"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Advertising spend being too high is a symptom of a supply glut.  Too many products in the marketplace, not enough consumers to buy them.&lt;p&gt;In a different world where there are higher wages, more people would have more spending power.  Then companies wouldn't have to spend as many dollars on advertising, which they could split between higher wages, higher margins and lower prices.&lt;p&gt;Alas, the short-term single-firm directional incentive for company decision makers in that world leads to marginal prioritization of higher margins.  The loss of wages leads to loss of consumer spending power but it's spread across the economy.  But every firm has the same incentive so they all do the same thing, and the good thing gets ruined.&lt;p&gt;This line of thinking leads to a Georgist-ish conclusion:  The class conflict &lt;i&gt;shouldn't&lt;/i&gt; be between workers and employers.  They should be allies; the real cause of nobody being able to afford anything is rent extractors.  (Writing in the 1800's, George [1] was most concerned about land rents; but the advertising monopoly of Google / Meta may be another form of extractive rent with similar characteristics.)&lt;p&gt;Maybe Henry Ford was on to something when he shocked the world by paying his employees enough to afford the product they were making (more than doubling many workers' wages)...&lt;p&gt;[1] &lt;a href="https://www.astralcodexten.com/p/your-book-review-progress-and-poverty" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://www.astralcodexten.com/p/your-book-review-progress-a...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 18 Jan 2026 16:56:56 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46669491</link><dc:creator>csense</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46669491</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46669491</guid></item><item><title>New comment by jesse__ in "Command-line Tools can be 235x Faster than your Hadoop Cluster (2014)"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I've done a handful of interviews recently where the 'scaling' problem involves something that comfortably fits on one machine.  The funniest one was ingesting something like 1gb of json &lt;i&gt;per day&lt;/i&gt;.  I explained, from first principals, how it fits, and received feedback along the lines of "our engineers agreed with your technical assessment, but that's not the answer we wanted, so we're going to pass".  I've had this experience a good handful of times.&lt;p&gt;I think a lot of people don't realize machines come with TBs of RAM and hundreds of physical cores.  One machine is fucking huge these days.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 18 Jan 2026 16:40:39 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46669253</link><dc:creator>jesse__</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46669253</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46669253</guid></item><item><title>New comment by bearjaws in "Predicting OpenAI's ad strategy"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;There is something to be said about the state of advertising.&lt;p&gt;Increasingly it seems you must go to the almighty Google or Meta in order to launch any business.&lt;p&gt;We're looking to expand into a new business line and have out grown our pharmacy capacity.&lt;p&gt;The new business line will cost about $2M in software dev, and $3M for the new facility. The advertising budget? $40,000,000 (annual).&lt;p&gt;We can build 10 robotic pharmacies (~10 staff per 4000 fills daily, each) for the price of just the advertising.&lt;p&gt;Increasingly we wonder why America doesn't build more and here is why. You are going to give all your revenue to two platforms. Unless you operate in a business line with 50% margin you are screwed.&lt;p&gt;I don't know what the solution is, but its clear that the platforms are figuring out how much margin everyone has and slowly eroding it. Somewhere between 8-15% of the cost of all products we purchase is advertising spend.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 18 Jan 2026 15:15:37 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46668449</link><dc:creator>bearjaws</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46668449</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46668449</guid></item><item><title>New comment by lordnacho in "Software engineers can no longer neglect their soft skills"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I don't think it has ever been the case that you could neglect soft skills. You will hear this over and over, in every area of every business: people become successful by adjusting their behaviour to what works for the business. Sometimes this is called being a slick politician, sometimes it is called avoiding getting bogged down in politics.&lt;p&gt;But it's never been the case that a dev could just focus on technical things and not spend any time figuring out the context they are working in, and behaving accordingly.&lt;p&gt;My first day of work, this is what my boss said to me: "Look at this trading floor. There's screens everywhere, everything is numbers. Deltas, gammas, vegas. Everything is calculated by computers. But don't forget, every business is a people business!"&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 18 Jan 2026 14:51:57 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46668224</link><dc:creator>lordnacho</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46668224</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46668224</guid></item><item><title>New comment by MontyCarloHall in "Predicting OpenAI's ad strategy"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I think ads will inevitably roll out across all tiers, even the expensive paid ones. Ad revenue isn't uniformly distributed across users, but rather heavily skewed towards the wealthiest users, exactly the users most able to purchase an ad-free experience. The users paying $20 or $200/month for premium tiers of ChatGPT are precisely the ones you don't want to exclude from generating ad revenue.&lt;p&gt;Google realized this a long time ago; there is no ad-free paid version of Google Search.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 18 Jan 2026 14:41:36 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46668134</link><dc:creator>MontyCarloHall</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46668134</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46668134</guid></item><item><title>New comment by MarginalGainz in "Command-line Tools can be 235x Faster than your Hadoop Cluster (2014)"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;The saddest part about this article being from 2014 is that the situation has arguably gotten worse.&lt;p&gt;We now have even more layers of abstraction (Airflow, dbt, Snowflake) applied to datasets that often fit entirely in RAM.&lt;p&gt;I've seen startups burning $5k/mo on distributed compute clusters to process &lt;10GB of daily logs, purely because setting up a 'Modern Data Stack' is what gets you promoted, while writing a robust bash script is seen as 'unscalable' or 'hacky'. The incentives are misaligned with efficiency.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 18 Jan 2026 11:59:43 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46667098</link><dc:creator>MarginalGainz</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46667098</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46667098</guid></item><item><title>New comment by blakewatson in "jQuery 4"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Related: This is a nice write-up of how to write reactive jQuery. It's presented as an alternative to jQuery spaghetti code, in the context of being in a legacy codebase where you might not have access to newer frameworks.&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://css-tricks.com/reactive-jquery-for-spaghetti-fied-legacy-codebases-or-when-you-cant-have-nice-things/" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://css-tricks.com/reactive-jquery-for-spaghetti-fied-le...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 18 Jan 2026 06:12:49 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46665252</link><dc:creator>blakewatson</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46665252</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46665252</guid></item><item><title>New comment by karim79 in "jQuery 4"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Still one of my favourite libs on the whole planet. I will always love jQuery. It is responsible for my career in (real) companies.&lt;p&gt;Live on jQuery! Go forth and multiply!&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 18 Jan 2026 05:54:07 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46665162</link><dc:creator>karim79</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46665162</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46665162</guid></item><item><title>New comment by xeeeeeeeeeeenu in "Erdos 281 solved with ChatGPT 5.2 Pro"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&gt; no prior solutions found.&lt;p&gt;This is no longer true, a prior solution has just been found[1], so the LLM proof has been moved to the Section 2 of Terence Tao's wiki[2].&lt;p&gt;[1] - &lt;a href="https://www.erdosproblems.com/forum/thread/281#post-3325" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://www.erdosproblems.com/forum/thread/281#post-3325&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;[2] - &lt;a href="https://github.com/teorth/erdosproblems/wiki/AI-contributions-to-Erd%C5%91s-problems#2-fully-ai-generated-solutions-to-problems-for-which-subsequent-literature-review-found-full-or-partial-solutions" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://github.com/teorth/erdosproblems/wiki/AI-contribution...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 18 Jan 2026 05:15:14 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46664976</link><dc:creator>xeeeeeeeeeeenu</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46664976</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46664976</guid></item><item><title>New comment by davnicwil in "The recurring dream of replacing developers"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;In the end, I think the dream underneath this dream is about being able to manifest things into reality without having to get into the details.&lt;p&gt;The details are what stops it from working in every form it's
been tried.&lt;p&gt;You cannot escape the details. You must engage with them and solve them directly, meticulously. It's messy, it's extremely complicated and it's just plain hard.&lt;p&gt;There is no level of abstraction that saves you from this, because the last level is simply things happening in the world in the way you want them to, and it's really really complicated to engineer that to happen.&lt;p&gt;I think this is evident by looking at the extreme case. There are plenty of companies with software engineers who truly can turn instructions articulated in plain language into software. But you see lots of these not being successful for the simple reason that those providing the instructions are not sufficiently engaged with the detail, or have the detail wrong. Conversely, for the most successful companies the opposite is true.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 18 Jan 2026 02:33:10 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46664302</link><dc:creator>davnicwil</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46664302</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46664302</guid></item><item><title>New comment by nine_k in "If you put Apple icons in reverse it looks like someone getting good at design"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&gt; &lt;i&gt;no one really complained&lt;/i&gt;&lt;p&gt;They were happy that someone finally made a decision, and freed them from the burden of fruitless repeated deliberation.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 18 Jan 2026 02:18:43 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46664201</link><dc:creator>nine_k</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46664201</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46664201</guid></item><item><title>New comment by danpalmer in "If you put Apple icons in reverse it looks like someone getting good at design"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;It looks like someone getting good at illustration. Older icons are far better illustrations. However icon design is not just about illustration, it's about clarity and affordances. Icons don't exist in isolation like an illustration, they exist alongside the rest of the UX and other app icons, and being recognisable is important.&lt;p&gt;All that to say, the sweet pot was likely somewhere in the middle of this timeline. The earliest icons aren't recognisable enough as they're too illustrative. The later icons aren't recognisable enough because they're too basic. The middle are pretty, clear from colour, clear from shape, well branded.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 18 Jan 2026 01:00:31 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46663780</link><dc:creator>danpalmer</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46663780</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46663780</guid></item><item><title>New comment by Esophagus4 in "Raising money fucked me up"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&gt; It's much more comfortable to be the person that "could be X" than to be the person that tries to actually do it.&lt;p&gt;Brilliant insight.&lt;p&gt;Reminds of me this, from Theodore Roosevelt's Citizenship in a Republic:&lt;p&gt;&gt; It is not the critic who counts; not the man who points out how the strong man stumbles, or where the doer of deeds could have done them better. The credit belongs to the man who is actually in the arena, whose face is marred by dust and sweat and blood; who strives valiantly; who errs, who comes short again and again, because there is no effort without error and shortcoming; but who does actually strive to do the deeds; who knows great enthusiasms, the great devotions; who spends himself in a worthy cause; who at the best knows in the end the triumph of high achievement, and who at the worst, if he fails, at least fails while daring greatly, so that his place shall never be with those cold and timid souls who neither know victory nor defeat.&lt;p&gt;Good luck, and go get 'em.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 18 Jan 2026 00:51:04 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46663737</link><dc:creator>Esophagus4</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46663737</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46663737</guid></item><item><title>New comment by gpt5 in "OpenAI to test ads in ChatGPT as it burns through billions"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;All ads start as clearly labeled and distinctive. Then via the magic of iteration and A/B testing they magically evolve to become visually indistinguishable from the rest of the content except for what’s required by law.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 17 Jan 2026 20:24:58 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46661684</link><dc:creator>gpt5</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46661684</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46661684</guid></item><item><title>New comment by jijijijij in "Eight European countries face 10% tariff for opposing US control of Greenland"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Takes century to bake biggest cake ever. Clown enters stage, applause. Clown throws cake to the ground. Audience waits for joke. Curtain falls. 38 trillion dollar bill for cake. Audience is the joke.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 17 Jan 2026 18:16:47 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46660422</link><dc:creator>jijijijij</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46660422</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46660422</guid></item><item><title>New comment by dijit in "The recurring dream of replacing developers"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I've watched this pattern play out in systems administration over two decades. The pitch is always the same: higher abstractions will democratise specialist work. SREs are "fundamentally different" from sysadmins, Kubernetes "abstracts away complexity."&lt;p&gt;In practice, I see expensive reinvention. Developers debug database corruption after pod restarts without understanding filesystem semantics. They recreate monitoring strategies and networking patterns on top of CNI because they never learned the fundamentals these abstractions are built on. They're not learning faster: they're relearning the same operational lessons at orders of magnitude higher cost, now mediated through layers of YAML.&lt;p&gt;Each wave of "democratisation" doesn't eliminate specialists. It creates new specialists who must learn both the abstraction &lt;i&gt;and&lt;/i&gt; what it's abstracting. We've made expertise more expensive to acquire, not unnecessary.&lt;p&gt;Excel proves the rule. It's objectively terrible: 30% of genomics papers contain gene name errors from autocorrect, JP Morgan lost $6bn from formula errors, Public Health England lost 16,000 COVID cases hitting row limits. Yet it succeeded at democratisation by accepting catastrophic failures no proper system would tolerate.&lt;p&gt;The pattern repeats because we want Excel's accessibility with engineering reliability. You can't have both. Either accept disasters for democratisation, or accept that expertise remains required.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 17 Jan 2026 16:54:33 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46659560</link><dc:creator>dijit</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46659560</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46659560</guid></item><item><title>New comment by jackfranklyn in "The recurring dream of replacing developers"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;The pattern that gets missed in these discussions: every "no-code will replace developers" wave actually creates more developer jobs, not fewer.&lt;p&gt;COBOL was supposed to let managers write programs. VB let business users make apps. Squarespace killed the need for web developers. And now AI.&lt;p&gt;What actually happens: the tooling lowers the barrier to entry, way more people try to build things, and then those same people need actual developers when they hit the edges of what the tool can do. The total surface area of "stuff that needs building" keeps expanding.&lt;p&gt;The developers who get displaced are the ones doing purely mechanical work that was already well-specified. But the job of understanding what to build in the first place, or debugging why the automated thing isn't doing what you expected - that's still there. Usually there's more of it.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 17 Jan 2026 16:53:54 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46659554</link><dc:creator>jackfranklyn</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46659554</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46659554</guid></item><item><title>New comment by stephantul in "ASCII characters are not pixels: a deep dive into ASCII rendering"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Amazing post, I didn’t think this through a lot, but since you are normalizing the vectors and calculating the euclidean distance, you will get the same results using a simple matmul, because euclidean distance over normalized vectors is a linear transform of the cosine distance.&lt;p&gt;Since you are just interested in the ranking, not the actual distance, you could also consider skipping the sqrt. This gives the same ranking, but will be a little faster.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 17 Jan 2026 16:42:19 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46659438</link><dc:creator>stephantul</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46659438</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46659438</guid></item><item><title>New comment by cainxinth in "The Dilbert Afterlife"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;From a recent NYTimes article about his passing:&lt;p&gt;&gt; &lt;i&gt;“Dilbert” was a war cry against the management class — the system of deluded jerks you work for who think they know better. Workers posted it on their cubicles like resistance fighters chalking V’s on walls in occupied Paris. But their bosses posted “Dilbert” in their offices too, since they also had a boss who was an idiot.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2026/01/16/opinion/dilbert-scott-adams-maga.html" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://www.nytimes.com/2026/01/16/opinion/dilbert-scott-ada...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 17 Jan 2026 13:53:11 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46658072</link><dc:creator>cainxinth</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46658072</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46658072</guid></item><item><title>New comment by martinpw in "The Dilbert Afterlife"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&gt; This was the world of Dilbert’s rise. You’d put a Dilbert comic on your cubicle wall, and feel like you’d gotten away with something&lt;p&gt;My former manager used to have Dilbert comic strips on his wall. It always puzzled me - was it self deprecating humor? At a certain point though it became clear that in his mind the PHB was one layer ABOVE him in the management chain and not anyone at his level. I suspect it may be a recursive pattern.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 17 Jan 2026 13:24:02 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46657873</link><dc:creator>martinpw</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46657873</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46657873</guid></item><item><title>New comment by einsteinx2 in "PCs refuse to shut down after Microsoft patch"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&gt; Microsoft says that entering the command "shutdown /s /t 0" at the command prompt will, in fact, force your PC to turn off, whether it wants to or not.&lt;p&gt;Wow how the tables have turned…the argument used to be you used Windows instead of Linux because on Linux you might occasionally have to use the scary terminal to fix an issue haha.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 17 Jan 2026 12:50:21 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46657672</link><dc:creator>einsteinx2</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46657672</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46657672</guid></item><item><title>New comment by MPSimmons in "The Dilbert Afterlife"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I disliked Adams, but this is a good eulogy.&lt;p&gt;&gt;For Adams, God took a more creative and – dare I say, crueler – route. He created him only-slightly-above-average at everything except for a world-historical, Mozart-tier, absolutely Leonardo-level skill at making silly comics about hating work.&lt;p&gt;A+, no notes&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 17 Jan 2026 11:49:17 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46657287</link><dc:creator>MPSimmons</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46657287</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46657287</guid></item><item><title>New comment by maest in "Dell UltraSharp 52 Thunderbolt Hub Monitor"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;All the brand naming makes this read like something from American Psycho.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 17 Jan 2026 02:20:18 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46654672</link><dc:creator>maest</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46654672</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46654672</guid></item><item><title>New comment by madmod in "Dell UltraSharp 52 Thunderbolt Hub Monitor"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I have 3 27" 5k monitors in portrait and a 32" 4k horizontal above those. It is all mounted with vesa cheeseplates to manfrotto magic arms on t slot aluminum attached to a C stand with manfrotto super clamps. I also have two genelec studio monitors which sound amazing.&lt;p&gt;All of that cost less than this one monitor.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 17 Jan 2026 00:48:52 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46654195</link><dc:creator>madmod</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46654195</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46654195</guid></item></channel></rss>