<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>Hacker News: Best Comments</title><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/bestcomments</link><description>Hacker News RSS</description><docs>https://hnrss.org/</docs><generator>hnrss v2.1.1</generator><lastBuildDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 23:48:52 +0000</lastBuildDate><ns0:link href="https://hnrss.org/bestcomments" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item><title>New comment by simonw in "We're open-sourcing the successor of Jupyter notebook"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Way to undermine an interesting product launch through poorly chosen language:&lt;p&gt;&gt; Let’s be frank the single‑player notebook has felt outdated for a while now. We’re open‑sourcing its successor. Jupyter belongs in the hall of great ideas — alongside “Hello, world.” and “View Source.”&lt;p&gt;If you're trying to reach out to the Python community this is &lt;i&gt;not&lt;/i&gt; the way to do it. Completely unnecessary hostile language there! Have some respect.&lt;p&gt;My advice to Deepnote is to scrap this launch announcement (ideally with an apology) and try again. They've built something genuinely useful and interesting but it's going go get a lot less attention than it deserves if they introduce the open source version to the world like this.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 19:31:25 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45814982</link><dc:creator>simonw</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45814982</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45814982</guid></item><item><title>New comment by itsoktocry in "Tell HN: X is opening any tweet link in a webview whether you press it or not"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I've been a long-time Twitter user.  I don't hate Elon, so when he bought it I was cautiously optimistic.&lt;p&gt;I deactivated last week.  The platform is bad and getting worse.  It's scammy and spammy.  Everything is designed around garbage engagement, so that the X team can brag about how good the product is doing.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 15:53:27 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45812363</link><dc:creator>itsoktocry</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45812363</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45812363</guid></item><item><title>New comment by robinhood in "Tell HN: X is opening any tweet link in a webview whether you press it or not"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I find it so sad that Twitter still gets traffic at all. Even if we put aside the super shady content on this platform (free speech, lol), the app, either on the web or mobile, has a sub-par user experience.&lt;p&gt;I wish all the devs that I respect were using another platform.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 14:00:10 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45811111</link><dc:creator>robinhood</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45811111</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45811111</guid></item><item><title>New comment by Yizahi in "Ask HN: How to deal with long vibe-coded PRs?"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Alternative to the reject and request rewrite approach, which may not work in the corporation environment. You schedule a really long video call with the offending person, with the agenda politely describing that for such a huge and extensive change, a collaborative meeting is required. You then notify your lead that new huge task has arrived which will take X hours from you, so if he wishes to re-prioritize tasks, he is welcome. And then if the meeting happen, you literally go line by line, demanding that author explain them to you. And if explanation or a meeting are refused, you can reject RP with a clear explanation why.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 12:11:03 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45810025</link><dc:creator>Yizahi</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45810025</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45810025</guid></item><item><title>New comment by susam in "Bloom filters are good for search that does not scale"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;When I worked at RSA over a decade ago, we developed Bloom filter-based indexing to speed up querying on a proprietary database that was specialised for storing petabytes of network events and packet data.  I implemented the core Bloom filter-based indexer based on MurmurHash2 functions and I was quite proud of the work I did back then.  The resulting improvement in query performance looked impressive to our customers.  I remember the querying speed went up from roughly 49,000 records per second to roughly 1,490,000 records per second, so nearly a 30-fold increase.&lt;p&gt;However, the performance gain is not surprising at all since Bloom filters allow the querying engine to skip large blocks of data with certainty when the blocks do not contain the target data.  False negatives are impossible.  False positives occur but the rate of false positives can be made very small with well-chosen parameters and trade-offs.&lt;p&gt;With 4 hash functions (k = 4), 10007 bits per bloom filter (m = 10007) and a new bloom filter for every 1000 records (n = 1000), we achieved a theoretical false-positive rate of only 1.18% ((1 - e(-k * n / m)) ^ k = 0.0118).  In practice, over a period of 5 years, we found that the actual false positive rate varied between 1.13% and 1.29%.&lt;p&gt;The only downside of a false positive is that it makes the query engine read a data block unnecessarily to verify whether the target data is present.  This affects performance but not correctness; much like how CPU branch misprediction affects performance but not correctness.&lt;p&gt;A 30-fold increase in querying speed with just 1.25 kB of overhead per data block of 1000 records (each block roughly 1 MB to 2 MB in size) was, in my view, an excellent trade-off.  It made a lot of difference to the customer experience, turning what used to be a 2 minute wait for query results into a wait of just about 5 seconds, or in larger queries, reducing a 30 minute wait to about 1 minute.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 11:42:30 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45809842</link><dc:creator>susam</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45809842</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45809842</guid></item><item><title>New comment by 317070 in "You can't cURL a Border"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;First, the author is actually wrong. The date is not 5 years before you submit, but is 5 years before the form is received by the home office! So there are a few days of uncertainty, depending on how fast Royal Mail was with the physical documents.&lt;p&gt;Additionally, I did a request for my information from the home office prior to filling in my form. After all, you have the right to request the information they have on you that will be used to verify your form. Kafka would be proud.&lt;p&gt;Let me tell you, Home Office doesn't have a clue where you were 5 years ago. It had approximately 50% of my trips, and frequently only had only one leg of the journey. Plane, ferry, train, sailboat, ... it didn't matter. It seems like they have not been keeping the information very well.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 10:04:12 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45809226</link><dc:creator>317070</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45809226</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45809226</guid></item><item><title>New comment by keiferski in "The Case That A.I. Is Thinking"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I don’t see how being critical of this is a knee jerk response.&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Thinking&lt;/i&gt;, like &lt;i&gt;intelligence&lt;/i&gt; and many other words designating complex things, isn’t a simple topic. The word and concept developed in a world where it referred to human beings, and in a lesser sense, to animals.&lt;p&gt;To simply disregard that entire conceptual history and say, “well it’s doing a thing that looks like thinking, ergo it’s thinking” is the lazy move. What’s really needed is an analysis of what &lt;i&gt;thinking&lt;/i&gt; actually means, as a word. Unfortunately everyone is loathe to argue about definitions, even when that is fundamentally what this is all about.&lt;p&gt;Until that conceptual clarification happens, you can expect endless messy debates with no real resolution.&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;“For every complex problem there is an answer that is clear, simple, and wrong.”&lt;/i&gt;
- H. L. Mencken&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 08:58:35 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45808838</link><dc:creator>keiferski</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45808838</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45808838</guid></item><item><title>New comment by apexalpha in "You can't cURL a Border"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I had no idea travel was this difficult for people who aren't EU citizens.&lt;p&gt;Wow, I'm almost annoyed on the authors behalf of how much hoops there are to jump through.&lt;p&gt;&gt;To apply for British citizenship, you need to prove you were physically in the UK on your application date but five years ago. Not approximately five years, not that week—that exact day when you press "submit" on the form minus five years. Miss it by 24 hours and your application is reject after months of waiting, and you have to pay a hefty fee to re-apply.&lt;p&gt;That's a hilarious requirement. I wonder how that ended up in there.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 08:55:36 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45808817</link><dc:creator>apexalpha</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45808817</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45808817</guid></item><item><title>New comment by FearNotDaniel in "You can't cURL a Border"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&gt; buy a sausage roll at Greggs&lt;p&gt;If that's the first thing he thinks of while transiting through a UK airport, he deserves a citizenship, no questions.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 08:01:37 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45808523</link><dc:creator>FearNotDaniel</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45808523</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45808523</guid></item><item><title>New comment by robot-wrangler in "Tell HN: X is opening any tweet link in a webview whether you press it or not"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Since we're doing PSAs, isn't it also now just a completely broken platform on mobile for everyone who isn't logged in?&lt;p&gt;&gt; Something went wrong, but don't fret - let's give it another shot.&lt;p&gt;This is all I've seen for literally years now.  No real error, does not even say to login or install an app, just blames it on my privacy extensions (I don't actually have any) and offers a button to pointlessly try again.  No big loss, but surprising!  On the one hand, it's the only time big tech isn't engaged in obnoxious harassment, but it's also a conspicuously dumb oversight in the funnel&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 07:01:30 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45808154</link><dc:creator>robot-wrangler</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45808154</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45808154</guid></item><item><title>New comment by testdelacc1 in "Why AC is cheap, but AC repair is a luxury"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;The author makes an error while explaining Jevons’ Paradox. They say “the cheaper and faster we got at producing coal, the more coal we ended up using”. But that’s not paradoxical at all. That’s basic supply and demand curve from economics 101. It’s exactly what you’d expect.&lt;p&gt;Whereas if you take the extraordinarily difficult step of opening Wikipedia (&lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Jevons_paradox" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Jevons_paradox&lt;/a&gt;), you understand the real paradox. Jevons observed that when &lt;i&gt;steam engines&lt;/i&gt; get more efficient and individually use less coal, we end up deploying many more steam engines in many new industries and use cases, increasing coal consumption overall.&lt;p&gt;This seems like a basic oversight, maybe this guy hasn’t heard of Wikipedia. On the other hand, I think he wants to push the narrative that AI is seeing enormous productivity gains. He does this by using price per token, which has fallen. Very similar to Jevons supposedly observing “coal production”. But the author is struggling to point to new industries and use cases that were opened up by AI, like when we deployed steam engines back in the 1860s. So he misstates Jevons paradox, removes the paradoxical part, and makes it seem like his thesis makes sense.&lt;p&gt;Jevons’ Paradox could still apply here! I’m not saying it doesn’t. But we just haven’t seen the examples quite yet. A good example would be an observed surge in demand custom built software as software engineers become more efficient. But lower token costs ain’t it.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 06:32:10 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45807965</link><dc:creator>testdelacc1</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45807965</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45807965</guid></item><item><title>New comment by viccis in "Ask HN: How to deal with long vibe-coded PRs?"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Open source? Close it and ask them resubmit a smaller one and justify the complexity of things like a DSL if they wanted it included.&lt;p&gt;For work? Close it and remind them that their AI velocity doesn't save the company time if it takes me many hours (or even days depending on the complexity of the 9k lines) to review something intended to be merged into an important service. Ask them to resubmit a smaller one and justify the complexity of things like a DSL if they wanted it included. If my boss forces me to review it, then I do so and start quietly applying for new jobs where my job isn't to spend 10x (or 100x) more time reviewing code than my coworkers did "writing" it.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 06:03:03 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45807823</link><dc:creator>viccis</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45807823</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45807823</guid></item><item><title>New comment by throwawayffffas in "Ask HN: How to deal with long vibe-coded PRs?"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&gt; How would you go about reviewing a PR like this?&lt;p&gt;Depends on the context. Is this from:&lt;p&gt;1. A colleague in your workplace. You go "Hey ____, That's kind of a big PR, I am not sure I can review this in a reasonable time frame can you split it up to more manageable pieces? PS: Do we really need a DSL for this?"&lt;p&gt;2. A new contributor to your open source project. You go "Hey ____, Thanks for your interest in helping us develop X. Unfortunately we don't have the resources to go over such a large PR. If you are still interested in helping please consider taking a swing at one of our existing issues that can be found here."&lt;p&gt;3. A contributor you already know. You go "Hey I can't review this ___, its just too long. Can we break it up to smaller parts?"&lt;p&gt;Regardless of the situation be honest, and point out you just can't review that long a PR.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 02:57:12 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45807006</link><dc:creator>throwawayffffas</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45807006</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45807006</guid></item><item><title>New comment by chemotaxis in "AI's Dial-Up Era"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&gt; I look forward to the "personal computing" period, with small models distributed everywhere...&lt;p&gt;One could argue that this period was just a brief fluke. Personal computers really took off only in the 1990s, web 2.0 happened in the mid-2000s. Now, for the average person, 95%+ of screen time boils down to using the computer as a dumb terminal to access centralized services "in the cloud".&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 23:31:04 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45805758</link><dc:creator>chemotaxis</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45805758</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45805758</guid></item><item><title>New comment by isaacdl in "Guideline has been acquired by Gusto"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I almost posted something this morning about this, because I received an email that really frustrated me. I have a 401k with Guideline from an old employer. The email was from Accrue &lt;no-reply@accrue401k.com&gt;, and said, in part:&lt;p&gt;&gt; &lt;i&gt;Login: Please visit my.accrue401k.com to log in. You’ll find that the 401(k) dashboard and user experience remain familiar. If you’ve set up your account, your same login credentials will provide you access into the dashboard. (Please note, Accrue does not currently offer a mobile app).&lt;/i&gt;&lt;p&gt;The my.accrue401k.com part was a hyperlink to that site. I've independently done some digging (and contacted my old employer to verify!) but this is precisely how a targeted phishing attack would work. Asking someone to enter their financial account credentials into a site they've never used or heard of, based entirely on an unsolicited email, is INSANE.&lt;p&gt;This email was the first time I've heard of Gusto, of Guideline being acquired, or of Accrue 401k (which apparently is the company created to hold Guideline's 401k accounts that are NOT affiliated with Gusto). Nice.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 23:24:08 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45805705</link><dc:creator>isaacdl</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45805705</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45805705</guid></item><item><title>New comment by saltysalt in "AI's Dial-Up Era"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Not sure the dial-up analogy fits, instead I tend to think we are in the mainframe period of AI, with large centralised computing models that are so big and expensive to host, only a few corporations can afford to do so. We rent a computing timeshare from them (tokens = punch cards).&lt;p&gt;I look forward to the "personal computing" period, with small models distributed everywhere...&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 22:32:58 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45805263</link><dc:creator>saltysalt</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45805263</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45805263</guid></item><item><title>New comment by tkz1312 in "The Case That A.I. Is Thinking"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Having seen LLMs so many times produce coherent, sensible and valid chains of reasoning to diagnose issues and bugs in software I work on, I am at this point in absolutely no doubt that they are thinking.&lt;p&gt;Consciousness or self awareness is of course a different question, and ones whose answer seems less clear right now.&lt;p&gt;Knee jerk dismissing the evidence in front of your eyes because you find it unbelievable that we can achieve true reasoning via scaled matrix multiplication is understandable, but also betrays a lack of imagination and flexibility of thought. The world is full of bizarre wonders and this is just one more to add to the list.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 22:13:58 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45805074</link><dc:creator>tkz1312</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45805074</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45805074</guid></item><item><title>New comment by booi in "&lt;/&gt; Htmx – The Fetch()ening"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&gt; So, eventually &amp; reluctantly, I have changed my mind: there will be another major version of htmx.&lt;p&gt;&gt; However, in order to keep my word that there will not be a htmx 3.0, the next release will instead be htmx 4.0.&lt;p&gt;technically correct.. the best kind of correct&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 20:54:11 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45804308</link><dc:creator>booi</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45804308</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45804308</guid></item><item><title>New comment by Symmetry in "The Case That A.I. Is Thinking"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;"The question of whether a computer can think is no more interesting than the question of whether a submarine can swim." - Edsger Dijkstra&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 19:04:40 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45802962</link><dc:creator>Symmetry</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45802962</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45802962</guid></item><item><title>New comment by JCM9 in "OpenAI signs $38B cloud computing deal with Amazon"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;OpenAI is generating $13B a year in revenue. Let’s be generous and say $20B. They’ve signed commitments to spend something like $1.4 trillion on compute. An asset that to date has proven to have a hyper-depreciation cycle.&lt;p&gt;Someone has to come up with $1.4 trillion in actual cash, fast, or this whole thing comes crashing down. Why? At the end of all this circular financing and deals are folks that actually want real cash (eg electricity utilities that aren’t going to accept OpenAI shares for payment).&lt;p&gt;If the above doesn’t freak you about a bit at how bonkers this whole thing has become then you need a reality check. “Selling ads” on ChatGPT ain’t gonna close that hole.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 18:34:25 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45802550</link><dc:creator>JCM9</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45802550</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45802550</guid></item><item><title>New comment by srpablo in "Why we migrated from Python to Node.js"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I'm really torn -- you and your engineers should be excited to work on your codebase. You should enter it and be like "yes, I've made good choices and this is a codebase I appreciate, and it has promise." If you have a set of storylines that make this migration appropriate, and its still early in the company that you can even do this in 3 days, then by all means, do it! And good luck. It'll never be cheaper to do it, and you are going to be "wearing" it for your company's lifetime.&lt;p&gt;But a part of me is reading this and thinking "friend... if PostHog was able to do what they're doing on the stack you're abandoning, do you think that stack is &lt;i&gt;actually&lt;/i&gt; going to limit your scalability in any way that matters?" Like, you have the counterexample right there! Other companies are making the "technically worse" choice but making it work.&lt;p&gt;I love coding and I recognize that human beings are made of narratives, but this feels like 3 days you could have spent on customer needs or feature dev or marketing, and instead you rolled around in the code mud for a bit. It's fine to do that every now and then, and if this was a more radical jump (e.g. a BEAM language like Elixir or Gleam, or hell, even Golang, which has that preemptive scheduler + fast compiles/binary deploys + designed around a type system...) than I'd buy it more. And I'm not in your shoes so it's easy to armchair quarterback. But it smells a bit like getting in your head on technical narratives that are more fun to apply your creativity to, instead of the ones your company really needs.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 18:34:02 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45802544</link><dc:creator>srpablo</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45802544</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45802544</guid></item><item><title>New comment by xfalcox in "The Case Against PGVector"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&gt; Nobody’s actually run this in production&lt;p&gt;We do at Discourse, in thousands of databases, and it's leveraged in most of the billions of page views we serve.&lt;p&gt;&gt; Pre- vs. Post-Filtering (or: why you need to become a query planner expert)&lt;p&gt;This was fixed in version 0.8.0 via Iterative Scans (&lt;a href="https://github.com/pgvector/pgvector?tab=readme-ov-file#iterative-scan-options" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://github.com/pgvector/pgvector?tab=readme-ov-file#iter...&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;p&gt;&gt; Just use a real vector database&lt;p&gt;If you are running a single service that may be an easier sell, but it's not a silver bullet.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 14:16:36 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45799162</link><dc:creator>xfalcox</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45799162</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45799162</guid></item><item><title>New comment by agys in "Tiny electric motor can produce more than 1,000 horsepower"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Everything but the Metric System: “The new YASA axial flux motor weighs just 28 pounds, or about the same as a small dog.” :)&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 10:15:05 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45797535</link><dc:creator>agys</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45797535</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45797535</guid></item><item><title>New comment by davedx in "Tiny electric motor can produce more than 1,000 horsepower"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Could lead to significant efficiency gains for EV's, because 1/4 of the motor weight means better power-to-weight ratio... a lot of things will automatically get better.&lt;p&gt;YASA was founded in 2009, a spin out from Oxford University following the PhD of founder and still CTO, Dr Tim Woolmer.&lt;p&gt;"Over the decades that followed both of these technologies were explored. But despite the potential for weight reduction, smaller size, shorter axle length and increased torque, it was the difficulty in manufacturing the axial flux technology that limited its commercial viability, because the motor could not be made by stacking laminations, as with radial machines."&lt;p&gt;"The breakthrough innovation came by segmenting the axial flux motor in discrete "pole-pieces", so the motor could be manufactured using Soft Magnetic Composite material.&lt;p&gt;SMC can be pressed at low cost into a wide variety of 3D shapes. This removed the need for the complex laminations, overcoming the major manufacturing challenge of the axial flux machine."&lt;p&gt;"In 2025, after a £12m investment, YASA opened the UK's first axial-flux super factory, in Oxfordshire.&lt;p&gt;The opening of this facility boosts YASA’s manufacturing capacity, setting new benchmarks in e-motor technology and quality, and enabling production to scale beyond 25,000 units per year."&lt;p&gt;This is awesome. Lighter motors also make electric flight more viable&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 09:39:58 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45797359</link><dc:creator>davedx</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45797359</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45797359</guid></item><item><title>New comment by darshanime in "First recording of a dying human brain shows waves similar to memory flashbacks (2022)"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;When I was around 15, I used to hang out with a guy who was much senior to me, and he would bully us sometimes. One day, when we were bantering, I cracked a joke that a third guy with us (who was my age) found funny and crackled. The bully grabbed my neck and choked me till I lost consciousness. I remember having memory flashbacks related to missing a train, and someone waiting at the wagon door, waving at me to hurry and jump in before it is too late. I remember feeling stressed about missing the train. The next thing I remember is slowly regaining consciousness to see the bully and the 3rd guy splashing water at my face, looking very amused.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 08:30:20 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45797004</link><dc:creator>darshanime</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45797004</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45797004</guid></item><item><title>New comment by kashnote in "Facts about throwing good parties"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Love all of these tips. I've hosted dozens of events since moving to NYC and figured I'd add 5 more:&lt;p&gt;1. If this is a dinner party (or people are all seated), force people to get up and move in a way that they'll meet new people. Do this when you're about 2/3 of the way through the party. Some will complain - do it anyway.&lt;p&gt;2. Plan 1 (ideally 2) interludes. It can be a small speech, moving people around, changing locations, having people vote on something, etc. For whatever reason, they make the night more memorable.&lt;p&gt;3. Do your best to make introductions natural and low-pressure. Saying things like "you two would really get along" can put pressure on people - especially shy ones. Bring up something they have in common and let them chat while you back away.&lt;p&gt;4. Go easy on folks who cancel last minute. They often don't feel good about doing it and you don't want to add more stress to them or yourself.&lt;p&gt;5. More music != more fun. Some music is good, but if people can't hear each other, turn it down.&lt;p&gt;If you're interested reading more about this stuff, read The Art of Gathering by Priya Parker.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 01:10:17 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45794946</link><dc:creator>kashnote</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45794946</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45794946</guid></item><item><title>New comment by dlisboa in "Facts about throwing good parties"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I feel like this is really an American culture thing where parties or dinner parties are mostly the responsibility of the host. In movies or TV there’s even a common theme of guests judging the host’s hosting abilities.&lt;p&gt;In Brazil you throw a party to people you like and they all have a hand in helping you, sharing the load. Everyone will be responsible for some part of it, all of it is organized informally, there are no real formalities to the event. No one cares about making a science out of it.&lt;p&gt;I’ve never heard of a person complaining about party quality or comparing hosting abilities.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 00:38:43 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45794756</link><dc:creator>dlisboa</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45794756</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45794756</guid></item><item><title>New comment by ssl-3 in "Facts about throwing good parties"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I had a halloween party once.  It had everything:  Substance abuse, debauchery, a proper PA system shaking the floor, good lighting, costumes, good people we knew, random other people we'd never met before, a keg of beer, epic bean dip...  everything but the police, somehow.&lt;p&gt;Anyway, my boss showed up.  I don't know if I invited him or if he just decided to be there on his own.  He was having a great time with everything, and then he went into the back where some folks were enjoying the not-booze.&lt;p&gt;It was at this point that I lost track of him.&lt;p&gt;His jacket was still there.  His motorcycle was still parked on the front sidewalk.  But he was nowhere to be found, and his phone went straight to voicemail.  It was like he'd simply vanished.&lt;p&gt;"Fuck," I thought to myself.  "I've only had this job for a few months."&lt;p&gt;It turns out that he'd walked home, a couple of miles away.  He woke up the next morning sitting at the picnic table in his back yard, shirtless, in the rain.&lt;p&gt;After that, I always made sure that I invited him to my other parties -- and he always made sure to decline, and tell me that he was never doing anything like that ever again.  I consider this to be a win.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 00:31:22 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45794712</link><dc:creator>ssl-3</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45794712</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45794712</guid></item><item><title>New comment by buildsjets in "Facts about throwing good parties"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I sure miss the kind of parties where they have to get an emergency court order to cut power the building at 3am.&lt;p&gt;I learned everything I need to know about throwing parties from Dave Barry.&lt;p&gt;If you throw a party, the worst thing that you can do would be to throw the kind of party where your guests wake up today, and call you to say they had a nice time.  Now you'll be be expected to throw another party next year.&lt;p&gt;What you should do is throw the kind of party where your guest wake up several days from now and call their lawyers to find out if they've been indicted for anything.  You want your guests to be so anxious to avoid a recurrence of your party that they immediately start planning parties of their own, a year in advance, just to prevent you from having another one.&lt;p&gt;If your party is successful, the police will knock on your door, unless your party is very successful in which case they will lob tear gas through your living room window.  As host, your job is to make sure that they don't arrest anybody.  Or if they're dead set on arresting someone, your job is to make sure it isn't you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 02 Nov 2025 23:54:47 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45794494</link><dc:creator>buildsjets</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45794494</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45794494</guid></item><item><title>New comment by ryukoposting in "Is Your Bluetooth Chip Leaking Secrets via RF Signals?"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;As someone who finally recently escaped bluetooth firmware development: yes, Bluetooth is leaking secrets and it doesn't even require any silly RF shenanigans. Almost nothing actually implements LESC. Apple refuses to implement OOB pairing, so no peripherals can force you to use it, so everything is subject to MITM attacks. The entire ecosystem is a mess of consultants and underpaid devs copy-pasting Nordic sample code, with no time or financial incentive to do more than the bare minumum. Never trust any product that moves sensitive data through Bluetooth.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 02 Nov 2025 23:15:44 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45794273</link><dc:creator>ryukoposting</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45794273</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45794273</guid></item></channel></rss>