<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>Hacker News: Best Comments</title><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/bestcomments</link><description>Hacker News RSS</description><docs>https://hnrss.org/</docs><generator>hnrss v2.1.1</generator><lastBuildDate>Sun, 30 Nov 2025 01:36:42 +0000</lastBuildDate><ns0:link href="https://hnrss.org/bestcomments" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item><title>New comment by jmward01 in "All it takes is for one to work out"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;This is why having a safety net and resources to try again is so powerful. Given enough chances you will make it, big. That means the #1 factor in success is the number of chances you get to fail and try again, not necessarily how inherently good you are. I try to remind myself of this often. I have been given so many chances, and I took them.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 29 Nov 2025 21:09:48 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46090792</link><dc:creator>jmward01</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46090792</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46090792</guid></item><item><title>New comment by NietTim in "Be Like Clippy"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Clippy was never open source or "good" in any way, it not selling your data was a result of its time, not a conscious choice by its creators. The entire forced clippy "movement" is incredibly poorly thought out&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 29 Nov 2025 20:26:53 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46090463</link><dc:creator>NietTim</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46090463</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46090463</guid></item><item><title>New comment by jampa in "Major AI conference flooded with peer reviews written by AI"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;While I think there's significant AI "offloading" in writing, the article's methodology relies on "AI-detectors," which reads like PR for Pangram. I don't need to explain why AI detectors are mostly bullshit and harmful for people who have never used LLMs. [1]&lt;p&gt;1: &lt;a href="https://hn.algolia.com/?dateRange=all&amp;page=0&amp;prefix=true&amp;query=ai%20detector&amp;sort=byPopularity&amp;type=story" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://hn.algolia.com/?dateRange=all&amp;page=0&amp;prefix=true&amp;que...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 29 Nov 2025 16:07:29 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46088580</link><dc:creator>jampa</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46088580</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46088580</guid></item><item><title>New comment by serf in "Leak confirms OpenAI is preparing ads on ChatGPT for public roll out"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;this is one of those HN style comments where business acumen and pertinent sarcasm are wholly indistinguishable .&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 29 Nov 2025 15:37:00 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46088304</link><dc:creator>serf</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46088304</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46088304</guid></item><item><title>New comment by chrisweekly in "It's Always the Process, Stupid"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&gt; &lt;i&gt;Let’s rip the Band-Aid off immediately: If your underlying business process is a mess, sprinkling "AI dust" on it won’t turn it into gold. It will just speed up the rate at which you generate garbage.&lt;p&gt;In the world of Business IT, we get seduced by the shiny new toy. Right now, that toy is Artificial Intelligence. Boardrooms are buzzing with buzzwords like LLMs, agentic workflows, and generative reasoning. Executives are frantically asking, "What is our AI strategy?"&lt;p&gt;But here is the hard truth:&lt;p&gt;There is no such thing as an AI strategy.
There is only Business Process Optimization (BPO).&lt;/i&gt;&lt;p&gt;This is well-expressed, and almost certainly true for an overwhelming majority of companies.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 29 Nov 2025 14:37:09 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46087858</link><dc:creator>chrisweekly</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46087858</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46087858</guid></item><item><title>New comment by afavour in "Leak confirms OpenAI is preparing ads on ChatGPT for public roll out"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&gt; most normal people don't know what Claude or Gemini are&lt;p&gt;In think the point is that they don’t need to know what Gemini is, they just need to know Google, which they most definitely do.&lt;p&gt;IMO ads rollout won’t be as simple as you’re describing it. A lot of people have switched from Google search to AI specifically &lt;i&gt;because&lt;/i&gt; it isn’t filled with SEO, ad filled nonsense. So they’ll need to tread very, very carefully to introduce it without alienating customers. Not to mention mollifying advertisers who are nervous what their product will be shown alongside and OpenAI will probably struggle to offer iron clad guarantees about it. And people generally speaking don’t like ads. If competitors like Google are able to hold out longer with no ads (they certainly aren’t wanting for ad display surfaces) they might be able to pull users away from OpenAI.&lt;p&gt;IMO pivoting to ads is a sign of core weakness for OpenAI. Anyone trying to set up their own ad network in 2025 has to reckon with Google and Meta, the two absolute behemoths of online ads. And both also happen to be major competitors of OpenAI. If they need ads that’s a problem.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 29 Nov 2025 14:06:42 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46087622</link><dc:creator>afavour</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46087622</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46087622</guid></item><item><title>New comment by aurareturn in "Leak confirms OpenAI is preparing ads on ChatGPT for public roll out"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;- ~1 billion users in just 3 years&lt;p&gt;- Extremely personal data on users&lt;p&gt;- Novel way of introducing and learning more about sponsored products&lt;p&gt;- Strong branding for non-techie people (most normal people don't know what Claude or Gemini are)&lt;p&gt;- An app that is getting more and more addictive/indispensable&lt;p&gt;I think OpenAI is going to kill it in ads eventually. This is why Meta and Google went all in on AI. Their lucrative digital ad business is in an existential threat.&lt;p&gt;I think people who kept saying there is no moat in AI is about to be shocked at how strong of a moat there actually is for ChatGPT.&lt;p&gt;All free LLM chat apps will need to support ads or they will eventually die due to worse unit economics or run out of funding.&lt;p&gt;PS. Sam just said OpenAI's revenue will finish at $20b this year. 6x growth from 2024. Zero revenue from non-sub users. What do you guys think their revenue will end up in 2026?&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 29 Nov 2025 12:44:24 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46087109</link><dc:creator>aurareturn</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46087109</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46087109</guid></item><item><title>New comment by addaon in "Airbus A320 – intense solar radiation may corrupt data critical for flight"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I’d really, really like to know what microcontroller family this was found on. Assuming that this is a safety processor (lockstep, ECC, etc) it suggests that ECC was insufficient for the level of bit flips they’re seeing — and if the concern is data corruption, not unintended restart, it means it’s enough flips in one word to be undetectable. The environment they’re operating in isn’t that different from everyone else, so unless they ate some margin elsewhere (bad voltage corner or something), this can definitely be relevant to others. Also would be interesting to know if it’s NVM or SRAM that’s effected.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 29 Nov 2025 02:00:30 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46084635</link><dc:creator>addaon</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46084635</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46084635</guid></item><item><title>New comment by jagged-chisel in "How good engineers write bad code at big companies"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&gt; Why does bad code bother engineers so much?&lt;p&gt;I’ll take a stab.&lt;p&gt;Because I’m being held accountable for the bad results of the bad code. Because I’m being held to task to fix the problems caused by the bad code on a schedule that I didn’t agree with. Because management is using someone else’s bad code to deny me a positive annual review.&lt;p&gt;“You’re a senior engineer - why did fixing this take so long?” Because of the garbage I had to wade through to even find the problem. Because I wasn’t yet working here when this was written and I have to take time to get my head around the insanity.&lt;p&gt;Yes, these are management problems. I’ve spent years managing managers and attempting to educate them on how bad code causes errors and delays. But for many reasons, it’s a Sysiphean task.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 29 Nov 2025 01:22:10 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46084448</link><dc:creator>jagged-chisel</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46084448</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46084448</guid></item><item><title>New comment by sfpotter in "How good engineers write bad code at big companies"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I've read a few of this guys posts now and have consistently been rubbed the wrong way by them. I think I know why now. It's not that he's &lt;i&gt;wrong&lt;/i&gt;. His analysis is reasonable and straightforward. I think it's that the basis for his analysis is ultimately a form of nihilism, coming from someone who (maybe?) used to be an idealist but was burnt by a bad experience and must now explain why believing in anything is misguided.&lt;p&gt;My instinct after reading this article is to pull back a bit and ask some larger questions. Why is it necessary for big tech companies to act this way? Why does bad code bother engineers so much? Are they actually misguided for feeling like bad code is a catastrophe, or is it really the fault of the broader economic sphere we all inhabit? Is it actually maturity to reconcile ourselves to drift powerlessly as faceless and titanic forces sculpt our reality? So many possible questions.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 23:55:45 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46083941</link><dc:creator>sfpotter</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46083941</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46083941</guid></item><item><title>New comment by jsight in "Confessions of a Software Developer: No More Self-Censorship"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Every time that I read this about remote work, all I can think is how much I miss IRC and the culture that came from it.&lt;p&gt;We were doing remote work effectively decades ago. Don't have hallway conversations to fix bugs? Easy, just post your problems on the team chat and someone (often one of several people) would love to drop by to help.&lt;p&gt;I'm not sure exactly all of the forces that have led to this changing so much, but I'm certain that merely blaming "remote work" isn't it.&lt;p&gt;Somehow we were better at using remote tools while literally in the same office than some teams are at using them now while fully remote.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 23:50:38 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46083904</link><dc:creator>jsight</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46083904</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46083904</guid></item><item><title>New comment by mikert89 in "How good engineers write bad code at big companies"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;what I see alot is that the syntax and overall code architecture is text book, but its the completely wrong approach that creates extremely complicated tech debt. All the code reviews will be on the syntax, and none on the big picture of the business problem, or whether the implementation is overcomplicated.&lt;p&gt;in the short run (1-2 years) there is no repercussion for this, but eventually making changes will be extremely risky and complicated. The individuals that built the software will lord over everyone else with their arcane knowledge of this big pile of junk&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 22:26:16 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46083339</link><dc:creator>mikert89</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46083339</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46083339</guid></item><item><title>New comment by loeg in "Flight disruption warning as Airbus requests modifications to 6k planes"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;The live feed buries the only useful information at the very bottom of the article:&lt;p&gt;&gt; The plane manufacturer says it has found that intense radiation from the Sun could corrupt data crucial to flight controls.&lt;p&gt;&gt; It’s thought most will be able to undergo a simple software update.&lt;p&gt;&gt; The issue was discovered after a JetBlue aircraft en-route from Mexico to the United States in October experienced a ‘sudden drop in altitude’.&lt;p&gt;&gt; The plane made an emergency landing, with reports at the time suggesting 15 to 20 people suffered minor injuries.&lt;p&gt;&gt; It’s thought the incident was caused by intense solar radiation, which corrupted data in a computer used to help control the aircraft.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 22:18:46 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46083284</link><dc:creator>loeg</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46083284</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46083284</guid></item><item><title>New comment by arianvanp in "Can Dutch universities do without Microsoft?"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I studied at Utrecht University and all the programming classes in the Bachelor were C#, Visual Studio, XNA, DirectX. Windows. Database class i had to learn in Proprietary Microsoft tools too. All Microsoft stuff.  Sure nobody would complain if you did stuff on Linux but all the support by TAs and teachers was on Microsoft platforms only.. The Master was much better but the Bachelor basically was grooming people to become Microsoft consultants.&lt;p&gt;If the rot starts at the core of your education curriculum there is no saving your dependence on Microsoft.&lt;p&gt;I always found this choice puzzling to teach people proprietary technologies in a public institution. This was before DotNet core and VSCode was a thing and Microsoft hadnt whitewashed themselves to look like an open source friendly brand yet.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 21:42:59 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46083022</link><dc:creator>arianvanp</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46083022</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46083022</guid></item><item><title>New comment by n3dm in "Molly: An Improved Signal App"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I've used Molly for over a year. Overnight it lost the device registration and will not contact the servers to re-register. The backup feature also does not work which left me dead in the water for several days with no fix. I switched back to signal and had to start a new database. It was a disaster. YMMV&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 21:22:36 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46082867</link><dc:creator>n3dm</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46082867</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46082867</guid></item><item><title>New comment by JoshTriplett in "Imgur geo-blocked the UK, so I geo-unblocked my network"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I was hoping, from the title ("Geo-Unblocked") that this would be about arranging an IP address block that wasn't associated with the UK, rather than just selectively running some traffic through a VPN.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 19:26:23 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46081916</link><dc:creator>JoshTriplett</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46081916</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46081916</guid></item><item><title>New comment by grishka in "Molly: An Improved Signal App"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&gt; What "proprietary blobs" does Signal have?&lt;p&gt;As they say in the Github readme, FCM and Google Maps.&lt;p&gt;FCM doesn't technically &lt;i&gt;require&lt;/i&gt; a blob — it's just that Google wants you to think it does. I reverse engineered their library and it turned out to be a criminally over-engineered wrapper around two broadcast receivers. So, the Mastodon app is proudly the first app ever to both support FCM push notifications, &lt;i&gt;and&lt;/i&gt; be 100% open-source.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 19:20:08 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46081855</link><dc:creator>grishka</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46081855</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46081855</guid></item><item><title>New comment by minimaxir in "28M Hacker News comments as vector embedding search dataset"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Don't use all-MiniLM-L6-v2 for new vector embeddings datasets.&lt;p&gt;Yes, it's the open-weights embedding model used in all the tutorials and it &lt;i&gt;was&lt;/i&gt; the most pragmatic model to use in sentence-transformers when vector stores were in their infancy, but it's old and does not implement the newest advances in architectures and data training pipelines, and it has a low context length of 512 when embedding models can do 2k+ with even more efficient tokenizers.&lt;p&gt;For open-weights, I would recommend EmbeddingGemma (&lt;a href="https://huggingface.co/google/embeddinggemma-300m" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://huggingface.co/google/embeddinggemma-300m&lt;/a&gt;) instead which has incredible benchmarks and a 2k context window: although it's larger/slower to encode, the payoff is worth it. For a compromise, bge-base-en-v1.5 (&lt;a href="https://huggingface.co/BAAI/bge-base-en-v1.5" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://huggingface.co/BAAI/bge-base-en-v1.5&lt;/a&gt;) or nomic-embed-text-v1.5 (&lt;a href="https://huggingface.co/nomic-ai/nomic-embed-text-v1.5" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://huggingface.co/nomic-ai/nomic-embed-text-v1.5&lt;/a&gt;) are also good.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 19:14:51 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46081800</link><dc:creator>minimaxir</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46081800</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46081800</guid></item><item><title>New comment by elevation in "Bringing Sexy Back. Internet surveillance has killed eroticism"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&gt; She demanded that I apologize to the women&lt;p&gt;This is antisocial advice.  It's beyond inappropriate to use the pretense of apology to announce your intimate fantasies to strangers.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 18:43:13 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46081476</link><dc:creator>elevation</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46081476</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46081476</guid></item><item><title>New comment by mjr00 in "Bringing Sexy Back. Internet surveillance has killed eroticism"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;The main thing I get out of this article is how easy it is to get trapped in a bubble thanks to algorithmic social media.&lt;p&gt;For the most part, sexy never left, and statistics bear this out. OnlyFans brings in enormous amount of revenue, even after an expensive, failed attempt to be not-just-a-porn-site. Hypersexualized gacha games are pulling in tens of millions of dollars per month, and not just for men; the women-targeted &lt;i&gt;Love and Deepspace&lt;/i&gt; had over $50 million in revenue in October. Marvel Rivals, criticized in some circles (such as the social circles of those in the article) for being an oversexualized "gooner game" has remained in the top 10 games played on Steam since its release a year ago. And nothing drives it home more than stumbling across the shady side of YouTube and finding videos in the "woman with large breasts not wearing a bra does something mundane" genre with multiple millions of views.&lt;p&gt;&gt; I choose these examples from my personal life because they express sentiments that were once the kind of stuff I encountered only in the messy battlegrounds of Twitter, amid discussions about whether Sabrina Carpenter is being oversexualized, whether kinks are akin to a sexual orientation, whether a woman can truly consent in an age-gap relationship, and whether exposure to sex scenes in movies violates viewer consent.&lt;p&gt;Ultimately, these are the kind of things discussed only by a small, vocal, very online (some might say &lt;i&gt;terminally&lt;/i&gt; online) minority. To think that they represent more than a tiny fraction of the world is, again, reflective of how easy it is to get trapped into online echo chambers.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 18:00:50 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46081037</link><dc:creator>mjr00</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46081037</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46081037</guid></item><item><title>New comment by titzer in "Bringing Sexy Back. Internet surveillance has killed eroticism"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&gt; “Who are you defending yourself against?” To which he answered, to my astonishment: “I don’t know. The world.”&lt;p&gt;Indeed. Moving our every interaction in daily life plus our innermost thoughts to the internet has instilled a low-key fear in all of us that we'll be raked over the coals and villified as the world's worst villains. The digital tar and feathers are lurking always, a menacing psychological force. And it can even happen without our knowledge; some stranger can post a two second context-less clip or a snippet of a conversation and make us look our worst.&lt;p&gt;It's shocking how we can have so much outrage over unknown people but we're flush out of rage for the system that makes us so angry all the time.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 17:53:29 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46080964</link><dc:creator>titzer</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46080964</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46080964</guid></item><item><title>New comment by simonw in "So you wanna build a local RAG?"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;My advice for building something like this: don't get hung up on a need for vector databases and embedding.&lt;p&gt;Full text search or even grep/rg are a lot faster and cheaper to work with - no need to maintain a vector database index - and turn out to work really well if you put them in some kind of agentic tool loop.&lt;p&gt;The big benefit of semantic search was that it could handle fuzzy searching - returning results that mention dogs if someone searches for canines, for example.&lt;p&gt;Give a good LLM a search tool and it can come up with searches like "dog OR canine" on its own - and refine those queries over multiple rounds of searches.&lt;p&gt;Plus it means you don't have to solve the chunking problem!&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 17:50:14 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46080933</link><dc:creator>simonw</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46080933</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46080933</guid></item><item><title>New comment by leo_e in "Moss: a Rust Linux-compatible kernel in 26,000 lines of code"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;The choice of MIT for a kernel feels like setting up the project to be cannibalized rather than contributed to.&lt;p&gt;We've seen this movie before with the BSDs. Hardware vendors love permissive licenses because they can fork, add their proprietary HAL/drivers, and ship a closed binary blob without ever upstreaming a single fix.&lt;p&gt;Linux won specifically because the GPL forced the "greedy" actors to collaborate. In the embedded space, an MIT kernel is just free R&amp;D for a vendor who will lock the bootloader anyway.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 16:41:11 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46080203</link><dc:creator>leo_e</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46080203</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46080203</guid></item><item><title>New comment by simianparrot in "A Remarkable Assertion from A16Z"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Keep this in mind if you _ever_ feel tempted to take A16Z seriously. Absolute charlatans and clowns.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 14:30:45 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46078969</link><dc:creator>simianparrot</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46078969</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46078969</guid></item><item><title>New comment by jsheard in "A Remarkable Assertion from A16Z"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Since the commit history is public, there's a much easier way to tell that AI had a hand in writing that list.&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/a16z-infra/reading-list/commit/93bc3abb04e241ccc1e6b79f4f698247177fb765" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://github.com/a16z-infra/reading-list/commit/93bc3abb04...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;&gt; opus descriptions in cursor, raw&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 14:14:44 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46078827</link><dc:creator>jsheard</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46078827</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46078827</guid></item><item><title>New comment by kylecazar in "A Remarkable Assertion from A16Z"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;It would have been really great to end the blog post mid-sentence.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 13:09:34 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46078330</link><dc:creator>kylecazar</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46078330</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46078330</guid></item><item><title>New comment by SiempreViernes in "EU Council Approves New "Chat Control" Mandate Pushing Mass Surveillance"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Well, the impression of speed is mainly in the head of the headline writers.&lt;p&gt;What has actually happened is that after about three years of faffing about the Council finally decided on it negotiation position begore the Coreper 2 meeting last week, thought it seems they ran put of time at actual the meeting and had to have the formal approval this week.&lt;p&gt;The Council is only one of three parties that draft new laws, so now there's are still several rounds of negotiations left.&lt;p&gt;Nothing substantial has happened to the three texts since last week, it's just that "chat control is back" drives traffic and "Council preparatory body formally approves draft position that got consensus previously but didn't formally get passed because people were fighting over Ukraine stuff for too long" doesn't.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 11:23:41 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46077663</link><dc:creator>SiempreViernes</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46077663</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46077663</guid></item><item><title>New comment by piker in "EU Council Approves New "Chat Control" Mandate Pushing Mass Surveillance"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Even living nearby in the UK it blows my mind how quickly the EU proposes, kills and then revives and passes controversial legislation in such a short timeframe.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 10:57:03 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46077508</link><dc:creator>piker</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46077508</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46077508</guid></item><item><title>New comment by qubex in "GitLab discovers widespread NPM supply chain attack"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;About a month ago I had a rather annoying task to perform, and I found an NPM package that handled it. I threw “brew install NPM” or whatever onto the terminal and watched a veritable deluge of dependencies download and install. Then I typed in ‘npm ’ and my hand hovered on the keyboard after the space as I suddenly thought long and hard about where I was on the risk/benefit curve and then I backspaced and typed “brew uninstall npm” instead, and eventually strung together an oldschool unix utilities pipeline with some awk thrown in. Probably the best decision of my life, in retrospect.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 10:25:28 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46077359</link><dc:creator>qubex</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46077359</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46077359</guid></item><item><title>New comment by ano-ther in "Vsora Jotunn-8 5nm European inference chip"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I don’t get the negativity.&lt;p&gt;The specs look impressive. It is always good to have competition.&lt;p&gt;They announced tapeout in October with planned dev boards next year. Vaporware is when things don’t appear, not when they are on their way (it takes some time for hardware).&lt;p&gt;It’s also strategically important for Europe to have its own supply. The current and last US administration have both threatened to limit supply of AI chips to European countries, and China would do the same (as they have shown with Nexperia).&lt;p&gt;And of course you need the software stack with it. They will have thought of that.&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://vsora.com/vsora-announces-tape-out-of-game-changing-inference-chip-putting-europe-at-the-forefront-of-data-center-ai/" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://vsora.com/vsora-announces-tape-out-of-game-changing-...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 07:20:19 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46076334</link><dc:creator>ano-ther</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46076334</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46076334</guid></item></channel></rss>