<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>Hacker News: Best Comments</title><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/bestcomments</link><description>Hacker News RSS</description><docs>https://hnrss.org/</docs><generator>hnrss v2.1.1</generator><lastBuildDate>Sun, 08 Feb 2026 02:55:32 +0000</lastBuildDate><ns0:link href="https://hnrss.org/bestcomments" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item><title>New comment by wlesieutre in "Microsoft account bugs locked me out of Notepad – Are thin clients ruining PCs?"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;&gt; I'm still a Windows guy, and I always will be.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;p&gt;And this is exactly why Microsoft can get away with a buggy mess of a user hostile operating system.&lt;p&gt;They only have an incentive to make a good OS if people are willing to leave when it’s a bad one.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 07 Feb 2026 20:14:09 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46927434</link><dc:creator>wlesieutre</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46927434</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46927434</guid></item><item><title>New comment by rossdavidh in "The AI boom is causing shortages everywhere else"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;"JPMorgan calculated last fall that the tech industry must collect an extra $650 billion in revenue every year — three times the annual revenue of AI chip giant Nvidia — to earn a reasonable investment return. That marker is probably even higher now because AI spending has increased."&lt;p&gt;That pretty much tells you how this will end, right there.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 07 Feb 2026 19:49:40 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46927073</link><dc:creator>rossdavidh</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46927073</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46927073</guid></item><item><title>New comment by sosomoxie in "We mourn our craft"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I started programming over 40 years ago because it felt like computers were magic. They feel more magic today than ever before. We're literally living in the 1980s fantasy where you could talk to your computer and it had a personality. I can't believe it's actually happening, and I've never had more fun computing.&lt;p&gt;I can't empathize with the complaint that we've "lost something" at all. We're on the precipice of something incredible. That's not to say there aren't downsides (WOPR almost killed everyone after all), but we're definitely in a golden age of computing.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 07 Feb 2026 19:23:40 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46926724</link><dc:creator>sosomoxie</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46926724</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46926724</guid></item><item><title>New comment by iambateman in "We mourn our craft"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I do not mourn.&lt;p&gt;For my whole life I’ve been trying to make things—beautiful elegant things.&lt;p&gt;When I was a child, I found a cracked version of Photoshop and made images which seemed like magic.&lt;p&gt;When I was in college, I learned to make websites through careful, painstaking effort.&lt;p&gt;When I was a young professional, I used those skills and others to make websites for hospitals and summer camps and conferences.&lt;p&gt;Then I learned software development and practiced the slow, methodical process of writing and debugging software.&lt;p&gt;Now, I get to make beautiful things by speaking, guiding, and directing a system which is capable of handling the drudgery while I think about how to make the system wonderful and functional and beautiful.&lt;p&gt;It was, for me, never about the code. It was always about making something useful for myself and others. And that has never been easier.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 07 Feb 2026 19:22:59 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46926715</link><dc:creator>iambateman</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46926715</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46926715</guid></item><item><title>New comment by Herring in "U.S. jobs disappear at fastest January pace since great recession"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Since the end of WW2, Democratic administrations have presided over significantly higher job growth than Republican administrations.&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://arc-anglerfish-washpost-prod-washpost.s3.amazonaws.com/public/ZXZLAMEEVJHZRDDY5LGDFZ3OEQ.png" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://arc-anglerfish-washpost-prod-washpost.s3.amazonaws.c...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 07 Feb 2026 18:59:51 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46926506</link><dc:creator>Herring</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46926506</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46926506</guid></item><item><title>New comment by rglover in "Coding agents have replaced every framework I used"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;A significant number of developers and businesses are going to have an absolutely brutal rude awakening in the not too distant future.&lt;p&gt;You can build things this way, and they may work for a time, but you don't know what you don't know (and experience teaches you that you only find most stuff by building/struggling; not sipping a soda while the AI blurts out potentially secure/stable code).&lt;p&gt;The hubris around AI is going to be hard to watch unwind. What the moment is I can't predict (nor do I care to), but there will be a shift when all of these vibe code only folks get cooked in a way that's closer to existential than benign.&lt;p&gt;Good time to be in business if you can see through the bs and understand how these systems actually function (hint: you won't have much competition soon as most people won't care until it's too late and will "price themselves out of the market").&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 07 Feb 2026 16:18:02 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46924984</link><dc:creator>rglover</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46924984</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46924984</guid></item><item><title>New comment by ipsento606 in "Coding agents have replaced every framework I used"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&gt; Software engineers are scared of designing things themselves.&lt;p&gt;When I use a framework, it's because I believe that the designers of that framework are i) probably better at software engineering than I am, and ii) have encountered all sorts of problems and scaling issues (both in terms of usage and actual codebase size) that I haven't encountered yet, and have designed the framework to ameliorate those problems.&lt;p&gt;Those beliefs aren't always true, but they're often true.&lt;p&gt;Starting projects is easy. You often don't get to the really thorny problems until you're already operating at scale and under considerable pressure. Trying to rearchitect things at that point sucks.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 07 Feb 2026 15:50:35 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46924775</link><dc:creator>ipsento606</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46924775</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46924775</guid></item><item><title>New comment by YousefED in "France's homegrown open source online office suite"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Great to see this on HN. fyi, La Suite is an umbrella project built by DINUM in France that started several years ago, mainly to enable people in the public administration to use more independent tools. It's built in-house, often on top of other open source technologies. E.g.: Matrix powers chat and LiveKit powers Visio (which was recently featured on HN as well when they announced it's rolled out to replace Zoom / Teams, etc [1])&lt;p&gt;I'm fortunate to be collaborating with them as their Docs product is built on top of our open source BlockNote text editor (&lt;a href="https://www.blocknotejs.org" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://www.blocknotejs.org&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;p&gt;Docs specifically started as an international collaboration with Germany [2] to explore how different EU countries can collaborate in building sovereign workplace solutions (several other countries including NL have shown interest as well).&lt;p&gt;They're actively supporting us, and related projects like Yjs (&lt;a href="https://yjs.dev" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://yjs.dev&lt;/a&gt;) by sponsoring feature development.&lt;p&gt;I'm sure many of the team members will follow along here as well! Happy to answer any questions.&lt;p&gt;[1] &lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46873294"&gt;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46873294&lt;/a&gt;
[2] &lt;a href="https://www.zendis.de/en" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://www.zendis.de/en&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 07 Feb 2026 15:24:16 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46924576</link><dc:creator>YousefED</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46924576</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46924576</guid></item><item><title>New comment by abcde666777 in "Coding agents have replaced every framework I used"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;It's strange to me when articles like this describe the 'pain of writing code'. I've always found that the easy part.&lt;p&gt;Anyway, this stuff makes me think of what it would be like if you had Tolkein around today using AI to assist him in his writing.&lt;p&gt;'Claude, generate me a paragraph describing Frodo and Sam having an argument over the trustworthiness of Gollum. Frodo should be defending Gollum and Sam should be on his side.'&lt;p&gt;'Revise that so that Sam is Harsher and Frodo more stubborn.'&lt;p&gt;Sooner or later I look at that and think he'd be better off just writing the damned book instead of wasting so much time writing prompts.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 07 Feb 2026 14:20:11 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46924114</link><dc:creator>abcde666777</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46924114</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46924114</guid></item><item><title>New comment by Kon5ole in "The AI boom is causing shortages everywhere else"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;It's hard to comprehend the scale of these investments. Comparing them to notable industrial projects, it's almost unbelievable.&lt;p&gt;Every week in 2026 Google will pay for the cost of a Burj Khalifa. Amazon for a Wembley Stadium.&lt;p&gt;Facebook will spend a France-England tunnel every month.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 07 Feb 2026 14:11:09 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46924033</link><dc:creator>Kon5ole</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46924033</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46924033</guid></item><item><title>New comment by selfawareMammal in "Why I Joined OpenAI"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&gt; it's not just about saving costs – it's about saving the planet. I have joined OpenAI to work on this challenge directly.&lt;p&gt;I couldn't go on reading.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 07 Feb 2026 09:25:14 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46922513</link><dc:creator>selfawareMammal</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46922513</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46922513</guid></item><item><title>New comment by greazy in "I'm going to cure my girlfriend's brain tumor"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;OP if you're reading this, your time is better spent advocating for your partner, being there for her and loving her.&lt;p&gt;We've been using "AI" in science far longer than you realise. We happily take on new tech at breath taking speed.&lt;p&gt;Don't waste your time, please just focus on her and not the disease.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 07 Feb 2026 05:02:28 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46921463</link><dc:creator>greazy</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46921463</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46921463</guid></item><item><title>New comment by ahhhhnoooo in "I'm going to cure my girlfriend's brain tumor"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I'm... concerned for the health of this man. I appreciate his dedication, but I read a level of love that's pressing past caring for the human and into beating yourself up.&lt;p&gt;Did she ask you to cure this tumor? Did she ask you to post about it?&lt;p&gt;This is a common story in disability and chronic illness communities -- a partner gets so fixated on the illness they forget the human afflicted with it. The ill partner goes to the grave wishing their partner would stop fighting and start just spending their remaining time filling their lives with joy.&lt;p&gt;It leads to especially dark places when they don't succeed.&lt;p&gt;I wish him all the best, but don't lose sight of the human suffering the illness and what &lt;i&gt;they&lt;/i&gt; want.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 07 Feb 2026 02:14:07 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46920644</link><dc:creator>ahhhhnoooo</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46920644</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46920644</guid></item><item><title>New comment by cwillu in "OpenCiv3: Open-source, cross-platform reimagining of Civilization III"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;“Mac will try hard not to let you run this; it will tell you the app is damaged and can’t be opened and helpfully offer to trash it for you. From a terminal you can xattr -cr /path/to/OpenCiv3.app to enable running it.”&lt;p&gt;How far OSX has come since the days of the “cancel or allow” parody advert.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 07 Feb 2026 00:50:50 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46920160</link><dc:creator>cwillu</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46920160</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46920160</guid></item><item><title>New comment by bgentry in "An Update on Heroku"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;As somebody whose first day working at Heroku was the day this acquisition closed, I think it’s mostly a misconception to blame Salesforce for Heroku’s stagnation and eventual irrelevance. Salesforce gave Heroku a ton of funding to build out a vision that was way ahead of its time. Docker didn’t even come out until 2013, AWS didn’t even have multiple regions when it was built. They mostly served as an investor and left us alone to do our thing, or so it seemed those first couple years.&lt;p&gt;The launch of the multi language Cedar runtime in 2011 led to incredible growth and by 2012 we were drowning in tech debt and scaling challenges. Despite more than tripling our headcount in that first year (~20 to 74) we could not keep up.&lt;p&gt;Mid 2012 was especially bad as we were severely impacted by two us-east-1 outages just 2 weeks apart. To the extent it wasn’t already, reliability and paying down tech debt became the main focus and I think we went about 18 months between major user-facing platform launches (Europe region and eventually larger sized dynos being the biggest things we eventually shipped after that drought). The organization lost its ability to ship significant changes or maybe never really had that ability at scale.&lt;p&gt;That time coincided with the founders taking a step back, leaving a loss of leadership and vision that was filled by people more concerned with process than results. I left in 2014 and at that time it already seemed clear to me that the product was basically stalled.&lt;p&gt;I’m not sure how much of this could have been done better even in hindsight. In theory Salesforce could have taken a more hands on approach early on but I don’t think that could have ended better. They were so far from profitability in late 2010 that they could not stay independent without raising more funding. The venture market in ~2010 was much smaller than a few years later—tiny rounds and low valuations. Had the company spent its pre-acquisition engineering cycles building for scalability &amp; reliability at the expense of product velocity they probably would have never gotten successful.&lt;p&gt;Even still, it was the most amazing professional experience of my career, full of brilliant and passionate people, and it’s sad to see it end this way.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 23:23:43 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46919556</link><dc:creator>bgentry</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46919556</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46919556</guid></item><item><title>New comment by WildWeazel in "OpenCiv3: Open-source, cross-platform reimagining of Civilization III"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Hi all, OpenCiv3 founder here. Thanks for the support! Check us out on Civfanatics or Discord to keep up with the project.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 23:19:21 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46919513</link><dc:creator>WildWeazel</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46919513</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46919513</guid></item><item><title>New comment by OptionOfT in "How to effectively write quality code with AI"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I wonder at the end of this if it's the still worth the risk?&lt;p&gt;A lot of how I form my thoughts is driven by writing code, and seeing it on screen, running into its limitations.&lt;p&gt;Maybe it's the kind of work I'm doing, or maybe I just suck, but the code to me is a forcing mechanism into ironing out the details, and I don't get that when I'm writing a specification.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 20:12:54 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46917567</link><dc:creator>OptionOfT</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46917567</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46917567</guid></item><item><title>New comment by nielsbot in "Show HN: I spent 4 years building a UI design tool with only the features I use"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I think a successful product strategy can be "build something you love, see if others love it too". If that's enough customers, you can judiciously expand out from there. The "fail honestly" method.&lt;p&gt;I think the Apple II is one example of this.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 19:57:53 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46917379</link><dc:creator>nielsbot</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46917379</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46917379</guid></item><item><title>New comment by mattlondon in "The Waymo World Model"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Suddenly all this focus on world models by Deep mind starts to make sense. I've never really thought of Waymo as a robot in the same way as e.g. a Boston Dynamics humanoid, but of course it is a robot of sorts.&lt;p&gt;Google/Alphabet are so vertically integrated for AI when you think about it. Compare what they're doing - their own power generation , their own silicon, their own data centers, search Gmail YouTube Gemini workspace wallet, billions and billions of Android and Chromebook users, their ads everywhere, their browser everywhere, waymo, probably buy back Boston dynamics soon enough (they're recently partnered together), fusion research, drugs discovery.... and then look at ChatGPT's chatbot or grok's porn. Pales in comparison.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 18:09:31 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46916092</link><dc:creator>mattlondon</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46916092</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46916092</guid></item><item><title>New comment by herodoturtle in "Hackers (1995) Animated Experience"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I’ve probably watched Hackers over a hundred times. My all time favourite movie. My first crush as a young teenager was Burn. It led to a career in software. So many kindred spirits on this thread - makes me smile.&lt;p&gt;And after 30+ years of watching Hackers, it only occurred to me recently that the biggest noob in the movie Joey beat the Gibson, twice. Sure he had assistance the second time, but still poetic imho.&lt;p&gt;Hack the planet &lt;3&lt;p&gt;You’re in the butter zone now, baby!&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 17:27:08 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46915619</link><dc:creator>herodoturtle</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46915619</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46915619</guid></item><item><title>New comment by cosmic_cheese in "NIMBYs aren't just shutting down housing"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;The thing that gets me is how many people are seemingly in favor of preserving zoning that keeps out mom and pop corner grocers and cute coffee shops and the like.&lt;p&gt;It’s just like… why?! I can’t wrap my head around it. There’s no downside to being able to top off on milk and eggs by taking a leisurely stroll on a sunny Saturday morning. That sounds downright idyllic.&lt;p&gt;People would rather stay marooned in the middle of an endless desert of houses with essentials being a 30-45m drive away.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 16:54:37 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46915201</link><dc:creator>cosmic_cheese</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46915201</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46915201</guid></item><item><title>New comment by xnx in "The Waymo World Model"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&gt; The Waymo World Model can convert those kinds of videos, or any taken with a regular camera, into a multimodal simulation—showing how the Waymo Driver would see that exact scene.&lt;p&gt;Subtle brag that Waymo could drive in camera-only mode if they chose to. They've stated as much previously, but that doesn't seem widely known.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 16:30:29 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46914921</link><dc:creator>xnx</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46914921</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46914921</guid></item><item><title>New comment by simonw in "An Update on Heroku"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;"We know changes like this can raise questions, and we want to be clear about what this means for customers."&lt;p&gt;Proceeds to not be clear about what this means for customers.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 15:51:53 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46914321</link><dc:creator>simonw</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46914321</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46914321</guid></item><item><title>New comment by g8oz in "An Update on Heroku"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;"transitioning to a sustaining engineering model".
 I don't care what anyone says, it takes real talent to come up with lines like this.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 15:46:47 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46914252</link><dc:creator>g8oz</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46914252</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46914252</guid></item><item><title>New comment by jamesblonde in "TikTok's 'addictive design' found to be illegal in Europe"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I gave a talk at PyData Berlin on how to build your own TikTok recommendation algorithm. The TikTok personalized recommendation engine is the world's most valuable AI. It's TikTok's differentiation. It updates recommendations within 1 second of you clicking - at human perceivable latency. If your AI recommender has poor feature freshness, it will be perceived as slow, not intelligent - no matter how good the recommendations are.&lt;p&gt;TikTok's recommender is partly built on European Technology (Apache Flink for real-time feature computation), along with Kafka, and distributed model training infrastructure. The Monolith paper is misleading that the 'online training' is key. It is not. It is that your clicks are made available as features for predicitons in less than 1 second. You need a per-event stream processing architecture for this (like Flink - Feldera would be my modern choice as an incremental streaming engine).&lt;p&gt;* &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=skZ1HcF7AsM" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=skZ1HcF7AsM&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;* Monolith paper - &lt;a href="https://arxiv.org/pdf/2209.07663" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://arxiv.org/pdf/2209.07663&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 13:27:26 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46912562</link><dc:creator>jamesblonde</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46912562</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46912562</guid></item><item><title>New comment by elashri in "I now assume that all ads on Apple news are scams"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;We should assume that all ads in general are scams. The noise to signal ratio is too large to care. Word of mouth and maybe trusted communities like HN is the only way to reliably discover new things.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 13:09:21 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46912393</link><dc:creator>elashri</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46912393</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46912393</guid></item><item><title>New comment by speak_plainly in "I now assume that all ads on Apple news are scams"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Apple News and News+ represent everything wrong with modern Apple: a ham-fisted approach to simplicity that ignores the end user. It is their most mediocre service, jarringly jamming cheap clickbait next to serious journalism in a layout that makes no sense.&lt;p&gt;The technical execution is just as lazy. While some magazines are tailored, many are just flat, low-res PDFs that look terrible on the high-end Retina screens Apple sells. Worst of all, Apple had the leverage to revolutionize a struggling industry; instead, they settled for a half-baked aggregator.&lt;p&gt;It’s a toxic mix of Apple tropes that simply weren't thought through. The ads are the cherry on the cake.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 13:04:11 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46912336</link><dc:creator>speak_plainly</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46912336</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46912336</guid></item><item><title>New comment by grey-area in "Claude Opus 4.6"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Surely the corpus Opus 4.6 ingested would include whatever reference you used to check the spells were there. I mean, there are probably dozens of pages on the internet like this:&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.wizardemporium.com/blog/complete-list-of-harry-potter-spells" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://www.wizardemporium.com/blog/complete-list-of-harry-p...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;Why is this impressive?&lt;p&gt;Do you think it's actually ingesting the books and only using those as a reference? Is that how LLMs work at all? It seems more likely it's predicting these spell names from all the other references it has found on the internet, including lists of spells.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 09:52:31 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46910927</link><dc:creator>grey-area</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46910927</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46910927</guid></item><item><title>New comment by atomicnumber3 in "My AI Adoption Journey"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;"When was the last time you reviewed the machine code produced by a compiler?"&lt;p&gt;Compilers will produce working output given working input literally 100% of my time in my career. I've never personally found a compiler bug.&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile AI can't be trusted to give me a recipe for potato soup. That is to say, I would under no circumstances blindly follow the output of an LLM I asked to make soup. While I have, every day of my life, gladly sent all of the compiler output to the CPU without ever checking it.&lt;p&gt;The compiler metaphor is simply incorrect and people trying to say LLMs compile English into code insult compiler devs and English speakers alike.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 03:55:41 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46908906</link><dc:creator>atomicnumber3</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46908906</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46908906</guid></item><item><title>New comment by digiown in "The RCE that AMD won't fix"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;One good thing we can say about Linux bundling all the drivers is that it obviates the need to run almost all of this type of low quality (if not outright spyware) driver management software. They are especially problematic because they can't be sandboxed easily like most other proprietary crap.&lt;p&gt;For whatever reason, distro maintainers working for free seem a lot more competent with security than billion dollar hardware vendors&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 02:32:51 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46908296</link><dc:creator>digiown</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46908296</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46908296</guid></item></channel></rss>