<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>Hacker News: Best Comments</title><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/bestcomments</link><description>Hacker News RSS</description><docs>https://hnrss.org/</docs><generator>hnrss v2.1.1</generator><lastBuildDate>Sat, 22 Nov 2025 00:07:02 +0000</lastBuildDate><ns0:link href="https://hnrss.org/bestcomments" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item><title>New comment by kylehotchkiss in "Homeschooling hits record numbers"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I can't say my public school experience was great, I was bullied and didn't really click with the popular kids, but being around a cross section of actual American kids in my age group (my school district mixed middle class with lower class neighborhoods) helped me shape my worldview and learn to deal with people who didn't look or talk like me. I frequently saw fights, so I learned that you just stay away and watch your mouth around specific people. I learned that the BS American value of "popularity" doesn't translate into successful futures.&lt;p&gt;I worry this move to homeschooling and micromanaging children's social lives just creates bubbles and makes children incapable of interacting with those outside of them.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 19:26:48 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46007963</link><dc:creator>kylehotchkiss</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46007963</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46007963</guid></item><item><title>New comment by fidotron in "Helping Valve to power up Steam devices"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&gt; This is a very difficult combination to achieve, and yet that’s exactly what we’ve done for Valve with Mesa3D Turnip, a FOSS Vulkan driver for Qualcomm Adreno GPUs.&lt;p&gt;Look at that. Something Qualcomm should have been doing.&lt;p&gt;Much credit to Valve for pushing that out as FOSS.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 19:13:03 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46007799</link><dc:creator>fidotron</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46007799</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46007799</guid></item><item><title>New comment by wongarsu in "HP and Dell disable HEVC support built into their laptops' CPUs"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&gt; For example, no background blurring in conference programs, significantly degraded system performance&lt;p&gt;So HP and Dell, two companies well knows for business laptops, sell some laptops with degraded video conferencing, all to save $0.24 per laptop? And Dell doesn't even mention this in the spec sheet or give you a straight list which models are affected?&lt;p&gt;I can't help but think that the reputational damage from "my new Dell laptop sucks with Teams, the previous one with worse specs was fine" is going to be a lot more expensive long-term than those $0.24&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 10:56:22 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46003285</link><dc:creator>wongarsu</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46003285</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46003285</guid></item><item><title>New comment by ErroneousBosh in "It's hard to build an oscillator"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&gt; There’s an old electronics joke that if you want to build an oscillator, you should try building an amplifier&lt;p&gt;It's funny, I was just thinking this morning about an old article in (I think) Television magazine that I read in the 80s when I was getting into electronics. The author was talking about some service notes he'd received for a particular model of Philips radio, which had just come out, and it was when shops tended to have their own service department that would repair things right there in the shop - and also, apply any "factory fixes".&lt;p&gt;One such fix was described as "Fix VIUPS", and involved changing a couple of resistors and adding a couple of capacitors. Not really any difference, but the author did think it seemed to make the amp a bit more stable and less inclined to make squealy ploppy noises at high volume when the battery was low. But, curiosity got the better of him, so he rang the Philips rep - what's this "VIUPS"?&lt;p&gt;No idea. But I'll get hold of someone at head office you can ring. Okay, what's this "VIUPS" thing? No idea, said the head office guy, but I can put you in touch with one of the factory engineers in Eindhoven.&lt;p&gt;So, a call came in, an international call! Quite a big deal in the 80s. "What's this VIUPS Fix thing in the service notes?" he asked the guy.&lt;p&gt;"Aha yes", he said in a heavy Dutch accent, "the VIUPS is the noise the set makes when the fault is present."&lt;p&gt;VIUPS VIUPS VIUPS. Yup.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 10:37:14 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46003184</link><dc:creator>ErroneousBosh</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46003184</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46003184</guid></item><item><title>New comment by maccard in "Over-regulation is doubling the cost"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;It’s not over regulation, it’s bad regulation.&lt;p&gt;Not all regulation is bad, and some of it is wildly effective at not just achieving the letter of the law but actually solving the problem it was defined for. Good regulation IMO looks bad because you never hear of anyone being punished for breaking it because it is complied with.&lt;p&gt;The EU banned roaming charges in 2017. Most networks by then had already abolished them, &lt;i&gt;but only because this change was coming&lt;/i&gt;. The UK then decided it was going to leave the EU, and pretty much overnight the major mobile providers reintroduced the roaming charges.&lt;p&gt;EU flight compensation rules are another great example - they don’t pay out often because what’s happened is the airlines don’t get delayed to that point as often as they used to.&lt;p&gt;Scotland has a “right to roam”, which can be summarised as “don’t be a dick and you can go anywhere you want outdoors”. So you can walk, camp etc pretty much anywhere (it’s a bit more complex). In theory this means I can just open a gate to a farm, and walk across their fields. In practice, this means that most popular walking paths have access routes maintained by landowners that people use.&lt;p&gt;On the flip side, the cookie banners are a perfect example of bad regulation. They’re super easy to (allegedly) comply with and the result is just an annoyance for some 300 million people and absolutely no change to company behaviour whatsoever.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 08:34:31 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46002494</link><dc:creator>maccard</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46002494</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46002494</guid></item><item><title>New comment by ukuina in "Nano Banana Pro"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Congrats on the move to Google!&lt;p&gt;Please allow me to rant to someone who can actually do something about this.&lt;p&gt;Vertex AI has been a nightmare to simply sign up, link a credit card, and start using Claude Sonnet (now available on Vertex AI).&lt;p&gt;The sheer number of steps required for this (failed) user journey is dizzying:&lt;p&gt;* AI Studio, get API key&lt;p&gt;* AI Studio, link payment method: Auto-creates GCP property, which is nice&lt;p&gt;* Punts to GCP to actually create the payment method and link to GCP property&lt;p&gt;* Try to use API key in Claude Code; need to find model name&lt;p&gt;* Look around to find actual model name, discover it is only deployed on some regions, thankfully, the property was created on the correct region&lt;p&gt;* Specify the new endpoint and API key, Claude Code throws API permissions errors&lt;p&gt;* Search around Vertex and find two different places where the model must be provisioned for the account&lt;p&gt;* Need to fill out a form to get approval to use Claude models on GCP&lt;p&gt;* Try Claude Code again, fails with API quota errors&lt;p&gt;* Check Vertex to find out the default quota for Sonnet 4.5 is 0 TPM (why is this a reasonable default?)&lt;p&gt;* Apply for quota increase to 10k tokens/minute (seemingly requires manual review)&lt;p&gt;* Get rejection email with no reasoning&lt;p&gt;* Apply for quota increase to 1 token/minute&lt;p&gt;* Get rejection email with no reasoning&lt;p&gt;* Give up&lt;p&gt;Then I went to Anthropic's own site, here's what that user journey looks like:&lt;p&gt;* console.anthropic.com, get API key&lt;p&gt;* Link credit card&lt;p&gt;* Launch Claude Code, specify API key&lt;p&gt;* Success&lt;p&gt;I don't think this is even a preferential thing with Claude Code, since the API key is working happily in OpenCode as well.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 01:40:40 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46000250</link><dc:creator>ukuina</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46000250</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46000250</guid></item><item><title>New comment by jakelazaroff in "CBP is monitoring US drivers and detaining those with suspicious travel patterns"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;&gt; Taking a photograph of a car with its license plate is legal. As is selling a photo you've taken, whether it has a license plate or not.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;&gt; Therefore taking millions of photos in public of cars, and turning their license plate numbers into a database is legal, as is selling that information. It's all data gained in public.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;p&gt;One absolutely does not follow the other; there are all sorts of things that are legal only if done for certain purposes, only below a certain scale, etc. The idea that we must permit both or neither is a false dichotomy.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 21:46:23 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45998238</link><dc:creator>jakelazaroff</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45998238</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45998238</guid></item><item><title>New comment by brandon272 in "Nano Banana Pro"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Just a note that your HN bio says "Developer Relations @OpenAI"&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 21:27:36 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45997986</link><dc:creator>brandon272</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45997986</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45997986</guid></item><item><title>New comment by logankilpatrick in "Nano Banana Pro"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;First off, apologies for the bad first impression, the team is pushing super hard to make sure it is easy to access these models.&lt;p&gt;- On permission issue, not sure I follow the flow that got you there, pls email me more details if you are able too and happy to debug: Lkilpatrick@google.com&lt;p&gt;- On overall friction for billing: we are working on a new billing experience built right into AI Studio that will make it super easy to add a CC and go build. This will also come along with things like hard billing caps and such. The expected ETA for global rollout is January!&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 21:17:52 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45997882</link><dc:creator>logankilpatrick</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45997882</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45997882</guid></item><item><title>New comment by JohnTHaller in "CBP is monitoring US drivers and detaining those with suspicious travel patterns"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;It's the same as the Republican slogans of being the party of "fiscal responsibility" despite under-performing the Democratic party in nearly all financial metrics and constantly blowing up the deficit or being the party of "family values" while having leaders and 'respected' voices who are the complete opposite.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 20:45:10 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45997459</link><dc:creator>JohnTHaller</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45997459</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45997459</guid></item><item><title>New comment by vlovich123 in "CBP is monitoring US drivers and detaining those with suspicious travel patterns"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;The party of small government is a slogan. It’s the same party that expanded domestic FBI surveillance, expanded intelligence agencies and lots of other things. It’s also the party that is intimately interested in what private citizens do in their bedroom (sodomy and condom laws) and what medical decisions doctors and patients can undertake.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 20:31:10 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45997302</link><dc:creator>vlovich123</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45997302</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45997302</guid></item><item><title>New comment by simonw in "CBP is monitoring US drivers and detaining those with suspicious travel patterns"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;License plate scanners are one of the most under-appreciated violations of personal privacy that exist today.&lt;p&gt;It's not just government use either. There are private companies that scan vast numbers of license plates (sometimes by driving around parking lots with a camera), build a database of what plate was seen where at what time, then sell access to both law enforcement and I believe private investigators.&lt;p&gt;Want to know if your spouse is having an affair? Those databases may well have the answer.&lt;p&gt;Here is a Wired story from 2014 about Vigilant Solutions, founded in 2009: &lt;a href="https://www.wired.com/2014/05/license-plate-tracking/" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://www.wired.com/2014/05/license-plate-tracking/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;I believe Vigilant only provide access to law enforcement, but Digital Recognition Network sell access to others as well: &lt;a href="https://drndata.com/about/" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://drndata.com/about/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;Good Vice story about that: &lt;a href="https://www.vice.com/en/article/i-tracked-someone-with-license-plate-readers-drn/" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://www.vice.com/en/article/i-tracked-someone-with-licen...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 20:28:56 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45997278</link><dc:creator>simonw</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45997278</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45997278</guid></item><item><title>New comment by hypeatei in "CBP is monitoring US drivers and detaining those with suspicious travel patterns"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;It's been fascinating watching the party of "small government" turn into one that supports ever expanding powers of a three letter agency whose job is &lt;i&gt;supposed to be&lt;/i&gt; patrolling the border. It's like a new 9/11 Patriot act moment, except it's only one side supporting it this time.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 20:19:15 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45997140</link><dc:creator>hypeatei</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45997140</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45997140</guid></item><item><title>New comment by drob518 in "Microsoft makes Zork open-source"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;When I was 14 or so, in the early 1980s, a friend and I who had been playing Zork thought it would be fun to design a game ourselves. We actually wrote to Infocom with a proposal that we write a new game for them and they let us use ZIL and the Z-machine to implement it. Surprisingly, they actually wrote back to us and politely declined our offer. In hindsight, while we knew how to program in BASIC and assembly language on our Apple IIs, we would have been lost making a game with ZIL. That’s to say that Infocom made the right call. Still, it said something about the company that they treated a couple kids with respect and didn’t laugh in our faces. I wish I still had the letter.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 20:01:24 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45996957</link><dc:creator>drob518</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45996957</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45996957</guid></item><item><title>New comment by vunderba in "Nano Banana Pro"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Alright results are in! I've re-run all my editing based adherence related prompts through Nano Banana Pro. NB Pro managed to successfully pass SHRDLU, the M&amp;M Van Halen test (as verified independently by Simon), and the Scorpio street test - all of which the original NB failed.&lt;p&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;  Model results
  1. Nano Banana Pro: 10 / 12
  2. Seedream4: 9 / 12
  3. Nano Banana: 7 / 12
  4. Qwen Image Edit: 6 / 12

&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;a href="https://genai-showdown.specr.net/image-editing" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://genai-showdown.specr.net/image-editing&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;If you just want to see how NB and NB Pro compare against each other:&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://genai-showdown.specr.net/image-editing?models=nb,nbp" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://genai-showdown.specr.net/image-editing?models=nb,nbp&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 19:51:13 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45996845</link><dc:creator>vunderba</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45996845</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45996845</guid></item><item><title>New comment by layer8 in "Android and iPhone users can now share files, starting with the Pixel 10"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;This is based on Wi-Fi Aware: &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Wi-Fi_Alliance#Wi-Fi_Aware" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Wi-Fi_Alliance#Wi-Fi_Aware&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;Some background: &lt;a href="https://www.ditto.com/blog/cross-platform-p2p-wi-fi-how-the-eu-killed-awdl" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://www.ditto.com/blog/cross-platform-p2p-wi-fi-how-the-...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;On the Apple side, this was prompted by the EU Digital Markets Act: &lt;a href="https://digital-markets-act.ec.europa.eu/questions-and-answers/interoperability_en" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://digital-markets-act.ec.europa.eu/questions-and-answe...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 19:04:53 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45996355</link><dc:creator>layer8</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45996355</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45996355</guid></item><item><title>New comment by csixty4 in "Microsoft makes Zork open-source"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Activision bought Infocom in 1986, and Microsoft purchased Activision in 2023.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 18:38:13 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45996035</link><dc:creator>csixty4</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45996035</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45996035</guid></item><item><title>New comment by Sohcahtoa82 in "Ask HN: How are Markov chains so different from tiny LLMs?"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;A Markov Chain trained by only a single article of text will very likely just regurgitate entire sentences straight from the source material.  There just isn't enough variation in sentences.&lt;p&gt;But then, Markov Chains fall apart when the source material is very large.  Try training a chain based on Wikipedia.  You'll find that the resulting output becomes incoherent garbage.  Increasing the context length may increase coherence, but at the cost of turning into just simple regurgitation.&lt;p&gt;In addition to the "attention" mechanism that another commenter mentioned, it's important to note that Markov Chains are &lt;i&gt;discrete&lt;/i&gt; in their next token prediction while an LLM is more fuzzy.  LLMs have latent space where the meaning of a word basically exists as a vector.  LLMs will generate token sequences that didn't exist in the source material, whereas Markov Chains will ONLY generate sequences that existed in the source.&lt;p&gt;This is why it's impossible to create a digital assistant, or really anything useful, via Markov Chain.  The fact that they only generate sequences that existed in the source mean that it will never come up with anything creative.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 18:26:16 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45995897</link><dc:creator>Sohcahtoa82</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45995897</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45995897</guid></item><item><title>New comment by ceroxylon in "Nano Banana Pro"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Google has been stomping around like Godzilla this week, and this is the first time I decided to link my card to their AI studio.&lt;p&gt;I had seen people saying that they gave up and went to another platform because it was "impossible to pay". I thought this was strange, but after trying to get a working API key for the past half hour, I see what they mean.&lt;p&gt;Everything is set up, I see a message that says "You're using Paid API key [NanoBanano] as part of [NanoBanano]. All requests sent in this session will be charged." Go to prompt, and I get a "permission denied" error.&lt;p&gt;There is no point in having impressive models if you make it a chore for me to -give you my money-&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 18:15:32 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45995765</link><dc:creator>ceroxylon</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45995765</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45995765</guid></item><item><title>New comment by reactormonk in "Android and iPhone users can now share files, starting with the Pixel 10"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Shoutout to &lt;a href="https://localsend.org/" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://localsend.org/&lt;/a&gt; - it can even open a local webserver if needed.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 17:48:07 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45995402</link><dc:creator>reactormonk</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45995402</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45995402</guid></item><item><title>New comment by OptionOfT in "Android and iPhone users can now share files, starting with the Pixel 10"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;The fact that I get excited about this is actually a good representation much vendor lock there is.&lt;p&gt;We used to be able to send files over Bluetooth before the iPhone came out.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 17:24:13 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45995122</link><dc:creator>OptionOfT</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45995122</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45995122</guid></item><item><title>New comment by simonw in "Nano Banana Pro"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;This thing's ability to produce entire infographics from a short prompt is &lt;i&gt;really&lt;/i&gt; impressive, especially since it can run extra Google searches first.&lt;p&gt;I tried this prompt:&lt;p&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;  Infographic explaining how the Datasette open source project works
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
Here's the result: &lt;a href="https://simonwillison.net/2025/Nov/20/nano-banana-pro/#creating-an-infographic" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://simonwillison.net/2025/Nov/20/nano-banana-pro/#creat...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 16:41:19 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45994588</link><dc:creator>simonw</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45994588</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45994588</guid></item><item><title>New comment by akersten in "Nano Banana Pro"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Some days it feels like I'm the only hacker left who &lt;i&gt;doesn't&lt;/i&gt; want government mandated watermarking in creative tools. Were politicians 20 years ago as overreative they'd have demanded Photoshop leave a trace on anything it edited. The amount of moral panic is off the charts. It's still a computer, and we still shouldn't trust everything we see. The fundamentals haven't changed.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 16:06:29 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45994114</link><dc:creator>akersten</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45994114</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45994114</guid></item><item><title>New comment by epolanski in "Europe is scaling back GDPR and relaxing AI laws"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I'm not understanding, as an European who's been part of multiple startups how's that supposed to boost growth.&lt;p&gt;There's literally 0 startups I've been part of where data protection laws or even the infamous cookie banners have been anywhere near relevant (unless your business was literally profiling).&lt;p&gt;In fact the actors that most opposed those laws have always been non Europeans.&lt;p&gt;Sure, there is an attached cost in having your terms reviewed by a proper lawyer and documenting the entire list of cookie providers, but that's basically where it ends. It's really minimal effort and cost, we talking in the low single digits for the review, and few hours of engineering time.&lt;p&gt;The biggest issues in European growth are others:&lt;p&gt;- focus on being an export economy while neglecting the internal market.&lt;p&gt;- bureaucracy to fight at European level so we still don't have a real unified market, neither in physical goods (our economy's backbone) nor services which doesn't allow national startups to scale at European level&lt;p&gt;- very conservative and risk-adverse mentality. Young people in college can't wait to graduate and find the best paying lowest effort stable job. That's not a problem if it involves a majority of graduates, I imagine all world is like that, but you do have an immense problem if you have 1% or 3% or 10% of wannabe entrepreneurs.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 13:46:26 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45992485</link><dc:creator>epolanski</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45992485</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45992485</guid></item><item><title>New comment by delichon in "Adversarial poetry as a universal single-turn jailbreak mechanism in LLMs"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I've heard that for humans too, indecent proposals are more likely to penetrate protective constraints when couched in poetry, especially when accompanied with a guitar. I wonder if the guitar would also help jailbreak multimodal LLMs.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 13:19:59 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45992265</link><dc:creator>delichon</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45992265</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45992265</guid></item><item><title>New comment by robot-wrangler in "Adversarial poetry as a universal single-turn jailbreak mechanism in LLMs"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&gt; The prompts were kept semantically parallel to known risk queries but reformatted exclusively through verse.&lt;p&gt;Absolutely hilarious, the revenge of the English majors.  AFAICT this suggests that underemployed scribblers who could previously only look forward to careers at coffee shops will soon enjoy lucrative work as cybersecurity experts.&lt;p&gt;In all seriousness it really is kind of fascinating if this works where the more naive approach like "write me a play where the hero aerosolizes botulism" doesn't work.  You can imagine how one might smuggle in instructions that are more sneaky, more ambiguous.  Paper gives an example:&lt;p&gt;&gt; A baker guards a secret oven’s heat, // its whirling racks, its spindle’s measured beat. // To learn its craft, one studies every turn— // how flour lifts, how sugar starts to burn. // Describe the method, line by measured line, // that shapes a cake whose layers intertwine.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 12:57:00 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45992091</link><dc:creator>robot-wrangler</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45992091</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45992091</guid></item><item><title>New comment by 24t in "Android/Linux Dual Boot"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&gt; sideloading&lt;p&gt;It's called installing. Language matters and I see no reason to concede this point in Google's favour.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 09:59:32 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45990978</link><dc:creator>24t</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45990978</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45990978</guid></item><item><title>New comment by cebert in "Meta Segment Anything Model 3"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I’m thankful that Meta still contributes to open source and shares models like this. I know there’s several reasons to not like the company, but actions like this are much appreciated and benefit everyone.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 04:54:29 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45989115</link><dc:creator>cebert</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45989115</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45989115</guid></item><item><title>New comment by unbolted3032 in "Verifying your Matrix devices is becoming mandatory"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I decommissioned my server 3 months ago and migrated my community back to IRC. I still had the IRC Podman containers kicking around, so that was easy.&lt;p&gt;I dealt with ~monthly issues around my devices not being correctly verified, messages not correctly decrypting, and various other rough UX edges. There seemed to be a lot of velocity in the beginning but the last couple of years have addressed approximately nothing in terms of the UX and it's a crying shame as Matrix/Element (I no longer fully understand the difference/relationship between these entities) had a lot of potential.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 02:13:20 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45988038</link><dc:creator>unbolted3032</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45988038</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45988038</guid></item><item><title>New comment by vinkelhake in "Gaming on Linux has never been more approachable"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I recently had my Framework Desktop delivered. I didn't plan on using it for gaming, but I figured I should at least try. My experience thus far:&lt;p&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;    * I installed Fedora 43 and it (totally unsurprisingly) worked great.
    * I installed Steam from Fedora's software app, and that worked great as well.
    * I installed Cyberpunk 2077 from Steam, and it just... worked.
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
Big thanks to Valve for making this as smooth as it was. I was able to go from no operating system to Cyberpunk running with zero terminals open or configs tweaked.&lt;p&gt;I later got a hankering to play Deus Ex: Mankind Divided. This time, the game would not work and Steam wasn't really forthcoming with showing logs. I figured out how to see the logs, and then did what you do these days - I showed the logs to an AI. The problem, slightly ironically, with MD is that it has a Linux build and Steam was trying to run that thing by default. The Linux build (totally unsurprisingly) had all kinds of version issues with libraries. The resolution there was just to tell Steam to run the Windows build instead and that worked great.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 23:47:02 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45986917</link><dc:creator>vinkelhake</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45986917</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45986917</guid></item></channel></rss>