<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>Hacker News: Best Comments</title><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/bestcomments</link><description>Hacker News RSS</description><docs>https://hnrss.org/</docs><generator>hnrss v2.1.1</generator><lastBuildDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2025 00:17:09 +0000</lastBuildDate><ns0:link href="https://hnrss.org/bestcomments" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item><title>New comment by jjice in "Last Year on My Mac: Look Back in Disbelief"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I don't mind how Liquid Glass looks at all. It's just insane how buggy the system has become. Even Messages will bug out, like deleting my first word if I type too fast after opening a conversation or auto scrolling and not letting me scroll down until I exit and re-enter.&lt;p&gt;Unacceptable for the premium you pay for Apple software. Unacceptable for any software one is paying for. I hope they get their shit together and start fixing before they continue adding new stuff. 26.2 doesn't inspire me that they're on that trajectory.&lt;p&gt;The thing that amazes me most is that everyone on the teams responsible is probably using their Apple devices and running into these same bugs!&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 28 Dec 2025 16:13:20 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46412078</link><dc:creator>jjice</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46412078</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46412078</guid></item><item><title>New comment by jasode in "C++ says “We have try. . . finally at home”"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;The submitted title is missing the salient keyword &lt;i&gt;"finally"&lt;/i&gt; that motivates the blog post.  The actual subtitle Raymond Chen wrote is:  &lt;i&gt;"C++ says “We have try…finally at home.”"&lt;/i&gt;&lt;p&gt;It's a snowclone based on the meme, &lt;i&gt;"Mom, can we get &lt;X&gt;?  No, we have &lt;X&gt; at home."&lt;/i&gt; :  &lt;a href="https://www.google.com/search?q=%22we+have+x+at+home%22+meme" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://www.google.com/search?q=%22we+have+x+at+home%22+meme&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;In other words, Raymond is saying... "We already have Java feature of 'finally' at home in the C++ refrigerator and it's called 'destructor'"&lt;p&gt;To continue the meme analogy, the kid's idea of &lt;X&gt; doesn't match mom's idea of &lt;X&gt; and disagrees that they're equivalent.   E.g. "Mom, can we order pizza? No, we have leftover casserole in the fridge."&lt;p&gt;So some kids would complain that C++ destructors RAII philosophy require creating a whole "class X{public:~X()}" which is sometimes inconvenient so it doesn't exactly equal "finally".&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 28 Dec 2025 10:00:45 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46409904</link><dc:creator>jasode</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46409904</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46409904</guid></item><item><title>New comment by levmiseri in "Replacing JavaScript with Just HTML"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;A missed opportunity to not have all of these examples inline. The page/blog-post would be so much more convincing if it utilized all of these HTML replacements instead (or in addition) to linking to codepen.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 28 Dec 2025 09:32:39 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46409716</link><dc:creator>levmiseri</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46409716</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46409716</guid></item><item><title>New comment by butz in "Rainbow Six Siege hacked as players get billions of credits and random bans"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Nice to see anti-cheats working and protecting Linux players from hacks, by preventing them from actually playing the game.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 28 Dec 2025 08:33:39 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46409448</link><dc:creator>butz</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46409448</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46409448</guid></item><item><title>New comment by Vincent_Yan404 in "Growing up in “404 Not Found”: China's nuclear city in the Gobi Desert"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Hi HN, OP here.&lt;p&gt;I grew up in "Factory 404," a secret nuclear industrial city in the Gobi Desert that officially didn't exist on public maps. This is a memoir about my childhood there.&lt;p&gt;It was a surreal place: we had elite scientists living next to laborers, a zoo in the middle of the desert, and distinct "communist" welfare, all hidden behind a classified code.&lt;p&gt;This is Part 1 of the story. I'm happy to answer any questions about life in a Chinese nuclear base!&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 28 Dec 2025 06:58:07 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46409061</link><dc:creator>Vincent_Yan404</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46409061</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46409061</guid></item><item><title>New comment by abetusk in "Calendar"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;The neatnik calendar is very nice. Others are talking about enhancements they've done and I've done my own, creating a pretty faithful JavaScript implementation with enhancements:&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/abetusk/neatocal" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://github.com/abetusk/neatocal&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://abetusk.github.io/neatocal/" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://abetusk.github.io/neatocal/&lt;/a&gt; (demo)&lt;p&gt;URL parameters can be used to alter behavior. Here's a highlight of some of them:&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://abetusk.github.io/neatocal/?layout=aligned-weekdays&amp;highlight_color=fee" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://abetusk.github.io/neatocal/?layout=aligned-weekdays&amp;...&lt;/a&gt; (weekend highlighted, aligned)&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://abetusk.github.io/neatocal/?start_month=7" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://abetusk.github.io/neatocal/?start_month=7&lt;/a&gt; (academic)&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://abetusk.github.io/neatocal/?start_month=6&amp;n_month=6" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://abetusk.github.io/neatocal/?start_month=6&amp;n_month=6&lt;/a&gt; (second half, 6 month)&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://abetusk.github.io/neatocal/?month_code=1%E6%9C%88,2%E6%9C%88,3%E6%9C%88,4%E6%9C%88,5%E6%9C%88,6%E6%9C%88,7%E6%9C%88,8%E6%9C%88,9%E6%9C%88,10%E6%9C%88,11%E6%9C%88,12%E6%9C%88&amp;weekday_code=%E6%97%A5,%E4%B8%80,%E4%BA%8C,%E4%B8%89,%E5%9B%9B,%E4%BA%94,%E5%85%AD" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://abetusk.github.io/neatocal/?month_code=1%E6%9C%88,2%...&lt;/a&gt; (chinese month and day)&lt;p&gt;There's also a data file option for more complex date notes.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 28 Dec 2025 06:50:18 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46409027</link><dc:creator>abetusk</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46409027</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46409027</guid></item><item><title>New comment by jibal in "Fathers’ choices may be packaged and passed down in sperm RNA"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&gt; “This study shows that paternal exercise can confer benefits — enhanced endurance and metabolic health — to offspring,”&lt;p&gt;So good habits can be good for offspring.&lt;p&gt;&gt; For instance, mouse fathers  exposed to nicotine(opens a new tab) sire male pups with livers that are good at disarming not just nicotine but cocaine and other toxins as well.&lt;p&gt;So bad habits can be good for offspring.&lt;p&gt;&gt; “We just don’t have really any understanding of how RNAs can do this, and that’s the hand-wavy part,”&lt;p&gt;It seems to me to all be the handwavy part. I'm happy to wait until the research is considerably further advanced, past the clickbait stage.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 28 Dec 2025 06:48:08 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46409010</link><dc:creator>jibal</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46409010</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46409010</guid></item><item><title>New comment by vlovich123 in "Rex is a safe kernel extension framework that allows Rust in the place of eBPF"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;As a lover of Rust, ooo boy does this sound like a bad idea. The Rust compiler is not guaranteed to always output safe code against malicious inputs given that there’s numerous known soundness bugs that allow exploiting this. Unless I’m missing something this is a security nightmare of an idea.&lt;p&gt;Also there’s reasons why eBPF programs aren’t allowed to run arbitrarily long and this just ignores that problem too.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 28 Dec 2025 06:17:27 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46408899</link><dc:creator>vlovich123</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46408899</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46408899</guid></item><item><title>New comment by subdavis in "Replacing JavaScript with Just HTML"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;The details / summary thing absolutely kills me. There’s basically nothing you can’t do with them.  Hiding and replacing markers is easy.  But every component library just pretends they don’t exist.&lt;p&gt;It even saves you the effort of all the aria control and expanded tags: these tags don’t need them.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 28 Dec 2025 01:48:32 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46407603</link><dc:creator>subdavis</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46407603</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46407603</guid></item><item><title>New comment by anonzzzies in "Say No to Palantir in the NHS"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Everyone should say no to palantir anywhere, especially outside the US.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 28 Dec 2025 00:31:28 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46407068</link><dc:creator>anonzzzies</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46407068</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46407068</guid></item><item><title>New comment by NiloCK in "How we lost communication to entertainment"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Being born in 83, I experienced the shift from "serious local nightly news program" into the 24 hr cable news platforms as a loss of focused, serious journalism.&lt;p&gt;Only much later did I read Understanding Media, Amusing Ourselves to Death, etc, and understand that the prior shift from print to the "serious local nightly new program" was itself a loss of focused, serious journalism.&lt;p&gt;For today's youth, Tik Tok is "the air we breath" - the de-facto standard against which the future will be judged. It's &lt;i&gt;horrifying&lt;/i&gt; to imagine what will be worse.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 28 Dec 2025 00:30:03 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46407060</link><dc:creator>NiloCK</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46407060</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46407060</guid></item><item><title>New comment by Coffeewine in "[dead]"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I think this sums it up pretty well.&lt;p&gt;"When I am weaker than you, I ask you for freedom because that is according to your principles; when I am stronger than you, I take away your freedom because that is according to my principles,"&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 27 Dec 2025 21:41:03 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46405520</link><dc:creator>Coffeewine</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46405520</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46405520</guid></item><item><title>New comment by UniverseHacker in "Toll roads are spreading in America"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I live in the Bay Area and hate HOV lanes. I can look over and see that more than half of the drivers are in violation, and yet it is effectively unenforced. It is a system that punishes people willing to follow the rules.&lt;p&gt;Asking someone to waste maybe up to an hour of their life everyday to sit there and watch people willing to break the rules speed by and get to be home early with their families breeds massive resentment, and anger. It encourages people to abandon all sorts of social contracts.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 27 Dec 2025 21:38:30 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46405500</link><dc:creator>UniverseHacker</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46405500</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46405500</guid></item><item><title>New comment by epistasis in "[dead]"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&gt; "one of the largest sources of climate alarmism in the country."&lt;p&gt;It's amazing how fast free speech has been destroyed in the past year. Especially when it comes to censorship of science and science's conclusions.&lt;p&gt;However, I heard many many more people complaining about a lack of free speech in 2023 and 2024 than now. I really wonder what happened to all those principles! It's shocking.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 27 Dec 2025 21:37:00 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46405485</link><dc:creator>epistasis</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46405485</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46405485</guid></item><item><title>New comment by lll-o-lll in "How we lost communication to entertainment"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;We are destroying ourselves; the very core of what it is to be human. I say this acknowledging the irony of writing this on my phone, on a Sunday morning, when I should be engaging with the real world and people in my life.&lt;p&gt;Television was rightly criticised for being the opiate of the masses; a continuous stream of entertainment that allows you to ‘stop thinking’ to endure boredom. However it had some constraints. The box was in a fixed space, I could not bring it with me. The content was fixed, it could not always engage me.&lt;p&gt;Social media, and every other ‘content delivery’ system is not like this. It is in my pocket, there is &lt;i&gt;so much&lt;/i&gt; content, it can keep me continually engaged. AI content generation &lt;i&gt;optimises&lt;/i&gt; this, perhaps, but we already live in this dystopia.&lt;p&gt;Rise up and revolt! Put down our phones and refuse to engage! Our very lives, our &lt;i&gt;humanity&lt;/i&gt; depends on it!&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 27 Dec 2025 21:34:22 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46405455</link><dc:creator>lll-o-lll</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46405455</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46405455</guid></item><item><title>New comment by ChuckMcM in "They made me an offer I couldn't refuse (1997)"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Google's stance on this was fairly draconian when I was working there, basically Google's position was that they could be in ANY business at ANY time so that ANY thing you worked on was theirs. On the day I joined, one of the other new hires had a marked up copy of the agreement with some VERY simple wording changes that said basically "wasn't in this business at the time the employee started working on the project" (aka a no retro-active clause) because this individual pointed out quite reasonably that if they were working on something in good faith on their own that wasn't part of Google's business and it turned out to be a really good idea, then Google, based on how the agreement was written, could go back and say "but we're in that business now too and you were working for us so we own your idea."&lt;p&gt;To which the HR person at the orientation had said, "Don't worry Google wouldn't do that." And this individual said, "I'm sure they wouldn't, that's why it seems like a no-brainer to put it into the agreement, it just says they won't do something that you and I both agree they would never do. I can't sign the document as written without this." The HR person took the updated version off to someone (presumably legal). And then after lunch this person was not in the group (I had seen them eating lunch) So when we had finished up, before my mentor had arrived I went out and found them waiting on the circle for a ride and asked them what happened. They said, "Google said no and also said they were rescinding the offer of employment."&lt;p&gt;And that told me everything I needed to know about how Google really thought about things vs what they &lt;i&gt;said&lt;/i&gt; they thought about things.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 27 Dec 2025 21:31:18 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46405437</link><dc:creator>ChuckMcM</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46405437</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46405437</guid></item><item><title>New comment by bentcorner in "How we lost communication to entertainment"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I love this paragrpah and I think it provides an interesting insight:&lt;p&gt;&gt; &lt;i&gt;They are entertainment platforms that delegate media creation to the users themselves the same way Uber replaced taxis by having people drive others in their own car.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;p&gt;Taking this analogy further, is today's end goal of social media to provide AI generated content that users can endlessly consume?  I think Facebook is heading this direction.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 27 Dec 2025 21:22:27 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46405371</link><dc:creator>bentcorner</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46405371</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46405371</guid></item><item><title>New comment by tptacek in "Gpg.fail"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;One of those WONTFIX's is on an insane vulnerability: you can bitflip known plaintext in a PGP message to switch it into handling compression, allowing attackers to instruct GnuPG packet processing to look back to arbitrary positions in the message, all while suppressing the authentication failure message. GPG's position was: they print, in those circumstances, &lt;i&gt;an error of some sort&lt;/i&gt;, and that's enough. It's an attack that reveals plaintext bytes!&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 27 Dec 2025 19:44:22 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46404589</link><dc:creator>tptacek</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46404589</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46404589</guid></item><item><title>New comment by smusamashah in "Floor796"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;The editor that is used to draw these animations &lt;a href="https://floor796.com/editor/l0" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://floor796.com/editor/l0&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;Author has a YouTube channel too somewhere where you can see him making a drawing start to end. (edit: &lt;a href="https://m.youtube.com/channel/UCribkEGzOuMQ9ozb0ektMCQ" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://m.youtube.com/channel/UCribkEGzOuMQ9ozb0ektMCQ&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;p&gt;From FAQs&lt;p&gt;&gt; The creation of Floor796 started in 2018. I spent the first year creating the animation editor, the rendering engine and the site itself. Then I started drawing the first characters. I drew slowly at first, as I had to get used to the projection and constantly improve the animation editor. I've been creating the first block for over 8 months. Now I draw 1 block in about 1-1.5 months.&lt;p&gt;Author made everything, including the editor, by himself.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 27 Dec 2025 19:17:23 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46404319</link><dc:creator>smusamashah</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46404319</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46404319</guid></item><item><title>New comment by arjie in "Toll roads are spreading in America"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Two things I like are:&lt;p&gt;* HOT lanes in the Bay Area: they allocate demand efficiently and subsidize multi-people transport. I wish there were more.&lt;p&gt;* Toll roads in Texas: you can take the slip roads almost everywhere but they’re slow. The highways were fast but you had to pay.&lt;p&gt;Overall, I think fare at point of use is a great structure. In the past we couldn’t enforce it but now we can do this for more things.&lt;p&gt;The only problem is that we’ve decided that impounding cars that don’t have license plates or which have license plate covers is unacceptable because the poor do this most frequently. I hope we will clean up enforcement and then we will have the right incentives here.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 27 Dec 2025 19:12:24 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46404282</link><dc:creator>arjie</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46404282</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46404282</guid></item><item><title>New comment by Tempest1981 in "Show HN: Ez FFmpeg – Video editing in plain English"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&gt; It's really not that hard,&lt;p&gt;I've learned not to say this. Different things are easy/hard for each of us.&lt;p&gt;Reminds me of a discussion where someone argued, "why don't all the poor/homeless people just go get good jobs?"&lt;p&gt;Edit: I know your comment was meant to inspire/motivate us to try harder. Maybe it's easier than it appears.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 27 Dec 2025 16:00:58 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46402721</link><dc:creator>Tempest1981</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46402721</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46402721</guid></item><item><title>New comment by juujian in "Show HN: Ez FFmpeg – Video editing in plain English"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Yes, I use ffmpeg about once a year, in about 350 years I really ought to have all the syntax figure out.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 27 Dec 2025 14:52:37 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46402248</link><dc:creator>juujian</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46402248</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46402248</guid></item><item><title>New comment by RobotToaster in "Apple releases open-source model that instantly turns 2D photos into 3D views"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/apple/ml-sharp/refs/heads/main/LICENSE_MODEL" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/apple/ml-sharp/refs/heads/...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;"Exclusively for research purposes" so not actually open source.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 27 Dec 2025 14:43:48 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46402179</link><dc:creator>RobotToaster</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46402179</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46402179</guid></item><item><title>New comment by qbow883 in "Show HN: Ez FFmpeg – Video editing in plain English"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Days since last ffmpeg CLI wrapper: 0&lt;p&gt;It's incredible what lengths people go to to avoid memorizing basic ffmpeg usage. It's really not that hard, and the (F.) manual explains the basic concepts fairly well.&lt;p&gt;Now, granted, ffmpeg's defaults (reencoding by default and only keeping one stream of each type unless otherwise specified) aren't great, which can create some footguns, but as long as you remember to pass `-c copy` by default you should be fine.&lt;p&gt;Also, &lt;i&gt;hiding&lt;/i&gt; those footguns is likely to create more harm than it fixes. Case in point: "ff convert video.mkv to mp4" (an extremely common usecase) maps to `ffmpeg -i video.mkv -y video.mp4` here, which does a full reencode (losing quality and wasting time) for what can usually just be a simple remux.&lt;p&gt;Similarly, "ffmpeg extract audio from video.mp4" will unconditionally reencode the audio to mp3, again losing quality. The quality settings are also hardcoded and hidden from the user.&lt;p&gt;I can sympathize with ffmpeg syntax looking complicated at first glance, but the main reason for this is just that multimedia is &lt;i&gt;really complicated&lt;/i&gt; and that some of this complexity is &lt;i&gt;necessary&lt;/i&gt; in order to not make stupid mistakes that lose quality or waste CPU resources. I truly believe that these ffmpeg wrappers that try to make it seem overly simple (at least when it's &lt;i&gt;this&lt;/i&gt; simple, i.e. not even exposing quality settings or differentiating between reencoding and remuxing) are more hurtful than helpful. Not only can they give worse results, but by hiding this complexity from users they also give users the wrong ideas about how multimedia works. "Abstractions" like this are exactly how beliefs like "resolution and quality are the same thing" come to be. I believe the way to go should be &lt;i&gt;educating&lt;/i&gt; users about video formats and proper ffmpeg usage (e.g. with good cheat sheets), not by hiding complexity that really should not be hidden.&lt;p&gt;Edit: Reading through my comment again, I have to apologize for the slightly facetious opening statement, even if I quality it later on. The fact that so many ffmpeg wrappers exists &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; saying something about its apparent difficulty, but as I argue above, a) there are reasons for this (namely, multimedia itself just being complicated), and b) I believe there are good and bad ways to "fix" this, with oversimplified wrappers being more on the "bad" side.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 27 Dec 2025 13:41:29 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46401788</link><dc:creator>qbow883</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46401788</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46401788</guid></item><item><title>New comment by sccxy in "Exe.dev"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;That must be worst website ever made.&lt;p&gt;Zero information available on mobile.&lt;p&gt;I thought it is some kind of portfolio site that does not work on mobile.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 27 Dec 2025 07:27:33 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46399903</link><dc:creator>sccxy</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46399903</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46399903</guid></item><item><title>New comment by crystal_revenge in "Publishing your work increases your luck"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&gt; Having your OSS library take off&lt;p&gt;All of the other bullet points there are pretty reasonable, but, having worked in OSS professionally, I genuinely &lt;i&gt;hope&lt;/i&gt; none of my GH projects take off in the OSS world.&lt;p&gt;I have a few projects that are in the  &gt;50 stars range, and am both grateful for other people's interests and very glad that none of them crossed the threshold to becoming &lt;i&gt;real&lt;/i&gt; OSS projects. I like sharing my interesting experiments, but I absolutely do not want to be stuck with the nightmare of maintaining OSS software &lt;i&gt;for years&lt;/i&gt;.&lt;p&gt;Even on these small projects, I've had times when I'm pressured to do a bug fix on a 5 year old project where I don't even remember how it works or review and merge an enthusiastic PR solving a problem I don't actually care about. It has eaten up a few weekends, and was a relatively minor annoyance, but it gave me the taste for what OSS work involved. Working professionally for an OSS company gave me even more insight.&lt;p&gt;Maintaining OSS is a royal pain in the butt and I am forever grateful for the people who &lt;i&gt;choose&lt;/i&gt; to do this. Running a popular OSS library is not a prize. It's &lt;i&gt;at least&lt;/i&gt; a part time job you aren't paid for. The benefits are slim; even the "fame" part (name your top 10 favorite OSS tools, now name the maintainers of those), and has really limited rewards outside of that. I've know plenty of brilliant creators of OSS libraries who struggle to find jobs in industry that are appropriate to their skill level.&lt;p&gt;In fact, it's really hard to both run a successful OSS project &lt;i&gt;and&lt;/i&gt; have a full time job (especially a high paying one that wants a lot of your brain and time) if you can't some how manage to make that OSS project your full time job... and even then you will be under constant pressure to find a way to monetize your OSS project (which inevitably leads to either losing that job or making decisions not in the interest of your community of OSS users).&lt;p&gt;OSS maintainers are &lt;i&gt;saints&lt;/i&gt; as far as I'm concerned. So much of the world's software depends on them (even moreso in the age of LLMs) and the &lt;i&gt;vast&lt;/i&gt; majority are compensated way less than your average FAANG engineer.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 27 Dec 2025 07:21:40 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46399871</link><dc:creator>crystal_revenge</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46399871</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46399871</guid></item><item><title>New comment by estimator7292 in "Experts explore new mushroom which causes fairytale-like hallucinations"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;It's really fucking suspicious that mushrooms evolved mechanisms to produce serotonin.&lt;p&gt;But it helps when you remember that a mushroom is the &lt;i&gt;fruit&lt;/i&gt; of a (usually) much larger organism. Then you can start applying normal fruit rules. Some want to be eaten, or picked up and moved around. Some want to keep insects from infesting the fruit. Others don't give a damn and release spores into the wind or water.&lt;p&gt;Also remember that nicotine is an insecticide. Insects that nibble on tobacco die, which prevents infestation at scale. (Un?)fortunately it's also neuroactive in apes, so we farm incredible quantities of tobacco to extract its poisons.&lt;p&gt;There is no logic in evolution at large scales. Things happen, sometimes there's fourth order effects like some oddball internal hormone causing wild hallucinations in apes. It's all random optimization for small scale problems that ripple out to unintended large scale consequences.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 27 Dec 2025 01:12:09 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46398177</link><dc:creator>estimator7292</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46398177</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46398177</guid></item><item><title>New comment by Nextgrid in "How uv got so fast"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;It's not just greenfield-ness but the fact it's a &lt;i&gt;commercial&lt;/i&gt; endeavor (even if the code is open-source).&lt;p&gt;Building a &lt;i&gt;commercial&lt;/i&gt; product means you pay money (or something they equally value) to people to do your bidding. You don't have to worry about politics, licensing, and all the usual FOSS-related drama. You pay them to set their opinions aside and build what &lt;i&gt;you&lt;/i&gt; want, not what &lt;i&gt;they&lt;/i&gt; want (and if that doesn't work, it just means you need to offer more money).&lt;p&gt;In this case it's a company that believes they can make a "good" package manager they can sell/monetize somehow and so built that "good" package manager. Turns out it's at least &lt;i&gt;good enough&lt;/i&gt; that other people now like it too.&lt;p&gt;This would never work in a FOSS world because the project will be stuck in endless planning as everyone will have an opinion on how it should be done and nothing will &lt;i&gt;actually&lt;/i&gt; get done.&lt;p&gt;Similar story with systemd - all the bitching you hear about it (to this day!) is the stuff that would've happened during its development phase had it been developed as a typical FOSS project and ultimately made it go nowhere - but instead it's one guy that just did what he wanted and shared it with the world, and enough other people liked it and started building upon it.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 27 Dec 2025 00:26:38 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46397883</link><dc:creator>Nextgrid</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46397883</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46397883</guid></item><item><title>New comment by orliesaurus in "How uv got so fast"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;The most surprising part of uv's success to me isn't Rust at all, it's how much speed we "unlocked" just by finally treating Python packaging as a well-specified systems problem instead of a pile of historical accidents. If uv had been written in Go or even highly optimized CPython, but with the same design decisions (PEP 517/518/621/658 focus, HTTP range tricks, aggressive wheel-first strategy, ignoring obviously defensive upper bounds, etc.), I strongly suspect we'd be debating a 1.3× vs 1.5× speedup instead of a 10× headline — but the conversation here keeps collapsing back to "Rust rewrite good/bad." That feels like cargo-culting the toolchain instead of asking the uncomfortable question: why did it take a greenfield project to give Python the package manager behavior people clearly wanted for the last decade?&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 26 Dec 2025 23:40:11 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46397584</link><dc:creator>orliesaurus</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46397584</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46397584</guid></item><item><title>New comment by numbsafari in "Ask HN: What did you read in 2025?"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;This year:&lt;p&gt;- I read the entire “Frog &amp; Toad” collection. Probably about 30 times, some stories more.&lt;p&gt;- “Little Shrew’s Day”… probably 25 times.&lt;p&gt;- Many of the “Construction Site” series books, especially the OG “Goodnight, Goodnight, Construction Site”. The “Garbage Crew” and “Airport” books featured heavily.&lt;p&gt;- Started to mix in some “Pete the Cat” titles.&lt;p&gt;- “Detective Dog Nell” got a lot of air play.&lt;p&gt;Lots of others, but those are definitely the frequent fliers.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 26 Dec 2025 23:37:56 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46397563</link><dc:creator>numbsafari</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46397563</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46397563</guid></item></channel></rss>