<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>Hacker News: Best Comments</title><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/bestcomments</link><description>Hacker News RSS</description><docs>https://hnrss.org/</docs><generator>hnrss v2.1.1</generator><lastBuildDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 01:07:09 +0000</lastBuildDate><ns0:link href="https://hnrss.org/bestcomments" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item><title>New comment by Animats in "Micron Announces Exit from Crucial Consumer Business"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Wow. They're not selling off the business, they're totally exiting it.&lt;p&gt;This is a big loss. Crucial offered a supply chain direct from Micron. Most other consumer DRAM sources pass through middlemen, where fake parts and re-labeled rejects can be inserted.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 20:24:15 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46139607</link><dc:creator>Animats</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46139607</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46139607</guid></item><item><title>New comment by bccdee in "Everyone in Seattle hates AI"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&gt; Engineers don't try because they think they can't.&lt;p&gt;This article assumes that AI is the centre of the universe, failing to understand that that assumption is exactly what's causing the attitude they're pointing to.&lt;p&gt;There's a dichotomy in the software world between real products (which have customers and use cases and make money by giving people things they need) and hype products (which exist to get investors excited, so they'll fork over more money). This isn't a strict dichotomy; often companies with real products will mix in tidbits of hype, such as Microsoft's "pivot to AI" which is discussed in the article. But moving toward one pole moves you away from the other.&lt;p&gt;I think many engineers want to stay as far from hype-driven tech as they can. LLMs are a more substantive technology than blockchain ever was, but like blockchain, their potential has been greatly overstated. I'd rather spend my time delivering value to customers than performing "big potential" to investors.&lt;p&gt;So, no. I don't think "engineers don't try because they think they can't." I think engineers KNOW they CAN and resent being asked to look pretty and do nothing of value.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 20:11:50 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46139440</link><dc:creator>bccdee</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46139440</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46139440</guid></item><item><title>New comment by pkasting in "Everyone in Seattle hates AI"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Ex-Google here; there are many people both current and past-Google that feel the same way as the composite coworker in the linked post.&lt;p&gt;I haven't escaped this mindset myself. I'm convinced there are a small number of places where LLMs make truly effective tools (see: generation of "must be plausible, need not be accurate" data, e.g. concept art or crowd animations in movies), a large number of places where LLMs make apparently-effective tools that have negative long-term consequences (see: anything involving learning a new skill, anything where correctness is critical), and a large number of places where LLMs are simply ineffective from the get-go but will increasingly be rammed down consumers' throats.&lt;p&gt;Accordingly I tend to be overly skeptical of AI proponents and anything touching AI. It would be nice if I was more rational, but I'm not; I want everyone working on AI and making money from AI to crash and burn hard. (See also: cryptocurrency)&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 20:11:50 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46139439</link><dc:creator>pkasting</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46139439</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46139439</guid></item><item><title>New comment by levocardia in "Valve reveals it’s the architect behind a push to bring Windows games to Arm"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Valve is one of the few companies regularly seen on HN where the headline is something like "[company] is secretly doing something really great" as opposed to "[company] is secretly doing something evil"&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 19:19:32 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46138720</link><dc:creator>levocardia</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46138720</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46138720</guid></item><item><title>New comment by adverbly in "Valve reveals it’s the architect behind a push to bring Windows games to Arm"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Everything valve doing for linux is making such a huge impact.&lt;p&gt;The HL3 memes don't even seem fair to use anymore. I don't even want to un-seriously make joke fun of them at this point. They are just genuinely doing so much for the community.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 18:47:45 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46138331</link><dc:creator>adverbly</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46138331</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46138331</guid></item><item><title>New comment by ApolloFortyNine in "“Captain Gains” on Capitol Hill"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&gt;This is saying that people in congressional leadership positions do 47% better than other members of Congress.&lt;p&gt;It's even more damning than that I think.&lt;p&gt;&gt;we find that lawmakers who later ascend to leadership positions perform similarly to matched peers beforehand but outperform them by 47 percentage points annually after ascension.&lt;p&gt;The same person makes more after being put in a leadership position than before. That essentially removes any possibility of 'well maybe they're just more knowledgable and that's why they're in leadership.'&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 14:28:54 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46134860</link><dc:creator>ApolloFortyNine</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46134860</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46134860</guid></item><item><title>New comment by burkaman in "“Captain Gains” on Capitol Hill"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Incorrect title, the finding is "lawmakers who later ascend to leadership positions perform similarly to matched peers beforehand but outperform them by 47 percentage points annually after ascension." This is saying that people in congressional leadership positions do 47% better than other members of Congress.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 14:07:20 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46134623</link><dc:creator>burkaman</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46134623</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46134623</guid></item><item><title>New comment by snet0 in "Helldivers 2 devs slash install size from 154GB to 23GB"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&gt; With their latest data measurements specific to the game, the developers have confirmed the small number of players (11% last week) using mechanical hard drives will witness mission load times increase by only a few seconds in worst cases. Additionally, the post reads, “the majority of the loading time in Helldivers 2 is due to level-generation rather than asset loading. This level generation happens in parallel with loading assets from the disk and so is the main determining factor of the loading time.”&lt;p&gt;It seems bizarre to me that they'd have accepted such a high cost (150GB+ installation size!) without entirely verifying that it was necessary!&lt;p&gt;I expect it's a story that'll never get told in enough detail to satisfy curiosity, but it certainly seems strange from the outside for this optimisation to be both possible and acceptable.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 14:01:12 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46134547</link><dc:creator>snet0</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46134547</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46134547</guid></item><item><title>New comment by dannersy in "Zig quits GitHub, says Microsoft's AI obsession has ruined the service"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I often find we don't appreciate enough people accepting their failures and changing their mind. For some reason I see the opposite: people respecting those who "stick to their guns" or double down when something is clearly wrong. As you say, the context matters and these edits seem to be learning from the feedback rather than saving face since the sentiment stands, just in a less needlessly targeted way.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 12:29:48 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46133742</link><dc:creator>dannersy</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46133742</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46133742</guid></item><item><title>New comment by styanax in "Zig quits GitHub, says Microsoft's AI obsession has ruined the service"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;On the previous HN article, I recall many a comment talking about how they should change this, leave the politics/negative juju out because it was a bad look for the Zig community.&lt;p&gt;It would appear they listened to that feedback, swallowed their ego/pride and did what was best for the Zig community with these edits. I commend them for their actions in doing what's best for the community at the cost of some personal mea culpa edits.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 11:23:34 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46133219</link><dc:creator>styanax</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46133219</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46133219</guid></item><item><title>New comment by brushfoot in "Zig quits GitHub, says Microsoft's AI obsession has ruined the service"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;The edit history of the announcement is quite a ride:&lt;p&gt;&gt; [2025-11-27T02:10:07Z] it’s abundantly clear that the talented folks who used to work on the product have moved on to bigger and better things, with the remaining losers eager to inflict some kind of bloated, buggy JavaScript framework on us in the name of progress [1]&lt;p&gt;&gt; [2025-11-27T14:04:47Z] it’s abundantly clear that the talented folks who used to work on the product have moved on to bigger and better things, with the remaining rookies eager to inflict some kind of bloated, buggy JavaScript framework on us in the name of progress [2]&lt;p&gt;&gt; [2025-11-28T09:21:12Z] it’s abundantly clear that the engineering excellence that created GitHub’s success is no longer driving it [3]&lt;p&gt;---&lt;p&gt;1: &lt;a href="https://web.archive.org/web/20251127021007/https://ziglang.org/news/migrating-from-github-to-codeberg/" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://web.archive.org/web/20251127021007/https://ziglang.o...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;2: &lt;a href="https://web.archive.org/web/20251127140447/https://ziglang.org/news/migrating-from-github-to-codeberg/" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://web.archive.org/web/20251127140447/https://ziglang.o...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;3: &lt;a href="https://web.archive.org/web/20251128092112/https://ziglang.org/news/migrating-from-github-to-codeberg/" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://web.archive.org/web/20251128092112/https://ziglang.o...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 11:19:04 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46133179</link><dc:creator>brushfoot</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46133179</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46133179</guid></item><item><title>New comment by sigmoid10 in "Accepting US car standards would risk European lives"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&gt;EU vehicle safety regulations have supported a 36% reduction in European road deaths since 2010. By contrast, road deaths in the US over the same period increased 30%, with pedestrian deaths up 80% and cyclist deaths up 50%&lt;p&gt;I didn't know this, but it is absolutely crazy. Every EU politician who tries to subvert car safety should be dismissed and tried for endangering public safety.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 08:15:06 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46131574</link><dc:creator>sigmoid10</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46131574</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46131574</guid></item><item><title>New comment by CalRobert in "Accepting US car standards would risk European lives"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;NotJustBikes just put out a video about this issue - &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=--832LV9a3I" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=--832LV9a3I&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;A couple years ago he also made a video about these trucks more broadly - &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=jN7mSXMruEo" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=jN7mSXMruEo&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;What's truly maddening is how many of these vehicles which _do not_ meet European safety standards are _already_ in Europe. Walk around Hilversum in the Netherlands and you will see plenty of Dodge Rams (mostly 1500's, but there's even a 2500 Dually usually parked on the sidewalk ("pavement "for Brits) where my kids used to go to school). They're imported under "Individual Vehicle Approval" rules, exempting them from type safety requirements, and on top of that are almost always registered as "business vehicles" (you can tell from the V plate) which means they pay an absolute pittance in tax.&lt;p&gt;I moved here to get away from American kindercrushers (among other reasons) and I am profoundly concerned that Europe is being invaded by these machines.&lt;p&gt;(Edit)
Worth noting is that a lot of Dutch street design is based on the idea that people _can_ share space with cars in dense, low speed environments, but that assumption flies out the window when the vehicles are so large you can't even see a kid walking or biking to school.&lt;p&gt;Further edit - source - &lt;a href="https://www.motorfinanceonline.com/news/dodge-ram-registrations-surge-in-europe-prompting-calls-for-regulatory-action/" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://www.motorfinanceonline.com/news/dodge-ram-registrati...&lt;/a&gt;
5,000 Dodge Rams imported in to Europe in 2023 alone.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 08:12:46 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46131554</link><dc:creator>CalRobert</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46131554</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46131554</guid></item><item><title>New comment by helsinkiandrew in "IBM CEO says there is 'no way' spending on AI data centers will pay off"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&gt; IBM has not exactly had a stellar record at identifying the future.&lt;p&gt;IBM invented/developed/introduced magnetic stripe cards, UPC Barcodes, the modern ATM, Hard drives, floppies, DRAM, SQL, the 360 Family of Mainframes, the PC, Apollo guidance computers, Deep Blue.  IBM created a far share of the future we're living in.&lt;p&gt;I'm no fan of much of what IBM is doing at the moment but it could be argued that its consultancy/service orientation gives it a good view of how business is and is planning to use AI.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 07:28:02 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46131245</link><dc:creator>helsinkiandrew</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46131245</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46131245</guid></item><item><title>New comment by mattkevan in "Japanese game devs face font dilemma as license increases from $380 to $20k"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Ah Monotype. Knew before reading the article it would be them. Their whole MO is buying up smaller type foundries, massively increasing the licensing fees and shaking down the previous customers. They send in auditors, demand to see traffic data and threaten fines. Happened to me twice now.&lt;p&gt;Creating type is an extremely difficult and skilled discipline and designers deserve to be compensated fairly. However Monotype’s business practices are such that I won’t approve anything but open source fonts for new projects.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 07:15:13 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46131149</link><dc:creator>mattkevan</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46131149</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46131149</guid></item><item><title>New comment by hxtk in "AI agents break rules under everyday pressure"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Blameless postmortem culture recognizes human error as an inevitability and asks those with influence to design systems that maintain safety in the face of human error. In the software engineering world, this typically means automation, because while automation can and usually does have faults, it doesn't suffer from human error.&lt;p&gt;Now we've invented automation that commits human-like error at scale.&lt;p&gt;I wouldn't call myself anti-AI, but it does seem fairly obvious to me that directly automating things with AI will probably always have substantial risk and you have much more assurance, if you involve AI in the process, using it to develop a traditional automation. As a low-stakes personal example, instead of using AI to generate boilerplate code, I'll often try to use AI to generate a traditional code generator to convert whatever DSL specification into the chosen development language source code, rather than asking AI to generate the development language source code directly from the DSL.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 05:44:22 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46130680</link><dc:creator>hxtk</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46130680</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46130680</guid></item><item><title>New comment by kentonv in "Anthropic acquires Bun"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I built Cloudflare Workers?&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 01:03:34 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46129044</link><dc:creator>kentonv</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46129044</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46129044</guid></item><item><title>New comment by jdoliner in "OpenAI declares 'code red' as Google catches up in AI race"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I've seen a rumor going around that OpenAI hasn't had a successful pre-training run since mid 2024. This seemed insane to me but if you give ChatGPT 5.1 a query about current events and instruct it not to use the internet it will tell you its knowledge cutoff is June 2024. Not sure if maybe that's just the smaller model or what. But I don't think it's a good sign to get that from any frontier model today, that's 18 months ago.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 20:55:44 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46126750</link><dc:creator>jdoliner</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46126750</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46126750</guid></item><item><title>New comment by dts in "Anthropic acquires Bun"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;A lot of people seem confused about this acquisition because they think of Bun as a node.js compatible bundler / runtime and just compare it to Deno / npm. But I think its a really smart move if you think of where Bun has been pushing into lately which is a kind of cloud-native self contained runtime (S3 API, SQL, streaming, etc). For an agent like Claude Code this trajectory is really interesting as you are creating a runtime where your agent can work inside of cloud services as fluently as it currently does with a local filesystem. Claude will be able to leverage these capabilities to extend its reach across the cloud and add more value in enterprise use cases&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 20:52:05 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46126685</link><dc:creator>dts</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46126685</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46126685</guid></item><item><title>New comment by stack_framer in "OpenAI declares 'code red' as Google catches up in AI race"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I can generate $20 billion in ARR this year too! I just need you to give me $100 billion and allow me to sell each of your dollars for 0.2 dollars.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 20:38:29 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46126517</link><dc:creator>stack_framer</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46126517</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46126517</guid></item><item><title>New comment by Jarred in "Anthropic acquires Bun"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I work on Bun.&lt;p&gt;Happy to answer any questions&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 20:28:51 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46126387</link><dc:creator>Jarred</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46126387</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46126387</guid></item><item><title>New comment by felixfurtak in "OpenAI declares 'code red' as Google catches up in AI race"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;OpenAI is basically just Netscape at this point. An innovative product with no means of significant revenue generation.&lt;p&gt;One one side it's up against large competitors with an already established user base and product line that can simply bundle their AI offerings into those products. Google will do just what Microsoft did with Internet Explorer and bundle Gemini in for 'Free' with their already other profitable products and established ad-funded revenue streams.&lt;p&gt;At the same time, Deepseek/Qwen, etc. are open sourcing stuff to undercut them on the other side. It's a classic squeeze on their already fairly dubious business model.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 20:27:19 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46126373</link><dc:creator>felixfurtak</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46126373</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46126373</guid></item><item><title>New comment by strickjb9 in "The Junior Hiring Crisis"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Adding to this: it's not just that the apprenticeship ladder is gone—it's that nobody wants to deal with juniors who spit out AI code they don't really understand.&lt;p&gt;In the past, a junior would write bad code and you'd work with them to make it better. Now I just assume they're taking my feedback and feeding it right back to the LLM. Ends up taking more of my time than if I'd done it myself. The whole mentorship thing breaks down when you're basically collaborating with a model through a proxy.&lt;p&gt;I think highly motivated juniors who actually want to learn are still valuable. But it's hard to get past "why bother mentoring when I could just use AI directly?"&lt;p&gt;I don't have answers here. Just thinking maybe we're not seeing the end of software engineering for those of us already in it—but the door might be closing for anyone trying to come up behind us.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 19:08:21 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46125216</link><dc:creator>strickjb9</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46125216</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46125216</guid></item><item><title>New comment by andrewl-hn in "Anthropic acquires Bun"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I’ll be honest, while I have my doubts about the match of interests and cohesion between an AI company and a JS runtime company I have to say this is the single best acquisition announcement blog post I’ve seen in 20 years or so.&lt;p&gt;Very direct, very plain and detailed. They cover all the bases about the why, the how, and what to expect. I really appreciate it.&lt;p&gt;Best of luck to the team and hopefully the new home will support them well.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 18:28:07 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46124566</link><dc:creator>andrewl-hn</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46124566</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46124566</guid></item><item><title>New comment by AndyKelley in "Zig's new plan for asynchronous programs"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Overall this article is accurate and well-researched. Thanks to Daroc Alden for due diligence. Here are a couple of minor corrections:&lt;p&gt;&gt; When using an Io.Threaded instance, the async() function doesn't actually do anything asynchronously — it just runs the provided function right away.&lt;p&gt;While this is a legal implementation strategy, this is not what std.Io.Threaded does. By default, it will use a configurably sized thread pool to dispatch async tasks. It can, however, be statically initialized with init_single_threaded in which case it does have the behavior described in the article.&lt;p&gt;The only other issue I spotted is:&lt;p&gt;&gt; For that use case, the Io interface provides a separate function, asyncConcurrent() that explicitly asks for the provided function to be run in parallel.&lt;p&gt;There was a brief moment where we had asyncConcurrent() but it has since been renamed more simply to concurrent().&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 17:03:59 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46123432</link><dc:creator>AndyKelley</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46123432</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46123432</guid></item><item><title>New comment by DigitalDopamine in "Learning music with Strudel"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Loved playing with it! &lt;a href="https://strudel.cc/?qVv8Cr0OD6cc" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://strudel.cc/?qVv8Cr0OD6cc&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 14:56:55 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46121827</link><dc:creator>DigitalDopamine</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46121827</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46121827</guid></item><item><title>New comment by messe in "Rootless Pings in Rust"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&gt; It turns out you can create a UDP socket with a protocol flag, which allows you to send the ping rootless&lt;p&gt;This is wrong, despite the Rust library in question's naming convention. You're not creating a UDP socket. You're creating an IP (AF_INET), datagram socket (SOCK_DGRAM), using protocol ICMP (IPPROTO_ICMP). The issue is that the rust library apparently conflates datagram and UDP, when they're not the same thing.&lt;p&gt;You can do the same in C, by calling socket(2) with the above arguments. It hinges on Linux allowing rootless pings from the GIDs in&lt;p&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;  $ sysctl net.ipv4.ping_group_range
  net.ipv4.ping_group_range = 999 59999
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
EDIT: s/ICMP4/ICMP/g&lt;p&gt;EDIT2: more spelling mistakes&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 09:33:12 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46119375</link><dc:creator>messe</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46119375</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46119375</guid></item><item><title>New comment by densh in "Apple Releases Open Weights Video Model"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&gt; As a blind person, AI has changed my life.&lt;p&gt;Something one doesn't see in news headlines. Happy to see this comment.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 08:44:08 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46119040</link><dc:creator>densh</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46119040</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46119040</guid></item><item><title>New comment by devinprater in "Apple Releases Open Weights Video Model"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Apple has a video understanding model too. I can't wait to find out what accessibility stuff they'll do with the models. As a blind person, AI has changed my life.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 08:34:44 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46118991</link><dc:creator>devinprater</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46118991</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46118991</guid></item><item><title>New comment by bcrosby95 in "What will enter the public domain in 2026?"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;The length of copyright is absurd.  Corporations have hijacked a concept that should exist on human timescales.&lt;p&gt;Ideally, a child could legally provide their own spin on IP they consumed by the time they reach adulthood.  But also, people need to make a living.&lt;p&gt;I actually think the original 14+14 year copyright is the right balance.  It gives people time to make their profits, but also guarantees the right of people to tweak and modify content they consume within their lifetime.  It's a balanced time scale rather than one that exists solely to serve mega corporations giving them the capability to hold cultural icons hostage.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 07:54:32 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46118773</link><dc:creator>bcrosby95</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46118773</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46118773</guid></item></channel></rss>