<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>Hacker News: Best Comments</title><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/bestcomments</link><description>Hacker News RSS</description><docs>https://hnrss.org/</docs><generator>hnrss v2.1.1</generator><lastBuildDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2025 23:49:16 +0000</lastBuildDate><ns0:link href="https://hnrss.org/bestcomments" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item><title>New comment by dkersten in "GPT-5.1: A smarter, more conversational ChatGPT"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I don’t want more conversational, I want more to the point. Less telling me how great my question is, less about being friendly, instead I want more cold, hard, accurate, direct, and factual results.&lt;p&gt;It’s a machine and a tool, not a person and definitely not my friend.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2025 15:32:54 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45916076</link><dc:creator>dkersten</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45916076</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45916076</guid></item><item><title>New comment by joshmn in "Checkout.com hacked, refuses ransom payment, donates to security labs"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;It’s notable that there were ShinyHunters members arrested by the FBI a few years ago. I was in prison with Sebastian Raoult, one of them. We talked quite a bit.&lt;p&gt;The level of persistence these guys went through to phish at scale is astounding—which is how they gained most of their access. They’d otherwise look up API endpoints on GitHub and see if there were any leaked keys (he wasn’t fond of GitHub's automated scanner).&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.justice.gov/usao-wdwa/pr/member-notorious-international-hacking-crew-sentenced-prison" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://www.justice.gov/usao-wdwa/pr/member-notorious-intern...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2025 13:11:12 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45914502</link><dc:creator>joshmn</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45914502</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45914502</guid></item><item><title>New comment by rom1v in "Android developer verification: Early access starts"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I want to be able to install apps from alternative app stores like F-Droid and receive automatic updates, without requiring Google's authorization for app publication.&lt;p&gt;Manually installing an app via adb must, of course, be permitted. But that is not sufficient.&lt;p&gt;&gt; Keeping users safe on Android is our top priority.&lt;p&gt;Google's mandatory verification is not about security, but about control (they want to forbid apps like ReVanced that could reduce their advertising revenue).&lt;p&gt;When SimpleMobileTools was sold to a shady company (&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=38505229"&gt;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=38505229&lt;/a&gt;), the new owner was able to push any user-hostile changes they wanted to all users who had installed the original app through Google Play (that's the very reason why the initial app could be sold in the first place, to exploit a large, preexisting user base that had the initial version installed).&lt;p&gt;That was not the case on F-Droid, which blocked the new user-hostile version and recommended the open source fork (Fossify Apps). (see also this comment: &lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45410805"&gt;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45410805&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2025 08:46:26 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45912425</link><dc:creator>rom1v</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45912425</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45912425</guid></item><item><title>New comment by cambaceres in "Project Euler"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;12 years ago I was a failed computer science student, wasting my time on drugs. Having failed so many classes I did not see any future at all, and I was considering killing myself to get out of the anxiety and stress.
My confidence regarding programming etc was 0.&lt;p&gt;I decided to apply for a junior developer job. I got an interview and to prepare for an interview I found this site, Project Euler. I did ten or so tasks.&lt;p&gt;The interview started out pretty bad, they asked me some technical questions which I did not give good answers to, and I saw that they where not impressed. Then they wanted me to solve two programming problems on a white board. Imagine the relief I felt when both of these questions where from the ones that I solved on Project Euler a couple of days before! I nailed them and the interviewers where clearly impressed. In the end they hired me and motivated it with that although I lack a lot of theory I am obviously a very good coder haha.&lt;p&gt;Anyway, that was what I needed, when I got this job I quit the drugs and got my act together. 12 years later I live a confortable life as a freelancer and have even managed to build my own SaaS with paying customers! Thank you Project Euler.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2025 07:25:49 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45911812</link><dc:creator>cambaceres</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45911812</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45911812</guid></item><item><title>New comment by Ey7NFZ3P0nzAe in "Steam Machine"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&gt; Install your own apps, or even another operating system. Who are we to tell you how to use your computer?&lt;p&gt;I'm so happy to read this&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2025 05:57:28 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45911243</link><dc:creator>Ey7NFZ3P0nzAe</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45911243</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45911243</guid></item><item><title>New comment by twodave in "My dad could still be alive, but he's not"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I feel this, but in reverse. My son could be dead, but he’s not. He was born on the floor of a trailer park apartment, not breathing. His birth mother’s partner called 911, who dispatched an ambulance. All rescue units for his zone were already busy. An ambulance returning from the nearby hospital to another zone heard the call over the radio and happened to be passing by. The hospital was expecting a DOA, but the paramedics (HEROES) managed to get him breathing again on the way. He’s 11 now, and he is the source of all kinds of trouble and joy. Our home would be very different without him.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2025 03:41:26 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45910323</link><dc:creator>twodave</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45910323</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45910323</guid></item><item><title>New comment by Normal_gaussian in "Valve is about to win the console generation"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Valve certainly won't win it, but they're bringing the heat where it wasn't before.&lt;p&gt;SteamOS is the important part here - if it is proven to be a good console experience (which the deck has basically proven already) then licensing of the OS to other manufacturers will put a lot of pressure on integrated h/w s/w manufacturers.&lt;p&gt;Unlike the handheld format, the tvbox console is fairly easy to manufacture and is tolerant of a lot of spec and price variety. Any slip up by Sony and Microsoft in specs and price will result in steam machine variants carving away market share, which could force more frequent console releases.&lt;p&gt;The steam machine will almost certainly come in at a higher price point than the PS5, but with no 'online' subscription charge and reasonably priced storage upgrades we may see these revenue streams disappear from the next console generation in order to compete.&lt;p&gt;SteamOS isn't perfect, and the variety inherent in the platform that is a strength is also a weakness. The core markets for Nintendo and for Sony aren't going anywhere.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2025 02:51:14 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45909928</link><dc:creator>Normal_gaussian</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45909928</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45909928</guid></item><item><title>New comment by svat in "Android developer verification: Early access starts"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;From the very first announcement of this, Google has hinted that they were doing this under pressure from the governments in a few countries. (I don't remember the URL of the first announcement, but &lt;a href="https://android-developers.googleblog.com/2025/08/elevating-android-security.html" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://android-developers.googleblog.com/2025/08/elevating-...&lt;/a&gt; is from 2025-August-25 and mentions “These requirements go into effect in Brazil, Indonesia, Singapore, and Thailand”.) The “Why verification is important” section of this blog post goes into a bit more detail (see also the &lt;i&gt;We are designing this flow specifically to resist coercion, ensuring that users aren't tricked into bypassing these safety checks while under pressure from a scammer&lt;/i&gt;), but ultimately the point is:&lt;p&gt;there &lt;i&gt;cannot&lt;/i&gt; exist an easy way for a typical non-technical user to install “unverified apps” (whatever that means), because the governments of countries where such scams are widespread will hold Google responsible.&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile this very fact seems fundamentally unacceptable to many, so there will be no end to this discourse IMO.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2025 01:33:26 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45909348</link><dc:creator>svat</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45909348</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45909348</guid></item><item><title>New comment by arnaudsm in "Steam Frame"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;This is the first standalone headset with an open ecosystem. That's a big deal.&lt;p&gt;Meta Quests &amp; Apple Visions require developer verification to run your own software, and provide no root access, which slowed down innovation significantly.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 22:09:53 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45907526</link><dc:creator>arnaudsm</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45907526</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45907526</guid></item><item><title>New comment by CobrastanJorji in "Steam Machine"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&gt; Install your own apps, or even another operating system. Who are we to tell you how to use your computer?&lt;p&gt;From your mouth to Tim Cook's ear, friend.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 21:24:55 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45906945</link><dc:creator>CobrastanJorji</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45906945</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45906945</guid></item><item><title>New comment by url00 in "GPT-5.1: A smarter, more conversational ChatGPT"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I don't want a more conversational GPT. I want the _exact_ opposite. I want a tool with the upper limit of "conversation" being something like LCARS from Star Trek. This is quite disappointing as a current ChatGPT subscriber.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 19:15:35 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45904749</link><dc:creator>url00</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45904749</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45904749</guid></item><item><title>New comment by minimaxir in "GPT-5.1: A smarter, more conversational ChatGPT"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;All the examples of "warmer" generations show that OpenAI's definition of warmer is synonymous with &lt;i&gt;sycophantic&lt;/i&gt;, which is a surprise given all the criticism against that particular aspect of ChatGPT.&lt;p&gt;I suspect this approach is a direct response to the backlash against removing 4o.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 19:13:14 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45904702</link><dc:creator>minimaxir</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45904702</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45904702</guid></item><item><title>New comment by modeless in "Steam Frame"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Foveated streaming! That's a great idea. Foveated rendering is complicated to implement with current rendering APIs in a way that actually improves performance, but foveated streaming seems like a much easier win that applies to all content automatically. And the dedicated 6 GHz dongle should do a much better job at streaming than typical wifi routers.&lt;p&gt;&gt; Just like any SteamOS device, install your own apps, open a browser, do what you want: It's your PC.&lt;p&gt;It's an ARM Linux PC that presumably gives you root access, in addition to being a VR headset. And it has an SD card slot for storage expansion. Very cool, should be very hackable. Very unlike every other standalone VR headset.&lt;p&gt;&gt; 2160 x 2160 LCD (per eye) 72-144Hz refresh rate&lt;p&gt;Roughly equivalent resolution to Quest 3 and less than Vision Pro. This won't be suitable as a monitor replacement for general desktop use. But the price is hopefully low. I'd love to see a high-end option with higher resolution displays in the future, good enough for monitor replacement.&lt;p&gt;&gt; Monochrome passthrough&lt;p&gt;So AR is not a focus here, which makes sense. However:&lt;p&gt;&gt; User accessible front expansion port w/ Dual high speed camera interface (8 lanes @ 2.5Gbps MIPI) / PCIe Gen 4 interface (1-lane)&lt;p&gt;Full color AR could be done as an optional expansion pack. And I can imagine people might come up with other fun things to put in there. Mouth tracking?&lt;p&gt;One thing I don't see here is optional tracking pucks for tracking objects or full body tracking. That's something the SteamVR Lighthouse tracking ecosystem had, and the Pico standalone headset also has it.&lt;p&gt;More detail from the LTT video: Apparently it can run Android APKs too? Quest compatibility layer maybe? There's an optional accessory kit that adds a top strap (I'm surprised it isn't standard) and palm straps that enable using the controllers in the style of the Valve Index's "knuckles" controllers.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 19:02:33 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45904494</link><dc:creator>modeless</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45904494</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45904494</guid></item><item><title>New comment by bbarnett in "The last-ever penny will be minted today in Philadelphia"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I know you're referencing more than pennies, but to speak to pennies, I find the current rounding noise in the US to be weird.  Likely, it's just more of the media, talking heads, and youtube personalities trying to turn a nothing into something, story.&lt;p&gt;Back when we did it in Canada, I don't recall a single person I knew concerned about penny rounding.  Everyone was sick of pennies.  No one cared.  Everyone was happy.  And the math seems fair enough:&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.budget.canada.ca/2012/themes/theme2-info-eng.html" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://www.budget.canada.ca/2012/themes/theme2-info-eng.htm...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;Basically, if something is $1.01 or $1.02, you round down.  If it's $1.03 or $1.04, you round up.  Rounding is to be applied after all taxes are paid, etc.&lt;p&gt;Of course, there was also central guidance and, well, everyone just followed it.  It's called "having a society".&lt;p&gt;People blathering on about stores fixing the rounding are morons, there's no way to do so if you buy more than one item.  No one gets ripped off with the above method.  In the end, it just works out.&lt;p&gt;And really, &lt;i&gt;who cares&lt;/i&gt;?!  It's a penny.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 18:51:49 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45904256</link><dc:creator>bbarnett</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45904256</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45904256</guid></item><item><title>New comment by thadt in "Steam Machine"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Pretty much the only reason I boot to Windows anymore is to play games with my kids and family. The direction of this thing is dangerously close to being all I'd care about from a desktop computer.&lt;p&gt;If Valve pivoted into making a well-supported laptop with good hardware that ran Linux &lt;i&gt;and&lt;/i&gt; played games...&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 18:29:33 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45903896</link><dc:creator>thadt</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45903896</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45903896</guid></item><item><title>New comment by jsheard in "Steam Machine"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Valve has been quietly working on integrating the FEX x86 emulator into Proton for a while, and it's official now.&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.tomshardware.com/peripherals/gaming-headsets/hands-on-with-valves-new-steam-frame-headset-arm-powered-mixed-mode-device-uses-new-fex-translation-layer-for-traditional-x86-games" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://www.tomshardware.com/peripherals/gaming-headsets/han...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 18:13:55 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45903610</link><dc:creator>jsheard</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45903610</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45903610</guid></item><item><title>New comment by Night_Thastus in "The last-ever penny will be minted today in Philadelphia"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I'd say screw it, get rid of nickles and dimes as well. Quarters can stay, for now.&lt;p&gt;It's a complete waste of money and time continuing to mint such low-value currency. It can't be used for just about anything.&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, I do see the problem with part of this. For a handful of items where it does matter, it will force people to use cards more if they want to avoid rounding. And the card providers already have a choke-hold on retailers, and the whole thing is basically a scheme that funnels money from the poor to the wealthy via interest and fees on the consumer, interchange fees, and rewards programs.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 18:13:53 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45903609</link><dc:creator>Night_Thastus</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45903609</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45903609</guid></item><item><title>New comment by teroshan in "Steam Machine"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://store.steampowered.com/sale/steamframe" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://store.steampowered.com/sale/steamframe&lt;/a&gt; [1]&lt;p&gt;&gt; Steam Frame is a PC, and runs SteamOS powered by a Snapdragon® 8 Series Processor. With 16GB of RAM, Steam Frame supports stand-alone play on a growing number of both VR and non-VR games without needing to stream from your PC.&lt;p&gt;So Steam + Proton works on aarch64? Is this something already available/supported, or is this an announcement?&lt;p&gt;[1] Steam Frame, which is the VR Headset releasing alongside the Steam Machine. Dedicated discussion here &lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45903325"&gt;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45903325&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 18:10:53 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45903562</link><dc:creator>teroshan</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45903562</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45903562</guid></item><item><title>New comment by wkat4242 in "Fighting the New York Times' invasion of user privacy"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;If OpenAI hadn't used data from the NYT without permission in the first place this wouldn't have happened. That is the root cause of all this.&lt;p&gt;I'm glad the NYT is fighting them. They've infringed the rights of almost every news outlet but someone has to bring this case.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 18:06:51 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45903497</link><dc:creator>wkat4242</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45903497</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45903497</guid></item><item><title>New comment by mmmlinux in "Waymo robotaxis are now giving rides on freeways in LA, SF and Phoenix"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I was in SF a few weekend ago and rode both Waymo and normal Lyft style taxi cars. the Waymo was a better experience in every single way. One of the Lyfts i was in drove on the shoulder for a while like it was a lane. The Waymos were just smooth consistent driving. No aggressive driving to get you dumped off so they can get to the next fair.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 17:06:15 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45902647</link><dc:creator>mmmlinux</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45902647</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45902647</guid></item><item><title>New comment by 1vuio0pswjnm7 in "Fighting the New York Times' invasion of user privacy"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;"The New York Times is demanding that we turn over 20 million of your private ChatGPT conversations."&lt;p&gt;As might any plaintiff.  NYT might be the first of many others and the lawsuits may not be limited to copyright claims&lt;p&gt;Why has OpenAI collected and stored 20 million conversations (including "deleted chats")&lt;p&gt;What is the purpose of OpenAI storing millions of private conversations&lt;p&gt;By contrast the purpose of NYT's request is both clear and limited&lt;p&gt;The documents requested are not being made public by the plaintiffs.  The documents will presumably be redacted to protect any confidential information before being produced to the plaintiffs, the documents can only be used by the plaintiffs for the purpose of the litigation against OpenAI and, unlike OpenAI who has collected and stored these conversations for as long as OpenAI desires, the plaintiffs are prohibited from retaining copies of the documents after the litigation is concluded&lt;p&gt;The privacy issue here has been created by OpenAI for their own commercial benefit&lt;p&gt;It is not even clear what this benefit, if any, will be as OpenAI continues to search for a "business model"&lt;p&gt;Wanton data collection&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 16:11:27 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45901917</link><dc:creator>1vuio0pswjnm7</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45901917</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45901917</guid></item><item><title>New comment by Tabular-Iceberg in "Yt-dlp: External JavaScript runtime now required for full YouTube support"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I remember when QuickTime came out in 1991 and it was obvious to everyone that video should be copied, pasted and saved like any arbitrary data.&lt;p&gt;It's absolutely insane to me how bad the user experience is with video nowadays, even video that's not encumbered by DRM or complex JavaScript clients.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 13:36:17 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45899963</link><dc:creator>Tabular-Iceberg</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45899963</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45899963</guid></item><item><title>New comment by mehulashah in "Yann LeCun to depart Meta and launch AI startup focused on 'world models'"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Most of the folks on this topic are focused on Meta and Yann’s departure. But, I’m seeing something different.&lt;p&gt;This is the weirdest technology market that I’ve seen. Researchers are getting rewarded with VC money to try what remains a science experiment. That used to be a bad word and now that gets rewarded with billions of dollars in valuation.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 13:21:19 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45899804</link><dc:creator>mehulashah</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45899804</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45899804</guid></item><item><title>New comment by ineedasername in "Pakistani newspaper mistakenly prints AI prompt with the article"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;When reached for comment on how this occurred, the journalist in question replied:&lt;p&gt;“This is the perfect question that gets to the heart of this issue. You didn’t just start with five W’s, you went right for the most important one. Let’s examine why that question works so well in this instance…”&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 12:35:45 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45899395</link><dc:creator>ineedasername</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45899395</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45899395</guid></item><item><title>New comment by chrismorgan in "Pakistani newspaper mistakenly prints AI prompt with the article"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;The current title (“Pakistani newspaper mistakenly prints AI prompt with the article”) isn’t correct, it wasn’t the &lt;i&gt;prompt&lt;/i&gt; that was printed, but trailing chatbot fluff:&lt;p&gt;&gt; &lt;i&gt;If you want, I can also create an even snappier “front-page style” version with punchy one-line stats and a bold, infographic-ready layout—perfect for maximum reader impact. Do you want me to do that next?&lt;/i&gt;&lt;p&gt;The article in question is titled “Auto sales rev up in October” and is an exceedingly dry slab of statistic-laden prose, of the sort that LLMs &lt;i&gt;love&lt;/i&gt; to err in (though there’s no indication of whether they have or not), and for which alternative (non-prose) presentations can be drastically better. Honestly, if the entire thing came from “here’s tabular data, select insights and churn out prose”… I can understand not wanting to do such drudgework.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 12:05:15 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45899143</link><dc:creator>chrismorgan</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45899143</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45899143</guid></item><item><title>New comment by xuancanh in "Yann LeCun to depart Meta and launch AI startup focused on 'world models'"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;In industry research, someone in a chief position like LeCun should know how to balance long-term research with short-term projects. However, for whatever reason, he consistently shows hostility toward LLMs and engineering projects, even though Llama and PyTorch are two of the most influential projects from Meta AI. His attitude doesn’t really match what is expected from a Chief position at a product company like Facebook. When Llama 4 got criticized, he distanced himself from the project, stating that he only leads FAIR and that the project falls under a different organization. That kind of attitude doesn’t seem suitable for the face of AI at the company. It's not a surprise that Zuck tried to demote him.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 08:55:07 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45897885</link><dc:creator>xuancanh</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45897885</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45897885</guid></item><item><title>New comment by sebmellen in "Yann LeCun to depart Meta and launch AI startup focused on 'world models'"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Making LeCun report to Wang was the most boneheaded move imaginable. But… I suppose Zuckerberg knows what he wants, which is AI slopware and not truly groundbreaking foundation models.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 07:57:49 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45897467</link><dc:creator>sebmellen</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45897467</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45897467</guid></item><item><title>New comment by ivraatiems in "I can build enterprise software but I can't charge for it"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I am not a lawyer or diplomat or expert on trade, but I can make some general observations from an American/Western perspective:&lt;p&gt;First, the sanctions on Iran are such that any partnership with an Iranian person for business reasons is effectively impossible in the West, without the resources of a multi-million or billion-dollar company to circumvent them. The author says "I am not looking for anyone to bypass sanctions" but that is very obviously exactly what they are asking for.&lt;p&gt;Second, circumventing sanctions is illegal, and people regularly go to prison or are given massive monetary fines for this. OP, I don't question your motives, but you need to understand that people have literally gone to prison and lost their whole livelihoods for doing exactly what you are asking.&lt;p&gt;Therefore, posting this on a Western platform (Github) and advertising it on a Western message board (HN) is unlikely to help. I don't think the author's intentions are poor; I think they may simply not understand the intensity of the legal regime that makes working with them impossible.&lt;p&gt;There is also the matter of Westerners' general opinions on Iran, which - general attitudes of multiculturalism and tolerance nonwithstanding - is typically quite negative. The sanctions didn't come from nowhere.&lt;p&gt;I would recommend the author look into partnerships with persons from countries that are more sympathetic to their situation. The ones with strong tech industries would be Russia, China, and India. Vietnam is another example of a country with some tech industry which also has mostly positive relationships with Western countries, these days. I realize this is not as attractive as the West, but there are good people even in places whose governments I may as a Westerner may not particularly like, and English is a lingua franca the world over. I'd strongly recommend those places as a starting point.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 00:27:33 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45894833</link><dc:creator>ivraatiems</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45894833</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45894833</guid></item><item><title>New comment by judah in ".NET MAUI is coming to Linux and the browser"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;This is interesting for sure. Kudos for bringing this capability to the web!&lt;p&gt;One issue the demos reveal is, it doesn't _feel_ like the web. That is, I can't hit Ctrl+F to find text on a page. I can't select text with my cursor. I can't copy the address of a hyperlink. On my phone, I can't hard press on an image and share it to others. Screen readers can't handle it. I can't press a shortcut key to make everything larger.&lt;p&gt;These all may seem pedantic, but they contribute to the feeling "this is not the real web."&lt;p&gt;This is the same problem with Java applets in the late '90s, Flash and Silverlight in the early 2000s. They are islands of richness within a web page, but those islands are, well, opaque to browsers, search engines, and virtually all web tooling.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 11 Nov 2025 23:49:36 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45894501</link><dc:creator>judah</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45894501</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45894501</guid></item><item><title>New comment by fao_ in "FFmpeg to Google: Fund us or stop sending bugs"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;As yet, Valve is the only company I know of doing this, and it's paying off in dividends both for Linux and for Valve. In just 5ish years of Valve investing people and money into Linux- specifically mesa and WINE, Linux has gone from a product that is kind of shaky with Windows, to "I can throw a windows program or game at it and it usually works". Imagine how further the OSS ecosystem would be if Open Source hadn't existed, only FOSS; and companies were legally obligated to either publish source code or otherwise invest in the ecosystem.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 11 Nov 2025 23:47:41 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45894483</link><dc:creator>fao_</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45894483</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45894483</guid></item></channel></rss>