<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>Hacker News: Best Comments</title><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/bestcomments</link><description>Hacker News RSS</description><docs>https://hnrss.org/</docs><generator>hnrss v2.1.1</generator><lastBuildDate>Sun, 19 Oct 2025 23:57:39 +0000</lastBuildDate><ns0:link href="https://hnrss.org/bestcomments" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item><title>New comment by rahimnathwani in "Novo Nordisk's Canadian Mistake"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;AIUI, because they let the patent expire, the drug was not subject to price regulation by the government. So they could charge whatever.&lt;p&gt;And during most of that time, they were still protected by 'data exclusivity' which means that any generic producer could not get approved without doing their own clinical trials, until 8 years had passed.&lt;p&gt;So they gave up some period of exclusivity in return for being able to charge a higher price when they still had a monopoly.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 19 Oct 2025 21:34:54 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45638230</link><dc:creator>rahimnathwani</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45638230</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45638230</guid></item><item><title>New comment by brosco in "Doing well in your courses: Andrej's advice for success (2013)"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I have a tip for following lectures (or any technical talk, really) that I've been meaning to write about for a while.&lt;p&gt;As you follow along with the speaker, try to predict what they will say next. These can be either local or global predictions. Guess what they will write next, or what will be on the next slide. With some practice (and exposure to the subject area) you can usually get it right. Also try to keep track of how things fit into the big picture. For example in a math class, there may be a big theorem that they're working towards using lots of smaller lemmas. How will it all come together?&lt;p&gt;When you get it right, it will feel like you are figuring out the material on your own, rather than having it explained to you. This is the most important part.&lt;p&gt;If you can manage to stay one step ahead of the lecturer, it will keep you way more engaged than trying to write everything down. Writing puts you one step behind what the speaker is saying. Because of this, I usually don't take any notes at all. It obviously works better when lecture notes are made available, but you can always look at the textbook.&lt;p&gt;People often assume that I have read the material or otherwise prepared for lectures, seminars, etc., because of how closely I follow what the speaker is saying. But really most talks are quite logical, and if you stay engaged it's easy to follow along. The key is to not zone out or break your concentration, and I find this method helps me immensely.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 19 Oct 2025 17:41:32 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45636152</link><dc:creator>brosco</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45636152</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45636152</guid></item><item><title>New comment by raincole in "Replacement.ai"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;It's actually an extremely good analogy (but in the opposite way of what you imply), as you don't own your job or your wife. Banning AI for job security is like banning dildos because they make men feel insecure.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 19 Oct 2025 17:16:12 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45635905</link><dc:creator>raincole</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45635905</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45635905</guid></item><item><title>New comment by echelon_musk in "Comparing the power consumption of a 30 year old refrigerator to a new one"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&gt; &lt;i&gt;Comparing the power consumption of a [broken] 30 year old refrigerator to a brand new one&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 19 Oct 2025 16:11:45 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45635305</link><dc:creator>echelon_musk</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45635305</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45635305</guid></item><item><title>New comment by bos in "The Spherical Cows of Programming"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;This is a bizarre essay by someone who understands neither functional programming nor the history of computers.&lt;p&gt;&gt; To be kind, we’ve spent several decades twisting hardware to make the FP spherical cow work “faster”, at the expense of exponential growth in memory usage, and, some would argue, at the expense of increased fragility of software.&lt;p&gt;There is not one iota of support for functional programming in any modern CPU.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 19 Oct 2025 16:07:07 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45635263</link><dc:creator>bos</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45635263</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45635263</guid></item><item><title>New comment by warent in "Replacement.ai"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Equating “business” to “profound human intimacy” might be one of the most HackerNews comments of all time&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 19 Oct 2025 16:05:25 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45635246</link><dc:creator>warent</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45635246</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45635246</guid></item><item><title>New comment by ErikCorry in "RFCs: Blueprints of the Internet"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Forgotten? No mention of why we should think they are forgotten outside the headline.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 19 Oct 2025 16:02:09 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45635205</link><dc:creator>ErikCorry</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45635205</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45635205</guid></item><item><title>New comment by everdrive in "Replacement.ai"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;[flagged]&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 19 Oct 2025 15:56:21 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45635149</link><dc:creator>everdrive</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45635149</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45635149</guid></item><item><title>New comment by TechSquidTV in "Replacement.ai"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Personal belief, but robots coming for your jobs is not a valid argument against robots. If robots can do a job better and/or faster, they should be the ones doing the jobs. Specialization is how we got to the future.&lt;p&gt;So the problem isn't robots, it's the structure of how we humans rely on jobs for income. I don't necessarily feel like it's the AI company's problem to fix either.&lt;p&gt;This is what government is for, and not to stifle innovation by banning AI but by preparing society to move forward.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 19 Oct 2025 15:12:51 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45634750</link><dc:creator>TechSquidTV</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45634750</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45634750</guid></item><item><title>New comment by allturtles in "Replacement.ai"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;This is a brilliant piece of satire. "A Modest Proposal" for the AI age.&lt;p&gt;The leader bios are particularly priceless. "While working for 12 years as the Director of HR for a multinational, Faith realized that firing people gave her an almost-spiritual high. Out of the office, Faith coaches a little league softball team and looks after her sick mother - obligations she looks forward to being free of!"&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 19 Oct 2025 14:42:33 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45634510</link><dc:creator>allturtles</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45634510</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45634510</guid></item><item><title>New comment by darthoctopus in "Replacement.ai"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;that &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; the point of Luddism! the original Luddite movement was not ipso facto opposed to progress, but rather to the societal harm caused by society-scale economic obsolescence. the entire history of technology is &lt;i&gt;also&lt;/i&gt; powerful business interests smearing this movement as being intrinsically anti-progress, rather than directly addressing these concerns…&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 19 Oct 2025 14:33:06 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45634424</link><dc:creator>darthoctopus</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45634424</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45634424</guid></item><item><title>New comment by sincerely in "Replacement.ai"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I kind of get it, but at the same time...isn't "we made a machine to do something that people used to do" basically the entire history of of technology? It feels like somehow we should have figured out how to cope with the "but what about the old jobs" problem&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 19 Oct 2025 14:26:22 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45634372</link><dc:creator>sincerely</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45634372</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45634372</guid></item><item><title>New comment by digitalengineer in "GoFundMe CEO: economy is so bad his customers crowdfund to pay for groceries"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;“The GoFundMe CEO hopes younger donors, who are often more values-driven, digitally native, and community-oriented, will push giving higher and faster.”
I can’t believe it. THIS is what he &lt;i&gt;hopes for&lt;/i&gt;? He is not stating he hopes his country can get out of this mess? Or researching what his company can do? He’s just looking after his cut.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 19 Oct 2025 08:13:13 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45632733</link><dc:creator>digitalengineer</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45632733</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45632733</guid></item><item><title>New comment by aantix in "Friendship Begins at Home"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I've been pretty harsh on myself over the years.&lt;p&gt;I started carrying around a photo of myself as a kid.  I'm sitting against a wall, by a pillar, at our state capital.  My eyes are shut.  I was kind of a shy kid.&lt;p&gt;When I start to get frustrated and talk to myself in that short, abrasive, condescending tone, I think of that photo and of myself, as still that kid.&lt;p&gt;It helps me to be more compassionate towards myself in those moments.  I'm still that shy kid trying to make sense of the world.&lt;p&gt;I'm 47.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 19 Oct 2025 05:01:56 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45632158</link><dc:creator>aantix</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45632158</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45632158</guid></item><item><title>New comment by rdtsc in "Titan submersible’s $62 SanDisk memory card found undamaged at wreckage site"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&gt; No deep-sea shenanigans around the Titanic wreck were revealed. Manley explains in his Twitter thread that “the camera had been configured to dump data onto an external storage device, so nothing was found from the accident dive.” Nothing particularly pertinent to the tragic accident, that is.&lt;p&gt;This is about camera hardware and how it survived. It provides no information or footage about the incident (in case you were looking for it like I was).&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 19 Oct 2025 03:56:29 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45631983</link><dc:creator>rdtsc</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45631983</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45631983</guid></item><item><title>New comment by cperciva in "The reason GCC is not a library (2000)"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;It also speaks to an absolute failure of governance.  If I missed an important email on a FreeBSD mailing list, you can bet that a dozen other people would see it and either poke me about it or just go ahead and act upon it themselves.&lt;p&gt;The fact that RMS missed an email &lt;i&gt;and nobody else did anything about it either&lt;/i&gt; is a sign of an absolutely dysfunctional relationship between the project and its leadership.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 19 Oct 2025 03:37:39 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45631927</link><dc:creator>cperciva</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45631927</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45631927</guid></item><item><title>New comment by enriquto in "The reason GCC is not a library (2000)"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Oh, this is one of my favorite (and sad!) dramas in free software.&lt;p&gt;Five years later the main llvm developer proposed [0] to integrate it into gcc.&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, this critical message was missed by a mail mishap on Stallman's part; and he publicly regretted both his errors (missing the message and not accepting the offer), ten years later [1].&lt;p&gt;The drama was discussed in realtime here in HN [2].&lt;p&gt;[0] &lt;a href="https://gcc.gnu.org/legacy-ml/gcc/2005-11/msg00888.html" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://gcc.gnu.org/legacy-ml/gcc/2005-11/msg00888.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;[1] &lt;a href="https://lists.gnu.org/archive/html/emacs-devel/2015-02/msg00594.html" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://lists.gnu.org/archive/html/emacs-devel/2015-02/msg00...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;[2] &lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=9028738"&gt;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=9028738&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 19 Oct 2025 00:20:12 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45631284</link><dc:creator>enriquto</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45631284</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45631284</guid></item><item><title>New comment by RandomBK in "Titan submersible’s $62 SanDisk memory card found undamaged at wreckage site"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I see a lot of discussion in this thread stemming from some confusion+not reading the actual report[0].&lt;p&gt;Some key points:&lt;p&gt;1. The Camera+Card was encased in a separate enclosure made of titanium+sapphire, and did not seem to be exposed to extreme pressures.&lt;p&gt;2. The encryption was done via a variant of LUKS/dm-crypt, with the key stored on the NVRAM of a chip (Edited; not in TrustZone).&lt;p&gt;3. The recovery was done by transplanting the original chip onto a new working board. No manufacturer backdoors or other hidden mechanisms were used.&lt;p&gt;4. Interestingly, the camera vendor didn't seem to realize there was any encryption at all.&lt;p&gt;[0] &lt;a href="https://data.ntsb.gov/Docket/Document/docBLOB?ID=18741602&amp;FileExtension=pdf&amp;FileName=Underwater%20Camera%20-%20Specialist%27s%20Factual%20Report-Rel.pdf" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://data.ntsb.gov/Docket/Document/docBLOB?ID=18741602&amp;Fi...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 18 Oct 2025 21:39:33 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45630550</link><dc:creator>RandomBK</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45630550</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45630550</guid></item><item><title>New comment by jonas21 in "Titan submersible’s $62 SanDisk memory card found undamaged at wreckage site"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;The NTSB's original report has more detail on how the SD Card was encrypted and how the NTSB managed to decrypt it:&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://data.ntsb.gov/Docket/Document/docBLOB?ID=18741602&amp;FileExtension=pdf&amp;FileName=Underwater%20Camera%20-%20Specialist%27s%20Factual%20Report-Rel.pdf" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://data.ntsb.gov/Docket/Document/docBLOB?ID=18741602&amp;Fi...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 18 Oct 2025 20:39:06 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45630183</link><dc:creator>jonas21</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45630183</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45630183</guid></item><item><title>New comment by skrebbel in "Root System Drawings"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Ever thought you yanked a dandelion out by the entire root? Think again: &lt;a href="https://images.wur.nl/digital/collection/coll13/id/676/rec/3" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://images.wur.nl/digital/collection/coll13/id/676/rec/3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 18 Oct 2025 19:06:55 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45629651</link><dc:creator>skrebbel</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45629651</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45629651</guid></item><item><title>New comment by guilamu in "Tinnitus Neuromodulator"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;A message of hope.&lt;p&gt;I got mine in my 30's too. The first week I thought I was going crazy, and this was the end of my life. I was shocked, I couldn't go to work for a whole week.&lt;p&gt;I then saw a doctor who said to me: "Man, I've got tinnitus since 20 years and I barely hear it anymore. The more you accept it, the more it'll fade."&lt;p&gt;A decade later, my own experience is exactly this. I accepted it as one of the body malfunctions that comes with age for everybody. I barely hear it anymore except in extremely low noise situations and it doesn't bother me at all.&lt;p&gt;I wish you well.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 18 Oct 2025 17:37:28 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45629035</link><dc:creator>guilamu</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45629035</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45629035</guid></item><item><title>New comment by andy99 in "Attention is a luxury good"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;The article probably could just have been that statement, but I agree.&lt;p&gt;Every experience now just seems like people (companies) fighting over who can most obnoxiously distract you.&lt;p&gt;I bought a new phone recently for the first time in 8 years, and (a) had to set everything up all at once (ad blocking, no notifications, etc) which left me briefly exposed to how bad things are but (b) had to experience all the annoyingness of a modern phone trying to suggest things and sync things and bother me with stuff I don’t want.&lt;p&gt;No product is even remotely for the consumer anymore, they’re all just minimal pretenses to try and advertise you and extract more of your attention and money.&lt;p&gt;So yeah, outside some sheltered life of luxury, it’s a constant fight to preserve focus against people wanting to steal it.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 18 Oct 2025 16:49:49 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45628663</link><dc:creator>andy99</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45628663</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45628663</guid></item><item><title>New comment by 2bitencryption in "Ripgrep 15.0"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;the ripgrep codebase is ultimate “pour a drink, settle into your coziest chair, and read some high quality software” codebase. Just click around through it and marvel.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 18 Oct 2025 14:58:41 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45627907</link><dc:creator>2bitencryption</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45627907</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45627907</guid></item><item><title>New comment by CGamesPlay in "IDEs we had 30 years ago and lost (2023)"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;(Article is from 2023, so the title should be updated to say "32 years ago", or something)&lt;p&gt;The biggest loss in TUIs is the latest wave of asynchronous frameworks, which bring the joy of dropped keypresses to the terminal.&lt;p&gt;In any TUI released before the year 2000, if you press a key when the system wasn't ready, the key would just wait until the system was ready. Many TUIs today still do this, but increasingly frequently (with the modern "web-inspired" TUI frameworks), the system will be ready to take your keypress, and discard it because the async dialog box hasn't registered its event listener yet.&lt;p&gt;Other than that antipattern, TUIs are doing great these days. As for terminal IDEs, Neovim has never been more featureful, with LSPs and other plugins giving all the features this article discusses. I guess it isn't a mouse-driven TUI, so the author wouldn't be interested, but still.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 18 Oct 2025 14:58:01 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45627903</link><dc:creator>CGamesPlay</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45627903</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45627903</guid></item><item><title>New comment by floppyd in "./watch"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Great hardware design, awful watchface design. The pseudo terminal interface looks like something I'd design right after discovering Linux at 13yo and making it my whole identify for a while.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 18 Oct 2025 14:21:23 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45627611</link><dc:creator>floppyd</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45627611</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45627611</guid></item><item><title>New comment by mkovach in "IDEs we had 30 years ago and lost (2023)"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Ah, Borland’s IDE! An absolute delight. I’ve yet to find anything modern that matches it. Sure, nostalgia turns everything syrupy, but I actively hunt for excuses to use Free Pascal just to fire up that interface. Okay, fine—I like Pascal too. You caught me.&lt;p&gt;I also use Sam and Acme from Plan 9 (technically from the excellent plan9port), but let’s be honest: those aren’t IDEs. They’re editors. Tools that let me think instead of wrestle.&lt;p&gt;There’s a lot we could (and probably should) learn from the old TUIs. For example, it’s perfectly acceptable, even heroic, to spawn a shell from the File menu and run something before returning. Seems people are afraid of losing style points with such grievous actions.&lt;p&gt;And the keybindings! So many of those classic TUIs adopted WordStar’s sacred keystrokes. They’re burned into my muscle memory so thoroughly that using EMACS feels like trying to type with oven mitts. For years, joe (with the blessed jstar alias) was my editor of choice.&lt;p&gt;Anyway! Time to boot the Dr. DOS VM, spin the wheel of Advent of Code, and be nostalgically inefficient on purpose.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 18 Oct 2025 13:32:35 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45627234</link><dc:creator>mkovach</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45627234</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45627234</guid></item><item><title>New comment by blahgeek in "./watch"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&gt; taking inspiration from command-line interfaces&lt;p&gt;IMO the take away from command-line interfaces is compact, precise and minimal design. In a transitional shell prompt like #~$, each character has its meaning. Merely copying these symbols to a watch face is the exact opposite spirit of command like interfaces.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 18 Oct 2025 12:42:52 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45626902</link><dc:creator>blahgeek</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45626902</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45626902</guid></item><item><title>New comment by conartist6 in "Second Chances on YouTube"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Won't be available to anyone terminated for copyright stuff.&lt;p&gt;Woooow what a huge dick move.&lt;p&gt;That's the one massively imbalanced power dynamic that I hear people really fear losing their livelihood to for no good reason, and they're leaving it there to terrorize and ruin livelihoods for future generations.&lt;p&gt;I put up a video of a funeral service for my grandma and like 5 minutes later I was getting threatening legalese mail about my channel by cancelled forever because some record label has a recording of a thousand year old hymn and they don't give a shit about threatening people with no legal basis at all&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 18 Oct 2025 11:48:06 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45626590</link><dc:creator>conartist6</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45626590</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45626590</guid></item><item><title>New comment by SoftTalker in "Jeep wrangler owners waiting for answers week after an update bricked their cars"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;However, a second update has now been pushed that reportedly reverts the software to the previous version, and Jeep Cares cautioned that customers will not be able to tell which version they currently have by looking at Uconnect, because the problematic package doesn’t make any changes to the infotainment suite itself, meaning the version numbers will appear the same.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;p&gt;What kind of complete amateur hour operation are they running there at Jeep/Stellantis?&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 18 Oct 2025 02:06:59 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45624296</link><dc:creator>SoftTalker</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45624296</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45624296</guid></item><item><title>New comment by JimDabell in "New Work by Gary Larson"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;It might’ve started then, but the latest entry is a tribute to Jane Goodall that was posted three days ago:&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.thefarside.com/new-stuff/363/club-gombe" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://www.thefarside.com/new-stuff/363/club-gombe&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 18 Oct 2025 01:54:03 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45624207</link><dc:creator>JimDabell</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45624207</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45624207</guid></item></channel></rss>