<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>Hacker News: Best Comments</title><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/bestcomments</link><description>Hacker News RSS</description><docs>https://hnrss.org/</docs><generator>hnrss v2.1.1</generator><lastBuildDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2025 00:18:06 +0000</lastBuildDate><ns0:link href="https://hnrss.org/bestcomments" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item><title>New comment by OkayPhysicist in "10M people watched a YouTuber shim a lock; the lock company sued him – bad idea"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;LPL owns Covert Instruments, who employs McNally, the YouTuber who got sued in this case. Probably not a coincidence that Covert Instruments &lt;i&gt;wasn't&lt;/i&gt; named in the lawsuit.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2025 18:41:56 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45724734</link><dc:creator>OkayPhysicist</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45724734</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45724734</guid></item><item><title>New comment by jwr in "10M people watched a YouTuber shim a lock; the lock company sued him – bad idea"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;If you don't know him already, I highly recommend videos by LockPickingLawyer — he routinely destroys bogus claims of various companies within seconds. It's quite entertaining to see how little security you actually get from most locks.&lt;p&gt;I wonder if anybody tried suing him…&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2025 18:15:40 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45724434</link><dc:creator>jwr</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45724434</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45724434</guid></item><item><title>New comment by aerostable_slug in "Avoid 2:00 and 3:00 am cron jobs (2013)"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I've had to try to clean up after a similar early decision and it was very painful.&lt;p&gt;Please stick with utc across the board people, someone someday may have to clean up your mess.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2025 17:58:22 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45724243</link><dc:creator>aerostable_slug</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45724243</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45724243</guid></item><item><title>New comment by jedberg in "Avoid 2:00 and 3:00 am cron jobs (2013)"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I've told this story before, but it's super relevant here.  When I set up all the servers for reddit, I set them all to Arizona time.  Arizona does not have DST, and is only one hour off of California (where we all were) for five months, and the same as here the rest of the year.&lt;p&gt;I didn't use UTC because subtracting eight when reading raw logs is a lot harder than subtracting one.&lt;p&gt;They use UTC now, which makes sense since they have a global workforce and log reading interfaces that can automatically change timezones on display.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2025 17:44:17 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45724071</link><dc:creator>jedberg</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45724071</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45724071</guid></item><item><title>New comment by thatjoeoverthr in "It's insulting to read AI-generated blog posts"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Even letting the LLM “clean it up” puts its voice on your text. In general, you don’t want its voice. The associations are LinkedIn, warnings from HR and affiliate marketing hustles. It’s the modern equivalent of “talking like a used car salesman”. Not everyone will catch it but do think twice.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2025 17:08:54 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45723556</link><dc:creator>thatjoeoverthr</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45723556</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45723556</guid></item><item><title>New comment by cube00 in "Claude for Excel"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I don't trust LLMs to do the kind of precise deterministic work you need in a spreadsheet.&lt;p&gt;It's one thing to fudge the language in a report summary, it can be subjective, however numbers are not subjective. It's widely known LLMs are terrible at even basic maths.&lt;p&gt;Even Google's own AI summary admits it which I was surprised at, marketing won't be happy.&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Yes, it is true that LLMs are often bad at math because they don't "understand" it as a logical system but rather process it as text, relying on pattern recognition from their training data.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2025 16:48:26 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45723243</link><dc:creator>cube00</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45723243</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45723243</guid></item><item><title>New comment by extr in "Claude for Excel"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;What is with the negativity in these comments? This is a huge, huge surface area that touches a large percentage of white collar work. Even just basic automation/scaffolding of spreadsheets would be a big productivity boost for many employees.&lt;p&gt;My wife works in insurance operations - everyone she manages from the top down lives in Excel. For line employees a large percentage of their job is something like "Look at this internal system, export the data to excel, combine it with some other internal system, do some basic interpretation, verify it, make a recommendation". Computer Use + Excel Use isn't there yet...but these jobs are going to be the first on the chopping block as these integrations mature. No offense to these people but Sonnet 4.5 is already at the level where it would be able to replicate or beat the level of analysis they typically provide.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2025 16:45:12 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45723179</link><dc:creator>extr</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45723179</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45723179</guid></item><item><title>New comment by jihadjihad in "It's insulting to read AI-generated blog posts"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;It's similarly insulting to read your AI-generated pull request. If I see another "dart-on-target" emoji...&lt;p&gt;You're telling me I need to use 100% of my brain, reasoning power, and time to go over your code, but you didn't feel the need to hold yourself to the same standard?&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2025 16:38:07 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45723057</link><dc:creator>jihadjihad</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45723057</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45723057</guid></item><item><title>New comment by aspir in "PSF has withdrawn $1.5M proposal to US Government grant program"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;This isn't good for the PSF, but if these "poison pill" terms are a pattern that applies to all NSF and (presumably) other government research funding, the entire state of modern scientific research is at risk.&lt;p&gt;Regardless of how you, as an individual, might feel about "DEI," imposing onerous political terms on scientific grants harms everyone in the long term.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2025 15:50:59 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45722391</link><dc:creator>aspir</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45722391</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45722391</guid></item><item><title>New comment by ProllyInfamous in "10M people watched a YouTuber shim a lock; the lock company sued him – bad idea"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Back in 2007, I published the first YouTube bypass of the Master Lock #175 (very common 4-digit code lock), using a paperclip.&lt;p&gt;After the video reached 1.5M views (over a couple years), the video was eventually demonetized (no official reason given). I suspect there was a similarly-frivolous DMCA / claim, but at that point in my life I didn't have any money (was worth &lt;i&gt;negative&lt;/i&gt;) so I just accepted YouTube's ruling.&lt;p&gt;Eventually shut down the account, not wanting to help thieves bypass one of the most-common utility locks around — but definitely am in a position now where I understand that videos like mine and McNally's force manufacturers to actually improve their locks' securities/mechanisms.&lt;p&gt;It is lovely now to see that the tolerances on the #175 have been tightened enough that a paperclip no longer defeats the lock (at least non-destructively); but thin high-tensile picks still do the trick (of bypassing the lock) via the exact same mechanism.&lt;p&gt;Locks keep honest people honest, but to claim Master's products &lt;i&gt;high security&lt;/i&gt; is inherently dishonest (e.g. in their advertising). Thievery is about ease of opportunity; if I were stealing from a jobsite with multiple lockboxes, the ones with Master locks would be attacked first (particularly wafer cylinders).&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2025 15:30:19 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45722107</link><dc:creator>ProllyInfamous</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45722107</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45722107</guid></item><item><title>New comment by agentultra in "Recall for Linux"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;It's bad in concept as well.&lt;p&gt;All of that data sent to a third party server is going to be public on the Internet &lt;i&gt;at some point&lt;/i&gt;. Security? Don't make me laugh. Countries that required government IDs to participate online have already made this mistake and those IDs have been leaked. Just because it's open source or run by $NOT_MICROSOFT won't make it any safer.&lt;p&gt;The problem with other people consenting to it is that it makes every one else less safe. People get compromised and scammers can use that compromised data to work against people who didn't share their data with the, "Benevolent Open Source Recall Service."&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2025 13:21:52 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45720788</link><dc:creator>agentultra</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45720788</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45720788</guid></item><item><title>New comment by everdrive in "What happened to running what you wanted on your own machine?"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;It's important to understand that we could genuinely lose general purpose computing. I don't think it's in serious danger at the moment, but we've been in the midst of a slide in that direction for the last 10-15 years. Part of it is mobile phones, part of it is TPM, part of it is market forces. The latest turn is strictly political. We've really foolishly built the technology necessary for authoritarianism just a few years head of a general global trend towards authoritarianism. At the moment, anyone can use Linux; it's better and easier than ever. Will the laws of your country make it harder or more difficult to avoid? Will major vendors lock you out of basic functions? Will age verification require an agent run on your Windows or macOS computer? (or worse, require the use of a smart phone just to use the internet?)&lt;p&gt;We're not anywhere there yet, but we're closer than we've ever been, and things keep moving in the wrong direction.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2025 13:15:25 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45720707</link><dc:creator>everdrive</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45720707</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45720707</guid></item><item><title>New comment by bre1010 in "You are how you act"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;[flagged]&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2025 12:10:54 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45720066</link><dc:creator>bre1010</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45720066</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45720066</guid></item><item><title>New comment by xandrius in "Why I'm teaching kids to hack computers"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Cool idea and execution but having in-app purchases to buy hints for a game targeted to kids is a big no.&lt;p&gt;I get the market forces and such but I don't want to have an app subtly teach my non-existent kids to reach out to in-app purchases like that.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2025 11:24:40 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45719707</link><dc:creator>xandrius</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45719707</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45719707</guid></item><item><title>New comment by varenc in "We saved $500k per year by rolling our own "S3""</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;In HN style, I'm going to diverge from the content and rant about the company:&lt;p&gt;Nanit needs this storage because they run cloud based baby cameras.  Every Nanit user is uploading video and audio of their home/baby
live to Nanit without any E2EE. It's a hot mic sending anything you say near it to the cloud.&lt;p&gt;Their hardware essentially requires a subscription to use, even though it costs $200/camera. You must spend an additional $200 on a Nanit floor stand if you want sleep tracking. This is purely a software limitation since there's plenty of other ways to get an overhead camera mount. (I'm curious how they even detect if you're using the stand since it's just a USB-C cable. Maybe etags?)&lt;p&gt;Of course Nanit is a popular and successful product that many parents swear by. It just pains me to see cloud based in-home audio/video storage being so normalized. Self-hosted video isn't that hard but no one makes a baby-monitor centric solution. I'm sure the cloud based video storage model will continue to be popular because it's easy, but also because it helps justifies a recurring subscription.&lt;p&gt;edit: just noticed an irony in my comment. I'm ranting about Nanit locking users into their 3rd party cloud video storage, and the article is about Nanit's engineering team moving off a 3rd party (S3) and self-hosting their own storage.  Props to them for getting off S3.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2025 04:22:35 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45717363</link><dc:creator>varenc</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45717363</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45717363</guid></item><item><title>New comment by binarymax in "Microsoft 365 Copilot – Arbitrary Data Exfiltration via Mermaid Diagrams"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&gt; &lt;i&gt;MSRC bounty team determined that M365 Copilot was out-of-scope for bounty and therefore not eligible for a reward.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;p&gt;What a shame. There’s probably LOTS of vulns in copilot. This just discourages researchers and responsible disclosure, likely leaving copilot very insecure in the long run.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2025 00:25:49 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45716217</link><dc:creator>binarymax</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45716217</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45716217</guid></item><item><title>New comment by flkiwi in "A definition of AGI"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&gt; defining AGI as matching the cognitive versatility and proficiency of a well-educated adult&lt;p&gt;I don't think people really realize how extraordinary accomplishment it would be to have an artificial system matching the cognitive versatility and proficiency of an uneducated child, much less a well-educated adult. Hell, AI matching the intelligence of some nonhuman animals would be an epoch-defining accomplishment.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 26 Oct 2025 20:25:28 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45714944</link><dc:creator>flkiwi</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45714944</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45714944</guid></item><item><title>New comment by INTPenis in "YouTube Just Ate TV. It's Only Getting Started"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;In my circle, piracy is making a comeback. We're tired of having to hunt down streaming services, and be extorted for hundreds of euro a month, just to see ads for their own programs.&lt;p&gt;Streaming was fun for a while, but as always these greedy execs are ruining it.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 26 Oct 2025 16:41:43 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45713207</link><dc:creator>INTPenis</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45713207</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45713207</guid></item><item><title>New comment by haskellshill in "A worker fell into a nuclear reactor pool"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Wow, people are really clueless about how nuclear power plants really work. It's really not that dangerous to fall into the water.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 26 Oct 2025 14:06:55 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45711991</link><dc:creator>haskellshill</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45711991</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45711991</guid></item><item><title>New comment by __MatrixMan__ in "You already have a Git server"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I've been using git since 2007, this only dawned on me last year.&lt;p&gt;Git is especially prone to the sort of confusion where all the experts you know use it in slightly different ways so the culture is to just wing it until you're your own unique kind of wizard who can't tie his shoes because he favors sandals anyhow.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 26 Oct 2025 13:52:09 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45711882</link><dc:creator>__MatrixMan__</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45711882</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45711882</guid></item><item><title>New comment by jonhohle in "You already have a Git server"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I feel like something was lost along the way.&lt;p&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;    git init —-bare
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
will give you a git repo without a working set (just the contents typically in the .git directory). This allows you to create things like `foo.git` instead of `foo/.git`.&lt;p&gt;“origin” is also just the default name for the cloned remote. It could be called anything, and you can have as many remotes as you’d like. You can even namespace where you push back to the same remotes by changing fetch and push paths. At one company it was common to push back to `$user/$feature` to avoid polluting the root namespace with personal branches. It was also common to have `backup/$user` for pushing having a backup of an entire local repo.&lt;p&gt;I often add a hostname namespace when I’m working from multiple hosts and then push between them directly to another instead of going back to a central server.&lt;p&gt;For a small static site repo that has documents and server config, I have a remote like:&lt;p&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;    [remote “my-server”]
    url = ssh+git://…/deploy/path.git
    fetch = +refs/heads/*:refs/remotes/my-server
    push = +refs/heads/*:refs/remotes/my-laptop
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
So I can push from my computer directly to that server, but those branches won’t overwrite the server’s branches. It acts like a reverse `git pull`, which can be useful for firewalls and other situations where my laptop wouldn’t be routable.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 26 Oct 2025 13:43:49 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45711822</link><dc:creator>jonhohle</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45711822</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45711822</guid></item><item><title>New comment by thyristan in "You already have a Git server"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Maybe I'm too old, but are there people that really didn't know that any ssh access is sufficient for using git?&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 26 Oct 2025 12:17:36 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45711160</link><dc:creator>thyristan</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45711160</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45711160</guid></item><item><title>New comment by jkhdigital in "A worker fell into a nuclear reactor pool"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;You’re right, you don’t know! When I worked on a nuclear aircraft carrier, I learned that the people working down in the reactor spaces got significantly less radiation exposure than the people working on the flight deck. My ship was ported in Japan when the Fukushima disaster happened, and we had to abruptly go out to sea because we couldn’t let the (minimal) fallout contaminate the reactor spaces and make it impossible to monitor the reactor itself properly.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 26 Oct 2025 10:49:34 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45710699</link><dc:creator>jkhdigital</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45710699</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45710699</guid></item><item><title>New comment by sa-code in "Why I code as a CTO"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&gt; I don’t particularly enjoy building orgs and figuring out people stuff. Engineering management involves navigating interpersonal dynamics, performance reviews, and organizational design. These are crucial functions, but they’re not where my strengths lie.&lt;p&gt;This bit got me. It's a direct quote from the linked post for those who haven't read it&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 26 Oct 2025 09:39:04 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45710397</link><dc:creator>sa-code</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45710397</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45710397</guid></item><item><title>New comment by thomascountz in "Advent of Code 2025: Number of puzzles reduce from 25 to 12 for the first time"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Whenever there's a change like this, my gut reaction is to grieve and try to imagine ways that things could be kept the same.&lt;p&gt;After thinking, "maybe puzzles could be designed by a group instead of an individual and they could share the work," I then thought, "and couldn't an LLM help?"&lt;p&gt;And with that, I had to remind myself: Advent of Code isn't about there being 25 puzzles, and so maintaining volume at all costs has nothing to do with it.&lt;p&gt;And aren't we so lucky that it isn't! Aren't we lucky to have had the prior 500+ challenges given as gifts over the years! Aren't we lucky to have a great demonstration of humility and care! Aren't we lucky to have 12 new gifts to look forward to this year!&lt;p&gt;Thank you!&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 26 Oct 2025 09:27:48 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45710338</link><dc:creator>thomascountz</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45710338</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45710338</guid></item><item><title>New comment by shrx in "Advent of Code 2025: Number of puzzles reduce from 25 to 12 for the first time"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;One of the reasons I stopped participating was that as the second half of december was approaching I had less and less free time for solving the puzzles. So to me it is also a welcome change, I will try to finish it again this year.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 26 Oct 2025 09:26:18 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45710328</link><dc:creator>shrx</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45710328</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45710328</guid></item><item><title>New comment by intermerda in "What if tariffs?"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;The number 39 refers to the 39% tariff rate on Switzerland.&lt;p&gt;Kind of insane that the American President just made up a lie that tariffs are paid by foreign countries and rest of the administration just went along with it. It flies in the face of any common sense.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 26 Oct 2025 08:47:38 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45710125</link><dc:creator>intermerda</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45710125</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45710125</guid></item><item><title>New comment by CobrastanJorji in "Why I code as a CTO"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Man, if I'm trying to decide which company to work for, and I see a blog post from its CTO crowing about regularly checking in code on Saturdays and Sundays, I'd start backing slowly away. And when I got to the bit that said "AI has made me three times as productive," I'd turn and run.&lt;p&gt;Your job at the top is, more than anything else, pushing down a healthy culture. That includes things like setting an example of not working through the weekend. If you're doing it, your reports and their reports will feel the need to do it, too. Don't. And if you do anyway, certainly don't brag about it!&lt;p&gt;And then listen to this insanity:&lt;p&gt;&gt; Our team had considered potentially having the customer build their own integration on top of our API in order to get around this requirement, and scoping it out properly would have required many meetings across product, legal, and engineering. I built and shipped a working version in a day. It wasn’t perfect, but it solved their immediate problem and preserved goodwill with the customer.&lt;p&gt;That's something you're willing to share out loud? Your company's technical process (which you're fully in control of, Mr. CTO) is so cumbersome that it seriously hinders your ability to execute, but, being above that process, you personally choose to circumvent it, foregoing required legal or engineering reviews, and shipping it immediately to your critically important customer? If one of the engineers who worked under you did that, you'd probably have fired him.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 26 Oct 2025 05:27:13 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45709378</link><dc:creator>CobrastanJorji</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45709378</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45709378</guid></item><item><title>New comment by robocat in "A worker fell into a nuclear reactor pool"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;FYI:&lt;p&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;  the primary hazard from acute, high-dose uranium ingestion is chemical toxicity leading to acute kidney failure (nephrotoxicity), not radiation.&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 26 Oct 2025 02:33:54 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45708694</link><dc:creator>robocat</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45708694</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45708694</guid></item><item><title>New comment by Animats in "A worker fell into a nuclear reactor pool"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Palisades MI reactor. Currently shut down and de-fueled but a restart of this reactor is apparently underway, with new fuel assemblies being delivered.[1]&lt;p&gt;Worker was wearing a life vest.[2]&lt;p&gt;[1] &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Palisades_Nuclear_Generating_Station" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Palisades_Nuclear_Generating_S...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;[2] &lt;a href="https://www.mlive.com/news/2025/10/michigan-nuclear-plant-worker-had-to-be-decontaminated-after-falling-into-reactor-pool.html" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://www.mlive.com/news/2025/10/michigan-nuclear-plant-wo...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 26 Oct 2025 02:00:04 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45708517</link><dc:creator>Animats</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45708517</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45708517</guid></item></channel></rss>