<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>Hacker News: Best Comments</title><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/bestcomments</link><description>Hacker News RSS</description><docs>https://hnrss.org/</docs><generator>hnrss v2.1.1</generator><lastBuildDate>Sun, 23 Nov 2025 23:58:16 +0000</lastBuildDate><ns0:link href="https://hnrss.org/bestcomments" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item><title>New comment by da_chicken in "Ubuntu LTS releases to 15 years with Legacy add-on"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I don't agree, and this feels like something written by someone who has never managed actual systems running actual business operations.&lt;p&gt;Operating systems in particular need to manage the hardware, manage memory, manage security, and otherwise absolutely need to &lt;i&gt;shut up and stay out of the fucking way&lt;/i&gt;. Established software changes SLOWLY. It doesn't need to reinvent itself with a brand new dichotomy every 3 years.&lt;p&gt;Nobody builds a server because they want to run the latest version of Python. They built it to run the software they bought 10 years ago for $5m and for which they're paying annual support contracts of $50k. They run what the support contracts require them to run, and they don't want to waste time with an OS upgrade because the cost of the downtime is too high and none of the software they use is going to utilize any of the newly available features. All it does is introduce a new way for the system to fail in ways you're not yet familiar with. It adds ZERO value because all we actually want and need is &lt;i&gt;the same shit but with security patches&lt;/i&gt;.&lt;p&gt;Genuinely I want HN to understand that not everyone is running a 25 person startup running a microservice they hope to scale to Twitter proportions. Very few people in IT are working in the tech industry. Most IT departments are understaffed and underfunded. If we can save three weeks of time over 10 years by not having to rebuild an entire system every 3 years, it's very much worth it.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 23 Nov 2025 14:16:33 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46023721</link><dc:creator>da_chicken</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46023721</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46023721</guid></item><item><title>New comment by pavlov in "After my dad died, we found the love letters"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Ouch. This hits incredibly hard.&lt;p&gt;I’ve been this dad who sits frozen at the TV every evening. I had the affairs with the emotionally unavailable men, and became one myself.&lt;p&gt;Before you judge the man in this story too harshly — and there’s certainly much to judge, especially given the follow-up post — consider the environment he and I grew up in. Being gay as a young teenager in the early 1990s could feel literally like a death sentence. AIDS panic was everywhere. Gay men in movies were comedy sidekicks or dying wrecks (“Philadelphia”). There was a real threat of violence from other kids. If you could pass as straight, why wouldn’t you give it your best shot? The alternative was to be a laughing stock and die alone in a hospital where nurses don’t dare touch you. (This is literally how I imagined gay life at age 13.)&lt;p&gt;I still feel like I’m barely getting started on the therapy journey to recover from those decades. Seems like the man in the story never had the chance for professional help (or didn’t seek it). The compartmentalization can be extremely taxing. He disappointed many people, but that doesn’t mean he was a bad person.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 23 Nov 2025 12:16:28 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46022960</link><dc:creator>pavlov</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46022960</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46022960</guid></item><item><title>New comment by throwaway142351 in "After my dad died, we found the love letters"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I'm a dad too, and I'm in a somewhat similar situation. My son is under five, and it feels like I'm still at the very beginning of his story. I've known I was gay since high school, probably even earlier, but I kept choosing whatever seemed like the easiest path. It felt easier to stay closeted. Easier to date a woman. Easier to move in together, propose, get married, and even have a child than to face my truth.&lt;p&gt;I love my wife and my son, and I feel loved by them in return, but I'm also painfully aware that the version of me they love is someone I constructed. I lie constantly: about why I don't want sex, about my affairs, about my feelings, about my motivations. No one really knows me, and I don't get to be myself, not even in the relationships where I should feel safest.&lt;p&gt;I've read &lt;i&gt;The Courage to Be Disliked&lt;/i&gt; by Ichiro Kishimi and other similar books, and I'm trying to build the courage to finally do something about all of this. It's incredibly difficult. But I refuse to use my son as an excuse to keep postponing coming out. This blog has pushed me even further in that direction.&lt;p&gt;They'll be angry (well at least my wife). Their lives will be upended. But at least they'll have the chance to ask questions, to understand. They'll see me taking responsibility for the consequences of my choices, and maybe just maybe, in some way, that clarity will be a relief for all of us.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 23 Nov 2025 11:55:14 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46022847</link><dc:creator>throwaway142351</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46022847</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46022847</guid></item><item><title>New comment by quitit in "After my dad died, we found the love letters"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;From reading both posts, there's a few things that come to my mind:&lt;p&gt;- It seems this is how the author is processing her father's passing, and it's not really up to us to make moral calls on the content of the posts. They are thoughts with gaps of missing context against a real life of highs and lows which is not readily condensed into a blog post.&lt;p&gt;- I'm peering into the life of a private person, that feels like a violation. Even though they have passed, the people around them are very much alive.&lt;p&gt;- We can't makes guesses at what a person truly values, neither positively nor negatively. What can be seen as promiscuity can also be seen as seeking validation, human motives and emotions exist in the grey area.&lt;p&gt;- This is a person who was deprived of the sort of genuine sexual and emotional attention that we take for granted from puberty age. They lived as a type of outsider in school, work, and their daily norms. The integrity of their actions shouldn't be evaluated against our own values which were likely built from a different life experience.&lt;p&gt;- It's ok not knowing or judging. One has to practice a type of "radical acceptance" when reviewing these sorts of life matters.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 23 Nov 2025 11:08:47 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46022548</link><dc:creator>quitit</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46022548</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46022548</guid></item><item><title>New comment by jackhuman in "Meta buried 'causal' evidence of social media harm, US court filings allege"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I’ve recently had to deal with my father cognitive decline &amp; falling for scams left &amp; right using Meta’s apps. This has been so hard on our family. I did a search the other day on marketplace and 100% of all sellers were scams, 20-30 of them.&lt;p&gt;Meta is a cancer on our society, I’m shutting down all my accounts. Back when TV/Radio/News paper were how you consumed news, you couldn’t get scams this bad at this scale. Our parents dealt with their parents so much easier as they cognitively declined. We need legal protections for elders and youth online more than ever. Companies need to be liable for their ads and scam accounts. Then you’d see a better internet.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 23 Nov 2025 07:39:05 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46021569</link><dc:creator>jackhuman</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46021569</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46021569</guid></item><item><title>New comment by Ozzie_osman in "Meta buried 'causal' evidence of social media harm, US court filings allege"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;At this point, I think all of the big tech companies have had some accusations of them acting unethically, but usually, the accusations are around them acting anticompetitively or issues around privacy.&lt;p&gt;Meta (and social media more broadly) are the only case where we have (in my opinion) substantiated allegations of a company being aware of a large, negative impact on society (mental wellness, of teens no less), and still prioritizing growth and profit. The mix is usually: grow at all costs mindset, being "data-driven", optimizing for engagement/addiction, and monetizing via ads. The center of gravity of this has all been Meta (and social media), but that thinking has permeated lots of other tech as well.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 23 Nov 2025 05:33:24 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46021049</link><dc:creator>Ozzie_osman</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46021049</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46021049</guid></item><item><title>New comment by themafia in "A monopoly ISP refuses to fix upstream infrastructure"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;The comment at the bottom of the article I believe is correct.  I believe this because our neighborhood had the same problem.  One day my neighbor,  frustrated beyond his capacity,  and seemingly very high on something,  went outside and started ripping infrastructure out by hand and damaging everything else he could find with a hammer.&lt;p&gt;They came out and replaced a lot of the damaged equipment and did a few upgrades.  After that the intermittent 2 minute drop problems disappeared.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 23 Nov 2025 04:06:48 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46020670</link><dc:creator>themafia</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46020670</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46020670</guid></item><item><title>New comment by pseudolus in "NTSB report: Decryption of images from the Titan submersible camera [pdf] (2024)"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;There's a fascinating and redacted interview with an "anonymous" subject about the disaster. To say the least it's an unsuccessful attempt to hide the identity of the individual:&lt;p&gt;"Q. So how did you get yourself started into submersible operations?&lt;p&gt;A. Well, I'm sure you're familiar with my film Titanic. When I set down the path to make that film, the first thing that I did was arrange to be introduced to the head of the submersible program at the P.P. Shirshov Institute in Moscow, a guy named..."&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://media.defense.gov/2025/Sep/17/2003800984/-1/-1/0/CG-115_INTERVIEW-DEEP-SEA-EXPLORER_REDACTED.PDF" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://media.defense.gov/2025/Sep/17/2003800984/-1/-1/0/CG-...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 23 Nov 2025 03:11:47 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46020427</link><dc:creator>pseudolus</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46020427</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46020427</guid></item><item><title>New comment by tfvlrue in "A monopoly ISP refuses to fix upstream infrastructure"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I had a similar problem with a different ISP, Optimum, in Northern NJ. It wasn't as regular as the author's problem -- my cable modem would desync intermittently throughout the day despite the signal strength numbers being in spec.&lt;p&gt;I replaced everything downstream of the drop from the street, all new wiring inside, a new modem/router/etc. All signs pointed to the problem being outside the house. I went so far as to connect an oscilloscope to the coax line to look for patterns. I discovered that if I physically manipulated a particular section of the line from the pole, a huge interference pattern appeared and the modem's connection dropped. Eventually I could reproduce the connection loss fairly easily.&lt;p&gt;Convincing the ISP to actually do anything about it was much harder. Despite first-hand evidence that the coax from the pole needed to be replaced, their tech support insisted that someone had to come into the house to inspect the interior wiring. No amount of insistence on my part would convince them that it was not necessary. The building was a vacation home, and this was during peak COVID time, so there was basically no chance of that happening. The appointment came with threats of service charges if they sent a tech and could not enter the building or reproduce the problem, so I cancelled it.&lt;p&gt;Coincidentally, I happened to discover that the mayor of the town had started a hotline specifically for reporting home Internet problems in the town. So I sent in a message to that service, not really expecting anything to come of it. But shortly after I get a phone call from some higher-up department of the ISP. They had a truck out within a few days to replace the drop -- with no one home -- and the connection was rock solid ever since.&lt;p&gt;This experience taught me that ISPs often have distinct support channels that governmental departments use to contact them. I think they called it the "executive support team" or something along those lines. Basically, if you can get a message in that way, it's possible to circumvent the useless consumer-level support. Long story short, I think escalating this through the local or state level government may be the author's best shot at getting this resolved.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 23 Nov 2025 03:00:14 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46020375</link><dc:creator>tfvlrue</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46020375</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46020375</guid></item><item><title>New comment by stego-tech in "A monopoly ISP refuses to fix upstream infrastructure"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I sympathize with the author. I remain on Charter’s shitlist to this day because I had a very similar issue about twenty years ago, except our connection cut out entirely after ~10MB of data had downloaded in a continuous stream, and the cable modem had to wait for the line to become available again. No amount of technical documentation, logs, traceroutes, equipment swaps, or anything on my end would convince them it was a problem with their infrastructure.&lt;p&gt;So, exasperated, I filed a complaint with the FCC. A week later, it got fixed along with an apology, no truck roll needed.&lt;p&gt;I miss when the government had teeth and used it against companies, man.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 23 Nov 2025 02:58:32 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46020361</link><dc:creator>stego-tech</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46020361</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46020361</guid></item><item><title>New comment by amake in "`satisfies` is my favorite TypeScript keyword (2024)"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;99% of my use of `satisfies` is to type-check exhaustivity in `switch` statements:&lt;p&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;    type Foo = 'foo' | 'bar';
    
    const myFoo: Foo = 'foo';
    switch (myFoo) {
      case 'foo':
        // do stuff
        break;
      default:
        myFoo satisfies never; // Error here because 'bar' not handled
    }&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 23 Nov 2025 00:31:00 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46019613</link><dc:creator>amake</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46019613</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46019613</guid></item><item><title>New comment by jayd16 in "We Induced Smells With Ultrasound"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Finally some progress towards smellovision.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 22 Nov 2025 23:51:17 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46019416</link><dc:creator>jayd16</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46019416</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46019416</guid></item><item><title>New comment by decasia in "The realities of being a pop star"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I thought this was a really good piece of writing. It’s rare to do something like this because the job discourages it by putting PR filters on everything you say.&lt;p&gt;My uncle was a pretty big pop star in the 1960s. His group at one point had a big fanzine, they were household names across the country, over time they had stalkers and weird fans and all that, made movies and albums, had big parties and knew other famous people, pretty much all those things that the OP writes about (circa 50 years later, some of it has changed but not that much).&lt;p&gt;He could be charismatic and surprisingly eloquent and I could picture him writing a piece like this, if the mood had struck.&lt;p&gt;He also lost pretty much all the money through mismanagement (several times over), eventually moved out of LA, had a tumultuous family life with numerous spouses and wasn’t around much for his kids, and after his 40s was trapped in a sad cycle of reunion tours because the band still needed the money. The tours still had some level of excitement and crowd enthusiasm, even pretty late in life and I guess he always loved the stage, the performing, all that. But in the end, I kinda felt it seemed like a lonely existence. Hard to form really deep connections when you’re always traveling and often away in your head.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 22 Nov 2025 22:46:48 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46019015</link><dc:creator>decasia</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46019015</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46019015</guid></item><item><title>New comment by dschuessler in "Markdown is holding you back"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;You can include arbitrary HTML tags in Markdown at any place you need them.[0] I am not aware of any Markdown tooling that does not support this.&lt;p&gt;So, no, Markdown is not holding me back. It is perfectly capable of what the author claims it isn't.&lt;p&gt;[0]: &lt;a href="https://daringfireball.net/projects/markdown/syntax#html" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://daringfireball.net/projects/markdown/syntax#html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 22 Nov 2025 22:20:59 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46018817</link><dc:creator>dschuessler</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46018817</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46018817</guid></item><item><title>New comment by schmichael in "WorldGen – Text to Immersive 3D Worlds"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;It’s a fun demo but they never go into buildings, the buildings all have similar size, the towns have similar layouts, there’s numerous visual inconsistencies, and the towns don’t really make sense. It generates stylistically similar boxes, puts them on a grid, and lets you wander the spaces between?&lt;p&gt;I know progress happens in incremental steps, but this seems like quite the baby step from other world gen demos unless I’m missing something.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 22 Nov 2025 21:50:13 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46018560</link><dc:creator>schmichael</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46018560</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46018560</guid></item><item><title>New comment by credit_guy in "China reaches energy milestone by "breeding" uranium from thorium"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Before anybody gets too excited, it's better to understand what exactly happened.&lt;p&gt;China ran an experimental reactor that achieved &lt;i&gt;some&lt;/i&gt; conversion of thorium into uranium. More precisely, the conversion ratio was 0.1 [1]. This means that for each new fissile atom generated from thorium (i.e. uranium-233) 10 atoms have been burned from the original fissile inventory.&lt;p&gt;Now, conversion happens in every nuclear reactor. Some new fissile material (generally Pu-239) is generated out of "fertile material" (generally U-238). And, surprisingly, that conversion ratio is quite high: 0.6 for pressurized light water reactors and 0.8 for pressurized heavy water reactors [2].&lt;p&gt;What China has achieved therefore is well below what is business as usual in regular reactors. The only novelty is that the breeding used thorium, rather than uranium.&lt;p&gt;Is this useless? No, it is not. In principle increasing the conversion ratio from 0.1 to something higher than 1.0 should be doable. But then, going from 0.8 in heavy water reactors to more than 1.0 should be even easier. Why don't people do it already? Because the investment needed to do all the research is quite significant, and the profits that can be derived from that are quite uncertain and overall the risk adjusted return on investment is not justified. If you are a state, you can ignore that. If China continues the research in thorium breeding, and eventually an economically profitable thorium breeder reactor comes out of that, the entire world will benefit. But the best case scenario is that this would be three decades in the future.&lt;p&gt;[1] &lt;a href="https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/articles/chinese-msr-achieves-conversion-of-thorium-uranium-fuel" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://www.world-nuclear-news.org/articles/chinese-msr-achi...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;[2] &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Breeder_reactor#Conversion_ratio" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Breeder_reactor#Conversion_rat...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 22 Nov 2025 20:37:23 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46018044</link><dc:creator>credit_guy</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46018044</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46018044</guid></item><item><title>New comment by aragonite in "The privacy nightmare of browser fingerprinting"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Some time ago I noticed that in Chrome, every time you click "Never translate $language", $language quietly gets added to the Accept-Language header that Chrome sends to every website!&lt;p&gt;My header ended up looking like a permuted version of this:&lt;p&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;  en-US,en;q=0.9,zh-CN;q=0.8,de;q=0.7,ja;q=0.6
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
I never manually configured any of those extra languages in the browser settings. All I had done was tell Chrome not to translate a few pages on some foreign news sites. Chrome then turned those one-off choices into persistent signals attached to every request.&lt;p&gt;I'd be surprised if anyone in my vicinity share my exact combination of languages in that exact order, so this seems like a pretty strong fingerprinting vector.&lt;p&gt;There was even a proposal to reduce this surface area, but it wasn't adopted:&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/explainers-by-googlers/reduce-accept-language" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://github.com/explainers-by-googlers/reduce-accept-lang...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 22 Nov 2025 20:35:05 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46018023</link><dc:creator>aragonite</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46018023</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46018023</guid></item><item><title>New comment by AshamedCaptain in "$1900 Bug Bounty to Fix the Lenovo Legion Pro 7 16IAX10H's Speakers on Linux"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I wish there was an actual thriving business model like this -- just fixing most annoying bugs, for a price, of commonly used desktop software. Why proprietary software companies cannot or do not want to provide this service is over me. Perhaps I'm too much used to consulting.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 22 Nov 2025 19:15:30 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46017415</link><dc:creator>AshamedCaptain</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46017415</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46017415</guid></item><item><title>New comment by Broussebar in "'The French people want to save us': help pours in for glassmaker Duralex"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;As the article said Duralex was the brand use by a large number of school cantinas in France. Inside of each glass there’s a small number used by the brand to identify the mold used for the creation of the glass. For kids that was a way to decide who is going to fetch the water for the table (smaller number or higher number of the table). 
That’s why the CE is holding his glass like that in the guardian article.
Beside the nostalgia i think a lot of people support them because it’s a SCOP (the majority of the capital of the company is owned by the employees) [1] and it’s nice to see that another kind of company is possible.&lt;p&gt;[1] &lt;a href="https://fr.wikipedia.org/wiki/Soci%C3%A9t%C3%A9_coop%C3%A9rative_et_participative" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://fr.wikipedia.org/wiki/Soci%C3%A9t%C3%A9_coop%C3%A9ra...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 22 Nov 2025 18:30:01 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46017023</link><dc:creator>Broussebar</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46017023</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46017023</guid></item><item><title>New comment by yndoendo in "In a U.S. First, New Mexico Opens Doors to Free Child Care for All"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;US actually provided child care to mothers employed during WWII. [0]&lt;p&gt;Richard Nixon vetoed the bill that would have expanded it out to all families. [1]&lt;p&gt;Funny how we keep forgetting the past and reject what benefited us as a whole with a moved to pure individualism built around selfishness. AKA The rich keep getting richer.&lt;p&gt;[0] &lt;a href="https://www.wwiimemorialfriends.org/blog/the-lanham-act-and-universal-childcare-during-world-war-ii" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://www.wwiimemorialfriends.org/blog/the-lanham-act-and-...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;[1] &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Comprehensive_Child_Development_Act" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Comprehensive_Child_Developmen...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 22 Nov 2025 16:55:15 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46016130</link><dc:creator>yndoendo</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46016130</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46016130</guid></item><item><title>New comment by _pdp_ in "Agent design is still hard"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I've started a company in this space about 2 years ago. We are doing fine. What we've learned so far is that a lot of these techniques are simply optimisations to tackle some deficiency in LLMs that is a problem "today". These are not going to be problems tomorrow because the technology will shift. As it happened many time in the span of the last 2 years.&lt;p&gt;So yah, cool, caching all of that... but give it a couple of months and a better technique will come out - or more capable models.&lt;p&gt;Many years ago when disc encryption on AWS was not an option, my team and I had to spend 3 months to come up with a way to encrypt the discs and do so well because at the time there was no standard way. It was very difficult as that required pushing encrypted images (as far as I remember). Soon after we started, AWS introduced standard disc encryption that you can turn on by clicking a button. We wasted 3 months for nothing. We should have waited!&lt;p&gt;What I've learned from this is that often times it is better to do absolutely nothing.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 22 Nov 2025 14:17:43 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46014987</link><dc:creator>_pdp_</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46014987</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46014987</guid></item><item><title>New comment by jandrewrogers in "Kodak ran a nuclear device in its basement for decades"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;When I studied chemistry at university, only a handful of select students were introduced to the nuclear science lab in the basement. It had a lot of spicy isotopes, neutron sources, etc. Even as a chemistry student with free run of the place for years I had no idea it was in the building until the department head pulled a few of us aside.&lt;p&gt;The reason for the informal secrecy, as it was explained to me, is that every so often someone would find out there was plutonium etc in the basement and have a public freak out, including on occasion other (non-STEM) professors at the same university. These people would try to organize crusades to get it shut down because evil. Intentionally obscuring its existence greatly mitigated this drama. They appreciated us continuing the tradition of keeping it out of sight and out of mind from the general public.&lt;p&gt;The publicity around this Kodak case was an example of why no one talks about nuclear labs. The public cannot be trusted to engage in a discussion about anything “nuclear” in good faith. There are quite a few areas of science like this.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 22 Nov 2025 13:27:41 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46014624</link><dc:creator>jandrewrogers</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46014624</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46014624</guid></item><item><title>New comment by cjonas in "ADHD and monotropism (2023)"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I was diagnosed with ADD as a kid (before it was ADHD). People always describe the disorder as "lack of focus" but that's a really poor description for what I have.&lt;p&gt;I would say I have "hyper focus", to the point where if I'm working on something interesting, I will lose track of time and am unable to redirect my attention to anything else.&lt;p&gt;This makes me incredibly "spacey" as often my mind is still fixated on the task even long after I've stopped working on it.  It also makes it very hard for me to accomplish any task I don't think are interesting...&lt;p&gt;And often a new idea will strike me like an epiphany that immediately takes the top spot of my attention.&lt;p&gt;The result is I have hundreds of half finished projects in flight across countless areas of interest.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 22 Nov 2025 13:15:20 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46014541</link><dc:creator>cjonas</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46014541</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46014541</guid></item><item><title>New comment by sebmellen in "Original Superman comic becomes the highest-priced comic book ever sold"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;He added: “This isn’t simply a blurb of words and phrases. This is not just a stock statement from an LLM.&lt;p&gt;This is a testament to outsourcing, laziness and the unexpected ways technology finds ways to change every press release.”&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 22 Nov 2025 06:07:54 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46012518</link><dc:creator>sebmellen</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46012518</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46012518</guid></item><item><title>New comment by dbacar in "Original Superman comic becomes the highest-priced comic book ever sold"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;"He added: "This isn't simply a story about old paper and ink. This was never just about a collectible.&lt;p&gt;"This is a testament to memory, family and the unexpected ways the past finds its way back to us."
"""
Men going extreme in sentimental when they just sold a $9M collectible :).&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 22 Nov 2025 05:49:37 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46012442</link><dc:creator>dbacar</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46012442</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46012442</guid></item><item><title>New comment by simonw in "Personal blogs are back, should niche blogs be next?"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Here are some reasons to start a personal blog:&lt;p&gt;1. It's a great way to learn. Teaching something to someone else has always been the best learning tool, and writing about something with an audience in mind is an effective way to capture some of that value.&lt;p&gt;2. It can be a big boost in job hunting. As a hiring manager two of the most important questions I have about a potential candidate are: Can they code? Can they communicate well? If a candidate has a blog with just two articles on it that hasn't been updated in five years that's &lt;i&gt;still&lt;/i&gt; a big boost over candidates with nothing like that at all. In a competitive market that could be the boost you need to make it from the resume review to the first round.&lt;p&gt;3. If you blog more frequently than that it can be a really valuable resource for your future self. I love being able to look back on what I was thinking and writing about ten years ago. Having a good tagging system helps with this too - I can review my tag of "scaling" or "postgresql" and see a timeline of how my understanding developed.&lt;p&gt;4. It's a great way to help establish credibility. If someone asks you about X and you have a blog entry about X from five years ago you can point them to that.&lt;p&gt;5. Building a blog is really fun! It used to be one of the classic starter projects for new web developers, I think that needs to come back. It's a fun project and one that's great to keep on hacking on long into the future.&lt;p&gt;Notably none of the above reasons require your blog to attract readers! There's a ton of value to be had even if nobody actually reads the thing.&lt;p&gt;As a general rule, assume nobody will read your blog unless you actively encourage them to. That's fine. What matters isn't the quantity of readers, it's their quality. I'd rather have a piece read by just a single person that leads to a new opportunity for me than 1,000 people who read it and never interact with me ever again.&lt;p&gt;If you DO start to get readers things get even more valuable. I've been blogging since 2002 and most of the opportunities in my career came from people I met via blogging. Today I get invited to all sorts of interesting events because I have a prominent blog covering stuff relating to AI and LLMs.&lt;p&gt;But I do honestly think that a blog is a powerful professional tool even if nobody else is reading it at all.&lt;p&gt;If you want to give it a go I've written a few things that might be useful:&lt;p&gt;- What to blog about: &lt;a href="https://simonwillison.net/2022/Nov/6/what-to-blog-about/" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://simonwillison.net/2022/Nov/6/what-to-blog-about/&lt;/a&gt; - Today I learned and write about your projects&lt;p&gt;- My approach to running a link blog - &lt;a href="https://simonwillison.net/2024/Dec/22/link-blog/" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://simonwillison.net/2024/Dec/22/link-blog/&lt;/a&gt; - aka write about stuff you've found&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 22 Nov 2025 03:38:48 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46011877</link><dc:creator>simonw</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46011877</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46011877</guid></item><item><title>New comment by 12_throw_away in "Arduino Terms of Service and Privacy Policy update: setting the record straight"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;"We are Arduino. We are open. We’re not going anywhere."&lt;p&gt;-- statement from Qualcomm without a single human being's name on it&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 22 Nov 2025 02:57:15 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46011661</link><dc:creator>12_throw_away</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46011661</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46011661</guid></item><item><title>New comment by ajb in "Samsung's 60% DRAM price hike signals a new phase of global memory tightening"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Dram alternates between feast and famine; it's the nature of a business when the granularity of investment is so huge (you have a fab or you don't, and they cost billions -maybe trillions by now). So, it will swing back. Unfortunately it looks like maybe 3-5 years on average, from some analysis here: 
&lt;a href="https://storagesearch.com/memory-boom-bust-cycles.html" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://storagesearch.com/memory-boom-bust-cycles.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;(That's just me eyeballing it, feel free to do the math)&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 22 Nov 2025 02:07:09 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46011404</link><dc:creator>ajb</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46011404</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46011404</guid></item><item><title>New comment by taurath in "Childhood Friends, Not Moms, Shape Attachment Styles Most"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;No, one study doesn’t upend the last few decades of understanding of emotional attachment.&lt;p&gt;The study simply says that ability to connect w friends is more predictive than observations they made of apparent attachment of parents.&lt;p&gt;This happens much later so of course it’s more predictive of the actual end effects - that’s when attachment styles actually show up for the first time. Kids grow up to be very adaptive toward their parents but when they get to the rest of society that’s when the failures of connection and the failed bids for attention show up.&lt;p&gt;A very resilient kid will do fine with friends even with a very bad attachment environment. A very sensitive kid or one with developmental problems will struggle in social environments.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 22 Nov 2025 00:20:58 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46010739</link><dc:creator>taurath</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46010739</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46010739</guid></item><item><title>New comment by willio58 in "California DMV approves map increase in Waymo driverless operations"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I didn’t think I’d be so pro Waymo but anecdotally I had a fantastic experience with one recently.&lt;p&gt;I was at a music show very late ~1-2am in SF and walked out to grab an uber to the airbnb I was staying at. I kept getting assigned an uber, then I’d wait 10 minutes, then they’d cancel. Rinse and repeat for 30 minutes, mind you I even resorted to calling Lyfts at the same time and nothing bit. Then I say screw it and download Waymo. 1 minute and it’s accepted my ride, and I know it’s not going to cancel because it’s a robot. 3 minutes and it picks me up. The car is clean, quiet, I can play my own music in it via Spotify, and it’s driving honestly more safely than some uber drivers I’ve had in SF. It’s one of the few things where the end result actually lives up to the promise from a tech company.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 22 Nov 2025 00:14:50 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46010696</link><dc:creator>willio58</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46010696</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46010696</guid></item></channel></rss>