<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>Hacker News: Best Comments</title><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/bestcomments</link><description>Hacker News RSS</description><docs>https://hnrss.org/</docs><generator>hnrss v2.1.1</generator><lastBuildDate>Sun, 07 Dec 2025 01:22:22 +0000</lastBuildDate><ns0:link href="https://hnrss.org/bestcomments" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item><title>New comment by jordanb in "Perl's decline was cultural"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I always found the Perl "community" to be really off-putting with all the monk and wizard nonsense. Then there was the whole one-liner thing that was all about being clever and obscure. Everything about Python came off as being much more serious and &lt;i&gt;normal&lt;/i&gt; for a young nerd who wasn't a theater kid.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 06 Dec 2025 18:16:28 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46175337</link><dc:creator>jordanb</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46175337</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46175337</guid></item><item><title>New comment by walterbell in "GrapheneOS is the only Android OS providing full security patches"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://tbot.substack.com/p/grapheneos-new-oem-partnership" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://tbot.substack.com/p/grapheneos-new-oem-partnership&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;&gt; GrapheneOS has officially confirmed a major new hardware partnership—one that marks the end of its long-standing Pixel exclusivity. According to the team, work with a major Android OEM began in June and is now moving toward the development of a next-generation smartphone built to meet GrapheneOS’ strict privacy and security standards.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 06 Dec 2025 16:46:13 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46174679</link><dc:creator>walterbell</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46174679</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46174679</guid></item><item><title>New comment by tayiorrobinson in "How I discovered a hidden microphone on a Chinese NanoKVM"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;To be fair, the microphone _is_ listed on the specsheet of the LicheeRV Nano&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://wiki.sipeed.com/hardware/en/lichee/RV_Nano/1_intro.html" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://wiki.sipeed.com/hardware/en/lichee/RV_Nano/1_intro.h...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;I assume they didn't intend to put a  mic on the KVM product, but they wanted to make a KVM product, already had this SBC product, which reusing their existing stock of helped keep cost low.&lt;p&gt;Should they have been more up front about it it? Sure, and it's not great that they had a bunch of security issues in the FW anyway, so not exactly great, but "hidden microphone in a Chinese KVM" lets the mind wander&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 06 Dec 2025 14:54:59 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46173784</link><dc:creator>tayiorrobinson</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46173784</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46173784</guid></item><item><title>New comment by cracki in "Schizophrenia sufferer mistakes smart fridge ad for psychotic episode"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Time to ban all adverts everywhere. I'm not the only one who is fed up with ads.&lt;p&gt;I don't see ads, thanks to ad blocking tech in browsers and smartphones. Any time that happens to fail and I get to endure an ad, I am amazed that regular people without ad blocking tech can endure this onslaught.&lt;p&gt;The time to negotiate a "middle ground" is long past. Let's not even entertain that idea.&lt;p&gt;An acceptable middle ground could have been designated areas for ads, which you have to seek out to see them. Think of the Yellow Pages.&lt;p&gt;Ad companies need to be reined in. They cannot control themselves. They are lobbying against all limits and controls. The only solution is to eradicate ads entirely and to make sure that anyone who gets that idea will never get it again.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 06 Dec 2025 11:27:55 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46172492</link><dc:creator>cracki</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46172492</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46172492</guid></item><item><title>New comment by xioxox in "Schizophrenia sufferer mistakes smart fridge ad for psychotic episode"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Although adverts on the fridge are absolutely terrible, is this genuine? Here's a reddit post some time before that suggesting the scenario: &lt;a href="https://old.reddit.com/r/assholedesign/comments/1ow6cpu/apparently_my_samsung_fridge_has_ads_now/nonrm5s/" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://old.reddit.com/r/assholedesign/comments/1ow6cpu/appa...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 06 Dec 2025 09:18:04 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46171868</link><dc:creator>xioxox</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46171868</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46171868</guid></item><item><title>New comment by brendangregg in "Leaving Intel"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I like to measure things. In real life and on computers. But I also have a couple of work reasons for it:&lt;p&gt;As a remote worker, I'm under extra pressure to prove that remoteness works.&lt;p&gt;As a senior employee, I'm also under pressure to regularly report where my time is spent.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 06 Dec 2025 05:11:04 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46170913</link><dc:creator>brendangregg</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46170913</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46170913</guid></item><item><title>New comment by gyomu in "Leaving Intel"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&gt; "I also supported cloud computing, participating in 110 customer meetings, and created a company-wide strategy to win back the cloud with 33 specific recommendations, in collaboration with others across 6 organizations."&lt;p&gt;Man people keep count of this stuff?! Maybe I should too, it does make flexing easier.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 06 Dec 2025 01:47:51 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46169774</link><dc:creator>gyomu</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46169774</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46169774</guid></item><item><title>New comment by mixedbit in "Cloudflare outage on December 5, 2025"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;This is architectural problem, the LUA bug, the longer global outage last week, a long list of earlier such outages only uncover the problem with architecture underneath. The original, distributed, decentralized web architecture with heterogeneous endpoints managed by myriad of organisations is much more resistant to this kind of global outages. Homogeneous systems like Cloudflare will continue to cause global outages. Rust won't help, people will always make mistakes, also in Rust. Robust architecture addresses this by not allowing a single mistake to bring down myriad of unrelated services at once.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 22:54:13 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46168481</link><dc:creator>mixedbit</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46168481</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46168481</guid></item><item><title>New comment by Rover222 in "Gemini 3 Pro: the frontier of vision AI"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I just tried to get Gemini to produce an image of a dog with 5 legs to test this out, and it really struggled with that. It either made a normal dog, or turned the tail into a weird appendage.&lt;p&gt;Then I asked both Gemini and Grok to count the legs, both kept saying 4.&lt;p&gt;Gemini just refused to consider it was actually wrong.&lt;p&gt;Grok seemed to have an existential crisis when I told it it was wrong, becoming convinced that I had given it an elaborate riddle. After thinking for an additional 2.5 minutes, it concluded:
"Oh, I see now—upon closer inspection, this is that famous optical illusion photo of a "headless" dog. It's actually a three-legged dog (due to an amputation), with its head turned all the way back to lick its side, which creates the bizarre perspective making it look decapitated at first glance. So, you're right; the dog has 3 legs."&lt;p&gt;You're right, this is a good test. Right when I'm starting to feel LLMs are intelligent.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 20:56:14 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46167185</link><dc:creator>Rover222</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46167185</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46167185</guid></item><item><title>New comment by Workaccount2 in "Gemini 3 Pro: the frontier of vision AI"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Well&lt;p&gt;It is the first model to get &lt;i&gt;partial-credit&lt;/i&gt; on an LLM image test I have. Which is counting the legs of a dog. Specifically, a dog with 5 legs. This is a wild test, because LLMs get really pushy and insistent that the dog only has 4 legs.&lt;p&gt;In fact GPT5 wrote an edge detection script to see where "golden dog feet" met "bright green grass" to prove to me that there were only 4 legs. The script found 5, and GPT-5 then said it was a bug, and adjusted the script sensitivity so it only located 4, lol.&lt;p&gt;Anyway, Gemini 3, while still being unable to count the legs first try, did identify "male anatomy" (it's own words) also visible in the picture. The 5th leg was approximately where you could expect a well endowed dog to have a "5th leg".&lt;p&gt;That aside though, I still wouldn't call it particularly impressive.&lt;p&gt;As a note, Meta's image slicer correctly highlighted all 5 legs without a hitch. Maybe not quite a transformer, but interesting that it could properly interpret "dog leg" and ID them. Also the dog with many legs (I have a few of them) all had there extra legs added by nano-banana.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 20:26:05 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46166792</link><dc:creator>Workaccount2</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46166792</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46166792</guid></item><item><title>New comment by CrossVR in "The effect of shingles vaccination at different stages of dementia"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I wonder when we'll finally accept that there's no such thing as a harmless latent disease. Chickenpox, EBV, HPV, they're all associated with either neurodegeneration or cancer.&lt;p&gt;We should be vaccinating kids against all of them rather than sending them to Chickenpox parties.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 18:27:29 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46165209</link><dc:creator>CrossVR</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46165209</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46165209</guid></item><item><title>New comment by roughly in "Framework Laptop 13 gets ARM processor with 12 cores via upgrade kit"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Yeah, there’s a lot of critiques of the product/packaging/etc, but this feels like huge validation of the Framework model - this is an unrelated 3rd party looking to get a chip in consumer hands who decided to use the FW chassis. That’s Exactly what we all were hoping for when Framework first launched.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 17:24:11 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46164340</link><dc:creator>roughly</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46164340</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46164340</guid></item><item><title>New comment by lionkor in "Cloudflare outage on December 5, 2025"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Cloudflare is now below 99.9% uptime, for anyone keeping track. I reckon my home PC is at least 99.9%.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 16:45:21 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46163763</link><dc:creator>lionkor</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46163763</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46163763</guid></item><item><title>New comment by thayne in "Netflix to Acquire Warner Bros"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I want a separation between the streaming platform companies and the content making companies, so that the streaming companies can compete on making a better platform/service and the content companies compete on making better content.&lt;p&gt;I don't want one company that owns everything, I want several companies that are able to license whatever content they want. And ideally the customer can choose between a subscription that includes everything, and paying for content a la carte, or maybe subscriptions that focus on specific kinds of content (scifi/fantasy, stuff for kids, old movies, international, sports, etc.) regardless of what company made it.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 16:24:07 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46163452</link><dc:creator>thayne</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46163452</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46163452</guid></item><item><title>New comment by dkyc in "Cloudflare outage on December 5, 2025"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;One thing to keep in mind when judging what's 'appropriate' is that Cloudflare was effectively responding to an ongoing security incident outside of their control (the React Server RCE vulnerability). Part of Cloudlfare's value proposition is being &lt;i&gt;quick&lt;/i&gt; to react to such threats. That changes the equation a bit: any hour you wait longer to deploy, your customers are actively getting hacked through a known high-severity vulnerability.&lt;p&gt;In this case it's not just a matter of 'hold back for another day to make sure it's done right', like when adding a new feature to a normal SaaS application. In Cloudflare's case moving slower &lt;i&gt;also&lt;/i&gt; comes with a real cost.&lt;p&gt;That isn't to say it didn't work out badly this time, just that the calculation is a bit different.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 16:16:33 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46163343</link><dc:creator>dkyc</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46163343</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46163343</guid></item><item><title>New comment by emmp in "Framework Laptop 13 gets ARM processor with 12 cores via upgrade kit"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;No interest in this exactly, but I am interested in the idea that third parties are now targeting the Framework form factor explicitly to sell upgrades/replacements outside of the Framework marketplace.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 16:13:05 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46163269</link><dc:creator>emmp</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46163269</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46163269</guid></item><item><title>New comment by flaminHotSpeedo in "Cloudflare outage on December 5, 2025"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;What's the culture like at Cloudflare re: ops/deployment safety?&lt;p&gt;They saw errors related to a deployment, and because it was related to a security issue instead of rolling it back they decided to make another deployment with global blast radius instead?&lt;p&gt;Not only did they fail to apply the deployment safety 101 lesson of "when in doubt, roll back" but they also failed to assess the risk related to the same deployment system that caused their 11/18 outage.&lt;p&gt;Pure speculation, but to me that sounds like there's more to the story, this sounds like the sort of cowboy decision a team makes when they've either already broken all the rules or weren't following them in the first place&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 15:49:27 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46162868</link><dc:creator>flaminHotSpeedo</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46162868</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46162868</guid></item><item><title>New comment by jeffheard in "Most technical problems are people problems"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;And most people problems are communication problems. Engineers aren't engaged with the product vision or the customer base, and are allowed to silo themselves. Product doesn't see the point of engineers being engaged and feed the engineering team like an in-house outsourcing shop. Sales and CS fail to understand the cost of their promises to individual customers to the timelines of features they're hungry for from the product plan. Goals and metrics for success fail to align. And thus everyone rows in their own direction.&lt;p&gt;The solution usually isn't "better people." It's engaging people on the same goals and making sure each of them knows how their part fits with the others. It's also recognizing when hard stuff is worth doing. Yeah you've got a module with 15 years of tech debt that you didn't create, and no-one on the team is confident in touching anymore. Unlike acne, it won't get better if you &lt;i&gt;don't&lt;/i&gt; pick at it. Build out what that tech debt is costing the company and the risk it creates. Balance that against other goals, and find a plan that pays it down at the right time and the right speed.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 15:27:56 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46162551</link><dc:creator>jeffheard</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46162551</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46162551</guid></item><item><title>New comment by jasonvorhe in "Netflix to Acquire Warner Bros"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I cancelled all my content subscriptions and I'm back to torrenting. I barely watch anything made my Netflix regardless. I think either Dark or the 3rd season of Stranger Things was the last time. Snyder's SciFi movie wasn't much good either. By now the streaming services are en route to become as terrible as whatever they were set out to replace. Once one of them started heavily advertising their own productions everywhere inside their apps I would've cancelled any remaining subscription at the latest.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 14:50:12 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46162030</link><dc:creator>jasonvorhe</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46162030</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46162030</guid></item><item><title>New comment by nonethewiser in "Netflix to Acquire Warner Bros"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&gt; Any consolidation like this seems like a negative for consumers&lt;p&gt;This is a very common narrative to this news. But coming into this news, I think the most common narrative against streaming was essentially "There is not enough consolidation." People were happy when Netflix was &lt;i&gt;the&lt;/i&gt; streaming service, but then everyone pulled their content and have their own (Disney, Paramount, etc.)&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 14:43:08 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46161918</link><dc:creator>nonethewiser</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46161918</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46161918</guid></item><item><title>New comment by afavour in "Netflix to Acquire Warner Bros"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Any consolidation like this seems like a negative for consumers. But at least it wasn’t bought by Larry Ellison, as was considered very likely (assuming this merger gets approved, in the current administration you never know).&lt;p&gt;From a Hacker News perspective, I wonder what this means for engineers working on HBO Max. Netflix says they’re keeping the company separate but surely you’d be looking to move them to Netflix backend infrastructure at the very least.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 13:44:09 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46161166</link><dc:creator>afavour</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46161166</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46161166</guid></item><item><title>New comment by moolcool in "Netflix to Acquire Warner Bros"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://theonion.com/just-six-corporations-remain-1819564741/" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://theonion.com/just-six-corporations-remain-1819564741...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 13:38:11 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46161112</link><dc:creator>moolcool</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46161112</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46161112</guid></item><item><title>New comment by I-M-S in "Netflix to Acquire Warner Bros"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;“The goal is to become HBO faster than HBO can become us.” - Ted Sarandos in 2013&lt;p&gt;Seems Netflix won that race.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 12:51:52 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46160598</link><dc:creator>I-M-S</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46160598</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46160598</guid></item><item><title>New comment by phartenfeller in "Netflix to Acquire Warner Bros"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I don't like this. Netflix rarely creates excellent content; instead, it frequently produces mediocre or worse content. Will the same happen for Warner? Are cinemas now second behind streaming?&lt;p&gt;Edit: I agree Netflix has good Originals. But most are from the early days when they favored quality over quantity. It is sad to see that they reversed that. They have much funding power and should give it to great art that really sticks, has ambitions and something to tell, and values my time instead of mediocrity.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 12:50:48 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46160586</link><dc:creator>phartenfeller</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46160586</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46160586</guid></item><item><title>New comment by srameshc in "Netflix to Acquire Warner Bros"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I never imagined that a service that ships DVD via mail would one day buy Warner Brothers. It is amazing how innovation and focus can change the game. Someday a new startup will piggy bank on Netflix and probably buy it later.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 12:44:20 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46160524</link><dc:creator>srameshc</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46160524</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46160524</guid></item><item><title>New comment by JoeWiltshire in "Cloudflare Down Again – and DownDetector Is Also Down"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://downdetectorsdowndetectorsdowndetectorsdowndetector.com/" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://downdetectorsdowndetectorsdowndetectorsdowndetector....&lt;/a&gt; reports that &lt;a href="https://downdetectorsdowndetectorsdowndetector.com/" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://downdetectorsdowndetectorsdowndetector.com/&lt;/a&gt; is down, guessing downdetectorsdowndetectorsdowndetector runs via cloudflare!&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 09:04:33 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46158451</link><dc:creator>JoeWiltshire</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46158451</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46158451</guid></item><item><title>New comment by zkmon in "CSS now has an if() conditional function"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Give it enough time, every declarative language becomes a programming language. This is happening with all config files, markup languages, data formats.&lt;p&gt;The distinction between code, config and data is being erased. Everything is a soup now. Data is application, configuration is code. Code is an intermediate, volatile thing that is generated on the fly and executed in the temporary lambda containers.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 07:20:59 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46157649</link><dc:creator>zkmon</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46157649</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46157649</guid></item><item><title>New comment by notatoad in "Netflix’s AV1 Journey: From Android to TVs and Beyond"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I understand that sometimes the HN titles get edited to be less descriptive and more generic in order to match the actual article title.&lt;p&gt;What’s the logic with changing the title here from the actual article title it was originally submitted with “AV1 — Now Powering 30% of Netflix Streaming” to the generic and not at all representative title it currently has “AV1: a modern open codec”?  That is neither the article title nor representative of the article content.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 02:58:28 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46156393</link><dc:creator>notatoad</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46156393</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46156393</guid></item><item><title>New comment by crazygringo in "Netflix’s AV1 Journey: From Android to TVs and Beyond"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Wow. To me, the big news here is that ~30% of devices now support AV1 hardware decoding. The article lists a bunch of examples of devices that have gained it in the past few years. I had no idea it was getting that popular -- fantastic news!&lt;p&gt;So now that h.264, h.265, and AV1 seem to be the three major codecs with hardware support, I wonder what will be the next one?&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 00:58:24 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46155545</link><dc:creator>crazygringo</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46155545</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46155545</guid></item><item><title>New comment by IgorPartola in "Netflix’s AV1 Journey: From Android to TVs and Beyond"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Amazing. Proprietary video codecs need to not be the default and this is huge validation for AV1 as a production-ready codec.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 00:53:46 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46155508</link><dc:creator>IgorPartola</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46155508</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46155508</guid></item></channel></rss>