<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>Hacker News: Best Comments</title><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/bestcomments</link><description>Hacker News RSS</description><docs>https://hnrss.org/</docs><generator>hnrss v2.1.1</generator><lastBuildDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2025 00:26:05 +0000</lastBuildDate><ns0:link href="https://hnrss.org/bestcomments" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item><title>New comment by WA in "One-man campaign ravages EU 'Chat Control' bill"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I love it. Especially since:&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;&gt; The campaign has irked some recipients. “In terms of dialog within a democracy, this is not a dialog,” said Lena Düpont, a German member of the European People’s Party group and its home affairs spokesperson, of the mass emails.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;p&gt;It is a dialog. Millions are against it, a few (powerful people) in favor. The powerful are too detached from reality and consider this "not a dialog".&lt;p&gt;On a meta level, it even gives them a taste of the millions of messages that‘d get flagged false positively monthly, overwhelming police and other systems.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2025 20:15:58 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45520114</link><dc:creator>WA</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45520114</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45520114</guid></item><item><title>New comment by Aurornis in "Synology reverses policy banning third-party HDDs"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&gt; What is interesting here is that Synology leadership is quite technical&lt;p&gt;Vagueposting out of necessity: I worked at a different company that made popular consumer products and had leadership with technical backgrounds. That company also went through a period of trying to lock down the platform for profits, which everyone hated.&lt;p&gt;The root cause was that the technical leadership had started to think two things: That their customers were so loyal to the brand that they wouldn’t leave, and that the customers weren’t smart enough to recognize that the artificial restrictions had no real basis in reality.&lt;p&gt;I remember attending a meeting where the CEO bragged about a decision he made that arbitrarily worsened a product for consumers. He laughed that people still bought it and loved it. “Can you believe that? They’ll buy anything we tell them to.” was the paraphrased statement I remember.&lt;p&gt;Of course, the backlash came when they pushed too hard. Fortunately this company recognized what was going on and the CEO moved on to other matters, leaving product choices back to the teams. I wonder if something similar happened with Synology.&lt;p&gt;Regarding employee morale: It was very depressing for me during this period to open Hacker News and see threads complaining about my employer. I can confirm that it spurred a job search for me.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2025 14:00:01 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45516301</link><dc:creator>Aurornis</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45516301</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45516301</guid></item><item><title>New comment by cozzyd in "SEC approves Texas Stock Exchange, first new US integrated exchange in decades"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Hope they have ample backup power&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2025 12:14:27 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45515303</link><dc:creator>cozzyd</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45515303</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45515303</guid></item><item><title>New comment by 1gn15 in "One-man campaign ravages EU 'Chat Control' bill"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Thanks Joachim! Still frustrating that Politico still implies that the bill has any power to stop CSAM, given that everyone who wants to trade it will obviously just use another layer of encryption.&lt;p&gt;&gt; The campaign has irked some recipients. “In terms of dialog within a democracy, this is not a dialog,” said Lena Düpont, a German member of the European People’s Party group and its home affairs spokesperson, of the mass emails.&lt;p&gt;What is a dialog, then? A dialogue between well-connected lobbyists and bureaucrats, and everyone else should just shut up and take it?&lt;p&gt;Or, or, "normal people" sending emails only for the lawmakers to go "thanks for the feedback, we're doing it anyway"?&lt;p&gt;&gt; One EU diplomat said some EU member countries are now more hesitant to support Denmark’s proposal, at least in part because of the campaign: “There is a clear link.”&lt;p&gt;&gt; Ella Jakubowska, head of policy at digital rights group EDRi, said “This campaign seems to have raised the topic high up the agenda in member states where there was previously little to no public debate."&lt;p&gt;This is amazing, and makes me regain a bit of (much destroyed) faith in democracy.&lt;p&gt;&gt; But Danish Justice Minister Peter Hummelgaard, one of the loudest proponents of tough measures to get child abuse material off online platforms, said in a statement that his proposal is far more balanced than the Commission’s original version and would mean that scanning would only happen as a last resort.&lt;p&gt;If the option is there, it will be abused.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2025 11:26:05 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45514883</link><dc:creator>1gn15</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45514883</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45514883</guid></item><item><title>New comment by jacquesm in "Synology reverses policy banning third-party HDDs"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;What is interesting here is that Synology leadership is quite technical and there was no acquisition or other big event that I am aware of that resulted in this strategy. It was a complete own goal and as predictable as could be. Synology apparently wasn't aware of what their brand values were as perceived by their loyal customers and that's the kind of move you make at your peril. I'll be surprised if they survive this in the longer term, regardless of the reversal they've shown they do not have their customers interests at heart at all. It's dumber that it even seems: they were raking in a substantial amount of money precisely because of this one factor, and they pretty much shot the goose that was laying the golden eggs.&lt;p&gt;I've been a loyal customers of theirs and wasn't even looking at other options but there won't be another cent of mine going to Synology. I was already miffed at their mark-up for a little bit of memory before this happened. It is a matter of time before they crash and I don't want to end up with an unsupported piece of hardware. Trust is everything in the storage business.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2025 10:59:41 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45514686</link><dc:creator>jacquesm</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45514686</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45514686</guid></item><item><title>New comment by osivertsson in "Synology reverses policy banning third-party HDDs"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;When leadership makes decisions that are so out of touch with their customers it also severely impacts &lt;i&gt;internal&lt;/i&gt; morale.&lt;p&gt;Yeah, so they reversed eventually. But the technical and support people at Synology probably tried to fight this and lost. That feeling of being ignored despite having given this company your everything for many years. I bet many woke up feeling that the magic that made Synology a good place to work is gone.&lt;p&gt;My guess is they will continue to lose the most valuable employees unless they replace management with some internally well-respected staff that understands their customers well.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2025 09:01:23 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45513826</link><dc:creator>osivertsson</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45513826</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45513826</guid></item><item><title>New comment by simonw in "Vibe engineering"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I'm really sorry to hear this, because part of my goal here is to help push back against the idea that "programming skills are useless now, anyone can get an LLM to write code for them".&lt;p&gt;I think existing software development skills get a whole lot &lt;i&gt;more&lt;/i&gt; valuable with the addition of coding agents. You can take everything you've learned up to this point and accelerate the impact you can have with this new family of tools.&lt;p&gt;I said a version of this in the post:&lt;p&gt;&gt; AI tools &lt;i&gt;amplify existing expertise&lt;/i&gt;. The more skills and experience you have as a software engineer the faster and better the results you can get from working with LLMs and coding agents.&lt;p&gt;A brand new vibe coder may be able to get a cool UI out of ChatGPT, but they're not going to be able to rig up a set of automated tests with continuous integration and continuous deployment to a Kubernetes cluster somewhere. They're also not going to be able to direct three different agents at once in different areas of a large project that they've designed the architecture for.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2025 05:03:05 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45512258</link><dc:creator>simonw</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45512258</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45512258</guid></item><item><title>New comment by subarctic in "Vibe engineering"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I just feel so discouraged reading this somehow. I used to have this hard-to-get, in-demand skill that paid lots of money and felt like even though programming languages, libraries and web frameworks were always evolving I could always keep up because I'm smart. But now with these people like Simon Willison writing about the new way of coding with these agents and multiple streams of work going on at a time and it sounding like this is the future, I just feel discouraged because it sounds like so much work and I've tried using coding agents and they help a bit, but I find it way less fun to be waiting around for agents to do stuff and it's way harder to get into flow state managing multiple of these things. It makes me want to move into something completely different like sales&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2025 04:32:25 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45512098</link><dc:creator>subarctic</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45512098</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45512098</guid></item><item><title>New comment by thinkingkong in "Canadian bill would strip internet access from 'specified persons', no warrant"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;The argument made here seems to be that the power to prevent unlawful access or threats is somehow required to keep us all safe. But if someone was an actual threat, do we really think they’d be using the internet with their own identity? Like if someone is willing to hack into a power station or some other critical infrastructure, they’ll be simultaneously stupid enough to use their own credit card?&lt;p&gt;Illegal things are already illegal. Safety and security mechanisms already exist. We dont need additional, punitive, and opaque laws that can be abused.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 20:50:33 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45508688</link><dc:creator>thinkingkong</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45508688</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45508688</guid></item><item><title>New comment by nick__m in "Canadian bill would strip internet access from 'specified persons', no warrant"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I tought that the National Post was exaggerating the severity in their crusade against the Liberal like they frequently do. So I when to read the law and it's as bad as they say:  &lt;a href="https://www.parl.ca/DocumentViewer/en/45-1/bill/C-8/first-reading" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://www.parl.ca/DocumentViewer/en/45-1/bill/C-8/first-re...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;  ...
    Factor 
    Before making the order, the Governor in Council must consider

    (a) its operational impact on the affected telecommunications service providers;

    (b) its financial impact on the affected telecommunications service providers;

    (c) its effect on the provision of telecommunications services in Canada; and

    (d) any other factor that the Governor in Council considers relevant.

  ...
    No compensation
  
  (8) No one is entitled to any compensation from His Majesty in right of Canada       for any financial losses resulting from the making of an order under subsection  (1).&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 20:41:30 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45508568</link><dc:creator>nick__m</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45508568</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45508568</guid></item><item><title>New comment by ho_schi in "German government comes out against Chat Control"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;The CDU/CSU is doing something good. That didn't happened for a long time? I appreciate it.&lt;p&gt;Ausgerechnet Spahn. Manchmal glaubt man seinen Augen und Ohren nicht.
Wir müssen Wachsam bleiben. Mit dem Argument das es böse Menschen gibt, wurde schon viel böses getan. Massenüberwachung zerstört jede Gesellschaft. Deutschland hat mehrfach darunter gelitten. Und die Versuche Massenüberwachung einzuführen wiederholen sich.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 20:14:49 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45508251</link><dc:creator>ho_schi</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45508251</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45508251</guid></item><item><title>New comment by chaps in "Police Said They Surveilled Woman Who Had an Abortion for Her 'Safety.'"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;A lot of folk tried to justify the situation as being not as bad as it sounded, citing the official narrative as a source of truth.&lt;p&gt;It's amazing to me that people will still trust police narratives.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 16:24:13 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45505173</link><dc:creator>chaps</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45505173</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45505173</guid></item><item><title>New comment by observationist in "Microsoft is plugging more holes that let you use Windows 11 without MS account"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Companies that cannot run their businesses responsibly at scale should not be allowed to run their business at that scale.&lt;p&gt;If Microsoft can't do it, if Apple, Google, Facebook, X , OpenAI can't do it, then maybe we shouldn't allow companies to operate at scales which inevitably lead to widespread consumer harm.&lt;p&gt;They should be required to provide human customer service, with some sort of legal liability to ensure their products perform as advertised, without an end-user having to spend tens or hundreds of hours chasing down a solution, spending thousands of dollars on a lawyer, and all the rest of the hassle.&lt;p&gt;This is a legislation and regulation issue - the data barons are exploiting the effective absence of any accountability for harms they casually inflict on the public, ranging from gotcha situations like the OP to viral self harm trends among kids to mass surveillance and commercial invasion of privacy.&lt;p&gt;Pirate everything, support open source, pay content creators directly.&lt;p&gt;If they want to have billions of users, they damn well better be able to handle each and every one of those users in a commercially responsible fashion, or they have no business operating at that scale. We should be done with the "oops, we're too big and we make too much money to care that we just casually wrecked your life, oh well!" If the solution is to force users to have to buy a new PC, or a new phone, or create a new account, or anything in that vein, it's almost intentional, and casually malicious.&lt;p&gt;It's not like these companies don't know what they're doing, they can simply afford not to care. Until there's regulation and accountability that's more expensive than ignoring the consumer casualties, things will continue to get worse.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 16:00:04 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45504830</link><dc:creator>observationist</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45504830</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45504830</guid></item><item><title>New comment by wseqyrku in "Who needs Git when you have 1M context windows?"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;"Who needs git when [..]"&lt;p&gt;No matter how that sentence ends, I weep for our industry.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 15:39:05 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45504527</link><dc:creator>wseqyrku</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45504527</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45504527</guid></item><item><title>New comment by Night_Thastus in "Microsoft is plugging more holes that let you use Windows 11 without MS account"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;My biggest annoyance is that I specifically bought a Windows 11 license, from the MS store, using my MS account. I did this because I assumed that if something went wrong, I would always be able to recover it. I could never 'lose' the key if it was tied to my account.&lt;p&gt;Well unfortunately, MS screwed me. When I upgraded my PC I was apparently supposed to transfer the license before deleting the old PC from my account. Doing it in the wrong order lost the license forever - no way to transfer it.&lt;p&gt;Despite having one license, one account, and one PC registered, MS refused to help. I tried to call support, but there are NO on-call support anymore. Only automated online support. No chat. Nothing. I tried over and over for a couple days and got nowhere.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 15:19:39 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45504231</link><dc:creator>Night_Thastus</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45504231</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45504231</guid></item><item><title>New comment by magtux in "Qualcomm to acquire Arduino"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;This is a recipe for disaster. Arduino is great for education/tinkering. Qualcomm won't sell you anything even if you are ready to commit to buying 1000s. I tried to source some Qualcomm chips for a startup @ 10k qty and was told there would be no information or support. Qualcomm can have a much bigger market if they simply open up some product lines for distribution like MediaTek do.&lt;p&gt;China has a way more vibrant, innovative hardware industry simply because you can source everything made by Chinese firms.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 14:04:45 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45503202</link><dc:creator>magtux</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45503202</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45503202</guid></item><item><title>New comment by phoehne in "Qualcomm to acquire Arduino"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Don't look at just the specs.  You also need to look at the board design and programming environment.  I've used the ESP32 native tools and they are a lot more complex than Arduino.  But I'm an embedded firmware developer, so it's kind of what I expect.  But I used an Arduino, with 5V tolerant outputs, to light up Halloween costumes for years.  I do it in 1 page of code that's I write in their IDE.  I don't have to set up an SDK.  And the Arudino API hides all the details I don't care about.  Especially if I'm really just slinging solder and wiring something up quick.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 13:46:53 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45503017</link><dc:creator>phoehne</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45503017</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45503017</guid></item><item><title>New comment by chpatrick in "Qualcomm to acquire Arduino"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;ESP stuff is so damn cheap and capable now I'm not sure what you would use Arduino for these days.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 13:34:12 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45502871</link><dc:creator>chpatrick</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45502871</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45502871</guid></item><item><title>New comment by murillians in "Qualcomm to acquire Arduino"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I only feel dread when I see a Qualcomm story on HN anymore.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 13:20:18 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45502731</link><dc:creator>murillians</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45502731</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45502731</guid></item><item><title>New comment by geerlingguy in "Qualcomm to acquire Arduino"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Additionally, they're launching their first joint product, the $44 Uno Q SBC, which has a Dragonwing SoC and STM32 microcontroller on an Uno form factor board[1].&lt;p&gt;It seems like Arduino will keep their brand, maintain their existing product lines, and continue building devices using other vendor's chips (besides Qualcomm), etc... but as with all acquisitions—I wonder how long that state of affairs will last.&lt;p&gt;Alternatives like the Pi RP2040/2350 and Espressif's vast selection of boards can fill the gaps, but Arduino was what got me and many people I know into microcontrollers, so I have a special fondness for them!&lt;p&gt;[1] &lt;a href="https://www.arduino.cc/product-uno-q" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://www.arduino.cc/product-uno-q&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 13:19:19 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45502719</link><dc:creator>geerlingguy</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45502719</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45502719</guid></item><item><title>New comment by trollbridge in "Deloitte to refund the Australian government after using AI in $440k report"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;For a bit of background, this report concerned a problematic IT system that was incorrectly sending life-ruining fines to people for not meeting their requirements to apply for so many jobs, accept jobs, etc. whilst on government assistance. The fines came in the form of a judgment debt so people would literally have a debt bailiff show up and start carting their property away. Due to a seriously flawed IT system, this even happened to people who weren't on any government benefits at all.&lt;p&gt;So, a report gets commissioned that a company like Deloitte gets paid $440k for, and then they cheat and use AI to generate it, complete with more errors. Imagine what would happen if they retained Deloitte next to build the system. I foresee another repeat of the Fujitsu Royal Mail scandal.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 13:00:16 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45502542</link><dc:creator>trollbridge</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45502542</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45502542</guid></item><item><title>New comment by decimalenough in "Deloitte to refund the Australian government after using AI in $440k report"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;From my experience with using a $WITCH for a large support engagement, the A team woos you, the B team is what you get initially, and as soon as they think you've got your eye off the ball, they swap in the Z team.&lt;p&gt;This was for a contract where we made it very clear that quality/skill was paramount and we would happily &lt;i&gt;pay above market rates forever&lt;/i&gt; if they could maintain it. Of course they got greedy and lost the deal entirely.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 10:50:44 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45501549</link><dc:creator>decimalenough</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45501549</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45501549</guid></item><item><title>New comment by stephenlf in "The least amount of CSS for a decent looking site (2023)"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Kevin Powell makes wonderful content. I am saddened by the negative responses here. This article is a great intro for the absolute beginner to dip their toes into CSS.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 10:34:15 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45501426</link><dc:creator>stephenlf</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45501426</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45501426</guid></item><item><title>New comment by stavros in "A mechanic offered a reason why no one wants to work in the industry"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Every single time someone says "there's a shortage of &lt;profession&gt;", you can mentally substitute it for "we can't get &lt;profession&gt; for cheap".&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 09:38:40 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45501130</link><dc:creator>stavros</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45501130</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45501130</guid></item><item><title>New comment by potamic in "California law forces Netflix, Hulu to turn down ad volumes"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;It's sad that such a thing needs regulation in the first place. In real life if a salesman is being inconsiderate, I'll go out of my way to avoid their sales and find someone else who is better mannered. But we don't seem to apply the same measure to ads. Ads can be brash, insulting and manipulative, and yet that doesn't seem to cause a negative outcome for them. Rather it appears such ads work better and now that's what everyone's pushing towards. Human psychology is such a weird thing.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 06:29:36 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45499970</link><dc:creator>potamic</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45499970</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45499970</guid></item><item><title>New comment by mythz in "Microsoft is plugging more holes that let you use Windows 11 without MS account"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;The best thing to happen to Linux Desktop is Windows 11, with perfect timing too as modern Linux has been a joy to use as a daily driver.&lt;p&gt;Normally I'd be unhappy when a sleazy corp forces me to give up on 25 years of muscle memory of using my preferred OS, but I'm thankful they gave me the push I needed to rip off the ad/spyware laced Windows Band-Aid that I only need to do once in my life.&lt;p&gt;It's been over a year since I switched to Linux which has been a breath of fresh-air,  all my dev tools work natively, the console is far superior and I'm still able to play all my favorite Steam games.&lt;p&gt;Best of all I'm not reminded daily that I'm using an OS that works against my best interests, I can actually use an App Store again that's been designed for the benefit of its Users, imagine that.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 05:53:21 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45499783</link><dc:creator>mythz</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45499783</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45499783</guid></item><item><title>New comment by windows2020 in "Microsoft is plugging more holes that let you use Windows 11 without MS account"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Not sure Microsoft realizes the damage they're doing to the Windows brand. My first experience with Windows 11 was figuring out some dumb workaround to use a local account.&lt;p&gt;When I think back to Windows 7, the good feeling isn't nostalgia. It was the last user-focused Windows.&lt;p&gt;Maybe someone will develop a new user-focused OS that's somehow compatible with Windows programs. Or better yet, maybe Microsoft will realize very important parts of Windows are going downhill and remember what made Windows great.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 01:12:12 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45498304</link><dc:creator>windows2020</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45498304</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45498304</guid></item><item><title>New comment by onoesworkacct in "Why did Crunchyroll's subtitles just get worse?"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;How many customers watch each episode of popular shows? 100k+?&lt;p&gt;And we're talking a difference of ~7 hours of labor. $200 difference at most?&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 00:45:15 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45498093</link><dc:creator>onoesworkacct</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45498093</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45498093</guid></item><item><title>New comment by bonecrusher2102 in "Why did Crunchyroll's subtitles just get worse?"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Hah, this is my time to shine. I worked in anime subtitling and timing for a number of years. I helped write our style guide — things like how to handle signs, overlapping dialogue, colors etc.&lt;p&gt;It wound up being quite a large document!&lt;p&gt;But the thing to realize here is that, all of these subs have to be placed by hand. There are AI tools that can help you match in and out times, but they have a difficult time matching English subs to Japanese dialogue. So what you have to do is have a human with some small grasp of Japanese place each of these in/out times by hand.&lt;p&gt;If you’re &lt;i&gt;really&lt;/i&gt; good you can do one 25 minute episode in about 35 minutes. But that’s ONLY if you don’t spend any extra time coloring and moving the subs around the screen (as you would song and sign captions).&lt;p&gt;Elite tier subs can take up to two or even three or four hours per episode. That’s why the best subs, are always fan subs! Because a business will never put in 8x more time on an episodes subtitles than “bare minimum.”&lt;p&gt;Crunchy roll looks to have at least gone halfway for a while… but multiply those times across thousands of episodes over X years… and you can see why some manager somewhere finally decided 35 minutes was good enough.&lt;p&gt;I am in the Product world now, and I do think this was a bad move. Anime fans LOVE anime. The level of customer delight (and hate) in the anime industry is like no other. I really miss the excitement that my customers would get (and happily telegraph!) when I launched a product in those days. Which is all to say, you HAVE to factor delight into your product. Especially with a super fan base like you have in anime.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 00:20:52 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45497900</link><dc:creator>bonecrusher2102</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45497900</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45497900</guid></item><item><title>New comment by ashirviskas in "Who owns Express VPN, Nord, Surfshark? VPN relationships explained (2024)"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Don't forget ProtonVPN links to Tesonet, which they're trying hard to "debunk" (though no clue why, I have nothing against Tesonet). They only shared employees and accidentally signed apps with the same certificates, but are "totally unrelated". Their PR people are already on this thread.&lt;p&gt;If they didn't try so hard to fight it, people might care less.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 23:24:40 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45497454</link><dc:creator>ashirviskas</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45497454</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45497454</guid></item></channel></rss>