<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>Hacker News: Best Comments</title><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/bestcomments</link><description>Hacker News RSS</description><docs>https://hnrss.org/</docs><generator>hnrss v2.1.1</generator><lastBuildDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 00:05:25 +0000</lastBuildDate><ns0:link href="https://hnrss.org/bestcomments" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item><title>New comment by antirez in "Fabrice Bellard Releases MicroQuickJS"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;If this had been available in 2010, Redis scripting would have been JavaScript and not Lua. Lua was chosen based on the implementation requirements, not on the language ones... (small, fast, ANSI-C). I appreciate certain ideas in Lua, and people love it, but I was never able to &lt;i&gt;like&lt;/i&gt; Lua, because it departs from a more Algol-like syntax and semantics without good reasons, for my taste. This creates friction for newcomers. I love friction when it opens new useful ideas and abstractions that are worth it, if you learn SmallTalk or FORTH and for some time you are lost, it's part of how the languages are different. But I think for Lua this is not true enough: it feels like it departs from what people know without good reasons.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 19:49:27 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46368706</link><dc:creator>antirez</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46368706</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46368706</guid></item><item><title>New comment by groundzeros2015 in "Fabrice Bellard Releases MicroQuickJS"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;For all the praise he gets here, few seem interested in his methods: writing complete programs, based on robust computer science, with minimal dependencies and tooling.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 19:13:23 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46368341</link><dc:creator>groundzeros2015</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46368341</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46368341</guid></item><item><title>New comment by pizlonator in "Fabrice Bellard Releases MicroQuickJS"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;This engine restricts JS in all of the ways I wished I could restrict the language back when I was working on JSC.&lt;p&gt;You can’t restrict JS that way on the web because of compatibility. But I totally buy that restricting it this way for embedded systems will result in something that sparks joy&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 18:41:14 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46367946</link><dc:creator>pizlonator</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46367946</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46367946</guid></item><item><title>New comment by InsideOutSanta in "How did DOGE disrupt so much while saving so little?"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Perhaps because disrupting things was the actual goal, rather than saving money. DOGE was highly effective in harming the entities meant to oversee Musk's companies, stealing information about union organizing and labor complaints, reducing the government's ability to collect taxes, and destroying its regulatory capacity.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 18:11:14 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46367611</link><dc:creator>InsideOutSanta</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46367611</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46367611</guid></item><item><title>New comment by Fiveplus in "Meta is using the Linux scheduler designed for Valve's Steam Deck on its servers"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Valve is practically singlehandedly dragging the Linux ecosystem forward in areas that nobody else wanted to touch.&lt;p&gt;They needed Windows games to run on Linux so we got massive Proton/Wine advancements. They needed better display output for the deck and we got HDR and VRR support in wayland. They also needed smoother frame pacing and we got a scheduler that Zuck is now using to run data centers.&lt;p&gt;Its funny to think that Meta's server efficiency is being improved because Valve paid Igalia to make Elden Ring stutter less on a portable Linux PC. This is the best kind of open source trickledown.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 17:46:01 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46367336</link><dc:creator>Fiveplus</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46367336</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46367336</guid></item><item><title>New comment by ZeroCool2u in "Meta is using the Linux scheduler designed for Valve's Steam Deck on its servers"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Igalia is a bit unique as it serves as a single corporate entity for organizing a lot of sponsored work on the Linux kernel and open source projects. You'll notice in their blog posts they have collaborations with a number of other large companies seeking to sponsor very specific development work. For example, Google works with them a lot. I think it really just simplifies a lot of logistics for paying folks to do this kind of work, plus the Igalia employees can get shared efficiency's and savings for things like benefits etc.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 17:37:14 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46367263</link><dc:creator>ZeroCool2u</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46367263</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46367263</guid></item><item><title>New comment by gmd63 in "Inside CECOT – 60 Minutes [video]"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Larry Ellison is using his bags to purchase lies and silence.&lt;p&gt;No economy can be in true equilibrium when the consumers send profits to be spent in unforeseen and unrelated ways like this. Every purchase carries potentially immense future costs that are almost completely opaque.&lt;p&gt;Free market maximalists need to confront this fact before praying at the altar of complete deregulation, and every consumer should pay more attention to who they are buying from.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 16:18:18 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46366530</link><dc:creator>gmd63</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46366530</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46366530</guid></item><item><title>New comment by evan_ in "Inside CECOT – 60 Minutes [video]"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;The whole thing is poorly-conceived and obviously false but I just have to call this out-&lt;p&gt;&gt; Of the 252 Venezuelans sent to CECOT, we say nearly half have no criminal histories. In other words, more than half do have criminal histories. We should spend a beat explaining this.&lt;p&gt;The story isn't that people found guilty of crimes went to jail, the story is that half weren't even charged with crimes! That's the whole point of the story! We should not be aiming for a balanced diet of criminals and not-criminals in our government-sponsored foreign death camps!&lt;p&gt;The fact that they exist at all is an affront to humanity, but to say "it's OK because a slim majority &lt;i&gt;deserve&lt;/i&gt; it"- I just don't know what to say.&lt;p&gt;&gt; We then say that only 8 of the 252 have been sentenced in America for violent offenses. But what about charged?&lt;p&gt;What about charged? What does charged with a crime have to do with anything? Why bring that up at all? Do we send people to prison because they were charged with a crime? Is Bari Weiss a newborn baby who has never heard about the presumption of innocence?&lt;p&gt;I feel sick.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 15:04:55 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46365815</link><dc:creator>evan_</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46365815</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46365815</guid></item><item><title>New comment by dcminter in "Ryanair fined €256M over ‘abusive strategy’ to limit ticket sales by OTAs"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;"O’Leary accused the travel agent industry of scamming and ripping off unsuspecting consumers by charging extra fees and markups on ticket prices."&lt;/i&gt;&lt;p&gt;That is ... pretty rich.&lt;p&gt;A couple of years ago I was going to go see my brother in the UK who lived near Stansted. As such Ryanair would have been the most convenient airline. The shere number of dark patterns I encountered trying to book the ticket was such that when  I got to the payment page and they tried to coax me into using my local currency instead of GBP and hid a £20 spread in the exchange rate I rage quit. I should have known better even then, but now I will only use them if I have literally no other choice. With luck that means "never."&lt;p&gt;I'm always happy to see the various EU competition authorities pushing back on this kind of thing.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 11:26:19 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46364427</link><dc:creator>dcminter</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46364427</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46364427</guid></item><item><title>New comment by Doches in "10 years bootstrapped: €6.5M revenue with a team of 13"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&gt; We're not bragging (okay, we're bragging a little) but it turns out that not burning through VC cash on ping-pong tables and "growth at all costs" actually works.&lt;p&gt;Have an internet fist-bump from a fellow successful bootstrapper; this is the way, and you're calling it out!&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 10:57:25 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46364290</link><dc:creator>Doches</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46364290</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46364290</guid></item><item><title>New comment by isodev in "iOS 26.3 brings AirPods-like pairing to third-party devices in EU under DMA"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;It’s fascinating the kind of cool features we can have when products are made to be useful, with their target user in mind. Go EU!&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 08:16:57 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46363454</link><dc:creator>isodev</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46363454</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46363454</guid></item><item><title>New comment by UncleMeat in "Inside CECOT – 60 Minutes [video]"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Weiss got her &lt;i&gt;start&lt;/i&gt; screaming about how various college professors should be fired. There has never once been a moment in her career where she seriously cared about open debate.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 02:47:46 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46361869</link><dc:creator>UncleMeat</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46361869</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46361869</guid></item><item><title>New comment by cdrnsf in "Inside CECOT – 60 Minutes [video]"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;She was hired following the acquisition of Paramount to do things exactly like this. She's not a journalist.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 01:08:20 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46361258</link><dc:creator>cdrnsf</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46361258</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46361258</guid></item><item><title>New comment by slg in "Inside CECOT – 60 Minutes [video]"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I'm reminded of the Letter on Justice and Open Debate[1] that Bari Weiss signed only a few years ago, now she's spiking stories like this one on CECOT for showing the current administration in a negative light.&lt;p&gt;I also wonder if this story will get the type of leeway to stay on HN to collect the 200+ upvotes and 300+ comments of that previous example or if it will be flagged off the front page within minutes like so many other similar stories.&lt;p&gt;EDIT: No idea how long this post actually lasted, but checking in an hour later to see this has been flagged completely off the first 10 pages of HN despite getting close to that 200 point total.&lt;p&gt;[1] - &lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=23759283"&gt;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=23759283&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 01:06:14 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46361248</link><dc:creator>slg</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46361248</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46361248</guid></item><item><title>New comment by scratchyone in "Inside CECOT – 60 Minutes [video]"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I have a feeling this will get DMCA-ed off of Internet Archive in an attempt to suppress it. Here's the infohash of the archive.org torrent download for future reference, this should allow the file to be retrieved in any torrent client as long as someone in the world is seeding it still.&lt;p&gt;8105370ed7dba50dc7ec659fd67550569b4dd8a0&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 00:55:58 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46361169</link><dc:creator>scratchyone</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46361169</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46361169</guid></item><item><title>New comment by dogman144 in "Flock Exposed Its AI-Powered Cameras to the Internet. We Tracked Ourselves"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Was fortunate to talk to a security lead who built the data-driven policing network for a major American city that was an early adopter. ALPR vendors like Flock either heavily augment and/or anchor the tech setups.&lt;p&gt;What was notable to me is the following, and it’s why I think a career spent on either security researching, or going to law school and suing, these vendors into the ground over 20 years would be the ultimate act of civil service:&lt;p&gt;1. It’s not just Flock cams. It’s the data eng into these networks - 18 wheeler feed cams, flock cams, retail user nest cams, traffic cams, ISP data sales&lt;p&gt;2. All in one hub, all searchable by your local PD and also the local PD across state lines who doesn’t like your abortion/marijuana/gun/whatever laws, and relying on:&lt;p&gt;3. The PD to setup and maintain proper RBAC in a nationwide surveillance network that is 100%, for sure, no doubt about it (wait how did that Texas cop track the abortion into Indiana/Illinois…?), configured for least privilege.&lt;p&gt;4. Or if the PD doesn’t want flock in town, they reinstall cameras against the ruling (Illinois iirc?) or just say “we have the feeds for the DoT cameras in/out of town and the truckers through town so might as well have control over it, PD!”&lt;p&gt;Layer the above with the current trend in the US, and 2025 model Nissan uploading stop-by-stop geolocation and telematics to cloud (then, sold into flock? Does even knowing for sure if it does or doesn’t even matter?)&lt;p&gt;Very bad line of companies. Again all is from primary sources who helped implement it over the years. If you spend enough time at cybersecurity conferences you’ll meet people with these jobs.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 23:42:16 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46360624</link><dc:creator>dogman144</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46360624</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46360624</guid></item><item><title>New comment by gardncl in "US blocks all offshore wind construction, says reason is classified"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;US deploys nuclear energy at over $10/watt meanwhile solar and wind are deployed around $2/watt (for levelized cost of electricity) including battery storage which means they are deployed for roughly the same cost as natural gas (so, direct competitors).&lt;p&gt;Don't let comments like this fool you, nuclear is far from being competitive with natural gas. Even in countries like south korea that can deploy nuclear the cheapest it's still $3/watt roughly.&lt;p&gt;Good news? Net new solar and wind plants can come "online" in less than two years. Net new natural gas takes four years. Part of why 95% of new energy deployed last year were renewables in the US, not just the subsidies.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 20:48:54 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46358871</link><dc:creator>gardncl</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46358871</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46358871</guid></item><item><title>New comment by beembeem in "US blocks all offshore wind construction, says reason is classified"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Result first (kill anything not carbon-based), find rationale later.&lt;p&gt;Same applies to how this admin forced layoffs at the green energy (hydro + nuclear) behemoth BPA [1] (which was funded entirely by ratepayers, not the federal government) then claimed an energy emergency to keep open coal plants serving the same geographies, coal plants that were already uneconomical and planned for shut down (or re-tooling to gas in the case of TransAlta's plant in WA). [2] Oh and they already re-hired some of the laid off staff at BPA because they overcut.&lt;p&gt;There is no point in taking these arguments at face value. It's an excuse generated after-the-fact, and in service of one outcome - kill renewable energy.&lt;p&gt;[1] &lt;a href="https://www.columbian.com/news/2025/mar/12/letter-cuts-at-bpa-generate-questions/" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://www.columbian.com/news/2025/mar/12/letter-cuts-at-bp...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;[2] &lt;a href="https://www.seattletimes.com/seattle-news/climate-lab/doe-orders-wa-coal-plant-to-continue-operating-despite-state-ban/" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://www.seattletimes.com/seattle-news/climate-lab/doe-or...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 20:24:43 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46358587</link><dc:creator>beembeem</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46358587</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46358587</guid></item><item><title>New comment by JohnTHaller in "US blocks all offshore wind construction, says reason is classified"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;We've been in the realm of intentionally doing damage for a while now. But we got these cool red hats.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 20:19:45 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46358519</link><dc:creator>JohnTHaller</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46358519</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46358519</guid></item><item><title>New comment by linuxhansl in "US blocks all offshore wind construction, says reason is classified"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;What the... It seems we crossed into the realm of intentionally doing damage.
I'm reminded of threatening tariffs to successfully derail global carbon levy on ship emissions.&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile China runs away with all the clean energy tech (solar, wind, batteries, etc, etc.) while we hold to fossil fuels to save less than 200,000 jobs.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 20:13:22 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46358445</link><dc:creator>linuxhansl</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46358445</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46358445</guid></item><item><title>New comment by tony_cannistra in "US blocks all offshore wind construction, says reason is classified"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I looked into this a little because I was curious. I guess the ostensible "national security" rationale (which clearly is not the only reason!) for this is that turbines severely degrade the utility of radar surveillance along the coastlines.&lt;p&gt;This is particularly relevant for low-altitude incursions and drones.&lt;p&gt;Now, other large governments (UK) have resolved this in several ways, including the deployment of additional radars on and within the turbine farms themselves.&lt;p&gt;So clearly this is politically motivated, and they're using what seems to be a real but solveable concern as a scapegoat.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 20:09:26 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46358405</link><dc:creator>tony_cannistra</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46358405</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46358405</guid></item><item><title>New comment by jjwiseman in "Flock Exposed Its AI-Powered Cameras to the Internet. We Tracked Ourselves"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;The CEO of Flock, Garrett Langley, called Deflock a terrorist group. It's unhinged. &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=l-kZGrDz7PU" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=l-kZGrDz7PU&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 19:28:06 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46357850</link><dc:creator>jjwiseman</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46357850</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46357850</guid></item><item><title>New comment by spullara in "Claude Code gets native LSP support"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I really can't understand why JetBrains hasn't integrated its refactoring tools into the AI system. Really missed the boat on making their platform transformational for AI coding. Imagine how much smaller the context would be for a tool that renames a function than editing hundreds of files. This LSP support is a good start but without the mutation functions it is still pretty lackluster. Plus LSPs aren't as good as JetBrains generally.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 18:41:33 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46357226</link><dc:creator>spullara</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46357226</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46357226</guid></item><item><title>New comment by kklisura in "Flock Exposed Its AI-Powered Cameras to the Internet. We Tracked Ourselves"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;For more context here Flock Safety is a YC-backed company [1][2]&lt;p&gt;[1] &lt;a href="https://www.ycombinator.com/companies/flock-safety"&gt;https://www.ycombinator.com/companies/flock-safety&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;[2] &lt;a href="https://x.com/garrytan/status/1856016868580151615" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://x.com/garrytan/status/1856016868580151615&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 18:17:52 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46356914</link><dc:creator>kklisura</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46356914</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46356914</guid></item><item><title>New comment by bane in "The U.S. Is Funding Fewer Grants in Every Area of Science and Medicine"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;The people I know who work in life sciences R&amp;D (basically anything bio) have had their funding absolutely annihilated. PhDs with 20 years of experience working second jobs as substitute high school teachers, lab workers taking up tech support positions paying a fraction of what was already terrible pay.&lt;p&gt;What's worse is that in &lt;i&gt;most&lt;/i&gt; of these fields, you don't really even &lt;i&gt;start&lt;/i&gt; working until after your PhD.&lt;p&gt;4 years is going to be a long time to underfund what's basically 4 entire classes of researchers coming out of Doctorate programs. It might take decades to recover our research programs.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 17:04:30 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46355979</link><dc:creator>bane</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46355979</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46355979</guid></item><item><title>New comment by edot in "Flock Exposed Its AI-Powered Cameras to the Internet. We Tracked Ourselves"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Flock or their defenders will lock in on the excuse that “oh these are misconfigured” or “yeah hacking is illegal, only cops should have this data”. The issue is neither of the above. The issue is the collection and collation of this footage in the first place! I don’t want hackers watching me all the time, sure, but I DEFINITELY don’t trust the state or megacorps to watch me all the time. Hackers concern me less, actually. I’m glad that Benn Jordan and others are giving this the airtime it needs, but they’re focusing the messaging on security vulnerabilities and not state surveillance. Thus Flock can go “ok we will do better about security” and the bureaucrats, average suburbanites, and law enforcement agencies will go “ok good they fixed the vulnerabilities I’m happy now”&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 16:54:08 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46355859</link><dc:creator>edot</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46355859</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46355859</guid></item><item><title>New comment by jsheard in "The biggest CRT ever made: Sony's PVM-4300"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Don't sleep on that Shank Mods video linked at the end, it's insane that he managed to pull that off.&lt;p&gt;He also made a second video (not linked) which shows off more of the actual hardware.&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Dgkw3uu19V8" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Dgkw3uu19V8&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 13:36:06 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46353992</link><dc:creator>jsheard</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46353992</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46353992</guid></item><item><title>New comment by sandebert in "Programming languages used for music"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Switch Angel live-code using Strudel. Really impressive and interesting stuff.&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://youtu.be/aPsq5nqvhxg" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://youtu.be/aPsq5nqvhxg&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 12:00:43 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46353493</link><dc:creator>sandebert</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46353493</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46353493</guid></item><item><title>New comment by Swizec in "If you don't design your career, someone else will (2014)"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;My favorite lens on this comes from Hamming:&lt;p&gt;&gt; It is well known the drunken sailor whos taggers to the left or right n independent random steps will, on the average, end up about sqrt(n) steps from the origin. But if there is a pretty girl in one direction, then his steps will tend to go in that direction and he will go a distance proportional to n. In a lifetime of many, many independent choices, small and large, a career with a vision will get you a distance proportional to n, while no vision will get you only the distance sqrt(n). In a sense, the main difference between those who go far and those who do not is some people have a vision and others do not and therefore can only react to the current events as they happen.&lt;p&gt;Just a tiny bit of bias towards a direction will get you very far very fast.&lt;p&gt;I once modeled+visualised this with a bit of javascript[1] and it's quite surprising to see the huge difference from even a tiny multiplication factor on each random/probabilistic decision.&lt;p&gt;[1] &lt;a href="https://swizec.com/blog/your-career-needs-a-vision/" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://swizec.com/blog/your-career-needs-a-vision/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 11:08:41 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46353187</link><dc:creator>Swizec</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46353187</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46353187</guid></item><item><title>New comment by gkoberger in "Disney Imagineering Debuts Next-Generation Robotic Character, Olaf"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;This is cool, but it will almost definitely never end up in a park, outside of some promotional situations.&lt;p&gt;Disney's been doing awesome work with "Living Characters", like a Mickey that moves his mouth or a BB-8 that can roll around. But for various reasons, they never tend to make it into regular usage.&lt;p&gt;If you have a few hours over Christmas break and want to watch a 4 hour YouTube video (I promise if you're on HN on a Sunday, you'll be delighted by it), I highly highly recommend this video:&lt;p&gt;"Disney's Living Characters: A Broken Promise" by Defunctland 
&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=NyIgV84fudM" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=NyIgV84fudM&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 21 Dec 2025 23:10:05 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46349591</link><dc:creator>gkoberger</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46349591</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46349591</guid></item></channel></rss>