<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>Hacker News: Best Comments</title><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/bestcomments</link><description>Hacker News RSS</description><docs>https://hnrss.org/</docs><generator>hnrss v2.1.1</generator><lastBuildDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2025 00:05:29 +0000</lastBuildDate><ns0:link href="https://hnrss.org/bestcomments" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item><title>New comment by lyricaljoke in "Just use a button"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;My very similar pet peeve is about websites that use `onclick` handlers and similar to implement navigation.  Just use a damn anchor tag, which gets you correct link behavior for free:&lt;p&gt;* works with middle click for new tab&lt;p&gt;* integrates with accessibility devices&lt;p&gt;* works with right click + open in new window or similar options&lt;p&gt;* etc. etc. etc.&lt;p&gt;If it's notionally navigation, don't use javascript soup: use a link.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2025 18:27:02 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45775130</link><dc:creator>lyricaljoke</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45775130</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45775130</guid></item><item><title>New comment by mentalgear in "Another European agency shifts off US Tech as digital sovereignty gains steam"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Why would ANY global business still rely on U.S. Tech? The U.S. government, through their executive orders and dissolving of the separations of powers, has demonstrated its ability to unilaterally disrupt or shut down private technology services at will. How can any business justify depending on U.S.-based tech infrastructure when its access could vanish overnight on a political whim by an unstable president?&lt;p&gt;If there is no rule of law, capital, talent and trust are flowing out of that country - for good reason.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2025 17:38:19 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45774588</link><dc:creator>mentalgear</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45774588</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45774588</guid></item><item><title>New comment by earless1 in "Attention lapses due to sleep deprivation due to flushing fluid from brain"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;So biological garbage collection pauses then? skip sleep, and the brain tries to run gc cycles during runtime. Causing attention and performance latency spikes. Evolution wrote the original JVM.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2025 14:40:32 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45772465</link><dc:creator>earless1</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45772465</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45772465</guid></item><item><title>New comment by jacquesm in "How OpenAI uses complex and circular deals to fuel its multibillion-dollar rise"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;These kinds of deals were very much a la mode just prior to the .com crash. Companies would buy advertising, then the websites and ad agencies would buy their services and they'd spend it again on advertising. The end result is immense revenues without profits.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2025 14:01:53 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45772081</link><dc:creator>jacquesm</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45772081</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45772081</guid></item><item><title>New comment by rendaw in "John Carmack on mutable variables"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I think the explanation is: When you mutate variables it implicitly creates an ordering dependency - later uses of the variable rely on previous mutations. However, this is an implicit dependency that isn't modeled by the language so reordering won't cause any errors.&lt;p&gt;With a very basic concrete example:&lt;p&gt;x = 7&lt;p&gt;x = x + 3&lt;p&gt;x = x / 2&lt;p&gt;Vs&lt;p&gt;x = 7&lt;p&gt;x1 = x + 3&lt;p&gt;x2 = x1 / 2&lt;p&gt;Reordering the first will have no error, but you'll get the wrong result. The second will produce an error if you try to reorder the statements.&lt;p&gt;Another way to look at it is that in the first example, the 3rd calculation doesn't have "x" as a dependency but rather "x in the state where addition has already been completed" (i.e. it's 3 different x's that all share the same name). Doing single assignment is just making this explicit.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2025 11:40:49 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45770924</link><dc:creator>rendaw</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45770924</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45770924</guid></item><item><title>New comment by EastLondonCoder in "John Carmack on mutable variables"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;After a 2 year Clojure stint I find it very hard to explain the clarity that comes with immutability for programmers used to trigger effects with a mutation.&lt;p&gt;I think it may be one of those things you have to see in order to understand.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2025 09:30:29 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45770007</link><dc:creator>EastLondonCoder</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45770007</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45770007</guid></item><item><title>New comment by fouronnes3 in "Rouille – Rust Programming, in French"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;As a native french speaker, I feel so uneasy reading source code in french. It feels very very uncanny. I've often wondered if English native speakers feel the same when reading normal source code which is always in English. They probably don't. But how? I've always associated the "other language-ness" to correctness and technicality. It must be so weird to code in your own language. Feels like reading bad pseudo code. It's very nice to be able to map "english" to "technical, correct" and "native language" to "descriptive, approximate, comments, pseudo-code". Having only a single language to work with is like removing a color from the rainbow.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2025 07:48:30 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45769332</link><dc:creator>fouronnes3</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45769332</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45769332</guid></item><item><title>New comment by ineedasername in "Denmark reportedly withdraws Chat Control proposal following controversy"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I’m continually astounded that so many people, faced with a societal problem, reflexively turn to “Hmmm, perhaps if we monitored and read and listened to every single thing that every person does, all of the time…”&lt;p&gt;As though it would 1) be a practical possibility and 2) be effective.&lt;p&gt;Compounding the issue is that the more technology can solve #1, the more these people fixate on it as the solution without regards to the lack of #2.&lt;p&gt;I wish there were a way, once and for all, to prevent this ridiculous idea from taking hold over and over again. If I could get a hold of such people when these ideas were in their infancy… perhaps I should monitor everything everyone does and watch for people considering the same as a solution to &lt;i&gt;their&lt;/i&gt; problem… ah well, no, still don’t see how that follows logically as a reasonable solution.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2025 03:35:45 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45768131</link><dc:creator>ineedasername</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45768131</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45768131</guid></item><item><title>New comment by SurceBeats in "ICE and the Smartphone Panopticon"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;The ICEBlock removal is absurd when you consider Waze has been warning drivers about police locations for... Years? The only difference is which government agency is being monitored. This sets a dangerous precedent for selective enforcement of ToS really&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2025 02:42:05 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45767762</link><dc:creator>SurceBeats</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45767762</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45767762</guid></item><item><title>New comment by jazzyjackson in "Affinity Studio now free"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I think it's really cool they can get AI money from the people who want to pay that, to give away the core for free. I can empathize with feeling their focus will be elsewhere (whatever increases revenue) but I figure AI isn't magic, they need to have the rest of the creative suite work well to, yaknow, synergize&lt;p&gt;Edit: I'll add that I much prefer purchasing perpetual licenses for software that can work without a cloud component. Opus, Sublime, Mathematica, totally agree that paying for software aligns incentives. But if it is online, it's a SaaS, and they can't very well offer you cloud services forever at a one time cost. (Rsync.net has a deal to prepay ~4 years worth upfront and they'll let you use it for life but it's capped at 1TB)&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 19:20:01 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45764127</link><dc:creator>jazzyjackson</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45764127</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45764127</guid></item><item><title>New comment by Ozzie_osman in "Israel demanded Google and Amazon use secret 'wink' to sidestep legal orders"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&gt; Microsoft said that using Azure in this way violated its terms of service and it was “not in the business of facilitating the mass surveillance of civilians”. Under the terms of the Nimbus deal, Google and Amazon are prohibited from taking such action as it would “discriminate” against the Israeli government. Doing so would incur financial penalties for the companies, as well as legal action for breach of contract.&lt;p&gt;Insane. Obeying the law or ToS, apparently, is discriminatory when it comes to Israel.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 18:32:19 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45763486</link><dc:creator>Ozzie_osman</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45763486</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45763486</guid></item><item><title>New comment by alt227 in "Affinity Studio now free"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;This is such a shame IMO. The Serif suite was great, and I used to try to get every designer I could to dump adobe and switch to serif.&lt;p&gt;Now that it has switched to a freemium model trying to get you to subscribe to AI, I wont be using this or telling other people about it any more. Their priorities have changed. No longer are they trying to to beat adobe at their own game, they are just chasing AI money like everyone else.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 18:19:32 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45763276</link><dc:creator>alt227</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45763276</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45763276</guid></item><item><title>New comment by andy99 in "Some people can't see mental images"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I’ve read tons of these and still have no idea if I have aphantasia or not. I can’t understand whether people just have different ways of describing what’s in their minds eye or if there’s really a fundamental difference.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 18:12:35 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45763166</link><dc:creator>andy99</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45763166</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45763166</guid></item><item><title>New comment by nirava in "Affinity Studio now free"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;This is a deletion.&lt;p&gt;- they're completely stopping all updates to v2; even image trace won't be coming to it. You might have paid for perpetual access to it 2 months ago, but it has completely stopped. As the world moves on (new chips, new OS features, just general software movement) this will increasingly feel like a second-class experience.&lt;p&gt;- the new "free" software is a sales funnel into the paid subscription, and will also increasingly have that "second-class" feeling as new pro-only things are added to it. it is also practically guaranteed to feed your work into AI unless you buy pro sometime in the next 5 years&lt;p&gt;In short, something secure, top class, the "best the company offers" product doesn't exist anymore. What was once there isn't.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 18:07:42 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45763101</link><dc:creator>nirava</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45763101</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45763101</guid></item><item><title>New comment by edbaskerville in "How the cochlea computes (2024)"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;To summarize: the ear does not do a Fourier transform, but it does do a time-localized frequency-domain transform akin to wavelets (specifically, intermediate between wavelet and Gabor transforms). It does this because the sounds processed by the ear are often localized in time.&lt;p&gt;The article also describes a theory that human speech evolved to occupy an unoccupied space in frequency vs. envelope duration space. It makes no explicit connection between that fact and the type of transform the ear does—but one would suspect that the specific characteristics of the human cochlea might be tuned to human speech while still being able to process environmental and animal sounds sufficiently well.&lt;p&gt;A more complicated hypothesis off the top of my head: the location of human speech in frequency/envelope is a tradeoff between (1) occupying an unfilled niche in sound space; (2) optimal information density taking brain processing speed into account; and (3) evolutionary constraints on physiology of sound production and hearing.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 17:52:38 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45762928</link><dc:creator>edbaskerville</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45762928</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45762928</guid></item><item><title>New comment by gspencley in "Free software scares normal people"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;A lot of this type of stuff boils down to what you're used to.&lt;p&gt;My wife is not particularly tech savvy. She is a Linux user, however. When we started a new business, we needed certain applications that only run on Windows and since she would be at the brick and mortar location full time, I figured we could multi-purpose a new laptop for her and have her switch to Windows.&lt;p&gt;She hated it and begged for us to get a dedicated Windows laptop for that stuff so she could go back to Linux.&lt;p&gt;Some of you might suggest that she has me for tech support, which is true, but I can't actually remember the last time she asked me to troubleshoot something for her with her laptop. The occasions that do come to mind are usually hardware failure related.&lt;p&gt;Obviously the thing about generlizations is that they're never going to fit all individuals uniformly. My wife might be an edge case. But she feels at home using Linux, as it's what she's used to ... and strongly loathed using Windows when it was offered to her.&lt;p&gt;I feel that kind of way about Mac vs PC as well. I am a lifelong PC user, and also a "power user." I have extremely particular preferences when it comes to my UI and keyboard mappings and fonts and windowing features. When I was forced to use a Mac for work, I honestly considered looking for a different position because it was just that painful for me. Nothing wrong with Mac OS X, a lot of people love it. But I was 10% as productive on it when compared to what I'm used to... and I'm "old dog" enough that it was just too much change to be able to bear and work with.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 17:30:32 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45762648</link><dc:creator>gspencley</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45762648</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45762648</guid></item><item><title>New comment by pentagrama in "Affinity Studio now free"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I used Affinity for several years, so to add some background here:&lt;p&gt;Serif is the company that originally built this software.&lt;p&gt;--------&lt;p&gt;2014–2024&lt;p&gt;Serif developed the Affinity suite, a collection of three independent desktop apps sold with a one-time payment model:&lt;p&gt;- Affinity Designer: vector graphic design (Adobe Illustrator equivalent)&lt;p&gt;- Affinity Photo: digital image editing (Adobe Photoshop equivalent)&lt;p&gt;- Affinity Publisher: print and layout design (Adobe InDesign equivalent)&lt;p&gt;They were solid, professional tools without subscriptions like Adobe, a big reason why many designers loved them.&lt;p&gt;-------&lt;p&gt;2024&lt;p&gt;Canva acquired Serif.&lt;p&gt;-------&lt;p&gt;2025 (today)&lt;p&gt;The product has been relaunched. The three apps are now merged into a single app, simply called Affinity, and it follows a freemium model.&lt;p&gt;From what I’ve tested, you need a Canva account to download and open the app (you can opt out of some telemetry during setup).&lt;p&gt;The new app has four tabs:&lt;p&gt;- Vector: formerly Affinity Designer&lt;p&gt;- Pixel: formerly Affinity Photo&lt;p&gt;- Layout: formerly Affinity Publisher&lt;p&gt;- Canva AI: a new, paid AI-powered section&lt;p&gt;Screenshot &lt;a href="https://imgur.com/a/h1S6fcK" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://imgur.com/a/h1S6fcK&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;Hope can help!&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 17:21:39 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45762521</link><dc:creator>pentagrama</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45762521</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45762521</guid></item><item><title>New comment by mns in "Affinity Studio now free"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Devastated about this. Good for them for making money on the sale to Canva, but still, this is a sad day. Studio is now freemium, in the future probably more and more features (outside of AI) will be added in the subscription, and you will end up with an app full of disabled features and pop-ups encouraging you to subscribe and unlock the new and shiny thing.&lt;p&gt;There is absolutely nothing in the world that anyone can say to convince me that this is not the end for Affinity. Every single product that went through this ended up being an ad data gathering subscription pushing unusable app for anything useful.&lt;p&gt;I have both a V1 and V2 license. V2 is probably now useless considering that it will never get any updates. This marks the death of one of the last popular pay once and use forever apps (in the sense that a V3 with new features will never exist).&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 17:21:01 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45762506</link><dc:creator>mns</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45762506</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45762506</guid></item><item><title>New comment by mmooss in "Falling panel prices lead to global solar boom, except for the US"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;As I wrote elsewhere, the US government and economy are now essentially a private equity takeover for a large segment of wealthy business: Squeeze out as much money as possible short term - including by issuing debt againts its assets, slashing and burning any costs regardless of ROI and with no regard for the future, and leave the bankrupt husk for someone else to deal with.&lt;p&gt;The treatment of fossil fuels and renewables fits: Block the obviously more economical and better long-term solution in order to shovel money toward the entrenched wealthy. That it sabotages the future due to climate change and economic inefficiency doesn't seem to be a significant factor to them.&lt;p&gt;I forgot, one of the entrenched corporate wealthy told us that climate change isn't a big deal, and we should send money to his and his friends for solutions.&lt;p&gt;I'm not anti-business; in fact, quite the opposite: These policies block a free market and the brilliant new businesses that can thrive and deliver solutions to everyone.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 17:14:01 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45762412</link><dc:creator>mmooss</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45762412</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45762412</guid></item><item><title>New comment by squeedles in "Free software scares normal people"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Good article, but the reasoning is wrong.   It isn't easy to make a simple interface in the same way that Pascal apologized for writing a long letter because he didn't have time to write a shorter one.&lt;p&gt;Implementing the UI for one exact use case is not much trouble, but figuring out what that use case &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; difficult.   And defending that use case from the line of people who want "that + this little extra thing", or the "I just need ..." is difficult.    It takes a single strong-willed defender, or some sort of onerous management structure, to prevent the interface from quickly devolving back into the million options or schizming into other projects.&lt;p&gt;Simply put, it is a desirable state, but an unstable one.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 16:12:19 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45761639</link><dc:creator>squeedles</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45761639</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45761639</guid></item><item><title>New comment by landl0rd in "US declines to join more than 70 countries in signing UN cybercrime treaty"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;China, north korea, and russia, all prolific cybercriminal nations with significant state backing of the same, are signatories.  This means it's at best meaningless and at worst surrenders power to a regime with partial control by objectively bad actors.  Staying out of this was the right move.&lt;p&gt;Plus it has too many implications for surveillance and security; poor idea in any case.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 15:09:34 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45760897</link><dc:creator>landl0rd</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45760897</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45760897</guid></item><item><title>New comment by shenberg in "US declines to join more than 70 countries in signing UN cybercrime treaty"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;When countries like North Korea, which depends on cybercrime to fund itself, are signatories, you have to wonder whether this agreement means what its title says.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 14:56:17 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45760748</link><dc:creator>shenberg</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45760748</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45760748</guid></item><item><title>New comment by tetris11 in "987654321 / 123456789"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I like calculator quirks like this. I remember as a kid playing with the number pad and noticing a geometric center of mass in number sequences&lt;p&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;    ┌───┬───┬───┐
    │ 7 │ 8 │ 9 │
    ├───┼───┼───┤
    │ 4 │ 5 │ 6 │
    ├───┼───┼───┤
    │ 1 │ 2 │ 3 │
    ├───┼───┼───┤
    │ 0 │ . │   │
    └───┴───┴───┘
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
I remember seeing that (14787 + 36989) / 2 would produce 25888, in that the mean of geometric shape traced by the two sequences would average out in the middle like that&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 14:33:24 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45760441</link><dc:creator>tetris11</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45760441</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45760441</guid></item><item><title>New comment by Aurornis in "US declines to join more than 70 countries in signing UN cybercrime treaty"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&gt; It also creates legal regimes to monitor, store and allow cross-border sharing of information without specific data protections. Access Now’s Raman Jit Singh Chima said the convention effectively justifies “cyber authoritarianism at home and transnational repression across borders.”&lt;p&gt;None of this sounds good for privacy and data protection.&lt;p&gt;Opting out of the treaty was probably a good choice. Opting out doesn’t preclude the US from cooperating with international cybercrime investigations, but it does avoid more data collection, surveillance, and sharing.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 14:31:56 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45760424</link><dc:creator>Aurornis</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45760424</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45760424</guid></item><item><title>New comment by linsomniac in "Show HN: In a single HTML file, an app to encourage my children to invest"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;There's an awful lot of negativity here, but as someone who's 55 and has earned a good wage since I was 17, I really wish I had taken investing more seriously from the very beginning.  While I &lt;i&gt;knew of&lt;/i&gt; compound interest, I really didn't &lt;i&gt;understand&lt;/i&gt; it until like a decade ago.  If I'd started putting 5% of my money into a target retirement plan from 17, I'd be retired now.  As it is I'm not doing badly, but I really wish I'd started earlier.&lt;p&gt;So I say: Good on you.&lt;p&gt;Somewhat related: I just got my son set up with a custodial account and put his "kid retirement" plan into it, and let him pick a couple stocks to put some money into, and put the majority of it into target retirement and a few stocks and EFTs, so he can get some ideas of how they perform, make it a little fun with picking things he's into, and also follow ups and downs of the market, all of which I think is good education.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 14:08:38 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45760200</link><dc:creator>linsomniac</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45760200</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45760200</guid></item><item><title>New comment by neya in "Tell HN: Azure outage"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;In Microsoft's defense, Azure has always been a complete joke. It's extremely developer unfriendly, buggy and overpriced.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 08:08:15 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45757500</link><dc:creator>neya</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45757500</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45757500</guid></item><item><title>New comment by xnorswap in "Tell HN: Azure outage"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;33 minutes from impact to status page for a complete outage is a joke.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 07:26:59 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45757288</link><dc:creator>xnorswap</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45757288</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45757288</guid></item><item><title>New comment by yanhangyhy in "China has added forest the size of Texas since 1990"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I don’t know how it is in other countries, but nearly thirty years ago when I was in elementary school, a Chinese propaganda slogan stuck with me: “If you want to get rich, build roads first; have fewer children, plant more trees.”
Every part of that slogan has been put into action, continuously, for decades. Although low birth rates have now become a problem, back then it seemed like a solution.&lt;p&gt;Xi Jinping may be a rather dull person, but his most famous saying is “Lucid waters and lush mountains are invaluable assets.”
As for building roads — the Belt and Road Initiative speaks for itself. We’ve built bridges in Croatia, in Bangladesh, in Mozambique, and roads and railways all over the world.
That slogan is probably engraved in every Chinese person’s memory.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 02:24:51 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45755760</link><dc:creator>yanhangyhy</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45755760</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45755760</guid></item><item><title>New comment by ederamen in "Uv is the best thing to happen to the Python ecosystem in a decade"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Uv is so good.  I'm a curmudgeon about adopting new tooling, and tried uv with a lot of skepticism, but it was just better in every way.  And even if it wasn't so polished and reliable, the raw speed makes it hard to go back to any other tool.&lt;p&gt;Uv combined with type hints reaching critical mass in the Python ecosystem, and how solid PyLance is in VSCode, feels so good it has made me consider investing in Python as my primary language for everything.  But then I remember that Python is dog slow compared to other languages with comparable ergonomics and first-class support for static typing, and...idk it's a tough sell.&lt;p&gt;I know the performance meta in Python is to...not use python (bind to C, Rust, JVM) - and you can get pretty far with that (see: uv), but I'd rather spend my limited time building expertise in a language that isn't constantly hemorrhaging resources unless your code secretly calls something written in another language :/&lt;p&gt;There are so many good language options available today that compete.  Python has become dominant in certain domains though, so you might not have a choice - which makes me grateful for these big steps forward in improving the tooling and ecosystem.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 00:38:08 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45755030</link><dc:creator>ederamen</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45755030</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45755030</guid></item><item><title>New comment by Daiz in "Crunchyroll is destroying its subtitles"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;This is the result of a ton of research into Crunchyroll's recent subtitle changes that have tanked the service's first-party presentation quality to an all-time low. The article ended up being quite long, so I highly appreciate anyone taking the time to read it in full!&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 00:21:38 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45754884</link><dc:creator>Daiz</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45754884</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45754884</guid></item></channel></rss>