<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>Hacker News: Best Comments</title><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/bestcomments</link><description>Hacker News RSS</description><docs>https://hnrss.org/</docs><generator>hnrss v2.1.1</generator><lastBuildDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 00:32:08 +0000</lastBuildDate><ns0:link href="https://hnrss.org/bestcomments" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item><title>New comment by dinkleberg in "Anthropic Outage for Opus 4.5 and Sonnet 4/4.5 across all services"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Props to them for actually updating their status page as issues are happening rather than hours later. I was working with claude code and hit an API error, checked the status page and sure enough there was an outage.&lt;p&gt;This should be a given for any service that others rely on, but sadly this is seldom the case.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 14 Dec 2025 22:17:15 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46267657</link><dc:creator>dinkleberg</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46267657</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46267657</guid></item><item><title>New comment by systemtest in "Ask HN: What Are You Working On? (December 2025)"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Simplification of my digital self. Removed most of my online accounts. Removed all my VPS's. Removed most apps from my phone except core ones. Cancelled a lot of online subscriptions.&lt;p&gt;In the real world finally moved everything to USB-C. Gave all my old cables away. I have two chargers in my home and a handful of C to C cables. Everything connects to everything now.&lt;p&gt;Home is now downgraded to a dumb home. Lights work on physical toggles. No hubs or sensors anywhere. Heat and AC is with a dumb panel on the wall.&lt;p&gt;It feels freeing.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 14 Dec 2025 20:36:08 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46266614</link><dc:creator>systemtest</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46266614</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46266614</guid></item><item><title>New comment by ripe in "AI and the ironies of automation – Part 2"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I really like this author's summary of the 1983 Bainbridge paper about industrial automation. I have often wondered how to apply those insights to AI agents, but I was never able to summarize it as well as OP.&lt;p&gt;Bainbridge by itself is a tough paper to read because it's so dense. It's just four pages long and worth following along:&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://ckrybus.com/static/papers/Bainbridge_1983_Automatica.pdf" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://ckrybus.com/static/papers/Bainbridge_1983_Automatica...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;For example, see this statement in the paper: "the present generation of automated systems, which are monitored by former manual operators, are riding on their skills, which later generations of operators cannot be expected to have."&lt;p&gt;This summarizes the first irony of automation, which is now familiar to everyone on HN: using AI agents effectively requires an expert programmer, but to build the skills to be an expert programmer, you have to program yourself.&lt;p&gt;It's full of insights like that. Highly recommended!&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 14 Dec 2025 16:23:44 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46264175</link><dc:creator>ripe</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46264175</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46264175</guid></item><item><title>New comment by ricardo81 in "Europeans' health data sold to US firm run by ex-Israeli spies"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;American tech companies have been pushing the needle on privacy ever since Google. Then Facebook. They've gradually normalised that privacy does not exist, all for their own capital gain.&lt;p&gt;There are European alternatives but they need support.&lt;p&gt;IMHO it requires conscious choices by European citizens to choose more carefully which online services they dedicate their time and money to. Or expect unintended consequences.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 14 Dec 2025 16:04:58 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46264030</link><dc:creator>ricardo81</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46264030</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46264030</guid></item><item><title>New comment by perrygeo in "The Gorman Paradox: Where Are All the AI-Generated Apps?"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;The link in the last paragraph provides some data to back up the claim. &lt;a href="https://mikelovesrobots.substack.com/p/wheres-the-shovelware-why-ai-coding" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://mikelovesrobots.substack.com/p/wheres-the-shovelware...&lt;/a&gt; - If the goal is to increase the rate of software production, there isn't much evidence that AI has moved the needle.&lt;p&gt;Sure, code gen is faster now. And the industry might finally be waking up to the fact that writing code is a small part of producing software. Getting infinitely faster at one step doesn't speed up the overall process. In fact, there's good evidence it that rapid code gen actually slows down other steps in the process like code review and QA.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 14 Dec 2025 13:30:15 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46262884</link><dc:creator>perrygeo</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46262884</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46262884</guid></item><item><title>New comment by preinheimer in "VPN location claims don't match real traffic exits"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I'm a co-founder at WonderProxy, we didn't make their list (we target people doing application testing, not consumer VPNs).&lt;p&gt;We're in 100+ countries, and I'll stand by that claim. It's a huge pain in the neck. In our early years we had a lot of problems with suppliers claiming to be in Mexico or South America who were actually just in Texas. I almost flew to Peru with a rackmount server in my luggage after weeks of problems, that plan died when we realized I'd need to figure out how to pay Peruvian income tax on the money I made in country before I could leave.&lt;p&gt;We've also had customers complaining that a given competitor had a country we'd had trouble sourcing in the Middle East. A little digging on our part and it's less than a ms away from our server in Germany.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 14 Dec 2025 00:38:19 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46259730</link><dc:creator>preinheimer</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46259730</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46259730</guid></item><item><title>New comment by mjr00 in "Why Twilio Segment moved from microservices back to a monolith"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&gt; Once the code for all destinations lived in a single repo, they could be merged into a single service. With every destination living in one service, our developer productivity substantially improved. We no longer had to deploy 140+ services for a change to one of the shared libraries. One engineer can deploy the service in a matter of minutes.&lt;p&gt;If you &lt;i&gt;must&lt;/i&gt; to deploy every service because of a library change, you don't have services, you have a distributed monolith. The entire idea of a "shared library" which must be kept updated across your entire service fleet is antithetical to how you need to treat services.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 13 Dec 2025 21:46:18 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46258431</link><dc:creator>mjr00</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46258431</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46258431</guid></item><item><title>New comment by reimertz in "VPN location claims don't match real traffic exits"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I know multiple people who worked / working at Mullvad and they take their business, security and privacy _very_ seriously. Not surprised to see them shine here.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 13 Dec 2025 21:17:14 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46258157</link><dc:creator>reimertz</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46258157</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46258157</guid></item><item><title>New comment by lpil in "I tried Gleam for Advent of Code"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Hi, I’m the creator of Gleam!&lt;p&gt;The comment you are replying to is correct, and you are incorrect.&lt;p&gt;All OTP APIs are usable as normal within Gleam, the language is designed with it in mind, and there’s an additional set of Gleam specific additions to OTP (which you have linked there).&lt;p&gt;Gleam does not have access to only a subset of OTP, and it does not have its own distinct OTP inspired OTP. It uses the OTP framework.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 13 Dec 2025 19:21:25 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46257117</link><dc:creator>lpil</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46257117</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46257117</guid></item><item><title>New comment by mox-1 in "What is the nicest thing a stranger has ever done for you?"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;A friend of mine and I (we are both Aussies) had been staying at my Grandma's house in a rural village in UK and were trying to make our way back to London on Boxing Day. The fact that it was Boxing Day meant that no buses were running, so we started sticking our thumbs out to try and hitch a lift to the nearest town's train station. As you would expect, picking up two 19 year old blokes in the middle of nowhere was not an attractive proposition to your average passerby.&lt;p&gt;Eventually a guy comes along and picks us up. Tells us he hitched all the way across Europe back in the day so he empathized with us. Says he's on the way to pick up his son (our age) from work, a department store that happened to be on the way to the station.&lt;p&gt;His son gets into the car, understandably pretty bemused as to why his dad has brought two random stragglers with him!&lt;p&gt;We get to the station only to find that it's closed, because, yes, it's Boxing Day and trains weren't running either (we hadn't really thought this through). Guy says:&lt;p&gt;"Don't worry lads, all the family are around ours for Christmas dinner. My brother lives in West London so he can give you a ride there at the end of the night."&lt;p&gt;So we found ourselves, two foreign students, invited to a complete stranger's Christmas dinner party. We all had so much fun and drank so much that we completely abandoned the London idea and went back to my Grandma's at the end of the night.&lt;p&gt;And the kid who was our age that got picked up from work? He ended up being my Best Man when I got married 15 years later. True story!&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 13 Dec 2025 19:21:17 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46257115</link><dc:creator>mox-1</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46257115</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46257115</guid></item><item><title>New comment by tjwebbnorfolk in "What is the nicest thing a stranger has ever done for you?"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I've got a weird one from a bank.&lt;p&gt;I was driving from South Carolina to Virginia, I was completely broke, and had exactly $20 in cash, and only a couple dollars in my checking account. I did my math wrong, and didn't have enough money for enough gas to make it home. I was trying to draft behind semi trucks and drive slow to conserve fuel, but it wasn't enough.&lt;p&gt;I called my bank at the gas station with my needle on empty and asked what would happen if I overdrew my account by $50, and the guy on the phone asked me to explain the situation.  Afterwards he said I was good to go.&lt;p&gt;I asked, what does that mean? He said there's now $50 in your account. You can use it to fill up your car on your debit card.&lt;p&gt;I filled up my car and made it home. When I checked my account later, expecting to see an overdraft fee, there was a deposit of $50 from some account I didn't recognize. The guy had just transferred me $50 from his own account. I never figured out who this was, so ~18 years later, I'll take this opportunity to say: thank you sir.&lt;p&gt;I don't know that this is THE nicest thing anyone has ever done, but it was a small thing that made a huge difference in that moment.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 13 Dec 2025 19:13:09 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46257058</link><dc:creator>tjwebbnorfolk</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46257058</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46257058</guid></item><item><title>New comment by ak217 in "Analysis finds anytime electricity from solar available as battery costs plummet"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Alas is right, China is poised to dominate battery, solar, and EV technology and to translate it to military technology as well. Meanwhile the Republicans are blowing up US alliances and sabotaging the battery/EV industrial development policy that was actually making progress in giving the US hope in catching up.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 13 Dec 2025 19:05:12 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46257000</link><dc:creator>ak217</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46257000</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46257000</guid></item><item><title>New comment by bcherny in "Ask HN: How can I get better at using AI for programming?"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Hey, Boris from the Claude Code team here. A few tips:&lt;p&gt;1. If there is anything Claude tends to repeatedly get wrong, not understand, or spend lots of tokens on, put it in your CLAUDE.md. Claude automatically reads this file and it’s a great way to avoid repeating yourself. I add to my team’s CLAUDE.md multiple times a week.&lt;p&gt;2. Use Plan mode (press shift-tab 2x). Go back and forth with Claude until you like the plan before you let Claude execute. This easily 2-3x’s results for harder tasks.&lt;p&gt;3. Give the model a way to check its work. For svelte, consider using the Puppeteer MCP server and tell Claude to check its work in the browser. This is another 2-3x.&lt;p&gt;4. Use Opus 4.5. It’s a step change from Sonnet 4.5 and earlier models.&lt;p&gt;Hope that helps!&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 13 Dec 2025 18:15:21 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46256606</link><dc:creator>bcherny</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46256606</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46256606</guid></item><item><title>New comment by lubujackson in "What is the nicest thing a stranger has ever done for you?"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;5th grade, my best friend at the time was in a basketball team, just a small town league for kids. I never really played basketball, so I was planning to watch the game then we'd hang out. It was the first game of the season and my friend was getting his uniform from a table when a dad running things asked me what team I was playing on and I said no, I'm just here to hang out with my friend.&lt;p&gt;He shook his head and said, "No, that won't do. You're on his team, too" and handed me a jersey. Then he went ahead and paid my registration fee.&lt;p&gt;More than the money, it was the proactive nature of it that struck me at the time. The thing is, if I had asked my parents they probably would have signed me up. But it was one of those things where it would have never crossed my mind to ask. I ws as one of those kids that needed a push every now and then and rarely got one.&lt;p&gt;I never got very good at basketball but I never missed a game and had a great time with my friend. So not a  tragic or desperate story, but still meaningful to me all these years later.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 13 Dec 2025 17:23:51 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46256190</link><dc:creator>lubujackson</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46256190</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46256190</guid></item><item><title>New comment by Sawpaw19 in "What is the nicest thing a stranger has ever done for you?"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;My best friend, his girlfriend, brother, sister and I piled into a minivan in July of 2018 and drove from Boston to SF. Best friend and I both took jobs there out of school and decided to make a trip of the life move.&lt;p&gt;We painted BOS &gt; SF on the back window. At a gas station in Memphis a random guy walked up to us and said "Make sure you go to Graceland. Can't miss it."&lt;p&gt;We sort of smile and nod politely and then walk into the gas station to use the bathroom, reload on snacks etc.&lt;p&gt;10 mins later we come back outside and the same guy comes over "I bought you all tickets to Graceland, who can I text them to?"&lt;p&gt;Truly such a sick moment. Graceland was a highlight of the trip and to have someone just do such a random kind thing made it that much better. Long live Elvis, long live the King. Thanks again to whoever you are that did that. Respect.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 13 Dec 2025 17:02:11 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46256005</link><dc:creator>Sawpaw19</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46256005</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46256005</guid></item><item><title>New comment by 1970-01-01 in "Apple has locked my Apple ID, and I have no recourse. A plea for help"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;The untapped answer is litigation. Call a lawyer and file against Apple. It may take several business days, and cost $$$$ but it will absolutely light a fire at Apple and get the attention of many-a-human. And if they ignore it, well, maybe a class action lawsuit awaits.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 13 Dec 2025 16:04:28 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46255532</link><dc:creator>1970-01-01</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46255532</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46255532</guid></item><item><title>New comment by rvnx in "Apple has locked my Apple ID, and I have no recourse. A plea for help"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Lot of arrogant people here who think they are safe and better than anybody and blame OP.&lt;p&gt;It is totally normal in today’s world to depend on cloud services and reasonably difficult to do without it. In China: no WeChat you are practically dead. Here try to join meetings without account, try to send a message on WhatsApp without account, etc… a lot can go wrong very fast. What if you used your Apple account as SSO to other services ?&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 13 Dec 2025 15:46:44 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46255379</link><dc:creator>rvnx</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46255379</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46255379</guid></item><item><title>New comment by tonymet in "Apple has locked my Apple ID, and I have no recourse. A plea for help"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I back up regularly using Google Takeout and similar tools, but I don’t think it’s fair to shame this author . Even if you have backups , your recent and essential content and credentials will be locked out . 1% of your content is the most important&lt;p&gt;We all depend heavily on cloud storage and sso . Everything works fine until you are locked out .&lt;p&gt;And using them isn’t fully voluntary. They are necessary for collaboration . You end up using what your team uses .&lt;p&gt;You can try to be that “own cloud” snob but it only works if you live in a basement&lt;p&gt;Every normal person has content in Google , iCloud , OneDrive , Dropbox and maybe more. That’s 4+ single points of failure&lt;p&gt;You’re just not imaginative enough if you think you’re safe .&lt;p&gt;OPs only recourse is an insider or a lawyer&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 13 Dec 2025 15:28:53 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46255200</link><dc:creator>tonymet</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46255200</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46255200</guid></item><item><title>New comment by ovi256 in "Apple has locked my Apple ID, and I have no recourse. A plea for help"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&gt; I have escalated this through my many friends in WWDR and SRE at Apple, with no success.
Ouch. If he can't get it fixed, it's scary&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 13 Dec 2025 14:40:01 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46254826</link><dc:creator>ovi256</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46254826</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46254826</guid></item><item><title>New comment by tzs in "Computer animator and Amiga fanatic Dick van Dyke turns 100"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Here’s a great quote by him:&lt;p&gt;&gt; In my 30’s, I exercised to look good. In my 50’s, to stay fit. In my 70’s, to stay ambulatory. In my 80’s, to avoid assisted living. Now in my 90’s, I’m just doing it out of pure defiance&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 13 Dec 2025 13:50:06 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46254490</link><dc:creator>tzs</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46254490</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46254490</guid></item><item><title>New comment by jasode in "Apple has locked my Apple ID, and I have no recourse. A plea for help"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;&gt;It's just insane that a gift card redemption can trigger this. &lt;/i&gt;&lt;p&gt;It's also the &lt;i&gt;buying&lt;/i&gt; of gift cards that can get Apple accounts locked:  
&lt;a href="https://old.reddit.com/r/apple/comments/r8b1lu/apple_will_permanently_disable_your_account_for/" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://old.reddit.com/r/apple/comments/r8b1lu/apple_will_pe...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;If enough of these horror stories are publicized, people will learn to never buy/redeem  Apple gift cards because of the real possibility of account bans.&lt;p&gt;- Don't give Apple gift cards to family and friends:  You're potentially ruining the recipient's digital life if they redeem it.&lt;p&gt;- Don't buy Apple gift cards:  You risk ruining your own digital life.&lt;p&gt;If you've been given an Apple gc for Christmas -- and you have paranoia of the risks -- don't buy anything online that's tied to your Apple ID.  Instead, go to the physical Apple store to redeem it.  And don't buy an iPhone with it because that will eventually get assigned to an Apple ID.  Instead, get a non-AppleID item such as the $249 ISSEY MIYAKE knit sock.&lt;p&gt;I have thousands of credit-card reward points that could be traded in for Apple gift cards but I don't do it because Apple's over-aggressive fraud tracking means Apple's store currency is too dangerous to use.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 13 Dec 2025 10:08:27 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46253454</link><dc:creator>jasode</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46253454</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46253454</guid></item><item><title>New comment by userbinator in "Apple has locked my Apple ID, and I have no recourse. A plea for help"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;To paraphrase an old saying: Live by Big Tech, die by Big Tech.&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;After nearly 30 years as a loyal customer&lt;/i&gt;&lt;p&gt;I've heard others say this (and was a "loyal advocate" of Windows for around 2 decades myself), but the reality is they simply do not care. You are merely a single user out of &lt;i&gt;several billion&lt;/i&gt;.&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Many of the reps I’ve spoken to have suggested strange things&lt;/i&gt;&lt;p&gt;That almost sounds like some sort of AI, not a human. But if I were in your situation I'd be inclined to print out that response as evidence, and then actually go there physically to see what happens.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 13 Dec 2025 06:31:32 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46252531</link><dc:creator>userbinator</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46252531</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46252531</guid></item><item><title>New comment by x3sphere in "Apple has locked my Apple ID, and I have no recourse. A plea for help"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;It's just insane that a gift card redemption can trigger this. What's the rationale? It would make more sense if they just locked the person out of redeeming gift cards or something, not the entire account.&lt;p&gt;But reading horror stories like this is is why I only use the very bare minimum of any of these cloud services. Keep local copies of everything. For developer accounts, I always create them under a separate email so they're not tied to my personal. At least it can minimize the damage somewhat.&lt;p&gt;It sucks that I have to take all these extra precautions though. It's definitely made me develop a do not trust any big corp mindset.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 13 Dec 2025 06:12:36 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46252462</link><dc:creator>x3sphere</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46252462</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46252462</guid></item><item><title>New comment by iamnothere in "Apple has locked my Apple ID, and I have no recourse. A plea for help"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;This is one of the worst stories I’ve seen yet. It sounds like they were “all in” on Apple with zero backups, which shows some questionable judgment, but still, this sort of thing shouldn’t be possible any more than a bank deciding to take all your money with no recourse. (They can close your account, but they can’t keep your money.) Maybe hosts should be required to mail you a hard drive with your data on it when they close your account. Regardless, never assume cloud data is in safe hands.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 13 Dec 2025 05:13:38 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46252196</link><dc:creator>iamnothere</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46252196</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46252196</guid></item><item><title>New comment by scottjenson in "Are we stuck with the same Desktop UX forever? [video]"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I've given dozens of talks, but this one seems to have struck a chord, as it's my most popular video in quite a while. It's got over 14k views in less than a day.&lt;p&gt;I'm excited so many people are interested in desktop UX!&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 13 Dec 2025 04:40:03 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46252036</link><dc:creator>scottjenson</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46252036</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46252036</guid></item><item><title>New comment by pabs3 in "Sick of smart TVs? Here are your best options"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;You shouldn't have to hack it, you should have the right to repair the software on your device. Hopefully the Vizio lawsuit will help with that for Linux based devices, signs are looking good though.&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://sfconservancy.org/copyleft-compliance/vizio.html" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://sfconservancy.org/copyleft-compliance/vizio.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 13 Dec 2025 04:02:49 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46251883</link><dc:creator>pabs3</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46251883</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46251883</guid></item><item><title>New comment by extr in "OpenAI are quietly adopting skills, now available in ChatGPT and Codex CLI"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;It’s crazy how Anthropic keeps coming up with sticky “so simple it seems obvious” product innovations and OpenAI plays catch up. MCP is barely a protocol. Skills are just md files. But they seem to have a knack for framing things in a way that just makes sense.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 13 Dec 2025 03:51:39 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46251820</link><dc:creator>extr</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46251820</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46251820</guid></item><item><title>New comment by taxmeifyoucan in "Sick of smart TVs? Here are your best options"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;For a hacker news article, it misses the crucial option - hacking a smart TV! I have LG OLED jailbroken using rootmy.tv, it was pretty trivial. It's basically a linux computer with a huge screen, you can customize it, SSH into it, map any commands to the remote, etc.&lt;p&gt;Before I only used monitor, simple DP/HDMI input is all I wanted. But being able to take full control of the tv and connect it with other devices in the house I would normally get Rpi for is pretty convenient!&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 13 Dec 2025 00:39:50 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46250796</link><dc:creator>taxmeifyoucan</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46250796</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46250796</guid></item><item><title>New comment by petetnt in "OpenAI are quietly adopting skills, now available in ChatGPT and Codex CLI"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;It’s impressive how every iteration tries to get further from pretending actual AGI would be anywhere close when we are basically writing library functions with the worst DSL known to man, markdown-with-english.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 13 Dec 2025 00:36:51 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46250774</link><dc:creator>petetnt</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46250774</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46250774</guid></item><item><title>New comment by simonw in "OpenAI are quietly adopting skills, now available in ChatGPT and Codex CLI"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I had a bunch of fun writing about this one, mainly because it was a great excuse to highlight the excellent news about Kākāpō breeding season this year.&lt;p&gt;(I'm not just about pelicans.)&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 23:55:11 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46250506</link><dc:creator>simonw</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46250506</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46250506</guid></item></channel></rss>