<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>Hacker News: Best Comments</title><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/bestcomments</link><description>Hacker News RSS</description><docs>https://hnrss.org/</docs><generator>hnrss v2.1.1</generator><lastBuildDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2025 00:16:23 +0000</lastBuildDate><ns0:link href="https://hnrss.org/bestcomments" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item><title>New comment by Fiveplus in "Netflix Open Content"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;This could be a huge deal for anyone working on video codecs or display tech. Finding legally clear, high-quality, uncompressed (or mezzanine) 4K HDR footage to test encoders against is surprisingly difficult. Most test footage you find online has already been stomped on by YouTube or Meta compression.&lt;p&gt;Having the raw EXR sequences and the IMF packages for Sol Levante and Meridian means researchers can finally benchmark AV1 vs HEVC vs VVC using source material that actually has the dynamic range to show the differences. The fact that they included the Dolby vision metadata is the cherry on top.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Dec 2025 13:46:08 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46433281</link><dc:creator>Fiveplus</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46433281</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46433281</guid></item><item><title>New comment by reddalo in "Netflix Open Content"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;It's because their blog is hosted on blogger.com (yeah, weird decision), which is owned by Google and does that by default.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Dec 2025 12:57:32 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46432873</link><dc:creator>reddalo</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46432873</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46432873</guid></item><item><title>New comment by hamishwhc in "Go away Python"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;The author’s point about “not caring about pip vs poetry vs uv” is missing that uv directly supports this use case, including PyPI dependencies, and all you need is uv and your preferred Python version installed: &lt;a href="https://docs.astral.sh/uv/guides/scripts/#using-a-shebang-to-create-an-executable-file" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://docs.astral.sh/uv/guides/scripts/#using-a-shebang-to...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Dec 2025 11:09:22 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46432032</link><dc:creator>hamishwhc</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46432032</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46432032</guid></item><item><title>New comment by sschueller in "HSBC blocks its app due to F-Droid-installed Bitwarden"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;That's Google's SafeNet. HSBC picked a level that causes this. Google manages the blacklist of apps.&lt;p&gt;We are rapidly losing our freedoms to the will of these companies. If they decide they don't want to they can even if the law doesn't forbid it.&lt;p&gt;People in Switzerland and the EU are being de-banked by local banks because of US pressure allowing them to force any bank that wants to use USD. The US has started to sanction people for free speech resulting in de-banking.&lt;p&gt;Swiss law requires one bank (Postfinance) to offer banking irregardless but if you are sanctioned you can't use the wire system, no other currencies, no credit cards and you cant use Twint either so it's in effect useless. You can't pay for your health insurance or rent.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Dec 2025 10:13:09 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46431572</link><dc:creator>sschueller</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46431572</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46431572</guid></item><item><title>New comment by omnicognate in "Stranger Things creator says turn off “garbage” settings"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;It would help if TV manufacturers would clearly document what these features do, and use consistent names that reflect that.&lt;p&gt;It seems they want to make these settings usable without specialist knowledge, but the end result of their opaque naming and vague descriptions is that anybody who actually cares about what they see and thinks they might benefit from some of the features has to either systematically try every possible combination of options or teach themselves video engineering and try to figure out for themselves what each one actually does.&lt;p&gt;This isn't unique to TVs. It's amazing really how much effort a company will put into adding a feature to a product only to completely negate any value it might have by assuming any attempt at clearly documenting it, even if buried deep in a manual, will cause their customers' brains to explode.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Dec 2025 08:58:41 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46431084</link><dc:creator>omnicognate</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46431084</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46431084</guid></item><item><title>New comment by pupppet in "Stranger Things creator says turn off “garbage” settings"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;The fact that I have to turn on closed captioning to understand anything tells me these producers have no idea what we want and shouldn’t be telling us what settings to use.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Dec 2025 04:38:27 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46429597</link><dc:creator>pupppet</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46429597</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46429597</guid></item><item><title>New comment by gbnwl in "Show HN: Stop Claude Code from forgetting everything"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I'm not sure how many HN users frequent other places related to agentic coding like the subreddits of particular providers, but this has got to be the 1000th "ultimate memory system"/break-free-of-the-context-limit-tyranny! project I've seen, and like all other similar projects there's never any evidence or even attempt at measuring any metric of performance improved by it. Of course it's hard to measure such a thing, but that's part of exactly why it's hard to build something like this. Here's user #1001 that's been told by Claude "What a fascinating idea! You've identified a real gap in the market for a simple database based memory system to extend agent memory."&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Dec 2025 01:22:17 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46428368</link><dc:creator>gbnwl</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46428368</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46428368</guid></item><item><title>New comment by cookiengineer in "Google is dead. Where do we go now?"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I had a very interesting discussion with a friend today, where I was talking to her about the /r/golang thread about Rob Pike's comments to OpenAI and how the thread was full of bots talking with other bots. No idea why the density of bots was so high in that thread, it was kind of absurd to see.&lt;p&gt;Then she said: "I know nobody that comments on online forums. Nobody would ever comment to strangers on the internet. It's too dangerous."&lt;p&gt;Took me a while to grasp what she meant with that, but I think she's right. Trust has eroded so much over the last two decades that most forums are either full of bots or full of annoyed and toxic people. It's very rare to find welcoming communities to newbies, and most of the ones I have discovered were offline connections.&lt;p&gt;She also mentioned that all of her friends use private profiles only, because having public profiles is too dangerous because of stalkers.&lt;p&gt;To me this sounded a bit absurd at first, but maybe that's a different perception on "how to use" the internet from a different younger generation that grew up post-socialmedia? My first contact with the internet was MIT opencourseware, her first contact was receiving dick pics at the age of 10 from assholes on the other side of the planet.&lt;p&gt;I miss the old phpbb forum days when the most toxic comment was someone being snarky and derailing the discussion into "did you use the search function?"&lt;p&gt;No idea how to fix the internet, maybe it's time to move to gopher or another protocol :-/&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2025 23:03:46 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46427089</link><dc:creator>cookiengineer</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46427089</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46427089</guid></item><item><title>New comment by kylecazar in "ManusAI Joins Meta"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;From their Wikipedia, because I had no idea who they were:&lt;p&gt;"Following Manus's launch in March 2025, Butterfly Effect raised $75 million in a funding round led by Benchmark at a valuation of approximately $500 million in April 2025."&lt;p&gt;Half a billion a month after launch and acquisition before the end of the same year. Wild times.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2025 22:42:09 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46426779</link><dc:creator>kylecazar</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46426779</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46426779</guid></item><item><title>New comment by nostrademons in "Google is dead. Where do we go now?"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;In my anecdotal experience, it's moved to private, trust-based channels: iMessage, WhatsApp, email, face-to-face interactions.  Our 30-year bender of putting our lives online and blurring the public and the private has finally ended: people don't &lt;i&gt;want&lt;/i&gt; to be online, don't trust social media, don't really trust any media, and are living simple local lives with a small circle of friends that they get together with regularly in person.&lt;p&gt;But then, my anecdotal experience may not be representative of most of the world.  Most of my friends have money, houses, kids, friends - all of which are, by the numbers, rarities these days.&lt;p&gt;It's an interesting thought experiment to explore what it means if that actually &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; the new normal, and people are not consuming media or much of anything, or even if the people who are still addicted to social media are now tapped out and don't have any more disposable income left to spend.  Probably economic depression.  If everybody bought only what they needed and ignored all the advertisements, our present level of economic activity would plunge.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2025 22:00:01 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46426283</link><dc:creator>nostrademons</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46426283</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46426283</guid></item><item><title>New comment by fairity in "Google is dead. Where do we go now?"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Surprised to see this upvoted because the takeaway is completely incorrect, and based on the anecdotal evidence of one advertiser.&lt;p&gt;As someone who spends seven figures every month on Google ads, what’s much more likely to be happening here is that the individual advertiser is either getting outcompeted or they’re executing ads poorly.&lt;p&gt;Google ads revenue in the US continues to grow every quarter.  And, since advertisers will generally invest in ads until the last dollar is break even, it’s likely that the total value advertisers unlock through Google ads is growing as well.  Whether that’s true or not, the notion that value generated for advertisers is “dead” is absurd.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2025 21:39:21 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46426043</link><dc:creator>fairity</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46426043</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46426043</guid></item><item><title>New comment by SunshineTheCat in "Google is dead. Where do we go now?"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I recently took someone to go and watch a hockey game. Been a little while but I personally played as a goalie myself.&lt;p&gt;The person kept making the comment that she couldn't see/find the puck and it made it frustrating to watch.&lt;p&gt;As a goalie, not being able to see the puck is pretty normal (especially with big bodies trying to screen you).&lt;p&gt;What I told her was that what matters a lot more than where the puck is, is where it's going to be in about two seconds. But the next best thing is to know where the puck is now.&lt;p&gt;If you can't see the puck then look at the players and as a last resort, look at the ref. 99% of the time they will be looking at the puck. Look where they're looking and soon enough it will appear.&lt;p&gt;I think this applies very much to this whole Google question.&lt;p&gt;The puck is gone (or on the way to the other side of the rink) and everyone is confused where it is or where it's going.&lt;p&gt;Look where everyone is looking and you'll find your answer there. It may not be in the same form as Google adwords, but the game is the same. Leveraging attention.&lt;p&gt;The tactics were different during the phonebook days (it was having your business start with the letter "A") as opposed to Google and will be different for the next thing as well.&lt;p&gt;From what I can tell, everyone seems to be looking at chatbots and vertical, shortform video. Not sure how that plays out in terms of advertising, but in terms of the answer to this article's question, that seems like a good place to start.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2025 21:07:38 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46425707</link><dc:creator>SunshineTheCat</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46425707</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46425707</guid></item><item><title>New comment by senthil_rajasek in "Google is dead. Where do we go now?"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I think the author intended the title to be,&lt;p&gt;"Google Ads is dead, Where do I promote my business now?"&lt;p&gt;When I hear "Google" I assume search, oof (sigh of relief).&lt;p&gt;They mention running ads on tiktok or instagram but no mention of youtube ads...&lt;p&gt;Also, In my own experience for my business ( also entertainment) I have found reddit ads to be useful.&lt;p&gt;So my next steps would be,&lt;p&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;  Reddit Ads
  Youtube Ads
  Instagram Ads
  Increase AI Visiblity
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
[Edit: Added Instagram Ads, from a different comment]&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2025 21:02:19 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46425627</link><dc:creator>senthil_rajasek</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46425627</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46425627</guid></item><item><title>New comment by brandonmenc in "Karpathy on Programming: “I've never felt this much behind”"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I admit to pangs of this, but it's really never made any sense because the implication is that the profession is now magically closed off to newcomers.&lt;p&gt;Imagine someone in the 90s saying "if you don't master the web NOW you will be forever behind!" and yet 20 years later kids who weren't even born then are building web apps and frameworks.&lt;p&gt;Waiting for it to all shake out and "mastering" it then is still a strategy. The only thing you'll sacrifice is an AI funding lottery ticket.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2025 20:59:02 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46425598</link><dc:creator>brandonmenc</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46425598</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46425598</guid></item><item><title>New comment by rambojohnson in "Karpathy on Programming: “I've never felt this much behind”"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;What exhausts me isn’t “falling behind.” It’s watching the profession collectively decide that the solution to uncertainty is to pile abstraction on top of abstraction until no one can explain what’s actually happening anymore.&lt;p&gt;This agentic arms race by C-suite know-nothings feels less like leverage and more like denial. We took a stochastic text generator, noticed it lies confidently, wipes entire databases and harddrives, and responded by wrapping it in managers, sub-agents, memories, tools, permissions, workflows, and orchestration layers so we don’t have to look directly at the fact that it still doesn’t understand anything.&lt;p&gt;Now we’re expected to maintain a mental model not just of our system, but of a swarm of half-reliable interns talking to each other in a language that isn’t executable, reproducible, or stable.&lt;p&gt;Work now feels duller than dishwater, enough to have forced me to career pivot for 2026.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2025 20:23:34 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46425127</link><dc:creator>rambojohnson</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46425127</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46425127</guid></item><item><title>New comment by ninth_ant in "GOG is getting acquired by its original co-founder"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&gt; They don't because too many people pirate games to make that a viable business.&lt;p&gt;This is an opinion, stated as if it’s fact.&lt;p&gt;There are many factors contributing to the ongoing success of steam. Ease of access, a strong network effect, word of mouth from satisfied customers, a strong ecosystem of tools and a modding platform, willingness to work across many platforms and a variety of vendors including competitors, and more.&lt;p&gt;Boiling this down to one factor of “too many people pirate” is dramatic oversimplification.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2025 18:59:33 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46424056</link><dc:creator>ninth_ant</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46424056</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46424056</guid></item><item><title>New comment by mr_mitm in "Tesla’s 4680 battery supply chain collapses as partner writes down deal by 99%"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;There is an entire Wikipedia article about Musk's (mostly) failed predictions: &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_predictions_for_autonomous_Tesla_vehicles_by_Elon_Musk" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_predictions_for_autono...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2025 18:49:44 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46423945</link><dc:creator>mr_mitm</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46423945</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46423945</guid></item><item><title>New comment by fencepost in "Tesla’s 4680 battery supply chain collapses as partner writes down deal by 99%"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Doing a quick bit of searching based on the 4680 makes me think that there has been or will be a change from NMC811 to LFP chemistry in the 4680, including one article talking about changing to US and European-based in-house manufacturing and reducing dependence on China.&lt;p&gt;I'm no fan of Tesla, but this looks like the collapse of the contract with the supplier for the battery chemistry they've moved away from, aka "no [more] big deal."&lt;p&gt;2023 article confirming NMC chemistry: &lt;a href="https://iopscience.iop.org/article/10.1149/1945-7111/ad14d0" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://iopscience.iop.org/article/10.1149/1945-7111/ad14d0&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;5/2025 article discussing change to LFP: &lt;a href="https://roboticsbiz.com/teslas-4680-lfp-battery-explained-cheaper-safer-and-made-in-the-usa/" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://roboticsbiz.com/teslas-4680-lfp-battery-explained-ch...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;3/2025 article comparing BYD's LFP and Tesla's NMC/NCM: &lt;a href="https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S2666386425000529" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S266638642...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2025 18:42:35 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46423846</link><dc:creator>fencepost</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46423846</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46423846</guid></item><item><title>New comment by jqpabc123 in "Tesla’s 4680 battery supply chain collapses as partner writes down deal by 99%"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;For years, we’ve been told that the 4680 cell was the “holy grail” that would allow Tesla to produce a $25,000 electric car.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;p&gt;For years, we've been told a lot of things that have never come to fruition.&lt;p&gt;Just 6 months ago, we were told that Robotaxi would be available to half the US population by the end of the year.&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://electrek.co/2025/07/23/elon-musk-with-straight-face-tesla-robotaxi-will-cover-half-us-population-end-year/" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://electrek.co/2025/07/23/elon-musk-with-straight-face-...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2025 18:11:33 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46423459</link><dc:creator>jqpabc123</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46423459</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46423459</guid></item><item><title>New comment by Fiveplus in "GOG is getting acquired by its original co-founder"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&gt; Can I still download offline installers? Yes.&lt;p&gt;This is the only line I was looking for. I stopped buying on Steam sometime ago because I realized I was just renting licenses. GOG is the only major storefront where I feel like I actually own the product. As long as offline installers remain a core tenet, I don't care who owns the company. That said, it helps that it's someone returning to their roots rather than a private equity firm looking to strip-mine the assets.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2025 17:40:31 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46423101</link><dc:creator>Fiveplus</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46423101</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46423101</guid></item><item><title>New comment by this_user in "Kidnapped by Deutsche Bahn"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;So much in German work culture - and also culture in general - is about covering your own arse. If you follow the procedure, even if the outcome is disaster, you are not at fault; you were just implementing the rules, and you cannot be held accountable. It's the fault of whoever came up with the rules, except that is usually not a single person, but some amorphous entity that ran through some decision making process years in the past. So, no one is really at fault or can be held accountable.&lt;p&gt;It's always some magical higher power preventing you from doing the sensible thing. One favourite excuse is insurance liability. We can't do the sensible thing, because the insurance wouldn't pay if something bad were to happen, even though the odds of something bad happening are virtually nil.&lt;p&gt;You can also observe this in German politics. "Oh, we absolutely cannot do &lt;common sense thing&gt; because the rules won't allow it." Well, you could change the rules, but then you would have to take some actual responsibility, and we can't have that.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2025 15:03:33 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46421417</link><dc:creator>this_user</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46421417</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46421417</guid></item><item><title>New comment by jimnotgym in "UK accounting body to halt remote exams amid AI cheating"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Ask an examiner from 20 years ago the risk of allowing people to take exams in their own home. They would have said 'cheating', even with no concept of AI.&lt;p&gt;Here is what happened. ACCA, one of several accountancy bodies in the UK, charge their students extraordinary sums of money to take their exams. When I took accountancy exams there were 9of 3 hour written exams, in a real building,  with real invigilators. All of the bodies at the same time realised that they could charge the same amount, pay Pearson to administer an electronic test and make more money out of their students. It was a disgrace then and it is a disgrace now&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2025 13:50:45 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46420746</link><dc:creator>jimnotgym</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46420746</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46420746</guid></item><item><title>New comment by Zealotux in "Kidnapped by Deutsche Bahn"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I worked for a massive German company you heard of, this sounds more like the typical German philosophy of strictly following the process -- as absurd as it might be -- and refusing to take initiative for anything that is not explicitly defined as one's responsibility.&lt;p&gt;As a French, the culture shock was brutal and I never really got around that work attitude. I went through a similar issue back when I used to take a regional train in France, and the crew swiftly adapted by bending rules to accommodate a difficult situation caused by bad weather. I'm not sure this could happen today, but it was a thing 10 years ago, we used to trust the operators back then.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2025 13:41:11 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46420641</link><dc:creator>Zealotux</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46420641</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46420641</guid></item><item><title>New comment by BloondAndDoom in "Kidnapped by Deutsche Bahn"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I feel like we lost humanity somewhere in modern world. I grew up in 3rd world country and if this were to happen, train would literally stop somewhere, anywhere. (With the assumption it’s safe from crewing into another train).&lt;p&gt;But the idea that you go 55 minutes just because of policy; and skip 15 stations is crazy to me. Again with the assumptions that it can safely stop somewhere for 5m and I’m pretty sure the answer is yes.&lt;p&gt;I have fond memories of train stopping close to my house for various random reasons and I’d  just get out so I don’t have to walk back from the station. The modern world where everything is “safety issue” and “someone else’s problem” is where we lost our ways, and it’s never coming back.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2025 13:18:44 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46420414</link><dc:creator>BloondAndDoom</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46420414</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46420414</guid></item><item><title>New comment by indiantinker in "Kidnapped by Deutsche Bahn"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;DB is weird. They seem to make their own rules and then run the game and “dont tell the rules to anyone”. I was on my way to catch a flight from Munich to my home (Madrid). I didn’t knew that apparently at one point the train splits into two parts and the front part goes to the airport and the other part just goes to the nearby cattle farms and comes back in 3 hours.&lt;p&gt;Google Maps - No idea
Citymapper - what?
English announcement - nien.&lt;p&gt;Thanks to an old lady, who told me that i needed to switch coaches to go the airport. Madre mia!!&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2025 12:44:47 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46420105</link><dc:creator>indiantinker</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46420105</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46420105</guid></item><item><title>New comment by throwfaraway135 in "Staying ahead of censors in 2025"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Considering the staggering number of arrest for online/offensive communications in England &amp; Wales, we should add Britain to the list of Russia and Iran&lt;p&gt;2017: ~5,500 arrests&lt;p&gt;2019: ~7,734 arrests&lt;p&gt;2023: ~12,183 arrests&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2025 07:33:48 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46418295</link><dc:creator>throwfaraway135</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46418295</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46418295</guid></item><item><title>New comment by torginus in "As AI gobbles up chips, prices for devices may rise"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;It's somewhat alarming to see that companies (owned by a very small slice of society) producing these AI thingies (whose current economic  is questionable value and actual future potential is up to hot debate), can easily price the rest of humanity out of computing goods.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2025 07:21:00 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46418217</link><dc:creator>torginus</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46418217</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46418217</guid></item><item><title>New comment by chrismorgan in "You can make up HTML tags"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;  &lt;div class=article&gt;
  &lt;div class=article-header&gt;
  &lt;div class=article-quote&gt;
  &lt;div class=quote-body&gt;
  ... a bunch more HTML ...
  &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
Just one quibble over this &lt;i&gt;specific&lt;/i&gt; example (not the broader concept, which is sound): it probably didn’t have to be div soup to begin with. Something like this may have been more reasonable:&lt;p&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;  &lt;article&gt;
  &lt;header&gt;
  &lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p class=quote-body&gt;
  ... a bunch more HTML ...
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/blockquote&gt;
  &lt;/header&gt;
  &lt;/article&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2025 03:40:14 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46417229</link><dc:creator>chrismorgan</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46417229</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46417229</guid></item><item><title>New comment by Sparkle-san in "CEOs are hugely expensive. Why not automate them? (2021)"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I'm deeply skeptical of CEOs being "built different" like some people are arguing here. If Elon can be CEO of three companies and the founder of a couple more while also finding time to tweet 50+ times a day, have a failed and embarrassing stint in trying to optimize the federal government, and get K-holed at parties then the demands of the job can't be that rigorous.&lt;p&gt;If anything, I would argue that the strategic decisions actually can be automated/performed via broader consensus. With that handled, all that's left is the cartel that CEOs have invented to justify their exhorbant pay packages.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2025 00:22:44 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46415970</link><dc:creator>Sparkle-san</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46415970</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46415970</guid></item><item><title>New comment by barishnamazov in "What an unprocessed photo looks like"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I love posts that peel back the abstraction layer of "images." It really highlights that modern photography is just signal processing with better marketing.&lt;p&gt;A fun tangent on the "green cast" mentioned in the post: the reason the Bayer pattern is RGGB (50% green) isn't just about color balance, but spatial resolution. The human eye is most sensitive to green light, so that channel effectively carries the majority of the luminance (brightness/detail) data.
In many advanced demosaicing algorithms, the pipeline actually reconstructs the green channel first to get a high-resolution luminance map, and then interpolates the red/blue signals—which act more like "color difference" layers—on top of it. We can get away with this because the human visual system is much more forgiving of low-resolution color data than it is of low-resolution brightness data. It’s the same psycho-visual principle that justifies 4:2:0 chroma subsampling in video compression.&lt;p&gt;Also, for anyone interested in how deep the rabbit hole goes, looking at the source code for dcraw (or libraw) is a rite of passage. It’s impressive how many edge cases exist just to interpret the "raw" voltages from different sensor manufacturers.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 28 Dec 2025 23:27:51 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46415558</link><dc:creator>barishnamazov</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46415558</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46415558</guid></item></channel></rss>