<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>Hacker News: Best Comments</title><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/bestcomments</link><description>Hacker News RSS</description><docs>https://hnrss.org/</docs><generator>hnrss v2.1.1</generator><lastBuildDate>Sat, 27 Dec 2025 00:00:02 +0000</lastBuildDate><ns0:link href="https://hnrss.org/bestcomments" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item><title>New comment by woodruffw in "How uv got so fast"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I think this post does a really good job of covering how multi-pronged performance is: it certainly doesn't hurt uv to be written in Rust, but it benefits &lt;i&gt;immensely&lt;/i&gt; from a decade of thoughtful standardization efforts in Python that lifted the ecosystem away from needing `setup.py` on the hot path for most packages.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 26 Dec 2025 20:24:03 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46395821</link><dc:creator>woodruffw</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46395821</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46395821</guid></item><item><title>New comment by crawshaw in "Rob Pike got spammed with an AI slop "act of kindness""</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;The important point that Simon makes in careful detail is: an "AI" did not send this email. The three people behind the Sage AI project used a tool to email him.&lt;p&gt;According to their website this email was sent by Adam Binksmith, Zak Miller, and Shoshannah Tekofsky and is the responsibility of the Sage 501(c)3.&lt;p&gt;No-one gets to disclaim ownership of sending an email. A human has to accept the Terms of Service of an email gateway and the credit card used to pay the email gateway. This performance art does not remove the human no matter how much they want to be removed.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 26 Dec 2025 19:13:47 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46395188</link><dc:creator>crawshaw</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46395188</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46395188</guid></item><item><title>New comment by merlindru in "FFmpeg has issued a DMCA takedown on GitHub"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;The repo in question incorporated FFmpeg code while claiming their code is Apache 2.0-licensed over 1.5 years ago[1]&lt;p&gt;This is not allowed under the LGPL, which mandates dynamic linking against the library. They copy-pasted FFmpeg code into their repo instead.&lt;p&gt;[1] &lt;a href="https://x.com/HermanChen1982/status/1761230920563233137" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://x.com/HermanChen1982/status/1761230920563233137&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 26 Dec 2025 17:48:25 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46394328</link><dc:creator>merlindru</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46394328</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46394328</guid></item><item><title>New comment by lambda in "Rob Pike goes nuclear over GenAI"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Data center power usage has been fairly flat for the last decade (until 2022 or so). While new capacity has been coming online, efficiency improvements have been keeping up, keeping total usage mostly flat.&lt;p&gt;The AI boom has completely changed that. Data center power usage is rocketing upwards now. It is estimated it will be more than 10% of all electric power usage in the US by 2030.&lt;p&gt;It's a completely different order of magnitude than the pre AI-boom data center usage.&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href="https://escholarship.org/uc/item/32d6m0d1" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://escholarship.org/uc/item/32d6m0d1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 26 Dec 2025 15:21:58 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46392930</link><dc:creator>lambda</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46392930</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46392930</guid></item><item><title>New comment by acheron in "Rob Pike goes nuclear over GenAI"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Google has been burning compute for the past 25 years to shove ads at people. We all lost there, too, but he apparently didn’t mind that.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 26 Dec 2025 15:05:46 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46392719</link><dc:creator>acheron</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46392719</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46392719</guid></item><item><title>New comment by Scubabear68 in "Rob Pike goes nuclear over GenAI"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;All I have to say is this post warmed my heart. I'm sure people here associate him with Go lang and Google, but I will always associate him with Bell Labs and Unix and The Practice of Programming, and overall the amazing contributions he has made to computing.&lt;p&gt;To purely associate with him with Google is a mistake, that (ironically?) the AI actually didn't make.&lt;p&gt;Just the haters here.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 26 Dec 2025 14:58:21 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46392626</link><dc:creator>Scubabear68</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46392626</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46392626</guid></item><item><title>New comment by InsideOutSanta in "Rob Pike goes nuclear over GenAI"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Everything humans do is harmful to some degree. I don't want to put words in Pike's mouth, but I'm assuming his point is that the cost-benefit-ratio of how LLMs are often used is out of whack.&lt;p&gt;Somebody burned compute to send him an LLM-generated thank-you note. Everybody involved in this transaction lost, nobody gained anything from it. It's pure destruction of resources.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 26 Dec 2025 14:57:43 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46392621</link><dc:creator>InsideOutSanta</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46392621</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46392621</guid></item><item><title>New comment by jabedude in "Rob Pike goes nuclear over GenAI"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Did Google, the company currently paying Rob Pike's extravagant salary, just start building data centers in 2025? Before 2025 was Google's infra running on dreams and pixie farts with baby deer and birdies chirping around? Why are the new data centers his company is building suddenly "raping the planet" and "unrecyclable"?&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 26 Dec 2025 14:39:27 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46392387</link><dc:creator>jabedude</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46392387</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46392387</guid></item><item><title>New comment by nkrisc in "Rob Pike goes nuclear over GenAI"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;What is going through the mind of someone who sends an AI-generated thank-you letter instead of writing it themselves? How can you be grateful enough to want to send someone such a letter but not grateful enough to write one?&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 26 Dec 2025 14:34:05 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46392315</link><dc:creator>nkrisc</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46392315</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46392315</guid></item><item><title>New comment by c-linkage in "Package managers keep using Git as a database, it never works out"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;This seems like a tragedy of the commons -- GitHub is free after all, and it has all of these great properties, so why not? -- but this kind of decision making occurs whenever externalities are present.&lt;p&gt;My favorite hill to die on (externality) is user time.  Most software houses spend so much time focusing on how expensive engineering time is that they neglect user time.  Software houses optimize for feature delivery and not user interaction time.  Yet if I spent one hour making my app one second faster for my million users, I can save 277 user hour per year. But since user hours are an externality, such optimization never gets done.&lt;p&gt;Externalities lead to users downloading extra gigabytes of data (wasted time) and waiting for software, all of which is waste that the developer isn't responsible for and doesn't care about.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 26 Dec 2025 13:52:41 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46391981</link><dc:creator>c-linkage</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46391981</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46391981</guid></item><item><title>New comment by nromiun in "Rob Pike goes nuclear over GenAI"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Funny how so many people in this comment section are saying Rob Pike is just feeling insecure about AI. Rob Pike created UTF-8, Go, Plan-9 etc. On the other hand I am trying hard to remember anything famous created by any LLM. Any famous tech product at all.&lt;p&gt;It is always the eternal tomorrow with AI.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 26 Dec 2025 06:52:50 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46389808</link><dc:creator>nromiun</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46389808</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46389808</guid></item><item><title>New comment by wrs in "Rob Pike goes nuclear over GenAI"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;To be clear, this email isn't from Anthropic, it's from "AI Village" [0], which seems to be a bunch of agents run by a 501(c)3 called Sage that are apparently allowed to run amok and send random emails.&lt;p&gt;At this moment, the Opus 4.5 agent is preparing to harass William Kahan similarly.&lt;p&gt;[0] &lt;a href="https://theaidigest.org/village" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://theaidigest.org/village&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 26 Dec 2025 06:05:41 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46389600</link><dc:creator>wrs</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46389600</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46389600</guid></item><item><title>New comment by jimrandomh in "Seven Diabetes Patients Die Due to Undisclosed Bug in Abbott's Glucose Monitors"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I'm a T1 diabetic, have worked on open source diabetes-tech (OpenAPS), and have used a number of different CGMs (though not this one specifically). This story... does not make very much sense.&lt;p&gt;CGMs (of any brand) are not, and have never been, reliable in the way that this story implies that people want them to be reliable. The physical biology of CGMs makes that sort of reliability infeasible. Where T1s are concerned, patient education has always included the need to check with fingerstick readings sometimes, and to be aware of mismatches between sensor readings and how you're feeling. If a brand of CGMs have an issue that sometimes causes false low readings, then fixing it if it's fixable is great, but that sort of thing was very much expected, and it doesn't seem reasonable to blame it for deaths. Moreover, there are two directions in which readings can be inaccurate (false low, false high) with very asymmetric risk profiles, and the report says that the errors were in the less-dangerous direction.&lt;p&gt;The FDA announcement doesn't say much about what the actual issue was, but given that it was linked to particular production batches, my bet is that it was a chemistry QC fail in one of the reagents used in the sensor wire. That's not something FOSS would be able to solve because it's not a software thing at all.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 26 Dec 2025 03:14:12 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46388885</link><dc:creator>jimrandomh</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46388885</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46388885</guid></item><item><title>New comment by delichon in "Maybe the default settings are too high"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;My dad was a busy construction contractor. One summer he tore himself away from work and took the family to a week long boat camp out next to a big beautiful lake. It turned out that our campsite was actually in the lake by a few inches at high water, but dad saw a way to dam it off and keep it dry, so he grabs the shovel and starts digging trenches and building walls and ordering us around.&lt;p&gt;About an hour into that, pouring sweat, he stops cold and says "what the hell am I doing?" The flooded camp was actually nice on a hot day and all we really had to do was move a couple of tents. He dropped the shovel and spent the rest of the week sunbathing, fishing, snorkeling and water skiing as God intended. He flipped a switch and went from Hyde to Jekyll on vacation. I've had to emulate that a few times.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 23:56:35 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46387876</link><dc:creator>delichon</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46387876</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46387876</guid></item><item><title>New comment by firefax in "Google is 'gradually rolling out' option to change your gmail.com address"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I wish they'd let me recover my original -- I lost my TOTP generator, and the codes I'd written down in a paper notebook were rejected. I even hunted down the electronic copy in case there was a transcription error -- seemed like some failure in their systems was causing me to lose access despite having followed proper procedures.&lt;p&gt;Lost a decade and a half of correspondence dating back to my teenage years. I had imported my phone number I'd had since I was 16 into voice, and it doubled as my Signal number. I even had a Gsuite subscription so I could use their (admittedly decently) UI to power my firstname @ lastname dot com email address.&lt;p&gt;I will never use their services again, I was really digusted by this failure.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 22:29:37 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46387439</link><dc:creator>firefax</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46387439</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46387439</guid></item><item><title>New comment by fcatalan in "We invited a man into our home at Christmas and he stayed with us for 45 years"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Not as hugely generous as this story, but during his whole college professor career since the 70s, my father always took care that none of his students spent any major holidays alone and away from home, so we always ended up having 2 or 3 of them around for Christmas, the New Year, Easter...
They were from everywhere around the country and the world, and it was so very enriching for me and my siblings. I had a huge postage stamp collection from the ever increasing well wishing mail that arrived.
It's also kind of comforting to think that anywhere in the world you are not that far from someone that remembers you fondly.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 20:49:51 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46386945</link><dc:creator>fcatalan</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46386945</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46386945</guid></item><item><title>New comment by JoeAltmaier in "Salesforce regrets firing 4000 experienced staff and replacing them with AI"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Somebody has to be the brave experimenter that tries the new thing. I'm just glad it was these folk. Since they make no tangible product and contribute nothing to society, they were perhaps the optimal choice to undergo these first catastrophic failed attempts at AI business.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 15:55:49 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46385114</link><dc:creator>JoeAltmaier</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46385114</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46385114</guid></item><item><title>New comment by A_D_E_P_T in "Alzheimer’s disease can be reversed in animal models? Study"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;The authors report that restoring NAD+ balance in the brain -- using a compound called P7C3-A20 -- completely reversed Alzheimer's pathology and recovered cognitive function in two different transgenic mouse models (one amyloid-based, one tau-based). The mice had advanced disease before treatment began.&lt;p&gt;Three comments:&lt;p&gt;- You can actually buy the drug here:  &lt;a href="https://focusbiomolecules.com/p7c3-a20-nampt-activator-proneurogenic-agent/" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://focusbiomolecules.com/p7c3-a20-nampt-activator-prone...&lt;/a&gt;
It's a simple small molecule.  If this stuff works, expect it to be everywhere within just a couple of years.&lt;p&gt;- There's room for skepticism.  As Derek Lowe once wrote: "Alzheimer's therapies have, for the most part, been a cliff over which people push bales of money. There are plenty of good reasons for this: we don't really know what the cause of Alzheimer's is, when you get down to it, and we're the only animal that we know of that gets it. Mouse models of the disease would be extremely useful – you wouldn't even have to know what the problem was to do some sort of phenotypic screen – but the transgenic mice used for these experiments clearly don't recapitulate the human disease. The hope for the last 25 years or so has been that they'd be close enough to get somewhere, but look where we are."&lt;p&gt;&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.science.org/content/blog-post/just-how-worthless-are-standard-alzheimer-s-models" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://www.science.org/content/blog-post/just-how-worthless...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;- If the drug's mechanism of action has been correctly assigned, it's very plausible that simply supplementing with NMN, NR, or NADH would work equally well.  The authors caution against this on, IMO, extremely shaky and unjustified grounds.  "Pieper emphasized that current over-the-counter NAD+-precursors have been shown in animal models to raise cellular NAD+ to dangerously high levels that promote cancer."&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 15:37:47 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46385008</link><dc:creator>A_D_E_P_T</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46385008</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46385008</guid></item><item><title>New comment by Zephilinox in "Mattermost restricted access to old messages after 10000 limit is reached"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;so not only did they enforce a ridiculously small message limit, they also did it for the self-hosted version, and they did it without announcing it AND without a suitable migration path&lt;p&gt;and still no one from that company has admitted to it being a mistake?&lt;p&gt;very nice&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 12:30:01 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46384018</link><dc:creator>Zephilinox</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46384018</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46384018</guid></item><item><title>New comment by cogman10 in "We invited a man into our home at Christmas and he stayed with us for 45 years"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Beautiful story but with a sad undertone.&lt;p&gt;A large percentage of the homeless have autism [1].  And that really sucks.  If these people don't have support, their lives can turn miserable fast.  And unfortunately it's just way too easy for these people to end up in abusive situations.&lt;p&gt;It's a lot of work to care for people with autism (moderate to severe).  There is no standard for what they need, their capabilities can be all over the board.  Some of them are capable like ronny in this story and they can hold down jobs.  But others need 24/7 caregiving in order to survive.  Unfortunately I don't think those with severe autism survive for long when they become homeless.&lt;p&gt;I hope this story at very least gets people to view the homeless a little differently.  They aren't all there because of vices or failure.  A large percentage are there because society does not care for those with mental disabilities.  It was good on this story to highlight that Ron had problems with gambling.  Autism does, in fact, make an individual more prone to various addictions.&lt;p&gt;My point in writing this, please have some humanity about the homeless.  I get that they can be inconvenient.  They are people and they aren't necessarily bad people due to their circumstances.&lt;p&gt;[1] &lt;a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/29633853/" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/29633853/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 11:57:55 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46383864</link><dc:creator>cogman10</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46383864</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46383864</guid></item><item><title>New comment by wjnc in "We invited a man into our home at Christmas and he stayed with us for 45 years"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;My parents once took a struggling man in. I think he stayed with them for about three years, up until the moment I was conceived and my mom started planning for a future for our family and helped him get into a housing project. For all of my life before adulthood this man would show up once in a while on his racing bike  for coffee, talk and proceed to stay for dinner. He was kind, funny and a tidbit strange. His life's story had more drama than a soap opera, but you wouldn't know it. After my father died I proceeded to look for him, but never found him. I still search online for him once in a while, fully knowing he probably isn't alive anymore and probably wouldn't use online anyways. There is some story in my head that he probably showed up to my dads doorstep once on his racing bike to find other people living there, but was too shy to ask for details. A trace lost.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 11:38:39 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46383792</link><dc:creator>wjnc</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46383792</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46383792</guid></item><item><title>New comment by onion2k in "Tell HN: Merry Christmas"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Pretty sure it's a regex to match email address strings.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 08:29:52 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46383008</link><dc:creator>onion2k</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46383008</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46383008</guid></item><item><title>New comment by jbkkd in "Nvidia to buy assets from Groq for $20B cash"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I have a friend who worked in a company that got "not acquired" in a similar deal.&lt;p&gt;She didn't see a dime out of it, and was let off (together with a big chunk of people) within 6 months.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 05:29:55 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46382321</link><dc:creator>jbkkd</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46382321</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46382321</guid></item><item><title>New comment by NaOH in "Tell HN: Merry Christmas"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I'm taking a moment to recognize once more the work that user @atdrummond (Alex Thomas Drummond) did for a couple years to help others here. I did not know him, don’t think I ever interacted with him, and I did not benefit from his generosity, but I admired his kindness. Just beautiful.&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Ask HN: Who needs holiday help? (Follow up thread)&lt;/i&gt; - &lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=38706167"&gt;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=38706167&lt;/a&gt; - Dec 2023 (9 comments)&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Ask HN: Who needs help this holidays?&lt;/i&gt; - &lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=38492378"&gt;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=38492378&lt;/a&gt; - Dec 2023 (210 comments)&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Tell HN: Thank You&lt;/i&gt; - &lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=34140096"&gt;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=34140096&lt;/a&gt; - Dec 2022 (42 comments)&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Tell HN: Everyone should have a holiday dinner this year&lt;/i&gt; - &lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=34122118"&gt;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=34122118&lt;/a&gt; - Dec 2022 (58 comments)&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, Alex died a few months after his last round of holiday giving, about 1½ years ago now.&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Tell HN: In Memory of Alexander Thomas Drummond&lt;/i&gt; - &lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=40508725"&gt;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=40508725&lt;/a&gt; - May 2024 (5 comments)&lt;p&gt;If you read the comments in that last thread, know that @toomuchtodo followed through last year and kept the tradition alive. Amazing and magnificent.&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Ask HN: Who needs help this holidays?&lt;/i&gt; - &lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42291246"&gt;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42291246&lt;/a&gt; - Dec 2024 (46 comments)&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 02:55:11 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46381665</link><dc:creator>NaOH</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46381665</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46381665</guid></item><item><title>New comment by andy_ppp in "Tell HN: Merry Christmas"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Happy Christmas everyone, I’m at 29000 feet on a flight to Hong Kong after a mini version of planes, trains and automobiles and including cancelled planes and taxis to different airports. I’m struck by honestly what a miracle it is that we can travel thousands of miles at hundreds of MPH and have okay internet access and communicate. I don’t think people quite realise how delicate all of the technology is now and how easily it could fail if we don’t all look after each other. I hope you all have a brilliant Christmas and new year!&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 00:32:21 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46380918</link><dc:creator>andy_ppp</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46380918</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46380918</guid></item><item><title>New comment by Grosvenor in "Tell HN: Merry Christmas"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;         *             ,
                      _/^\_
                     &lt;     &gt;
    *                 /.-.\         *
             *        `/&amp;\`                   *
                     ,@.*;@,
                    /_o.I %_\    *
       *           (`'--:o(_@;
                  /`;--.,__ `')             *
                 ;@`o % O,*`'`&amp;\
           *    (`'--)_@ ;o %'()\      *
                /`;--._`''--._O'@;
               /&amp;*,()~o`;-.,_ `""`)
    *          /`,@ ;+&amp; () o*`;-';\
              (`""--.,_0 +% @' &amp;()\
              /-.,_    ``''--....-'`)  *
         *    /@%;o`:;'--,.__   __.'\
             ;*,&amp;(); @ % &amp;^;~`"`o;@();         *
             /(); o^~; &amp; ().o@*&amp;`;&amp;%O\
       jgs   `"="==""==,,,.,="=="==="`
          __.----.(\-''#####---...___...-----._
        '`         \)_`"""""`
                .--' ')
              o(  )_-\
                `"""` `&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 23:57:01 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46380660</link><dc:creator>Grosvenor</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46380660</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46380660</guid></item><item><title>New comment by conqrr in "How I Left YouTube"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&gt; In the software engineering world, we exist on a ladder. We call this ”Leveling”.&lt;p&gt;Career is a made up game. There are no true levels or ladders in life that you have to chase. Nobody will care or remember what you did or what level you were given enough timespan. Take the bits that you want (money, skills etc) to live life, but don't get too caught up trying to win the game.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 23:45:48 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46380572</link><dc:creator>conqrr</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46380572</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46380572</guid></item><item><title>New comment by cluckindan in "Tell HN: Merry Christmas"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;      o
     / \
    o   o
       / \
      o   o
         / \
        o   o
       /   / \
      o   o   o
         /   / \
        o   o   o
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
I knew I should have invested in that fancy self-balancing one, oh well.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 23:40:31 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46380526</link><dc:creator>cluckindan</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46380526</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46380526</guid></item><item><title>New comment by DetectDefect in "Tell HN: Merry Christmas"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Shall we showcase our trees?&lt;p&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;        *
        |
       /.\
      /o..\
      /..O\
     /.o..o\
     /...o.\
    /..O..o.\
    ^^^[_]^^^&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 23:18:25 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46380357</link><dc:creator>DetectDefect</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46380357</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46380357</guid></item><item><title>New comment by sho_hn in "Phoenix: A modern X server written from scratch in Zig"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Pretty interesting approach to make an X server that is essentially "Wayland-like" (merging display server/compositor by default, isolated apps by default, no remoting of GLX, dropping legacy protocol features to the point of breaking compat with the core protocol, etc.). Not sure who this is for, but by itself it looks like a fairly reasonable set of choices.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 23:12:59 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46380322</link><dc:creator>sho_hn</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46380322</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46380322</guid></item></channel></rss>