<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>Hacker News: Best Comments</title><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/bestcomments</link><description>Hacker News RSS</description><docs>https://hnrss.org/</docs><generator>hnrss v2.1.1</generator><lastBuildDate>Fri, 17 Oct 2025 23:40:22 +0000</lastBuildDate><ns0:link href="https://hnrss.org/bestcomments" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item><title>New comment by Imnimo in "Andrej Karpathy – AGI is still a decade away"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&gt;What takes the long amount of time and the way to think about it is that it’s a march of nines. Every single nine is a constant amount of work. Every single nine is the same amount of work. When you get a demo and something works 90% of the time, that’s just the first nine. Then you need the second nine, a third nine, a fourth nine, a fifth nine. While I was at Tesla for five years or so, we went through maybe three nines or two nines. I don’t know what it is, but multiple nines of iteration. There are still more nines to go.&lt;p&gt;I think this is an important way of understanding AI progress. Capability improvements often look exponential on a particular fixed benchmark, but the difficulty of the next step up is also often exponential, and so you get net linear improvement with a wider perspective.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 17 Oct 2025 18:09:10 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45619916</link><dc:creator>Imnimo</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45619916</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45619916</guid></item><item><title>New comment by lanewinfield in "The Rapper 50 Cent, Adjusted for Inflation"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;hi, i made this. thank you for posting.&lt;p&gt;unfortunately due to the government shutdown, the BLS inflation data for September 2025 is delayed from October 15 (as it normally is) until October 24[1], so please check back then to see if he is &gt;109 Cent.&lt;p&gt;assuming future stability, the site will automatically update on the 15th of every month.&lt;p&gt;[1] &lt;a href="https://www.bls.gov/bls/092025-cpi-reschedule-notice.htm" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://www.bls.gov/bls/092025-cpi-reschedule-notice.htm&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 17 Oct 2025 17:26:07 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45619352</link><dc:creator>lanewinfield</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45619352</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45619352</guid></item><item><title>New comment by nostrademons in "EVs are depreciating faster than gas-powered cars"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Causality could be reversed here.  In markets where technology advances quickly and prices drop, there is very little market for used goods, because why would you buy a 4-year-old whatever when you can get a new one that's twice as good for half the price?  You see this in computers, smartphones, TVs, and solar panels (outside of the U.S, where prices are kept artificially high by tariffs).  People almost never buy used because there's no reason to.  You can just buy new, for the same or lower price, and get something way better.&lt;p&gt;Instead of threatening to derail the EV transition, lack of resale value might be &lt;i&gt;evidence of&lt;/i&gt; the EV transition, particularly when coupled with quickly growing overall sales of EVs globally.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 17 Oct 2025 16:15:35 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45618442</link><dc:creator>nostrademons</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45618442</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45618442</guid></item><item><title>New comment by sebiw in "Ruby core team takes ownership of RubyGems and Bundler"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I think this is the right move. Thank you to Ruby Core and Matz for stepping up and providing stability to the language and community as a whole.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 17 Oct 2025 12:21:30 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45615909</link><dc:creator>sebiw</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45615909</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45615909</guid></item><item><title>New comment by rightbyte in "Migrating from AWS to Hetzner"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;What is old is new again.&lt;p&gt;My employer is so conservative and slow that they are forerunning this Local Cloud Edge Our Basement thing by just not doing anything.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 17 Oct 2025 12:21:18 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45615906</link><dc:creator>rightbyte</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45615906</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45615906</guid></item><item><title>New comment by adamcharnock in "Migrating from AWS to Hetzner"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I cannot overstate the performance improvement of deploying onto bare metal. We typically see a doubling of performance, as well as extremely predictable baseline performance.&lt;p&gt;This is down to several things:&lt;p&gt;- Latency - having your own local network, rather than sharing some larger datacenter network fabric, gives around of order of magnitude reduced latency&lt;p&gt;- Caches – right-sizing a deployment for the underlying hardware, and so actually allowing a modern CPU to do its job, makes a huge difference&lt;p&gt;- Disk IO – Dedicated NVMe access is _fast_.&lt;p&gt;And with it comes a whole bunch of other benefits:&lt;p&gt;- Auto-scalers becomes less important, partly because you have 10x the hardware for the same price, partly because everything runs 2x the speed anyway, and partly because you have a fixed pool of hardware. This makes the whole system more stable and easier to reason about.&lt;p&gt;- No more sweating the S3 costs. Put a 15TB NVMe drive in each server and run your own MinIO/Garage cluster (alongside your other workloads). We're doing about 20GiB/s sustained on a 10 node cluster, 50k API calls per second (on S3 that is $20-$250 _per second_ on API calls!).&lt;p&gt;- You get the same bill every month.&lt;p&gt;- UPDATE: more benefits - cheap fast storage, run huge Postgresql instances at minimal cost, less engineering time spend working around hardware limitations and cloud vagaries.&lt;p&gt;And, if chose to invest in the above, it all costs 10x less than AWS.&lt;p&gt;Pitch: If you don't want to do this yourself, then we'll do it for you for half the price of AWS (and we'll be your DevOps team too):&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://lithus.eu" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://lithus.eu&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;Email: adam@ above domain&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 17 Oct 2025 12:16:07 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45615867</link><dc:creator>adamcharnock</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45615867</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45615867</guid></item><item><title>New comment by lisperforlife in "Migrating from AWS to Hetzner"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I think you can get much farther with dedicated servers. I run a couple of nodes on Hetzner. The performance you get from a dedicated machine even if it is a 3 year old machine that you can get on server auction is absolutely bonkers and cannot be compared to VMs. The thing is that most of the server hardware is focused towards high core count, low clock speed processors that optimize for I/O rather than compute. It is overprovisioned by all cloud providers. Even the I/O part of  the disk is crazy. It uses all sorts of shenanigans to get a drive that sitting on a NAS and emulating a local disk. Most startups do not need the hyper virtualized, NAS based drive. You can go much farther and much more cost-effectively with dedicated server rentals from Hetzner. I would love to know if they are any north-american (particularly canadian) companies that can compete with price and  the quality of service like Hetzner. I know  of OVH but I would love to know others in the same space.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 17 Oct 2025 10:34:50 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45615090</link><dc:creator>lisperforlife</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45615090</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45615090</guid></item><item><title>New comment by swiftcoder in "Ask HN: How to stop an AWS bot sending 2B requests/month?"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Making the obviously-abusive bot prohibitively expensive is one way to go, if you control the terminating server.&lt;p&gt;gzip bomb is good if the bot happens to be vulnerable, but even just slowing down their connection rate is often sufficient - waiting just 10 seconds before responding with your 404 is going to consume ~7,000 ports on their box, which should be enough to crash most linux processes (nginx + mod-http-echo is a really easy way to set this up)&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 17 Oct 2025 06:59:35 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45614001</link><dc:creator>swiftcoder</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45614001</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45614001</guid></item><item><title>New comment by omcnoe in "Meow.camera"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;These feeders are part of a stray cat control program in China, aiming to both feed &amp; neuter stray cat populations there.&lt;p&gt;There have been some distasteful incidents of online groups organizing to try and harm/kill specific cats famous through this feeder program. China lacks animal welfare laws to protect these cats, it's not a crime. So people have taken to identifying these abusers and reporting them to their employer, university etc. Abusers have been fired and expelled over such cases. Governments overseas whose citizens participate in such online abuse groups need to be doing more. Membership in online animal abuse groups needs to be criminalized.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 17 Oct 2025 06:25:17 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45613829</link><dc:creator>omcnoe</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45613829</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45613829</guid></item><item><title>New comment by dannyobrien in "How I bypassed Amazon's Kindle web DRM"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Fun fact: this is one of the few situations in the US where a prosecutor could claim that this is &lt;i&gt;criminal&lt;/i&gt; speech  (though I hope and trust they would not, and if it did it would get thrown out by any court respecting the First Amendment).&lt;p&gt;Not a civil issue, like libel or fraud, but the sort of talk that can get a policeman to come and drag you off to jail. If you've ever wondered why DRM is so roundly hated by engineers of a certain age, it's because not only it dumb makework that they are required to implement, not only is it extremely irritating to discover it interfering with your own computer, but if you &lt;i&gt;do&lt;/i&gt; effectively point out how dumb, irritating, and eminently circumventable it is, they made it against the law to even tell anyone.&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.eff.org/press/releases/licensing-scheme-fair-uses-and-other-speech-violates-first-amendment-eff-argues" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://www.eff.org/press/releases/licensing-scheme-fair-use...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 16 Oct 2025 23:26:42 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45611895</link><dc:creator>dannyobrien</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45611895</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45611895</guid></item><item><title>New comment by tschumacher in "Syntax highlighting is a waste of an information channel (2020)"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;My coworker recently showed me this plugin [1] that fades out all Rust code that is unrelated to the variable under the cursor. Think of it as a more powerful version of the "click to highlight all appearances" you can do in most IDEs but it actually does information flow analysis on the code.&lt;p&gt;[1]: &lt;a href="https://github.com/willcrichton/flowistry" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://github.com/willcrichton/flowistry&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 16 Oct 2025 22:13:08 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45611315</link><dc:creator>tschumacher</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45611315</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45611315</guid></item><item><title>New comment by vvpan in "DoorDash and Waymo launch autonomous delivery service in Phoenix"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;This is tangential, but I worked for a food delivery startup (a conscientious one) for a couple of years and food delivery is a terribly extractive business that kills restaurants. Either order from the restaurant directly or just go there yourself, Doordash et. al. will kill your favorite restaurant with your help. The numbers don't add up in the kitchen's favor.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 16 Oct 2025 22:03:56 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45611240</link><dc:creator>vvpan</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45611240</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45611240</guid></item><item><title>New comment by chmod775 in "How I bypassed Amazon's Kindle web DRM"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;For books only available through Amazon my workflow used to be buying it, downloading it with their desktop app, importing into Calibre, converting to epub and stripping DRM, then pushing it onto my Kobo.&lt;p&gt;They broke that a while ago by making their DRM even worse, so now I just pirate those books.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 16 Oct 2025 22:01:27 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45611217</link><dc:creator>chmod775</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45611217</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45611217</guid></item><item><title>New comment by emptybits in "How I bypassed Amazon's Kindle web DRM"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Hell hath no fury like an engineer angered! This was such a good read and epitomizes hacking:&lt;p&gt;"Was it worth it? To read one book? No. To prove a point? Absolutely. To learn about SVG rendering, perceptual hashing, and font metrics? Probably yes."&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 16 Oct 2025 21:58:23 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45611192</link><dc:creator>emptybits</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45611192</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45611192</guid></item><item><title>New comment by libraryofbabel in "Claude Skills"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;You forgot mcp-everything!&lt;p&gt;Yes, it's a mess, and there will be a lot of churn, you're not wrong, but there are foundational concepts underneath it all that you can learn and then it's easy to fit insert-new-feature into your mental model. (Or you can just ignore the new features, and roll your own tools. Some people here do that with a lot of success.)&lt;p&gt;The foundational mental model to get the hang of is really just:&lt;p&gt;* An LLM&lt;p&gt;* ...called in a loop&lt;p&gt;* ...maintaining a history of stuff it's done in the session (the "context")&lt;p&gt;* ...with access to tool calls to do things. Like, read files, write files, call bash, etc.&lt;p&gt;Some people call this "the agentic loop." Call it what you want, you can write it in 100 lines of Python. I encourage every programmer I talk to who is remotely curious about LLMs to try that. It is a lightbulb moment.&lt;p&gt;Once you've written your own basic agent, if a new tool comes along, you can easily demystify it by thinking about how you'd implement it yourself. For example, Claude Skills are really just:&lt;p&gt;1) Skills are just a bunch of files with instructions for the LLM in them.&lt;p&gt;2) Search for the available "skills" on startup and put all the short descriptions into the context so the LLM knows about them.&lt;p&gt;3) Also tell the LLM how to "use" a skill. Claude just uses the `bash` tool for that.&lt;p&gt;4) When Claude wants to use a skill, it uses the "call bash" tool to read in the skill files, then does the thing described in them.&lt;p&gt;and that's more or less it, glossing over a lot of things that are important but not foundational like ensuring granular tool permissions, etc.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 16 Oct 2025 20:00:05 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45610010</link><dc:creator>libraryofbabel</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45610010</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45610010</guid></item><item><title>New comment by fny in "Claude Skills"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I fear the conceptual churn we're going to endure in the coming years will rival frontend dev.&lt;p&gt;Across ChatGPT and Claude we now have tools, functions, skills, agents, subagents, commands, and apps, and there's a metastasizing complex of vibe frameworks feeding on this mess.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 16 Oct 2025 19:12:17 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45609468</link><dc:creator>fny</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45609468</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45609468</guid></item><item><title>New comment by tantalor in "DoorDash and Waymo launch autonomous delivery service in Phoenix"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;That's short sighted. A burrito is a perfect candidate for ballistic trajectory. They can easily absorb the high g-force associated with traditional mortar-style launch system, even up to exotic "space gun" capable of intercontinental delivery.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 16 Oct 2025 18:58:22 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45609302</link><dc:creator>tantalor</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45609302</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45609302</guid></item><item><title>New comment by ajkjk in "DoorDash and Waymo launch autonomous delivery service in Phoenix"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;best case scenario is walkable neighborhoods with lots of little tasty restaurants at affordable prices around the corner from everybody.&lt;p&gt;We've got a long way to go on actually building out our own country in a desirable way.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 16 Oct 2025 17:42:53 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45608390</link><dc:creator>ajkjk</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45608390</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45608390</guid></item><item><title>New comment by jmkni in "Gemini 3.0 spotted in the wild through A/B testing"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I might be in the minority here but I've consistently found Gemini to be better than ChatGPT, Claude and Deepseek (I get access to all of the pro models through work)&lt;p&gt;Maybe it's just the kind of work I'm doing, a lot of web development with html/scss, and Google has crawled the internet so they have more data to work with.&lt;p&gt;I reckon different models are better at different kinds of work, but Gemini is pretty excellent at UI/UX web development, in my experience&lt;p&gt;Very excited to see what 3.0 is like&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 16 Oct 2025 17:29:41 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45608194</link><dc:creator>jmkni</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45608194</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45608194</guid></item><item><title>New comment by Footnote7341 in "DoorDash and Waymo launch autonomous delivery service in Phoenix"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;We're still moving thousands of pounds of vehicle around a public highway to carry a 1lb burrito, obviously lightweight aerial drones are the future for food and grocery delivery.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 16 Oct 2025 17:27:38 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45608159</link><dc:creator>Footnote7341</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45608159</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45608159</guid></item><item><title>New comment by bko in "Video game union workers rally against $55B private acquisition of EA"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I don't think you need to "justify layoffs". If a company feels an employee is not being productive, they should be allowed to let them go. Same way if an employee feels he is getting underpaid or wants to work somewhere else, they should be allowed to leave.&lt;p&gt;I've actually always liked working for companies in which the objective was straight forward. None of this "we're a family" stuff. You should be kind, and all the places I was at were kind. But layoffs are a reality and reducing headcount at times is part of that. You need a way to get rid of dead wood, otherwise you would be too afraid to grow and hire when you need to.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 16 Oct 2025 16:07:41 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45607139</link><dc:creator>bko</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45607139</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45607139</guid></item><item><title>New comment by ryandrake in "Video game union workers rally against $55B private acquisition of EA"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&gt; "EA is not a struggling company," the statement reads. "With annual revenues reaching $7.5 billion and $1 billion in profit each year, EA is one of the largest video game developers and publishers in the world."&lt;p&gt;Seems to be a common theme in 2025: Actually-healthy companies cosplaying as struggling companies, as an excuse to justify layoffs and other activities that transfer wealth and power from employees to management and shareholders. Like, does anyone think any of these BigTech (and MediumTech) companies who are all doing layoffs are really "struggling" and "vulnerable"? It's always just an unbelievable excuse.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 16 Oct 2025 15:52:19 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45606925</link><dc:creator>ryandrake</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45606925</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45606925</guid></item><item><title>New comment by jeremymcanally in "TurboTax’s 20-year fight to stop Americans from filing taxes for free (2019)"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Precisely why I built &lt;a href="https://freetofile.com" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://freetofile.com&lt;/a&gt; (it’s a simple static site with React for internationalization that automatically renders in Spanish, Chinese, Haitian Creole, or English depending on browser settings).  It’s shocking and depressing how many low income people don’t know they don’t need to spend $100-200 to file their taxes.&lt;p&gt;I want to blanket my area (well the whole country really but baby steps…) in signs with the URL during tax season.  I really do loathe the entire industry at this point due to their gross practices around free filing.  Some offer “free” online filing but deceptively upsell until they squeeze some money out of the customer.  So I want to make any little push back I can against these companies.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 16 Oct 2025 12:15:12 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45604409</link><dc:creator>jeremymcanally</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45604409</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45604409</guid></item><item><title>New comment by sarchertech in "Liquibase continues to advertise itself as "open source" despite license switch"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Big tech companies (the money behind the Open Source Initiative) have done a few things.&lt;p&gt;1. They co-opted the free software movement and made it more business friendly.&lt;p&gt;2. They convinced people that Open Source is pure and software that isn’t Open Source is unclean.&lt;p&gt;3. They convinced a bunch of developers that their definition of Open Source that was specifically crafted to protect business interests is canon.&lt;p&gt;4. They convinced a well meaning subset of those developers to police the other devs and pressure them to release their software under big tech approved licenses.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 16 Oct 2025 11:03:00 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45603913</link><dc:creator>sarchertech</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45603913</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45603913</guid></item><item><title>New comment by alexandru_m in "TurboTax’s 20-year fight to stop Americans from filing taxes for free (2019)"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Why does the US have a tax prep industry in the first place?&lt;p&gt;In every other country in the world, taxes are handled by their respective financial authorities.&lt;p&gt;Why must every service and thing in the US must be a private profit making thing?&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 16 Oct 2025 09:22:33 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45603190</link><dc:creator>alexandru_m</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45603190</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45603190</guid></item><item><title>New comment by Havoc in "Journalists turn in access badges, exit Pentagon rather than agreeing new rules"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;First sign of a profession having a backbone in months.&lt;p&gt;Although the silent treatment the generals dished out at recent meeting wasn’t bad either&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 16 Oct 2025 07:59:13 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45602647</link><dc:creator>Havoc</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45602647</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45602647</guid></item><item><title>New comment by crbelaus in "Elixir 1.19"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;The progressive introduction of automated type checking in Elixir should serve as a reference on how to improve a programming language gracefully without breaking changes.&lt;p&gt;So many examples of programming languages have huge breaking changes between versions that end up creating a split in the ecosystem that takes years to resolve.&lt;p&gt;Thankfully José has been very clear about Elixir being &lt;i&gt;done&lt;/i&gt; since at least 2018. The language is stable and the language/core foundation is not changing anymore.&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=suOzNeMJXl0" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=suOzNeMJXl0&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;Truly outsanding work and stewardship.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 16 Oct 2025 07:55:23 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45602620</link><dc:creator>crbelaus</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45602620</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45602620</guid></item><item><title>New comment by heavyset_go in "Retiring Windows 10 and Microsoft's move towards a surveillance state"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&gt; &lt;i&gt;I would say that specifically with Secure Boot, Microsoft actually promoted user choice: A Windows Logo compliant PC needs to have Microsoft's root of trust installed by default. Microsoft could have stopped there, but they didn't.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;p&gt;This was not the case with the initial rollout of Secure Boot, it was combined with locked BIOS to lock PCs so that they could only boot Windows 8 on some devices. This was the case on Windows RT ARM machines from that era.&lt;p&gt;All that has to be done today for machines to be locked down again is to flip a bit or blow an e-fuse. It's already the case on phones and tablets.&lt;p&gt;There is also a real potential for abusing TPMs or cryptographic co-processors to enforce remote attestation.&lt;p&gt;I say this as someone who agrees with your first paragraph and uses Secure Boot + TPMs on all of my machines.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 16 Oct 2025 02:34:56 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45600837</link><dc:creator>heavyset_go</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45600837</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45600837</guid></item><item><title>New comment by jamestimmins in "A Gemma model helped discover a new potential cancer therapy pathway"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;For all the hate that Google (rightly) gets for some of their work in other domains, I appreciate that they continue to put major resources behind using AI to try and save lives in medicine and autonomous driving.&lt;p&gt;Easy to take for granted, but their peer companies are not doing this type of long term investment.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 16 Oct 2025 02:01:18 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45600681</link><dc:creator>jamestimmins</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45600681</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45600681</guid></item><item><title>New comment by trinsic2 in "Retiring Windows 10 and Microsoft's move towards a surveillance state"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I am a IT solutions provider for the public and small business. I think the changes to Windows 11 is gearing up to work with organizations to create a surveillance state.&lt;p&gt;So I have to decided to promote Linux over Windows for computers I build for customers. If you have any suggestions on how I can make this promotion, better let me know.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 16 Oct 2025 01:00:17 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45600339</link><dc:creator>trinsic2</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45600339</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45600339</guid></item></channel></rss>