<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>Hacker News: Best Comments</title><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/bestcomments</link><description>Hacker News RSS</description><docs>https://hnrss.org/</docs><generator>hnrss v2.1.1</generator><lastBuildDate>Sun, 02 Nov 2025 00:31:17 +0000</lastBuildDate><ns0:link href="https://hnrss.org/bestcomments" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item><title>New comment by efitz in "Updated practice for review articles and position papers in ArXiv CS category"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;There is a general problem with rewarding people for the volume of stuff they create, rather than the quality.&lt;p&gt;If you incentivize researchers to publish papers, individuals will find ways to game the system, meeting the minimum quality bar, while taking the least effort to create the most papers and thereby receive the greatest reward.&lt;p&gt;Similarly, if you reward content creators based on views, you will get view maximization behaviors.  If you reward ad placement based on impressions, you will see gaming for impressions.&lt;p&gt;Bad metrics or bad rewards cause bad behavior.&lt;p&gt;We see this over and over because the reward issuers are designing systems to optimize for their upstream metrics.&lt;p&gt;Put differently, the online world is optimized for algorithms, not humans.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2025 16:20:20 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45782897</link><dc:creator>efitz</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45782897</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45782897</guid></item><item><title>New comment by UniverseHacker in "You can't refuse to be scanned by ICE's facial recognition app, DHS document say"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Per thousands of videos on social media, it doesn’t matter what your rights are anymore, if you try to ask for them ICE will just become even more sadistic and violent, and the DOJ/government will refuse to cooperate in bringing them to justice for denying you your rights- you have no rights or recourse anymore even as a citizen. Moreover, the agents are masked and refuse to self identify as the law requires so you will never be able to say who violated your rights- they are hiding their identities because they are committing crimes. They are not police that follow laws, they are state sponsored white supremacist terrorists.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2025 15:43:25 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45782563</link><dc:creator>UniverseHacker</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45782563</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45782563</guid></item><item><title>New comment by jvanderbot in "Updated practice for review articles and position papers in ArXiv CS category"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;For &lt;i&gt;position&lt;/i&gt; (opinion) or &lt;i&gt;review&lt;/i&gt; (summarizing state of art and often laden with opinions on categories and future directions). LLMs would be happy to generate both these because they require zero technical contributions, working code, validated results, etc.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2025 15:26:39 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45782402</link><dc:creator>jvanderbot</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45782402</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45782402</guid></item><item><title>New comment by Sharlin in "Updated practice for review articles and position papers in ArXiv CS category"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;So what they no longer accept is preprints (or rejects…) It’s of course a pretty big deal given that arXiv &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; all about preprints. And an accepted journal paper presumably cannot be submitted  to arXiv anyway unless it’s an open journal.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2025 15:18:54 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45782329</link><dc:creator>Sharlin</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45782329</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45782329</guid></item><item><title>New comment by thomascountz in "Updated practice for review articles and position papers in ArXiv CS category"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;The HN submission title is incorrect.&lt;p&gt;&gt; Before being considered for submission to arXiv’s CS category, review articles and position papers must now be accepted at a journal or a conference and complete successful peer review.&lt;p&gt;Edit: original title was "arXiv No Longer Accepts Computer Science Position or Review Papers Due to LLMs"&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2025 15:11:50 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45782265</link><dc:creator>thomascountz</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45782265</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45782265</guid></item><item><title>New comment by lambdaone in "Hard Rust requirements from May onward"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;It's about time. Critical infrastructure still written in C - particularly code that parses data from untrusted sources - is technical debt that is only going to get worse over time. It's not as if Rust is that much more difficult to write than C. Rust is explicitly designed to be what you'd get if you were to re-create C knowing what we know now about language design and code safety.&lt;p&gt;If 32-bit x86 support can be dropped for pragmatic reasons, so can these architectures. If people really, really want to preserve these architectures as ongoing platforms for the future, they need to step up and create a backend for the Rust toolchain that supports them.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2025 14:55:43 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45782109</link><dc:creator>lambdaone</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45782109</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45782109</guid></item><item><title>New comment by asa400 in "SQLite concurrency and why you should care about it"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;In SQLite, transactions by default start in “deferred” mode. This means they do not take a write lock until they attempt to perform a write.&lt;p&gt;You get SQLITE_BUSY when transaction #1 starts in read mode, transaction #2 starts in write mode, and then transaction #1 attempts to upgrade from read to write mode while transaction #2 still holds the write lock.&lt;p&gt;The fix is to set a busy_timeout and to begin any transaction that does a write (any write, even if it is not the first operation in the transaction) in “immediate” mode rather than “deferred” mode.&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://zeroclarkthirty.com/2024-10-19-sqlite-database-is-locked" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://zeroclarkthirty.com/2024-10-19-sqlite-database-is-lo...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2025 13:32:31 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45781519</link><dc:creator>asa400</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45781519</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45781519</guid></item><item><title>New comment by hexbin010 in "You can't refuse to be scanned by ICE's facial recognition app, DHS document say"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&gt; “ICE officials have told us that an apparent biometric match by Mobile Fortify is a ‘definitive’ determination of a person’s status and that an ICE officer may ignore evidence of American citizenship—including a birth certificate—if the app says the person is an alien,”&lt;p&gt;This is "computer says no (not a citizen)". Which is horrifying&lt;p&gt;They've just created an app to justify what they were already doing right? And the argument will be "well it's a super complex app run by a very clever company so it can't be wrong"?&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2025 13:30:10 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45781498</link><dc:creator>hexbin010</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45781498</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45781498</guid></item><item><title>New comment by noodlesUK in "You can't refuse to be scanned by ICE's facial recognition app, DHS document say"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;This is going to be a huge pain. The US has a very fragmented identity system, and "move fast and break things" approaches like this to bring information from across government systems well outside the scope of what that information was collected for will result in real problems.&lt;p&gt;I worry what this app and systems like it might mean for me. I'm a US citizen, but I used to be an LPR. I never naturalized - I got my citizenship automatically by operation of law (INA 320, the child citizenship act). At some point I stopped being noodlesUK (LPR) and magically became noodlesUK (US Citizen), but not through the normal process. Presumably this means that there are entries in USCIS's systems that are orphaned, that likely indicate that I am an LPR who has abandoned their status, or at least been very bad about renewing their green card.&lt;p&gt;I fear that people in similar situations to my own might have a camera put in their face, some old database record that has no chance of being updated will be returned, and the obvious evidence in front of an officer's eyes, such as a US passport will be ignored. There are probably millions of people in similar situations to me, and millions more with even more complex statuses.&lt;p&gt;I know people who have multiple citizenships with multiple names, similar to this person: &lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45531721"&gt;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45531721&lt;/a&gt;. Will these hastily deployed systems be able to cope with the complex realities of real people?&lt;p&gt;EDIT: LPR is lawful permanent resident, i.e., green card holder&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2025 12:39:26 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45781183</link><dc:creator>noodlesUK</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45781183</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45781183</guid></item><item><title>New comment by shipman05 in "Addiction Markets"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;It feels like banning advertising for gambling would be a sweet spot between harm reduction and maintaining individual liberty.&lt;p&gt;Sports gambling ads have ruined sports media. State lottery ads are even worse. The government should not spend money to encourage its own citizens to partake in harmful activities.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2025 00:43:41 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45778266</link><dc:creator>shipman05</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45778266</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45778266</guid></item><item><title>New comment by Humorist2290 in "Addiction Markets"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;  But if you want to outlaw this harmful activity [licensed gambling], you have to find a way to replace 6.4% of Maryland’s budget, which is slightly less than the entire amount the state brings in from corporate taxes.
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
A fraction of the proceeds of losing bets from a fraction of Maryland's citizens contributes almost the same to state services -- EMS, education, road maintenance, etc -- than the total corporate taxes levied on all businesses.&lt;p&gt;Do I misunderstand, or is this just actually incredible?&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2025 23:50:46 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45777973</link><dc:creator>Humorist2290</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45777973</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45777973</guid></item><item><title>New comment by asimops in "A theoretical way to circumvent Android developer verification"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;While it is technically feasible, it is not a good idea to try and find a technical solution to a people/organisation problem.&lt;p&gt;Do not accept the premise of assholes.&lt;p&gt;I hope we can get the EU to fund a truly open Android Fork. Maybe under some organisation similar to NL Labs.&lt;p&gt;--- edit ---&lt;p&gt;Furthermore, the need for a trustworthy binary to be auditable to a certain hash or something would make banning this a simple task if Google would want to go that route.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2025 21:30:36 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45776925</link><dc:creator>asimops</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45776925</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45776925</guid></item><item><title>New comment by j1elo in "Apple reports fourth quarter results"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I really don't get how people do research work (like finding good flight tickets, or comparing hotels to stay in for a trip) without a computer. I really cannot stand seeing websites in a small screen without the ability to quickly open 4 browser windows with 4 tabs each for different combinations of dates, for example.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2025 20:35:51 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45776423</link><dc:creator>j1elo</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45776423</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45776423</guid></item><item><title>New comment by dr_pardee in "My Impressions of the MacBook Pro M4"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&gt; I still don’t like macOS and would prefer to run Linux on this laptop. But Asahi Linux still needs some work before it’s usable for me (I need external display output, and M4 support). This doesn’t bother me too much, though, as I don’t use this computer for serious work.&lt;p&gt;“I don’t use this computer for serious work.” Dropped $3K on MBP to play around with. Definitely should have gotten MBA&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2025 19:33:50 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45775823</link><dc:creator>dr_pardee</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45775823</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45775823</guid></item><item><title>New comment by LeoPanthera in "My Impressions of the MacBook Pro M4"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Historically, traditional matte screen finishes exhibited poor optical qualities by scattering ambient light, which tended to wash out colors. This scattering process also affected the light from individual pixels, causing it to refract into neighboring pixels.&lt;p&gt;This reduced overall image quality and caused pixel-fine details, such as small text, to appear smeary on high-density LCDs. In contrast, well-designed glossy displays provide a superior visual experience by minimizing internal refraction and reflecting ambient light at high angles, which reduces display pollution. Consequently, glossy screens often appear much brighter, blacks appear blacker without being washed out, colors show a higher dynamic range, and small details remain crisper. High-quality glass glossy displays are often easy to use even in full daylight, and reflections are manageable because they are full optical reflections with correct depth, allowing the user to focus on the screen content.&lt;p&gt;Apple's "nano texture" matte screens were engineered to solve the specific optical problems of traditional matte finishes, the washed-out colors and smeary details. But they cost more to make. The glossy option is still available, and still good.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2025 19:16:00 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45775641</link><dc:creator>LeoPanthera</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45775641</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45775641</guid></item><item><title>New comment by rottencupcakes in "My Impressions of the MacBook Pro M4"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;It's classic Apple to spend over a decade insisting that that glossy screens were the best option, and then to eventually roll out a matte screen as a "premium" feature with a bunch of marketing around it.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2025 19:00:49 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45775475</link><dc:creator>rottencupcakes</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45775475</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45775475</guid></item><item><title>New comment by lyricaljoke in "Just use a button"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;My very similar pet peeve is about websites that use `onclick` handlers and similar to implement navigation.  Just use a damn anchor tag, which gets you correct link behavior for free:&lt;p&gt;* works with middle click for new tab&lt;p&gt;* integrates with accessibility devices&lt;p&gt;* works with right click + open in new window or similar options&lt;p&gt;* etc. etc. etc.&lt;p&gt;If it's notionally navigation, don't use javascript soup: use a link.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2025 18:27:02 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45775130</link><dc:creator>lyricaljoke</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45775130</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45775130</guid></item><item><title>New comment by GolfPopper in "Fire TV: Amazon to block piracy apps in the future"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Piracy is just the excuse. What they're saying is that Amazon will allow a collection of corporations (including Amazon) to decide what you're allowed to do with the hardware they pretended to let you buy.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2025 17:44:58 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45774667</link><dc:creator>GolfPopper</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45774667</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45774667</guid></item><item><title>New comment by mentalgear in "Another European agency shifts off US Tech as digital sovereignty gains steam"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Why would ANY global business still rely on U.S. Tech? The U.S. government, through their executive orders and dissolving of the separations of powers, has demonstrated its ability to unilaterally disrupt or shut down private technology services at will. How can any business justify depending on U.S.-based tech infrastructure when its access could vanish overnight on a political whim by an unstable president?&lt;p&gt;If there is no rule of law, capital, talent and trust are flowing out of that country - for good reason.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2025 17:38:19 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45774588</link><dc:creator>mentalgear</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45774588</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45774588</guid></item><item><title>New comment by HEmanZ in "Attention lapses due to sleep deprivation due to flushing fluid from brain"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I hope that the actual medical field starts taking note of this.&lt;p&gt;My wife still has to work 24 hour shifts with no sleep, performing emergency surgeries no matter how long it has been since she slept. During residency only a few years ago she and her co-residents were almost weekly required to do 36 hour shifts (on top of their regular 16 hours per day, 5 day per week schedule) and once even a 48 hour shift when the hospital was short staffed.&lt;p&gt;Of course I’m sure they won’t. No one cares if doctors are over worked.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2025 16:26:22 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45773856</link><dc:creator>HEmanZ</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45773856</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45773856</guid></item><item><title>New comment by earless1 in "Attention lapses due to sleep deprivation due to flushing fluid from brain"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;So biological garbage collection pauses then? skip sleep, and the brain tries to run gc cycles during runtime. Causing attention and performance latency spikes. Evolution wrote the original JVM.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2025 14:40:32 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45772465</link><dc:creator>earless1</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45772465</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45772465</guid></item><item><title>New comment by jacquesm in "How OpenAI uses complex and circular deals to fuel its multibillion-dollar rise"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;These kinds of deals were very much a la mode just prior to the .com crash. Companies would buy advertising, then the websites and ad agencies would buy their services and they'd spend it again on advertising. The end result is immense revenues without profits.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2025 14:01:53 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45772081</link><dc:creator>jacquesm</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45772081</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45772081</guid></item><item><title>New comment by rendaw in "John Carmack on mutable variables"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I think the explanation is: When you mutate variables it implicitly creates an ordering dependency - later uses of the variable rely on previous mutations. However, this is an implicit dependency that isn't modeled by the language so reordering won't cause any errors.&lt;p&gt;With a very basic concrete example:&lt;p&gt;x = 7&lt;p&gt;x = x + 3&lt;p&gt;x = x / 2&lt;p&gt;Vs&lt;p&gt;x = 7&lt;p&gt;x1 = x + 3&lt;p&gt;x2 = x1 / 2&lt;p&gt;Reordering the first will have no error, but you'll get the wrong result. The second will produce an error if you try to reorder the statements.&lt;p&gt;Another way to look at it is that in the first example, the 3rd calculation doesn't have "x" as a dependency but rather "x in the state where addition has already been completed" (i.e. it's 3 different x's that all share the same name). Doing single assignment is just making this explicit.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2025 11:40:49 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45770924</link><dc:creator>rendaw</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45770924</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45770924</guid></item><item><title>New comment by EastLondonCoder in "John Carmack on mutable variables"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;After a 2 year Clojure stint I find it very hard to explain the clarity that comes with immutability for programmers used to trigger effects with a mutation.&lt;p&gt;I think it may be one of those things you have to see in order to understand.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2025 09:30:29 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45770007</link><dc:creator>EastLondonCoder</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45770007</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45770007</guid></item><item><title>New comment by fouronnes3 in "Rouille – Rust Programming, in French"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;As a native french speaker, I feel so uneasy reading source code in french. It feels very very uncanny. I've often wondered if English native speakers feel the same when reading normal source code which is always in English. They probably don't. But how? I've always associated the "other language-ness" to correctness and technicality. It must be so weird to code in your own language. Feels like reading bad pseudo code. It's very nice to be able to map "english" to "technical, correct" and "native language" to "descriptive, approximate, comments, pseudo-code". Having only a single language to work with is like removing a color from the rainbow.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2025 07:48:30 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45769332</link><dc:creator>fouronnes3</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45769332</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45769332</guid></item><item><title>New comment by ineedasername in "Denmark reportedly withdraws Chat Control proposal following controversy"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I’m continually astounded that so many people, faced with a societal problem, reflexively turn to “Hmmm, perhaps if we monitored and read and listened to every single thing that every person does, all of the time…”&lt;p&gt;As though it would 1) be a practical possibility and 2) be effective.&lt;p&gt;Compounding the issue is that the more technology can solve #1, the more these people fixate on it as the solution without regards to the lack of #2.&lt;p&gt;I wish there were a way, once and for all, to prevent this ridiculous idea from taking hold over and over again. If I could get a hold of such people when these ideas were in their infancy… perhaps I should monitor everything everyone does and watch for people considering the same as a solution to &lt;i&gt;their&lt;/i&gt; problem… ah well, no, still don’t see how that follows logically as a reasonable solution.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2025 03:35:45 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45768131</link><dc:creator>ineedasername</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45768131</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45768131</guid></item><item><title>New comment by ipython in "Ground stop at JFK due to staffing"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;My concern is that we will end up in a state of perpetual government "shutdown". The republicans, instead of reopening the entire government, will simply choose agencies to fund in order to keep the pain felt by the American people just low enough so they don't get fired (ala office space).&lt;p&gt;Once that happens, Congress has basically iced itself out. Oversight from unfriendly government agencies? No worries, they're shut down because they're unpaid. And clearly this demonstrates the executive needs more power, since Congress is completely frozen. Finally, the Supreme Court is no longer an issue either, since that's not funded either.&lt;p&gt;Someone tell me why this couldn't happen.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2025 03:05:58 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45767903</link><dc:creator>ipython</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45767903</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45767903</guid></item><item><title>New comment by yndoendo in "Ground stop at JFK due to staffing"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Who knew electing shitty representation leads to a shitty environment and economy? I wish those effected by the shitty government the best&lt;p&gt;Forcing people to work and not pay them is slavery!&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2025 02:50:32 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45767812</link><dc:creator>yndoendo</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45767812</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45767812</guid></item><item><title>New comment by SurceBeats in "ICE and the Smartphone Panopticon"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;The ICEBlock removal is absurd when you consider Waze has been warning drivers about police locations for... Years? The only difference is which government agency is being monitored. This sets a dangerous precedent for selective enforcement of ToS really&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2025 02:42:05 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45767762</link><dc:creator>SurceBeats</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45767762</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45767762</guid></item><item><title>New comment by derbOac in "Leaker reveals which Pixels are vulnerable to Cellebrite phone hacking"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;They couldn't answer the question most on my mind: "We’ve reached out to Google to inquire about why a custom ROM created by volunteers is more resistant to industrial phone hacking than the official Pixel OS. We’ll update this article if Google has anything to say."&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 23:39:27 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45766747</link><dc:creator>derbOac</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45766747</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45766747</guid></item></channel></rss>