<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>Hacker News: Best Comments</title><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/bestcomments</link><description>Hacker News RSS</description><docs>https://hnrss.org/</docs><generator>hnrss v2.1.1</generator><lastBuildDate>Sun, 21 Dec 2025 00:00:05 +0000</lastBuildDate><ns0:link href="https://hnrss.org/bestcomments" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item><title>New comment by crazygringo in "Backing Up Spotify"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;This is insane.&lt;p&gt;I definitely was not aware Spotify DRM had been cracked to enable downloading at scale like this.&lt;p&gt;The thing is, this doesn't even seem particularly useful for average consumers/listeners, since Spotify itself is so convenient, and trying to locate individual tracks in massive torrent files of presumably 10,000's of tracks each sounds horrible.&lt;p&gt;But this &lt;i&gt;does&lt;/i&gt; seem like it will be a godsend for researchers working on things like music classification and generation. The only thing is, you can't really publicly admit exactly what dataset you trained/tested on...?&lt;p&gt;Definitely wondering if this was in response to desire from AI researchers/companies who wanted this stuff. Or if the major record labels already license their entire catalogs for training purposes cheaply enough, so this really is just solely intended as a preservation effort?&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 20 Dec 2025 19:50:17 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46338973</link><dc:creator>crazygringo</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46338973</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46338973</guid></item><item><title>New comment by jimnotgym in "Airbus to migrate critical apps to a sovereign Euro cloud"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Freeloading?&lt;p&gt;My country spends less on defence as a percentage of GDP than the US. But it spends much of that with US companies.  This is not Freeloading. It was a deal. Cancel TSR-2, and buy American and we will lend you some money. Cancel your nuclear program and buy US submarine launched missiles and we will help you look after yourself.  Now let Visa and Mastercard skim off all your transactions and we will keep you secure to keep the money flowing. Sweetheart tax deals for US companies to operate,  and we will keep you safe to keep the money flowing. It is not Freeloading, it is colonialism&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 20 Dec 2025 10:46:41 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46335170</link><dc:creator>jimnotgym</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46335170</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46335170</guid></item><item><title>New comment by arn3n in "NTP at NIST Boulder Has Lost Power"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Wind gusts were reaching 125 MPH in Boulder county, if anyone’s curious. A lot of power was shut off preemptively to prevent downed power lines from starting wildfires. Energy providers gave warning to locals in advance. Shame that NIST’s backup generator failed, though.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 20 Dec 2025 09:48:31 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46334864</link><dc:creator>arn3n</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46334864</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46334864</guid></item><item><title>New comment by breve in "Airbus to migrate critical apps to a sovereign Euro cloud"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;A necessary step to reduce risk to infrastructure given that the US government has become erratic and has decided it is now anti-Europe.&lt;p&gt;The US means to undermine the EU: &lt;a href="https://www.dw.com/en/will-trump-pull-italy-austria-poland-hungary-from-eu/a-75134777" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://www.dw.com/en/will-trump-pull-italy-austria-poland-h...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;The US means to annex European territory: &lt;a href="https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/c0j9l08902eo" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/c0j9l08902eo&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;It's the same reason you don't want Chinese equipment in your telecommunications infrastructure. You can't trust what the Chinese government will do to it or with it.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 20 Dec 2025 09:42:30 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46334831</link><dc:creator>breve</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46334831</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46334831</guid></item><item><title>New comment by autarch in "NTP at NIST Boulder Has Lost Power"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Time travel is extremely dangerous right now. I highly recommend deferring time travel plans except for extreme temporal emergencies.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 20 Dec 2025 09:42:08 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46334829</link><dc:creator>autarch</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46334829</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46334829</guid></item><item><title>New comment by flumpcakes in "Airbus to migrate critical apps to a sovereign Euro cloud"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Some people in the US deride it's close allies as "freeloaders" because they choose to use and buy US tech, reinforcing the US's position as a global powerhouse. (Meanwhile US tech is built on the shoulders of their allies.) Now we see these same allies are starting to look inward and invest in technology they own completely because the US is acting decisively not like an ally. Something unthinkable since WW2.&lt;p&gt;I don't see this news as anything but a good thing. For every technology out there, the EU needs a native alternative. It's clear the current US administration wants to make the EU worse based on a politics of grievance.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 20 Dec 2025 09:32:32 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46334787</link><dc:creator>flumpcakes</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46334787</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46334787</guid></item><item><title>New comment by BrenBarn in "Android introduces $2-4 install fee and 10–20% cut for US external content links"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;The fact that this is being introduced after the whole Epic/Apple thing clearly shows that the penalties in that case were not nearly severe enough and the standards set were not nearly stringent enough.  The mere attempt to engage in policies like this should result in fines in the hundreds of billions.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 20 Dec 2025 07:12:46 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46334197</link><dc:creator>BrenBarn</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46334197</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46334197</guid></item><item><title>New comment by hirsin in "Android introduces $2-4 install fee and 10–20% cut for US external content links"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;The apparent information gathering and brutal review process is unbelievable here. If I'm understanding this correctly, the requirement is that eg Epic Game Store must register and upload every single APK for every app they offer, and cannot offer it in their store until Google approves it, which may take a week or more - including every time the app updates.&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile they get full competitive insight into which apps are being added to Epics store, their download rates apparently, and they even get the APKs to boot, potentially making it easier for those app devs to onboard if they like, and can pressure them to do so by dragging their feet on that review process.&lt;p&gt;&gt; Provide direct, publicly accessible customer support to end users through readily accessible communication channels.&lt;p&gt;This is an interesting requirement. I want to see someone provide the same level of support that Google does to see if it draws a ban.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 20 Dec 2025 06:43:19 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46334110</link><dc:creator>hirsin</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46334110</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46334110</guid></item><item><title>New comment by culi in "CSS Grid Lanes"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Props to the Safari team. They surprised us all when they suddenly shot to the top of interop-2025 this October&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://wpt.fyi/interop-2025" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://wpt.fyi/interop-2025&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Dec 2025 23:38:53 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46332259</link><dc:creator>culi</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46332259</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46332259</guid></item><item><title>New comment by noname123 in "Brown/MIT shooting suspect found dead, officials say"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I work on campus (very very close to the engineering building) and I previously lived near Brookline. So all of this hits home.&lt;p&gt;But what got me was the tipster who blew wide open the case is reportedly a homeless Brown graduate who lived in the basement of the engineering building (a la South Korean film Parasite). It made me so sad but also not surprised, that building does have a single occupancy bathroom with showers; and no keycard access was needed in the evening until 7pm.&lt;p&gt;So it made sense to me that he or she would've used that building for shelter and comfort. Also it didn't boggle my mind at all that a Brown grad (from the picture, the tipster looked like a artistic Brown student vs. the careerist type) would be homeless - given that I known many of my classmates who have a certain personality, brilliant but also idealistic/uncompromising that made them brittle unfortunately in a society that rewards conformity, settling and stability.&lt;p&gt;I can't get over the fact that two Brown student whom presumably have fallen on the wayside of society have chosen two different paths, (1) the homeless guy who still perseveres even in the basement of Barrus &amp; Holley for 15 years a la Parasite after 2010 graduation but still has the situational awareness and rises to the occasion to give the biggest tip to the Providence Police, (2) the other guy who harbors so much resentment over a course of 25 years to plan a trip from Florida to gun down innocent kids who are 18 and 19 and his classmate when they were 18 and 19 year old.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Dec 2025 21:03:12 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46330891</link><dc:creator>noname123</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46330891</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46330891</guid></item><item><title>New comment by Aliabid94 in "Brown/MIT shooting suspect found dead, officials say"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Worth noting that a partner at Sequoia (Shaun Maguire) publicly accused the wrong guy of being the shooter.&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.fastcompany.com/91463942/sequoia-shaun-maguire-brown-university-shooter-palestine" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://www.fastcompany.com/91463942/sequoia-shaun-maguire-b...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Dec 2025 20:57:03 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46330824</link><dc:creator>Aliabid94</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46330824</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46330824</guid></item><item><title>New comment by koakuma-chan in "Rust's Block Pattern"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I have one better: the try block pattern.&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://doc.rust-lang.org/beta/unstable-book/language-features/try-blocks.html" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://doc.rust-lang.org/beta/unstable-book/language-featur...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Dec 2025 20:31:01 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46330537</link><dc:creator>koakuma-chan</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46330537</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46330537</guid></item><item><title>New comment by rao-v in "TP-Link Tapo C200: Hardcoded Keys, Buffer Overflows and Privacy"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I'm a little frustrated with articles like this that scattershot their critique by conflating genuine failures with problems that even FAANGs struggle with.&lt;p&gt;In particular, I don't love it when an article attacks a best practice as a cheap gotcha:&lt;p&gt;"and this time it was super easy! After some basic reversing of the Tapo Android app, I found out that TP-Link have their entire firmware repository in an open S3 bucket. No authentication required. So, you can list and download every version of every firmware they’ve ever released for any device they ever produced"&lt;p&gt;That is a good thing - don't encourage security through obscurity! The impact of an article like this is as likely to get management to prescribe a ham-handed mandate to lock down firmware as it is to get them to properly upgrade their security practices.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Dec 2025 20:20:03 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46330416</link><dc:creator>rao-v</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46330416</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46330416</guid></item><item><title>New comment by jonathannorris in "Graphite is joining Cursor"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Yeah, hard disagree on that one, based on recent surveys, 80-90% of developers globally use IDEs over CLIs for their day-to-day work.&lt;p&gt;I was pretty worried about Cursor's business until they launched their Composer 1 model, which is fine-tuned to work amazingly well in their IDE. It's significantly faster than using any other model, and it's clearly fine-tuned for the type of work people use Cursor for. They are also clearly charging a premium for it and making a healthy margin on it, but for how fast + good it's totally worth it.&lt;p&gt;Composer 1 + now eventually creating an AI native version of GitHub with Graphite, that's a serious business, with a much clearer picture to me how Cursor gets to serious profitability vs the AI labs.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Dec 2025 17:41:14 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46328603</link><dc:creator>jonathannorris</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46328603</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46328603</guid></item><item><title>New comment by laser9 in "Hacker News front page now, but the titles are honest"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;A good Friday morning laugh! I think the tiles are not just honest, they are brutally honest. Some of my fav ones:&lt;p&gt;- Amazon finally adds a feature that has been standard since 2005&lt;p&gt;- Texas accidentally does something good for privacy&lt;p&gt;Would it possible to add a feature where hovering over a title displays the original title?&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Dec 2025 16:31:02 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46327626</link><dc:creator>laser9</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46327626</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46327626</guid></item><item><title>New comment by zeroonetwothree in "Graphite is joining Cursor"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;We’ve heard this many times before with other acquisitions so don’t be upset if people are a bit skeptical.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Dec 2025 16:23:56 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46327523</link><dc:creator>zeroonetwothree</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46327523</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46327523</guid></item><item><title>New comment by jvanderbot in "Hacker News front page now, but the titles are honest"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;OK, so the "Storing data in the network ... " title made me remember something.&lt;p&gt;If you transmit a message to Mars, say a rover command sequence, and the outgoing buffer is deleted on the sending side (the original code is preserved, but the transmission-encoded sequence doesn't stick around), then that data, for 20-90 minutes, exists nowhere _except_ space. It's just random-looking electrical fluctuations that are propagating through whatever is out there until it hits a conducting piece of metal millions of miles away and energizes a cap bank enough to be measured by a digital circuit and reconstructed into data.&lt;p&gt;So, if you calculate the data rate (9600 baud, even), and set up a loopback/echo transmitter on Mars, you could store ~4 MB "in space".  If you're using lasers, it's &gt;100x as much.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Dec 2025 15:53:04 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46327158</link><dc:creator>jvanderbot</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46327158</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46327158</guid></item><item><title>New comment by BeaverGoose in "Hacker News front page now, but the titles are honest"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;"Please star my repo so I can get a job" is brutal&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Dec 2025 15:45:22 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46327064</link><dc:creator>BeaverGoose</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46327064</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46327064</guid></item><item><title>New comment by egeozcan in "Amazon will allow ePub and PDF downloads for DRM-free eBooks"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;A friend of mine received a double shipment for a $300 order. Being honest, he contacted customer service to arrange a return. Everything seemed fine until a few days later when he noticed they had also refunded his original payment. He reached out again to let them know, and they said they’d just recharge his card. Apparently, that transaction failed (no clear reason why), and without any warning, they banned his account, wiping out his entire Kindle library in the process. Amazon works wonderfully right up until it fails spectacularly.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Dec 2025 13:08:58 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46325413</link><dc:creator>egeozcan</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46325413</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46325413</guid></item><item><title>New comment by icqFDR in "Amazon will allow ePub and PDF downloads for DRM-free eBooks"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I’d advise anyone buying e-books on Amazon to think it through carefully. My account was banned recently because, years ago, I ordered two paper books that Amazon said would be split into two shipments. Both books arrived without any issues, but later Amazon refunded me for one of them, claiming that one package never arrived. This happened 4–5 years ago.&lt;p&gt;Apparently, during a recent review, they decided this counted as fraud and banned my account. As a result, I can no longer log in and lost access to all my Kindle e-books. They also remotely wiped my Kindle, so my entire library is gone. I appealed the decision, but I’ve been waiting for over six months with no resolution.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Dec 2025 12:49:46 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46325241</link><dc:creator>icqFDR</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46325241</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46325241</guid></item><item><title>New comment by thomasahle in "Texas is suing all of the big TV makers for spying on what you watch"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;ACR — Automatic Content Recognition: tech in some smart TVs/apps that identifies what’s on-screen (often via audio/video “fingerprints”) and can report viewing data back to vendors/partners.&lt;p&gt;VPPA — Video Privacy Protection Act: a U.S. law aimed at limiting disclosure of people’s video-viewing/rental history.&lt;p&gt;HDCP — High-bandwidth Digital Content Protection: an anti-copy protocol used on HDMI/DisplayPort links to prevent interception/recording of protected video.&lt;p&gt;DRM — Digital Rights Management: a broad term for technical restrictions controlling how digital media can be accessed, copied, or shared.&lt;p&gt;MPAA — Motion Picture Association of America: the former name of the main U.S. film-industry trade group (now typically called the MPA, Motion Picture Association).&lt;p&gt;TV / TVs — Television(s).&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Dec 2025 08:56:54 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46323710</link><dc:creator>thomasahle</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46323710</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46323710</guid></item><item><title>New comment by tliltocatl in "Firefox will have an option to disable all AI features"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I think people screaming "but AI is the future" doesn't recognize what the problem is. The problem is not AI. The problem is that Mozilla keeps jumping on fads instead of focusing on their browser core. There are a tons of "we bundled all the latest crap" Chrome forks out there. Nobody needs more those. Stop pushing bells and whistles. Give us more extensibility instead. Keep supporting v2 manifest and add more. There were genuine technical reasons for why XUL and NPAPI had to die, but we need an equally powerful alternative.&lt;p&gt;And yea, having a faint through about removing adblock support, yet alone speaking it aloud is a really bad sign for Mozilla's future.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Dec 2025 08:55:45 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46323706</link><dc:creator>tliltocatl</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46323706</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46323706</guid></item><item><title>New comment by bjackman in "Getting bitten by Intel's poor naming schemes"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I work in CPU security and it's the same with microarchitecture. You wanna know if a machine is vulnerable to a certain issue?&lt;p&gt;- The technical experts (including Intel engineers) will say something like "it affects Blizzard Creek and Windy Bluff models'&lt;p&gt;- Intel's technical docs will say "if CPUID leaf 0x3aa asserts bit 63 then the CPU is affected". (There is no database for this you can only find it out by actually booting one up).&lt;p&gt;- The spec sheet for the hardware calls it a "Xeon Osmiridium X36667-IA"&lt;p&gt;Absolutely none of these forms of naming have any way to correlate between them. They also have different names for the same shit depending on whether it's a consumer or server chip.&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile, AMD's part numbers contain a digit that increments with each year but is off-by-one with regard to the "Zen" brand version.&lt;p&gt;Usually I just ask the LLM and accept that it's wrong 20% of the time.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Dec 2025 06:24:52 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46322816</link><dc:creator>bjackman</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46322816</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46322816</guid></item><item><title>New comment by hhoorzad in "2026 Apple introducing more ads to increase opportunity in search results"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&gt; I’d rather pay an extra $100 for the phone than have ads all over it.&lt;p&gt;In all likelihood, we will pay an extra $100 AND have ads.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Dec 2025 06:16:10 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46322766</link><dc:creator>hhoorzad</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46322766</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46322766</guid></item><item><title>New comment by yanhangyhy in "How China built its ‘Manhattan Project’ to rival the West in AI chips"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Domestically, we often put it this way: since it wasn’t made by God, we can definitely make it ourselves. It’s only a matter of time — if not this year, then next year; if we can’t do it next year, we’ll just keep going. This is how we approach everything.&lt;p&gt;There is a small caveat, though. China was not actually that far behind in the semiconductor field in the past. The problem was that corruption and fraudulent projects were quite serious, which undermined the Chinese government’s confidence in these efforts. A few years ago, there was even a so-called “transparent computing” scam project that was awarded a national-level prize.&lt;p&gt;Corruption and fraud can slow China’s progress, but they will not affect the final outcome. This is because it is not only a government policy, but also a Chinese way of thinking. Nothing can interrupt this process.&lt;p&gt;In fact, aside from high-end chips, China already dominates the mid- and low-end chip segments.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Dec 2025 05:56:08 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46322672</link><dc:creator>yanhangyhy</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46322672</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46322672</guid></item><item><title>New comment by al_borland in "2026 Apple introducing more ads to increase opportunity in search results"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I’m really not a fan of this direction for Apple. One of the differentiators between iOS and Google was a lack of ads, which make the experience feel more premium. Increasing ads, or having them at all, really erodes the user experience.&lt;p&gt;Apple managed to become the most valuable company in the world without ads. Adding them after hitting that milestone feels either greedy or desperate, maybe a little of both. I know the ads themselves aren’t new, but the steady increase is a worrying trend.&lt;p&gt;I’d rather pay an extra $100 for the phone than have ads all over it.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Dec 2025 05:45:31 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46322597</link><dc:creator>al_borland</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46322597</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46322597</guid></item><item><title>New comment by seizethecheese in "History LLMs: Models trained exclusively on pre-1913 texts"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&gt; Imagine you could interview thousands of educated individuals from 1913—readers of newspapers, novels, and political treatises—about their views on peace, progress, gender roles, or empire. Not just survey them with preset questions, but engage in open-ended dialogue, probe their assumptions, and explore the boundaries of thought in that moment.&lt;p&gt;Hell yeah, sold, let’s go…&lt;p&gt;&gt; We're developing a responsible access framework that makes models available to researchers for scholarly purposes while preventing misuse.&lt;p&gt;Oh. By “imagine you could interview…” they didn’t mean me.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Dec 2025 04:42:50 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46322339</link><dc:creator>seizethecheese</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46322339</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46322339</guid></item><item><title>New comment by jimmy76615 in "History LLMs: Models trained exclusively on pre-1913 texts"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&gt; We're developing a responsible access framework that makes models available to researchers for scholarly purposes while preventing misuse.&lt;p&gt;The idea of training such a model is really a great one, but not releasing it because someone might be offended by the output is just stupid beyond believe.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Dec 2025 00:54:50 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46320995</link><dc:creator>jimmy76615</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46320995</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46320995</guid></item><item><title>New comment by nneonneo in "Texas is suing all of the big TV makers for spying on what you watch"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;ACR needs to die. It’s an absurd abuse of the privileged position that a TV has - a gross violation of privacy just to make a few bucks. It should be absolutely nobody’s business to know what you watch except your own; the motivation behind the VPPA was to kill exactly this type of abuse.&lt;p&gt;The greatest irony is that HDCP goes to great lengths to try and prevent people from screenshotting copyrighted content, and here we have the smart TVs at the end just scraping the content willy-nilly. If someone manages to figure out how to use ACR to break DRM, maybe the MPAA will be motivated to kill ACR :)&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Dec 2025 00:22:44 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46320772</link><dc:creator>nneonneo</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46320772</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46320772</guid></item><item><title>New comment by saaaaaam in "History LLMs: Models trained exclusively on pre-1913 texts"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;“Time-locked models don't roleplay; they embody their training data. Ranke-4B-1913 doesn't know about WWI because WWI hasn't happened in its textual universe. It can be surprised by your questions in ways modern LLMs cannot.”&lt;p&gt;“Modern LLMs suffer from hindsight contamination. GPT-5 knows how the story ends—WWI, the League's failure, the Spanish flu.”&lt;p&gt;This is really fascinating. As someone who reads a lot of history and historical fiction I think this is really intriguing. Imagine having a conversation with someone genuinely from the period, where they don’t know the “end of the story”.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 23:16:16 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46320163</link><dc:creator>saaaaaam</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46320163</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46320163</guid></item></channel></rss>