<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>Hacker News: Best Comments</title><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/bestcomments</link><description>Hacker News RSS</description><docs>https://hnrss.org/</docs><generator>hnrss v2.1.1</generator><lastBuildDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2025 00:29:25 +0000</lastBuildDate><ns0:link href="https://hnrss.org/bestcomments" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item><title>New comment by NoraCodes in "Just let me select text"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Given that this page has the following styles which aren't applied anywhere else on the blog:&lt;p&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;   body {
       -webkit-user-select: none;
       -webkit-touch-callout: none;
       -moz-user-select: none;
       -ms-user-select: none;
       user-select: none;
    }
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
I think it's safe to assume that being unable to select text on this page is not unintentional, as several comments here assume, nor "ironic", but an intentional effort to demonstrate how annoying this behavior is.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 24 Sep 2025 14:27:00 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45360922</link><dc:creator>NoraCodes</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45360922</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45360922</guid></item><item><title>New comment by hackitup7 in "Libghostty is coming"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I love how this guy founds + takes public + sells a multibillion company and then just goes right back to hacking. Legend.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 23 Sep 2025 17:32:08 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45350260</link><dc:creator>hackitup7</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45350260</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45350260</guid></item><item><title>New comment by adastra22 in "Delete FROM users WHERE location = 'Iran';"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;OP, some context from the other side might be helpful.&lt;p&gt;Yes, there are fines for American companies if they do business with Iranians. That's how sanctions work as I'm sure you're aware. But the story doesn't stop there.&lt;p&gt;If an American finds out they are transacting with a sanctioned individual, or citizens of a sanctioned country like Iran or North Korea, the stakes go up: $1M USD fine &lt;i&gt;and up to 20 years in federal prison&lt;/i&gt;. Oh and that's a personal risk -- &lt;i&gt;you&lt;/i&gt;, the manager or executive in charge, and anyone else who is in the know on the transaction is now facing 20 years in federal pounding-in-the-ass prison if they don't immediately cease all communication and break off contact. Hence why they ghost you and remove your data from prod. It sucks, but I would do the same thing in that situation. Nobody should be expected to take that risk.&lt;p&gt;That's why you have these experiences :(&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 23 Sep 2025 05:58:38 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45343246</link><dc:creator>adastra22</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45343246</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45343246</guid></item><item><title>New comment by dansmith1919 in "You did this with an AI and you do not understand what you're doing here"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Crazy how he doubled down by just pasting badger's answer into Chat and submitting the (hilariously obvious AI) reply:&lt;p&gt;&gt; Thanks for the quick review. You’re right — my attached PoC does not exercise libcurl and therefore does not demonstrate a cURL bug. I retract the cookie overflow claim and apologize for the noise. Please close this report as invalid. If helpful, I can follow up separately with a minimal C reproducer that actually drives libcurl’s cookie parser (e.g., via an HTTP response with oversized Set-Cookie or using CURLOPT_COOKIELIST) and reference the exact function/line in lib/cookie.c should I find an issue.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 22 Sep 2025 09:51:46 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45331135</link><dc:creator>dansmith1919</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45331135</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45331135</guid></item><item><title>New comment by nomilk in "How I, a non-developer, read the tutorial you, a developer, wrote for me"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Can't recommend this approach highly enough: have someone with minimal expertise go through your docs with the goal of achieving the goal of the docs. Sit next to them or screenshare. Do not speak to them, certainly do not help, just watch. Watch them fumble. Watch them not know what to do. Watch them experience things you (the author) didn't, because you already had xyz configured on your machine and you forgot users won't have it. (even watch them pretend to know what they're supposed to do when they don't really).&lt;p&gt;If the user achieves what they need with minimal stress/guesswork/ambiguity, the docs pass. If not, note every single place they fail, address each one, and repeat &lt;i&gt;with a new user&lt;/i&gt;.&lt;p&gt;I've used FAANG docs that don't come close to passing the above criteria.&lt;p&gt;I've been incredibly grateful my org set this high bar. Especially when using docs for critical tech I only use from time to time (where I forget lots of it). Saves meetings, support inquiries, and video calls, because the user can self-serve.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 22 Sep 2025 04:15:40 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45329050</link><dc:creator>nomilk</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45329050</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45329050</guid></item><item><title>New comment by kaydub in "AI was supposed to help juniors shine. Why does it mostly make seniors stronger?"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Because juniors don't know when they're being taken down a rabbit hole. So they'll let the LLM go too deep in its hallucinations.&lt;p&gt;I have a Jr that was supposed to deploy a terraform module I built. This task has been hanging out for a while so I went to check in on them. They told me the problem they're having and asked me to take a look.&lt;p&gt;Their repo is a disaster, it's very obvious claude took them down a rabbit hole just from looking. When I asked, "Hey, why is all this python in here? The module has it self contained" and they respond with "I don't know, claude did that" affirming my assumptions.&lt;p&gt;They lack the experience and they're overly reliant on the LLM tools. Not just in the design and implementation phases but also for troubleshooting. And if you're troubleshooting with something that's hallucinating and you don't know enough to know it's hallucinating you're in for a long ride.&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile the LLM tools have taken away a lot of the type of work I hated doing. I can quickly tell when the LLM is going down a rabbit hole (in most cases at least) and prevent it from continuing. It's kinda re-lit my passion for coding and building software. So that's ended up in me producing more and giving better results.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 21 Sep 2025 16:16:33 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45324013</link><dc:creator>kaydub</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45324013</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45324013</guid></item><item><title>New comment by hellcow in "FLX1s phone is launched"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;The comments here are awful. What happened to “Hacker” news?&lt;p&gt;This is a Linux phone that actually works, running Debian. It has a battery that competes with the runtime of any modern phone. It has a snappy UI and can reliably make calls. Already it’s the best Linux phone in the world, just on that basis.&lt;p&gt;They’re selling it for the same price as the outgoing model despite tons of bullshit tariffs being levied against them. What an achievement!&lt;p&gt;I want a Linux phone that works, and I want to support a world where Linux phones exist and are financially viable to make, therefore I will buy this as my next phone.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 20 Sep 2025 13:38:41 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45313299</link><dc:creator>hellcow</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45313299</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45313299</guid></item><item><title>New comment by gejose in "Less is safer: Reducing the risk of supply chain attacks"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;This is one way to look at it, but ignores the fact that most users use third party community plugins.&lt;p&gt;Obsidian has a truly terrible security model for plugins. As I realized while building my own, Obsidian plugins have full, unrestricted access to all files in the vault.&lt;p&gt;Obsidian could've instead opted to be more 'batteries-included', at the cost of more development effort, but instead leaves this to the community, which in turn increases the attack surface significantly.&lt;p&gt;Or it could have a browser extension like manifest that declares all permissions used by the plugin, where attempting to access a permission that's not granted gets blocked.&lt;p&gt;Both of these approaches would've led to more real security to end users than "we have few third party dependencies".&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 23:42:12 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45308131</link><dc:creator>gejose</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45308131</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45308131</guid></item><item><title>New comment by roughly in "Trump to impose $100k fee for H-1B worker visas, White House says"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;The hollowing out of the middle class in the US isn't because of immigrants, it's because of a sustained campaign by capital to reduce the power of labor over the last 50-odd years and to concentrate wealth as best they can. Immigrant labor contributes to that because we've got inadequate labor protections and because we bought into the idea that lower consumer prices was a fine reason to ignore both labor and antitrust.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 21:31:12 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45306892</link><dc:creator>roughly</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45306892</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45306892</guid></item><item><title>New comment by molticrystal in "The best YouTube downloaders, and how Google silenced the press"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;The claim that Google secretly wants YouTube downloaders to work doesn't hold up. Their focus is on delivering videos across a vast range of devices without breaking playback(and even that is blurring[0]), not enabling downloads.&lt;p&gt;If you dive into the yt-dlp source code, you see the insane complexity of calculations needed to download a video. There is code to handle nsig checks, internal YouTube API quirks, and constant obfuscation that makes it a nightmare(and the maintainers heroes) to keep up.  Google frequently rejects download attempts, blocks certain devices or access methods, and breaks techniques that yt-dlp relies on.&lt;p&gt;Half the battle is working around attempts by Google to make ads unblockable, and the other half is working around their attempts to shut down downloaders. The idea of a "gray market ecosystem" they tacitly approve ignores how aggressively they tweak their systems to make downloading as unreliable as possible. If Google wanted downloaders to thrive, they wouldn't make developers jump through these hoops. Just look at the yt-dlp issue tracker overflowing with reports of broken functionality. There are no secret nods, handshakes, or other winks, as Google begins to care less and less about compatibility, the doors will close. For example, there is already a secret header used for authenticating that you are using the Google version of Chrome browser [1] [2] that will probably be expanded.&lt;p&gt;[0] Ask HN: Does anyone else notice YouTube causing 100% CPU usage and stattering?
&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45301499"&gt;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45301499&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;[1] Chrome's hidden X-Browser-Validation header reverse engineered &lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44527739"&gt;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44527739&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;[2] &lt;a href="https://github.com/dsekz/chrome-x-browser-validation-header" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://github.com/dsekz/chrome-x-browser-validation-header&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 20:49:53 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45306399</link><dc:creator>molticrystal</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45306399</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45306399</guid></item><item><title>New comment by jpadkins in "Trump to impose $100k fee for H-1B worker visas, White House says"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;The top end of H1B has been great for America.  In the last few decades, there has been growth of abuse of the program to get mid level talent at below market rates which really hurts the middle class in America.  People need to understand that most reformists don't want to get rid of the truly exceptional immigration to the US.  We need to limit the volume, especially the immigrants that are directly competing with a hollowed out middle class in the US.  Let me know if you want further reading on this topic.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 20:49:29 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45306392</link><dc:creator>jpadkins</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45306392</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45306392</guid></item><item><title>New comment by roughly in "Trump to impose $100k fee for H-1B worker visas, White House says"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I think there’s plenty of interesting debates to be had about immigration policy and its effects on the labor market, but one thing worth noting here is that the primary problem that damn near every other country on earth has isn’t immigration, it’s brain drain.&lt;p&gt;A core strategic strength of the US over the last century has been that everyone with any talent wants to come here to work, and by and large we’ve let them do so. You can argue how well that’s worked out for us - having worked with a great many extremely talented H1bs in an industry largely built by immigrants, I’d consider it pretty positive - but it damn sure hasn’t worked out well for the countries those talented folks came from.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 20:40:08 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45306289</link><dc:creator>roughly</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45306289</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45306289</guid></item><item><title>New comment by ToDougie in "Trevor Milton's Nikola case dropped by SEC following Trump pardon"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Lest we forget:&lt;p&gt;"The entire infotainment system is a HTML 5 super computer," Milton said. "That's the standard language for computer programmers around the world, so using it let's us build our own chips. And HTML 5 is very secure. Every component is linked on the data network, all speaking the same language. It's not a bunch of separate systems that somehow still manage to communicate."&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.truckinginfo.com/330475/whats-behind-the-grille-of-the-new-nikola-hydrogen-electric-truck" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://www.truckinginfo.com/330475/whats-behind-the-grille-...&lt;/a&gt; - April 24, 2019&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 15:24:45 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45302670</link><dc:creator>ToDougie</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45302670</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45302670</guid></item><item><title>New comment by Illniyar in "Help us raise $200k to free JavaScript from Oracle"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I don't get the hate here. This is practically a public service and Deno doesn't have any direct or obvious material gains from this. Definitely not more then dozens of other projects (from Chrome to Node.js to Tutorial sites and any company offering something with JS)&lt;p&gt;So what if they are a VC backed company? If you perform a public service, it's fair to ask the public for money.
No one is suggesting this money would go to fund their product.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 12:03:31 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45300639</link><dc:creator>Illniyar</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45300639</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45300639</guid></item><item><title>New comment by arghwhat in "Want to piss off your IT department? Are the links not malicious looking enough?"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Ah no need, corporate IT already make all URLs malicious looking through some microsoft "secure link" service, and constantly shows everyone shady looking prompts that constantly change and have cmd.exe windows flash in at random.&lt;p&gt;A phone call from Microsoft about my Norton anti-virus subscription putting me into debt that can only be settled with Nintendo gift cards bought in cash across 16 specific gas stations seem much more legitimate in comparison.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 09:16:50 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45299604</link><dc:creator>arghwhat</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45299604</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45299604</guid></item><item><title>New comment by fasbiner in "Slack has raised our charges by $195k per year"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;It's not a mistake that you're only reachable when your bad business practices are so heinous they go viral. You are an executive at a company that saves money by not offering customer support except when there's bad PR or a lawsuit.&lt;p&gt;Are you going to be fixing that your billing system is not human-reachable, or are you just going to be fixing this one incident while leaving the broken system as-is for everyone who didn't go viral?&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2025 17:56:43 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45292816</link><dc:creator>fasbiner</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45292816</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45292816</guid></item><item><title>New comment by evanjrowley in "Nvidia buys $5B in Intel"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Nvidia's stake in Intel could have terrible consequences. First, it is in Nvidia's interest to kill Intel's Arc graphics, and that would be very bad because it is the only thing brighing GPU prices down for consumers. Second, the death of Intel graphics / Arc would be extremely bad for Linux, because Intel's approach to GPU drivers is the best for compatibility, wheras Nvidia is actively hostile to drivers on Linux. Third, Intel is the only company marketing consumer-grade graphics virtualization (SR-IOV), and the loss of that would make Nvidia's enterprise chips the only game in town, meaning the average consumer gets less performance, less flexibility, and less security on their computers.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2025 16:22:10 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45291556</link><dc:creator>evanjrowley</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45291556</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45291556</guid></item><item><title>New comment by littlecranky67 in "Nvidia buys $5B in Intel"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;This is a death blow to the Intel GPU+AI efforts and should not be allowed by the regulators. It is clear that Intel needs the downstream, low-cost GPU market segment to have a portfolio of AI chips based on chiplets, where most defective ones end up in the consumer grade GPUs based on manufacturing yield. NVidias interest is now for Intel not to enter either the GPU market, nor the AI market -  which Intel was preparing for with its GPU efforts in recent years.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2025 14:53:28 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45290457</link><dc:creator>littlecranky67</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45290457</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45290457</guid></item><item><title>New comment by sirwhinesalot in "KDE is now my favorite desktop"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;We now live in a world where KDE looks nicer, more professional, and more consistent than the latest macOS. I don't know how that happened, and KDE isn't even particularly nice looking, but here we are.&lt;p&gt;For many years now KDE has focused on polish, bug fixing and "nice-to-have" improvements rather than major redesigns, and it paid off.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2025 13:47:40 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45289648</link><dc:creator>sirwhinesalot</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45289648</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45289648</guid></item><item><title>New comment by actionfromafar in "Slack has raised our charges by $195k per year"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Thousands of teen coders now hate Salesforce in &lt;i&gt;advance&lt;/i&gt;. This is very shortsighted.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2025 08:43:39 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45287173</link><dc:creator>actionfromafar</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45287173</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45287173</guid></item><item><title>New comment by solid_fuel in "Meta Ray-Ban Display"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Meta locked two games I already paid for - Blade &amp; Sorcery VR and Beat Saber - behind account verification on the Quest 2.  I already bought both of these, played them for a while, but now it won't let me use the headset without "verifying" my facebook account by sending them a photograph of my drivers license.  Neither of these games are online, neither allow me to interact with other users in any way.&lt;p&gt;I will never buy a Meta product again, the brand reputation is lower than dirt to me.  Even ignoring all the other awful things Meta does, they have no reason to require a verified account to play two local-only games that I already paid for.  No matter how cool glasses like these may look, I have no trust that the brand will not suddenly demand more money or information from me to continue using a product I have already purchased.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2025 04:21:18 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45285351</link><dc:creator>solid_fuel</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45285351</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45285351</guid></item><item><title>New comment by casq in "Slack has raised our charges by $195k per year"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Hi, I’m Christina, cofounder of Hack Club. We just announced this news to our community, and this post is from one of the teenagers in Hack Club.  It’s an accurate description of what’s happened, and we’re grateful to them for posting. Slack changed the terms of a special deal we were given last year to charge us for staff and volunteers (not for every teenager coding), and we built programs around that special rate. Then this spring they changed the terms to every single user without telling us or sending a new contract, and then ignored our outreach and delayed us and told us to ignore the bill and not to pay as late as Aug 29&lt;p&gt;Then, suddenly, they called us 2 days ago and said they are going to de-activate the Hack Club Slack, including all message history from 11 years, unless we pay them $50,000 USD this week and $200,000 USD/year moving forward (plus additional annual fees for new accounts, including inactive ones)&lt;p&gt;For anyone reading this, we would really appreciate any way to contact people at Salesforce to discuss time to migrate because deactivating us in 5 days destroys all the work of thousands of teen coders at Hack Club and alum unnecessarily. We are not asking for anything for free. This was an underhanded process by the sales team to raise our rate exorbitantly from a qualified educational 501(c)(3) charity serving young developers or destroy all their projects, DMs and work forever. If Salesforce’s goals have changed- ok. Give us a reasonable amount of time to migrate- and don’t club us over the head like this. We have had an 11 year great relationship with Slack- and have introduced the company to many many future engineers and founders. My email if you can help us: christina@hackclub.com&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2025 04:09:47 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45285280</link><dc:creator>casq</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45285280</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45285280</guid></item><item><title>New comment by kragen in "Slack has raised our charges by $195k per year"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Slack's business model has always been that you give them all your most critical data and they sell you access to it.  This is basically the business model of the traditional kind of ransomware, before people got better at making backups.&lt;p&gt;You probably should expect large bill increases over time from ransomware-as-a-service companies like Slack.  Not all of them—people are capable of behaving decently—but probably the nature of the category is such that you should expect it of most of them.&lt;p&gt;When switching providers is impossible, the pricing of maximum profit for the provider is the pricing where the buyer is exactly zero.  Slack presumably doesn't have quite enough information about their clients' businesses to calibrate this exactly, but if they can approach it approximately, they'll make a lot of money; even though they drive some of their customers out of business, those losses are compensated for by the higher revenues from their surviving customers.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2025 02:58:49 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45284709</link><dc:creator>kragen</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45284709</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45284709</guid></item><item><title>New comment by fn-mote in "Slack has raised our charges by $195k per year"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I was ready to be unsympathetic - too bad for the company - but then I read TFA and it's a rug pull on a nonprofit teaching coding to kids....&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://hackclub.com/" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://hackclub.com/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;(They do help clubs sell things, taking "7% of income", so they do have a revenue stream, but the money that Slack wants would pay a veritable &lt;i&gt;army&lt;/i&gt; of student interns.)&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2025 02:24:36 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45284378</link><dc:creator>fn-mote</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45284378</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45284378</guid></item><item><title>New comment by SchemaLoad in "Meta Ray-Ban Display"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&gt;Meta Ray-Ban Display glasses are designed to help you look up and stay present. With a quick glance at the in-lens display, you can accomplish everyday tasks—like checking messages, previewing photos, and collaborating with visual Meta AI prompts&lt;p&gt;Can you imagine trying to talk to someone face to face, but they are giving you a blank stare as random notifications and tiktok videos are being beamed inbetween their eyeballs and you.&lt;p&gt;Meta seems like one of the few large tech companies where if the whole company vanished, the world would be purely a better place.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2025 02:01:48 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45284135</link><dc:creator>SchemaLoad</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45284135</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45284135</guid></item><item><title>New comment by JKCalhoun in "Meta Ray-Ban Display"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;They have a brand problem. Absolutely no way I buy anything from Meta.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2025 02:01:08 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45284125</link><dc:creator>JKCalhoun</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45284125</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45284125</guid></item><item><title>New comment by spankalee in "YouTube addresses lower view counts which seem to be caused by ad blockers"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;It seems like this statement from YouTube[1] and this Github issue (referenced by  granzymes[2]) have key information being missed by a lot of commenters.&lt;p&gt;From YouTube:&lt;p&gt;&gt; Viewers Using Ad Blockers &amp; Other Content Blocking Tools: Ad blockers and other extensions can impact the accuracy of reported view counts. Channels whose audiences include a higher proportion of users utilizing such tools may see more fluctuations in traffic related to updates to these tools.&lt;p&gt;Quoting granzymes:&lt;p&gt;&gt; According to the GitHub issue, YouTube didn’t change anything. There are two endpoints that can be used to attribute a view. One is called multiple times throughout a video playback and has been in the easylist privacy filter for years. The other is called at the start of a playback, and was just added to the list (the timing lines up with the reports of view drops from tech YouTubers).&lt;p&gt;Source from the GitHub issue for easylist: &lt;a href="https://github.com/easylist/easylist/issues/22375#issuecomment-3299750332" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://github.com/easylist/easylist/issues/22375#issuecomme...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;[1]: &lt;a href="https://support.google.com/youtube/thread/373195597" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://support.google.com/youtube/thread/373195597&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;[2]: &lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45277768"&gt;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45277768&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2025 18:21:12 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45279453</link><dc:creator>spankalee</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45279453</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45279453</guid></item><item><title>New comment by tedggh in "Things you can do with a Software Defined Radio (2024)"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I got a walkie talkie set as a Christmas present when I was 8. Which was kind of an evil thing to do given I had no siblings or friends to play with. One day I turned one set on and listened for a while and I thought I heard someone talking behind all the static noise. So I said something and was shocked to hear the voice talking back to me. Fast forward a few decades, next week is my wedding and that voice on the other side of the radio is my best man.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2025 15:39:29 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45263749</link><dc:creator>tedggh</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45263749</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45263749</guid></item><item><title>New comment by tptacek in "Man jailed for parole violations after refusing to decrypt his Tor node"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;OK, I think I found the original thing Rockenhaus was convicted of.&lt;p&gt;Back in 2014, Rockenhaus worked for a travel booking company. He was fired. He used stale VPN access to connect back to the company's infrastructure, and then detached a SCSI LUN from the server cluster, crashing it. The company, not knowing he was involved, retained him to help diagnose and fix the problem. During the investigation, the company figured out he caused the crash, and terminated him again. He then somehow gained access to their disaster recovery facility and physically fucked up a bunch of servers. They were down a total of about 30 days and incurred $500k in losses.&lt;p&gt;(He plead this case out, so these are I guess uncontested claims).&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2025 13:33:57 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45262053</link><dc:creator>tptacek</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45262053</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45262053</guid></item><item><title>New comment by tptacek in "Man jailed for parole violations after refusing to decrypt his Tor node"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;For whatever it's worth, the Reddit story here says that the federal courts used "fraudulent warrants to jail my husband again". Maybe! The other side of that story, via PACER, is a detailed parole violation warrant (you can hear the marshal refer to it in the video); the violations in that warrant:&lt;p&gt;1. Admitting to using cannabis during supervised release&lt;p&gt;2. Failing to make scheduled restitution payments and to cooperate with the financial investigation that sets restitution payment amounts.&lt;p&gt;3. Falling out of contact with his probation officer, who attempted home visits to find him.&lt;p&gt;4. Opening several new lines of credit.&lt;p&gt;5. Using an unauthorized iPhone (all his Internet devices apparently have keyloggers as a condition of his release).&lt;p&gt;These read like kind of standard parole terms? I don't know what the hell happened to get him into this situation in the first place, though.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2025 13:26:02 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45261951</link><dc:creator>tptacek</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45261951</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45261951</guid></item></channel></rss>