<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>Hacker News: Best Comments</title><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/bestcomments</link><description>Hacker News RSS</description><docs>https://hnrss.org/</docs><generator>hnrss v2.1.1</generator><lastBuildDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 23:50:15 +0000</lastBuildDate><ns0:link href="https://hnrss.org/bestcomments" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item><title>New comment by budududuroiu in "Ireland wants to give its cops spyware, ability to crack encrypted messages"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Whenever these people ask for more power in order to "stop/prevent crime", there should be a bot that replies a list of times when the police didn't act to stop crime, despite having full knowledge of the crime occuring and potential to stop it from happening.&lt;p&gt;EU member and supporter of Chat Control, Romania, had a massive scandal where a kidnapped 15 year old girl called emergency services multiple times to report she was being kidnapped, every single time, the operators and the police officers spoke to her in an ironic and condescending tone. It took 19 hours to locate her, by which time, she was already dead. [1]&lt;p&gt;[1] &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Kidnapping_of_Alexandra_M%C4%83ce%C8%99anu_and_Luiza_Melencu" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Kidnapping_of_Alexandra_M%C4%8...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 15:05:04 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46706674</link><dc:creator>budududuroiu</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46706674</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46706674</guid></item><item><title>New comment by leosanchez in "Stories removed from the Hacker News Front Page, updated in real time (2024)"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&gt; it's hard to believe that HN users would be tired of LLM-related news.&lt;p&gt;Not hard to believe at all. While I don't flag any posts. I have no interest in LLM related content.&lt;p&gt;I also actively use AI tools btw. It's just tiring seeing everything with AI suffix including monitors.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 13:02:05 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46705122</link><dc:creator>leosanchez</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46705122</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46705122</guid></item><item><title>New comment by academia_hack in "EU–INC – A new pan-European legal entity"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;It's inordinately difficult and expensive to start an LLC or SA in some EU countries. It's even difficult and expensive to _stop_ an LLC and dissolve it. Huge amount of risk and cost on founders and a huge distraction from running a business.&lt;p&gt;I think that EU-Inc _could_ be an improvement, but it needs to avoid the committee laundry list of ideas/requirements/form fields that plagues the EU startup ecosystem. My worry is that the end result will require notarized declarations of honour, financial plans stretching decades into the future, 30 page business plan documents, reams of corporate governance documents, and tons of other nonsense to protect against the perceived risk that someone who failed at starting a business once fails a second time.&lt;p&gt;There needs to be UX requirements on the process from day one against which the end result is judged. (E.g. "a company should be able to register in x days", "a complete application should be no longer than y pages", "application costs should be less than z euros").&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 12:41:07 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46704872</link><dc:creator>academia_hack</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46704872</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46704872</guid></item><item><title>New comment by nkrisc in "SETI@home is in hiberation"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;This was my screensaver for several years starting in maybe 2001. It felt really cool as a 12 year old to be contributing to the project in some small way.&lt;p&gt;For a long time I would periodically check on the screen saver in case there would be some big message saying my computer found aliens or something. Never did though :)&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 12:27:07 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46704707</link><dc:creator>nkrisc</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46704707</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46704707</guid></item><item><title>New comment by reconnecting in "SETI@home is in hiberation"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I feel sorry for every child who didn't have &lt;i&gt;SETI@home&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;X-Files&lt;/i&gt; at the same time during their childhood.&lt;p&gt;The truth is still out there.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 12:24:25 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46704673</link><dc:creator>reconnecting</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46704673</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46704673</guid></item><item><title>New comment by mike_hearn in "Anthropic's original take home assignment open sourced"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;The question isn't clearly written down anywhere, that's why.  Presumably actual candidates would have been given more info over the phone or email. Part of the "challenge" is reverse engineering their Python; unclear if that's intentional.&lt;p&gt;If you look at the top of perf_takehome.py then there is a brief comment saying the challenge is to optimize a kernel. Kernel in GPU land means a program that computes on data in parallel, it's not an OS kernel:&lt;p&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;    Optimize the kernel (in KernelBuilder.build_kernel) as much as possible in the
    available time, as measured by test_kernel_cycles on a frozen separate copy
    of the simulator.
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
However, this kernel doesn't run on an actual GPU. It runs on a little interpreter for a custom assembly language written in Python. Thus you will be optimizing the program built in-memory by the function on this line:&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/anthropics/original_performance_takehome/blob/f88c9458dbc5ef09d7801d961d905698e7e7cae1/perf_takehome.py#L85" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://github.com/anthropics/original_performance_takehome/...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;This function is described only as:&lt;p&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;    Like reference_kernel2 but building actual instructions.
    Scalar implementation using only scalar ALU and load/store.
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
The KernelBuilder class has some fields like "instrs" but we can't immediately see what they're meant to be because this is Python and types are optional. Nonetheless we can see that instructions are being added to a list, and below we can see the test_kernel_cycles function that runs the interpreter on the program. So our mission is to change the build_kernel function to make a better program. And it says this is an assembly version of the python function reference_kernel2 which is found in problem.py.&lt;p&gt;What exactly is this kernel doing? The reference_kernel2 function doesn't explain itself either - it's some sort of parallel tree walk. Let's put that to one side for a second and explore the machine, which is defined in problem.py. The machine itself is also largely undocumented, but there's a brief description in a docstring on line 66.&lt;p&gt;At this point it helps to understand the design of exotic processors. The emulator is for a fictional CPU that uses a VLIW SIMD ISA. Normal programmers will never encounter such a chip. Intel tried to make such a machine decades ago and it never took off, since then the concept has been largely dead. I believe it's still used in some mobile DSPs like Qualcomm's Hexagon. Notably, NVIDIA PTX is &lt;i&gt;not&lt;/i&gt; such an ISA so this seems to have been chosen just to make things harder. As the comment explains, in a VLIW machine multiple instructions are packed together into a "slot" and executed in parallel. In a normal CPU the hardware reads a serial stream of instructions and works out just in time which can be executed in parallel, using fancy out-of-order circuitry. In a VLIW machine that's done ahead of time by the compiler or (in this case) the humble programmer, you. But this isn't just a VLIW machine, it's also multi-core, and multi-"engine", so there are multiple levels of execution going on. And it's SIMD, meaning each instruction can itself operate on multiple bits of data simultaneously.&lt;p&gt;This machine doesn't have registers or cache but it does have "scratch space", and so you can use the vector instructions to load data into a series of 32 bit scratch words and then do things on them in parallel. And multiple vector instructions can also run in parallel. "Broadcasting a scalar" in SIMD-speak means taking a single value and repeating it over multiple scratch space slots (or register subwords in a real machine), so you take e.g. 0xFF and get 0xFFFFFFFFFFFFFFFF.&lt;p&gt;And that's it, that's all we get. As the code says: "This comment is not meant to be full ISA documentation though, for the rest you should look through the simulator code". Possible point of confusion: real ISAs are serialized to bytes but this one is just Python tuples. The code is only partially typed; sometimes you're just left guessing.&lt;p&gt;So to recap, the problem is to optimize an undocumented program expressed in undocumented data structures returned by a Python function whose result is interpreted by a partly documented Python class that simulates a fictional exotic CPU architecture using an abandoned design that gives a lot of parallel computational capacity, but which requires all parallelism to be statically declared ahead of time, whilst simultaneously reverse engineering the Python that does all this.&lt;p&gt;Does that help? Sounds like a fun exercise :)&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Edit: I just checked and Google TPUs are much more VLIW like so perhaps this simulator is designed to match a TPU. I know Anthropic rely on TPUs for serving and have done some optimization for them.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 09:19:25 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46703086</link><dc:creator>mike_hearn</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46703086</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46703086</guid></item><item><title>New comment by lbreakjai in "Anthropic's original take home assignment open sourced"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I consider myself rather smart and good at what I do. It's nice to have a look at problems like these once in a while, to remind myself of how little I know, and how much closer I am to the average than to the top.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 07:10:39 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46702111</link><dc:creator>lbreakjai</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46702111</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46702111</guid></item><item><title>New comment by dlcarrier in "cURL removes bug bounties"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;An entry fee that is reimbursed if the bug turns out to matter would stop this, real quick.&lt;p&gt;Then again, I once submitted a bug report to my bank, because the login method could be switched from password+pin to pin only, when not logged in, and they closed it as "works as intended", because they had decided that an optional password was more convenient than a required password.  (And that's not even getting into the difference between real two-factor authentication the some-factor one-and-a-half-times they had implemented by adding a PIN to a password login.)  I've since learned that anything heavily regulated like hospitals and banks will have security procedures catering to compliance, not actual security.&lt;p&gt;Assuming the host of the bug bounty program is operating in good faith, adding some kind of barrier to entry or punishment for untested entries will weed out submitters acting in bad faith.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 06:59:24 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46702041</link><dc:creator>dlcarrier</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46702041</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46702041</guid></item><item><title>New comment by pvalue005 in "Anthropic's original take home assignment open sourced"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I suspect this was released by Anthropic as a DDOS attack on other AI companies. I prompted 'how do we solve this challenge?' into gemini cli in a cloned repo and it's been running non-stop for 20 minutes :)&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 05:36:26 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46701527</link><dc:creator>pvalue005</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46701527</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46701527</guid></item><item><title>New comment by al_borland in "Ask HN: Do you have any evidence that agentic coding works?"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;A principal engineer at Google posted on Twitter that Claude Code did in an hour what the team couldn’t do in a year.&lt;p&gt;Two days later, after people freaked out, context was added. The team built multiple versions in that year, each had its trade offs. All that context was given to the AI and it was able to produce a “toy” version. I can only assume it had similar trade offs.&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://xcancel.com/rakyll/status/2007659740126761033#m" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://xcancel.com/rakyll/status/2007659740126761033#m&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;My experience has been similar to yours, and I think a lot of the hype is from people like this Google engineer who play into the hype and leave out the context. This sets expectations way out of line from reality and leads to frustration and disappointment.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 00:41:09 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46699744</link><dc:creator>al_borland</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46699744</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46699744</guid></item><item><title>New comment by tecleandor in "Instabridge has acquired Nova Launcher"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;"We are a Swedish company building products that help people get online, used by millions of people worldwide."&lt;p&gt;So I look for them. They have a "Free wifi connection" / "Wifi passwords map" app. It surprises me because it has a good score on Google Play but then I begin to check the reviews, and a bunch of them go like: "Five stars because if you do a good review you can use it for free".&lt;p&gt;I install it and on starting it and in the first minute: Asks you to create an account but you can't click on the terms of service or privacy policy, the links don't work. I skip it. It tries to change your default launcher. It tries to change your default browser. It asks you to share your home wifi password with them. Pops up adds everywhere. Tries to get a good review from you.&lt;p&gt;No thanks, not even near.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 21:36:19 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46698060</link><dc:creator>tecleandor</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46698060</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46698060</guid></item><item><title>New comment by spicyusername in "I'm addicted to being useful"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Nothing wrong on the surface with this, and the author explicitly acknowledges this risk, but it bears repeating:&lt;p&gt;Corporate environments are almost always toxic places to fulfill your emotional needs.&lt;p&gt;It is true that finding a job that "resonates" with your personality is key to living a fulfilling life, and that software engineering is the kind of profession that is really going to fit certain personality types extremely well, but despite that corporate culture can and will take advantage of you, divide you and your work "friends", exploit your willingness to serve, and discard you like trash at any moment.&lt;p&gt;Be mindful of how much of yourself you derive from serving the financial goals of others.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 20:36:25 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46697424</link><dc:creator>spicyusername</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46697424</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46697424</guid></item><item><title>New comment by rdmuser in "Instabridge has acquired Nova Launcher"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;It was sold back in 2022 to Branch Metrics
&lt;a href="https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/branch-strikes-twice-with-nova-launcher-and-sesame-search-acquisition" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://www.androidcentral.com/apps-software/branch-strikes-...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;August 2024 everyone working on it was laid off except the original dev
&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2024/8/9/24217077/nova-launcher-layoffs-only-original-developer-remaining" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://www.theverge.com/2024/8/9/24217077/nova-launcher-lay...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;September 2025 the original dev left after being told to stop work on open sourcing it
&lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/news/773937/nova-launcher-founder-left-kevin-barry-branch-open-source-android" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://www.theverge.com/news/773937/nova-launcher-founder-l...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 19:46:35 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46696846</link><dc:creator>rdmuser</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46696846</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46696846</guid></item><item><title>New comment by mullingitover in "De-dollarization: Is the US dollar losing its dominance? (2025)"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I remember studying pre-WWI history, and particularly how carefully Bismarck arranged German foreign policy like he was the diplomatic equivalent of Bobby Fischer. Everything was situated perfectly and Germany was totally content.&lt;p&gt;Then along came the absolute moron Wilhelm, and he managed to Leroy Jenkins Germany's beautifully arranged relationships into an aggressive, tactless nightmare where all Germany's allies were turned into enemies, and everything turned out exactly like you'd expect.&lt;p&gt;As the saying goes, history doesn't repeat but it often rhymes.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 18:11:00 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46695546</link><dc:creator>mullingitover</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46695546</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46695546</guid></item><item><title>New comment by _fat_santa in "Nvidia Stock Crash Prediction"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;This article goes more into the technical analysis of the stock rather than the underlying business fundamentals that would lead to a stock dump.&lt;p&gt;My 30k ft view is that the stock will inevitably slide as AI datacenter spending goes down. Right now Nvidia is flying high because datacenters are breaking ground everywhere but eventually that will come to an end as the supply of compute goes up.&lt;p&gt;The counterargument to this is that the "economic lifespan" of an Nvidia GPU is 1-3 years depending on where it's used so there's a case to be made that Nvidia will always have customers coming back for the latest and greatest chips. The problem I have with this argument is that it's simply unsustainable to be spending that much every 2-3 years and we're already seeing this as Google and others are extending their depreciation of GPU's to something like 5-7 years.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 16:41:19 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46693996</link><dc:creator>_fat_santa</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46693996</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46693996</guid></item><item><title>New comment by touwer in "De-dollarization: Is the US dollar losing its dominance? (2025)"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;The US century is already over. It's just that a lot of US citizens don't see that. De-dollarization will happen when one is a traitor to it's allies&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 16:34:43 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46693885</link><dc:creator>touwer</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46693885</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46693885</guid></item><item><title>New comment by snovymgodym in "De-dollarization: Is the US dollar losing its dominance? (2025)"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;The international value of the dollar as a reserve and trade currency is inherently tied to the behavior of the US Government and the Federal Reserve.&lt;p&gt;The behavior of the US Government has been very unusual lately, and the independence of the Federal Reserve is actively being challenged.&lt;p&gt;So draw from that whatever conclusions you wish.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 16:21:50 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46693662</link><dc:creator>snovymgodym</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46693662</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46693662</guid></item><item><title>New comment by jacquesm in "De-dollarization: Is the US dollar losing its dominance? (2025)"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;It's not losing it so much as that it is being destroyed on purpose.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 16:20:22 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46693638</link><dc:creator>jacquesm</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46693638</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46693638</guid></item><item><title>New comment by azinman2 in "Danish pension fund divesting US Treasuries"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;You’re assuming the people in charge are sane, rationale, and value past decisions that have worked out. It’s quite clear with the now likely permanent damage to NATO this isn’t the case.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 16:11:25 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46693478</link><dc:creator>azinman2</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46693478</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46693478</guid></item><item><title>New comment by alphazard in "Danish pension fund divesting US Treasuries"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&gt; It's symbolism.&lt;p&gt;It's not.  This is where the financial rubber meets the road, actions have consequences, and the rest of the world is looking at the US as increasingly unlikely to pay above inflation on its debts.&lt;p&gt;The people managing the pension funds (if they are acting in good faith) really want to generate yield, and really want to preserve capital for the Danish people.
They don't want to symbolically do those things, they want to actually do them.
If treasuries were still part of what they believe to be the best strategy, they would still be holding them.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 16:02:11 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46693319</link><dc:creator>alphazard</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46693319</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46693319</guid></item><item><title>New comment by afavour in "Danish pension fund divesting US Treasuries"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;It's symbolism. But it's important symbolism. Far more notable, I think, is Macron saying this morning that Europe needs more investment from China. Canada signing a deal with China to allow their cars to be sold in the country.&lt;p&gt;It's all a sliding slope until it reaches a breaking point and falls off like a cliff.&lt;p&gt;EDIT: to quote the Canadian PN earlier today:&lt;p&gt;“American hegemony in particular helped provide public goods, a stable financial system... this bargain no longer works. Let me be direct. We are in the midst of a rupture, not a transition... recently, great powers have begun using economic integration as a weapon. Tariffs as leverage ..."&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 15:49:44 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46693087</link><dc:creator>afavour</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46693087</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46693087</guid></item><item><title>New comment by qgin in "Danish pension fund divesting US Treasuries"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;So much of the way the United States works is having a nearly limitless source of borrowing at low rates in the form of selling treasury bonds.&lt;p&gt;The further we get away from that being true, the more precarious things become.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 15:49:19 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46693083</link><dc:creator>qgin</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46693083</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46693083</guid></item><item><title>New comment by n4r9 in "I'm addicted to being useful"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I frame it not as turning a dial down, but as switching channel from practical problem-solver to emotional problem-solver.&lt;p&gt;Often when someone wants to talk about a situation involving difficult feelings, they're actually trying to process those feelings: to understand where the feelings are coming from, to be validated, and to be able to take a broader perspective.&lt;p&gt;You can help by being curious about what they're saying, reflecting it back to them in your own terms, explaining how what they're feeling is understandable, and offering context or alternative viewpoints. These are actually complex problem-solving skills, although they can all fall under the umbrella of what people mean when they say "to be heard".&lt;p&gt;As a man, I've realised that once my emotions feel validated and accepted, I relax and the practical solutions just pop into my mind.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 13:08:33 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46691435</link><dc:creator>n4r9</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46691435</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46691435</guid></item><item><title>New comment by tclancy in "I'm addicted to being useful"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&gt;  I don’t mind the ways in which my job is dysfunctional, because it matches the ways in which I myself am dysfunctional&lt;p&gt;As a fellow traveller, I offer one caution: learn to turn this down in personal relationships as it can be counterproductive. It took decades for my wife to finally get through and explain not every problem she voices is something that needs a solution. Some times people just want to be heard. It bugs the hell out of me because I tend to need to solve All The Problems before I can do any self-care, but rather than seem heroic, I think this attitude can seem transactional or uncaring as though everyone is just a screw that needed a bit of tightening, etc.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 12:39:18 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46691196</link><dc:creator>tclancy</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46691196</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46691196</guid></item><item><title>New comment by knallfrosch in "Giving university exams in the age of chatbots"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I don't understand.&lt;p&gt;10 years ago, we wrote exams by hand with whatever we understood (in our heads.)&lt;p&gt;No colleagues, no laptops, no internet, no LLMs.&lt;p&gt;This approach still works, why do something else? Unless you're specifically testing a student's ability to Google, they don't need access to it.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 09:39:11 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46689873</link><dc:creator>knallfrosch</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46689873</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46689873</guid></item><item><title>New comment by thecupisblue in "Prediction markets are ushering in a world in which news becomes about gambling"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Not just America, everything is.
With stock market, at least we can somehow stop the bad actors, insider traders, corporate manipulation, pumps and dumps - with prediction markets, there is no way.&lt;p&gt;With prediction markets? Next to impossible. The markets being tied to crypto makes it even worse - things get harder to track, jurisdictions get blurry, proving becomes a ping pong between bureaucracy. And proving something becomes moreso a question of free will - if I decided to do X and then someone bets millon dollars on me doing X when odds are low, how do you prove I haven't decided to do X before? Will you prevent me from exercising my free will because of suspect insider trading? What if I am a president/senator?&lt;p&gt;Years ago, I was a kid who discovered online betting - often it was the only time I could place bets on MMA events, especially because it wasn't as popular as it is now. Even then, the gambling sites had "Other" options where you could bet on presidents, popes, landing on mars etc. The new markets aren't that much different, but are just using a nicer way to talk about it.&lt;p&gt;It isn't gambling, it's prediction.&lt;p&gt;You aren't a gambler, you're a "hyperinformed high iq individual predicting the geopolitical moves". Just like crypto gave people the identity crutch of a "tech investor", this gives them the identity crutch of a "geopolitical strategist".&lt;p&gt;But in the end, it is still just gambling - wrapped in a nice ego stroking suit, but gambling none the less.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 09:09:47 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46689641</link><dc:creator>thecupisblue</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46689641</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46689641</guid></item><item><title>New comment by apparent in "Apple testing new App Store design that blurs the line between ads and results"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;The search results in the App Store are ridiculous. Sometimes I search for an app by name and have to scroll through dozens of other apps before finding the one I had searched for.&lt;p&gt;App Store search is as broken as Apple Mail search, if not worse.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 07:40:57 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46689008</link><dc:creator>apparent</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46689008</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46689008</guid></item><item><title>New comment by breput in "Nova Launcher added Facebook and Google Ads tracking"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I was a 10+ year long Nova Launcher user and knew this day was coming after the sale and layoffs[0][1]...&lt;p&gt;This evening I at looked several replacement launchers, such as Lawnchair and even the stock Pixel launcher again, but Octopi Launcher[2] is the more modern, more refined Nova replacement that you are looking for.&lt;p&gt;It was a very easy, natural transition process from Nova - all of the Nova features that I used were there (unlike Lawnchair), such as swipe up/down on icons to perform different actions. And little things like folder options, icon placement, and widget handling are SO much nicer on Octopi compared to Nova. Staggeringly better.&lt;p&gt;I took a screenshot of each home screen page, set Octopi as the new default launcher, and was back to my previous configuration but with a significantly improved visual appearance, in about 15 minutes. It's a no-brainer upgrade from Nova.&lt;p&gt;The Google Play install is free and basically unlimited, but there is an unobtrusive "Buy Me A Coffee" type button that allows you to donate either $1 or $3 to unlock some eye candy, which I did, but mostly just wanting to support the developer.&lt;p&gt;[0] &lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45170000"&gt;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45170000&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;[1] &lt;a href="https://www.androidpolice.com/exclusive-cliff-wade-nova-launcher-interview/" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://www.androidpolice.com/exclusive-cliff-wade-nova-laun...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;[2] &lt;a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.otp.octopilauncher&amp;hl=en_US"&gt;https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.otp.octopi...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 05:49:06 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46688336</link><dc:creator>breput</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46688336</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46688336</guid></item><item><title>New comment by melenaboija in "Porsche sold more electrified cars in Europe in 2025 than pure gas-powered cars"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&gt; Then I think you see an early indication not just of electric car dominance, but of the (very potential) rise of China as the premier automotive super power.&lt;p&gt;It’s done man. Americans are stuck in ICE engines because they’ve been told they’re “car enthusiasts” while the Chinese have been developing EV technology for years. Meanwhile, European makers are stuck not knowing what to do, make Americans happy or compete with the Chinese. The result: nothing has been done properly. And let’s be real, “car enthusiasts” are going to disappear in one or two generations. Practicality beats enthusiasm for 95% of car use.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 03:55:38 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46687749</link><dc:creator>melenaboija</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46687749</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46687749</guid></item><item><title>New comment by bnchrch in "Porsche sold more electrified cars in Europe in 2025 than pure gas-powered cars"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;While the headline is interesting.&lt;p&gt;I think the table at the end of the article is more so.&lt;p&gt;- Worldwide sales -10% YoY&lt;p&gt;- China sales -26% YoY&lt;p&gt;And when you cross compare Porsche saying they sold more EV powertrains than their gas equivalents against China's new found foothold as the market leader in consumer electric cars (BYD, NIO, Xiaomi, etc...)&lt;p&gt;Then I think you see an early indication not just of electric car dominance, but of the (very potential) rise of China as the premier automotive super power.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 01:20:49 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46686739</link><dc:creator>bnchrch</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46686739</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46686739</guid></item></channel></rss>