<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>Hacker News: Best Comments</title><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/bestcomments</link><description>Hacker News RSS</description><docs>https://hnrss.org/</docs><generator>hnrss v2.1.1</generator><lastBuildDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2025 23:51:06 +0000</lastBuildDate><ns0:link href="https://hnrss.org/bestcomments" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item><title>New comment by SunshineTheCat in "Google is dead. Where do we go now?"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I recently took someone to go and watch a hockey game. Been a little while but I personally played as a goalie myself.&lt;p&gt;The person kept making the comment that she couldn't see/find the puck and it made it frustrating to watch.&lt;p&gt;As a goalie, not being able to see the puck is pretty normal (especially with big bodies trying to screen you).&lt;p&gt;What I told her was that what matters a lot more than where the puck is, is where it's going to be in about two seconds. But the next best thing is to know where the puck is now.&lt;p&gt;If you can't see the puck then look at the players and as a last resort, look at the ref. 99% of the time they will be looking at the puck. Look where they're looking and soon enough it will appear.&lt;p&gt;I think this applies very much to this whole Google question.&lt;p&gt;The puck is gone (or on the way to the other side of the rink) and everyone is confused where it is or where it's going.&lt;p&gt;Look where everyone is looking and you'll find your answer there. It may not be in the same form as Google adwords, but the game is the same. Leveraging attention.&lt;p&gt;The tactics were different during the phonebook days (it was having your business start with the letter "A") as opposed to Google and will be different for the next thing as well.&lt;p&gt;From what I can tell, everyone seems to be looking at chatbots and vertical, shortform video. Not sure how that plays out in terms of advertising, but in terms of the answer to this article's question, that seems like a good place to start.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2025 21:07:38 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46425707</link><dc:creator>SunshineTheCat</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46425707</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46425707</guid></item><item><title>New comment by senthil_rajasek in "Google is dead. Where do we go now?"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I think the author intended the title to be,&lt;p&gt;"Google Ads is dead, Where do I promote my business now?"&lt;p&gt;When I hear "Google" I assume search, oof (sigh of relief).&lt;p&gt;They mention running ads on tiktok or instagram but no mention of youtube ads...&lt;p&gt;Also, In my own experience for my business ( also entertainment) I have found reddit ads to be useful.&lt;p&gt;So my next steps would be,&lt;p&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;  Reddit Ads
  Youtube Ads
  Instagram Ads
  Increase AI Visiblity
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
[Edit: Added Instagram Ads, from a different comment]&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2025 21:02:19 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46425627</link><dc:creator>senthil_rajasek</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46425627</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46425627</guid></item><item><title>New comment by rambojohnson in "Karpathy on Programming: "I've never felt this much behind""</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;What exhausts me isn’t “falling behind.” It’s watching the profession collectively decide that the solution to uncertainty is to pile abstraction on top of abstraction until no one can explain what’s actually happening anymore.&lt;p&gt;This agentic arms race by C-suite know-nothings feels less like leverage and more like denial. We took a stochastic text generator, noticed it lies confidently, wipes entire databases and harddrives, and responded by wrapping it in managers, sub-agents, memories, tools, permissions, workflows, and orchestration layers so we don’t have to look directly at the fact that it still doesn’t understand anything.&lt;p&gt;Now we’re expected to maintain a mental model not just of our system, but of a swarm of half-reliable interns talking to each other in a language that isn’t executable, reproducible, or stable.&lt;p&gt;Work now feels duller than dishwater, enough to have forced me to career pivot for 2026.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2025 20:23:34 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46425127</link><dc:creator>rambojohnson</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46425127</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46425127</guid></item><item><title>New comment by jqpabc123 in "Tesla's 4680 battery supply chain collapses as partner writes down deal by 99%"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;For years, we’ve been told that the 4680 cell was the “holy grail” that would allow Tesla to produce a $25,000 electric car.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;p&gt;For years, we've been told a lot of things that have never come to fruition.&lt;p&gt;Just 6 months ago, we were told that Robotaxi would be available to half the US population by the end of the year.&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://electrek.co/2025/07/23/elon-musk-with-straight-face-tesla-robotaxi-will-cover-half-us-population-end-year/" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://electrek.co/2025/07/23/elon-musk-with-straight-face-...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2025 18:11:33 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46423459</link><dc:creator>jqpabc123</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46423459</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46423459</guid></item><item><title>New comment by Fiveplus in "GOG is getting acquired by its original co-founder"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&gt; Can I still download offline installers? Yes.&lt;p&gt;This is the only line I was looking for. I stopped buying on Steam sometime ago because I realized I was just renting licenses. GOG is the only major storefront where I feel like I actually own the product. As long as offline installers remain a core tenet, I don't care who owns the company. That said, it helps that it's someone returning to their roots rather than a private equity firm looking to strip-mine the assets.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2025 17:40:31 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46423101</link><dc:creator>Fiveplus</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46423101</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46423101</guid></item><item><title>New comment by this_user in "Kidnapped by Deutsche Bahn"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;So much in German work culture - and also culture in general - is about covering your own arse. If you follow the procedure, even if the outcome is disaster, you are not at fault; you were just implementing the rules, and you cannot be held accountable. It's the fault of whoever came up with the rules, except that is usually not a single person, but some amorphous entity that ran through some decision making process years in the past. So, no one is really at fault or can be held accountable.&lt;p&gt;It's always some magical higher power preventing you from doing the sensible thing. One favourite excuse is insurance liability. We can't do the sensible thing, because the insurance wouldn't pay if something bad were to happen, even though the odds of something bad happening are virtually nil.&lt;p&gt;You can also observe this in German politics. "Oh, we absolutely cannot do &lt;common sense thing&gt; because the rules won't allow it." Well, you could change the rules, but then you would have to take some actual responsibility, and we can't have that.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2025 15:03:33 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46421417</link><dc:creator>this_user</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46421417</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46421417</guid></item><item><title>New comment by jimnotgym in "UK accounting body to halt remote exams amid AI cheating"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Ask an examiner from 20 years ago the risk of allowing people to take exams in their own home. They would have said 'cheating', even with no concept of AI.&lt;p&gt;Here is what happened. ACCA, one of several accountancy bodies in the UK, charge their students extraordinary sums of money to take their exams. When I took accountancy exams there were 9of 3 hour written exams, in a real building,  with real invigilators. All of the bodies at the same time realised that they could charge the same amount, pay Pearson to administer an electronic test and make more money out of their students. It was a disgrace then and it is a disgrace now&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2025 13:50:45 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46420746</link><dc:creator>jimnotgym</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46420746</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46420746</guid></item><item><title>New comment by hansmayer in "As AI gobbles up chips, prices for devices may rise"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I cannot stop thinking about the LLMs having this Midas touch quality, because everything they touch seems to ruin things or make people want to avoid them, for example:&lt;p&gt;- Ghibli studio style graphics,&lt;p&gt;- the infamous em-dashes and bullet points&lt;p&gt;- customer service (just try to use Klarnas "support" these days...)&lt;p&gt;- Oracle share price ;) - imagine being one of the worlds most solid and unassailable tech companies, losing to your CEOs crazy commitment to the LLMs...&lt;p&gt;- The internet content - We now tripple check every Internet source we dont know to the core ...&lt;p&gt;- And now also the chips ?&lt;p&gt;Where does it stop? When we decide to drop all technology as it is?&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2025 13:44:38 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46420684</link><dc:creator>hansmayer</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46420684</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46420684</guid></item><item><title>New comment by Zealotux in "Kidnapped by Deutsche Bahn"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I worked for a massive German company you heard of, this sounds more like the typical German philosophy of strictly following the process -- as absurd as it might be -- and refusing to take initiative for anything that is not explicitly defined as one's responsibility.&lt;p&gt;As a French, the culture shock was brutal and I never really got around that work attitude. I went through a similar issue back when I used to take a regional train in France, and the crew swiftly adapted by bending rules to accommodate a difficult situation caused by bad weather. I'm not sure this could happen today, but it was a thing 10 years ago, we used to trust the operators back then.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2025 13:41:11 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46420641</link><dc:creator>Zealotux</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46420641</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46420641</guid></item><item><title>New comment by BloondAndDoom in "Kidnapped by Deutsche Bahn"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I feel like we lost humanity somewhere in modern world. I grew up in 3rd world country and if this were to happen, train would literally stop somewhere, anywhere. (With the assumption it’s safe from crewing into another train).&lt;p&gt;But the idea that you go 55 minutes just because of policy; and skip 15 stations is crazy to me. Again with the assumptions that it can safely stop somewhere for 5m and I’m pretty sure the answer is yes.&lt;p&gt;I have fond memories of train stopping close to my house for various random reasons and I’d  just get out so I don’t have to walk back from the station. The modern world where everything is “safety issue” and “someone else’s problem” is where we lost our ways, and it’s never coming back.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2025 13:18:44 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46420414</link><dc:creator>BloondAndDoom</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46420414</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46420414</guid></item><item><title>New comment by indiantinker in "Kidnapped by Deutsche Bahn"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;DB is weird. They seem to make their own rules and then run the game and “dont tell the rules to anyone”. I was on my way to catch a flight from Munich to my home (Madrid). I didn’t knew that apparently at one point the train splits into two parts and the front part goes to the airport and the other part just goes to the nearby cattle farms and comes back in 3 hours.&lt;p&gt;Google Maps - No idea
Citymapper - what?
English announcement - nien.&lt;p&gt;Thanks to an old lady, who told me that i needed to switch coaches to go the airport. Madre mia!!&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2025 12:44:47 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46420105</link><dc:creator>indiantinker</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46420105</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46420105</guid></item><item><title>New comment by dannye in "You can make up HTML tags"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&lt;tag-name&gt; are NOT unrecognized tags!&lt;p&gt;I blogged about this: &lt;a href="https://dashed-html.github.io" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://dashed-html.github.io&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;◄ &lt;tagname&gt; = always an HTMLUnknownElement until the WHATWG adds it as new Element.&lt;p&gt;◄ &lt;tag-name&gt; = (No JS!) &lt;i&gt;UNDEFINED Custom Element&lt;/i&gt;, valid HTMLElement, great for layout and styling&lt;p&gt;◄ Upgraded with the JavaScript Custom Elements API it becomes a &lt;i&gt;DEFINED Custom Element&lt;/i&gt;&lt;p&gt;---&lt;p&gt;► This is standard behaviour in all browsers. Chrome (2016) Safari (2017) FireFox (2018) Edge (2020)&lt;p&gt;► The W3C HTML Validator accepts all &lt;tag-name&gt; Custom Elements with a dash as HTMLElement.
It does not accept &lt;tagname&gt; (no dash), those are HTMLUnknownElement&lt;p&gt;► The UA - UserAgent StyleSheet (Browsers default stylesheet)
defines CSS [hidden] { display:none }.
But Custom Elements do not inherit the default stylesheet;
so you have to add that behaviour yourself in your stylesheet.&lt;p&gt;► &lt;DIV&gt; is display:block only in the UA StyleSheet
You have to set the display property on these Custom Elements yourself
(You will forget this 20 times, then you never make the mistake again)&lt;p&gt;► The CSS :defined pseudo selector targets standard HTML tags and JavaScript defined Custom Elements&lt;p&gt;► Thus the CSS :not(:defined) pseudo selector targets the  UNDEFINED Custom Elements; they are still valid HTMLElement, CSS applies like any element&lt;p&gt;► DSD - Declarative ShadowDOM:
&lt;template shadowrootmode="open"&gt; creates the same undefined Custom Elements with a shadowDOM&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2025 08:46:18 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46418689</link><dc:creator>dannye</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46418689</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46418689</guid></item><item><title>New comment by throwfaraway135 in "Staying ahead of censors in 2025"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Considering the staggering number of arrest for online/offensive communications in England &amp; Wales, we should add Britain to the list of Russia and Iran&lt;p&gt;2017: ~5,500 arrests&lt;p&gt;2019: ~7,734 arrests&lt;p&gt;2023: ~12,183 arrests&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2025 07:33:48 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46418295</link><dc:creator>throwfaraway135</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46418295</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46418295</guid></item><item><title>New comment by torginus in "As AI gobbles up chips, prices for devices may rise"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;It's somewhat alarming to see that companies (owned by a very small slice of society) producing these AI thingies (whose current economic  is questionable value and actual future potential is up to hot debate), can easily price the rest of humanity out of computing goods.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2025 07:21:00 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46418217</link><dc:creator>torginus</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46418217</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46418217</guid></item><item><title>New comment by chrismorgan in "You can make up HTML tags"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;  &lt;div class=article&gt;
  &lt;div class=article-header&gt;
  &lt;div class=article-quote&gt;
  &lt;div class=quote-body&gt;
  ... a bunch more HTML ...
  &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
Just one quibble over this &lt;i&gt;specific&lt;/i&gt; example (not the broader concept, which is sound): it probably didn’t have to be div soup to begin with. Something like this may have been more reasonable:&lt;p&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;  &lt;article&gt;
  &lt;header&gt;
  &lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p class=quote-body&gt;
  ... a bunch more HTML ...
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/blockquote&gt;
  &lt;/header&gt;
  &lt;/article&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2025 03:40:14 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46417229</link><dc:creator>chrismorgan</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46417229</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46417229</guid></item><item><title>New comment by sallveburrpi in "Why I Disappeared – My week with minimal internet in a remote island chain"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Escaping the internet on a luxury trip doesn’t disprove political conflict… it just shows how privilege can opt out of reality and sell the experience as clickbaity insight.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2025 00:56:06 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46416156</link><dc:creator>sallveburrpi</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46416156</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46416156</guid></item><item><title>New comment by overfeed in "CEOs are hugely expensive. Why not automate them? (2021)"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&gt; With that handled, all that's left is the cartel that CEOs have invented to justify their exhorbant pay packages.&lt;p&gt;CEO compensation is determined by board committees mostly made up of &lt;i&gt;other&lt;/i&gt; CxOs. They write letters to each other's shareholders about how valuable CEOs are to build up the edifice.&lt;p&gt;I wish my compensation were determined by fellow engineers who "truly know my worth". I'd pay it forward if I were on a committee determining colleague's pay packets.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2025 00:30:22 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46416022</link><dc:creator>overfeed</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46416022</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46416022</guid></item><item><title>New comment by Sparkle-san in "CEOs are hugely expensive. Why not automate them? (2021)"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I'm deeply skeptical of CEOs being "built different" like some people are arguing here. If Elon can be CEO of three companies and the founder of a couple more while also finding time to tweet 50+ times a day, have a failed and embarrassing stint in trying to optimize the federal government, and get K-holed at parties then the demands of the job can't be that rigorous.&lt;p&gt;If anything, I would argue that the strategic decisions actually can be automated/performed via broader consensus. With that handled, all that's left is the cartel that CEOs have invented to justify their exhorbant pay packages.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2025 00:22:44 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46415970</link><dc:creator>Sparkle-san</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46415970</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46415970</guid></item><item><title>New comment by barishnamazov in "What an unprocessed photo looks like"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I love posts that peel back the abstraction layer of "images." It really highlights that modern photography is just signal processing with better marketing.&lt;p&gt;A fun tangent on the "green cast" mentioned in the post: the reason the Bayer pattern is RGGB (50% green) isn't just about color balance, but spatial resolution. The human eye is most sensitive to green light, so that channel effectively carries the majority of the luminance (brightness/detail) data.
In many advanced demosaicing algorithms, the pipeline actually reconstructs the green channel first to get a high-resolution luminance map, and then interpolates the red/blue signals—which act more like "color difference" layers—on top of it. We can get away with this because the human visual system is much more forgiving of low-resolution color data than it is of low-resolution brightness data. It’s the same psycho-visual principle that justifies 4:2:0 chroma subsampling in video compression.&lt;p&gt;Also, for anyone interested in how deep the rabbit hole goes, looking at the source code for dcraw (or libraw) is a rite of passage. It’s impressive how many edge cases exist just to interpret the "raw" voltages from different sensor manufacturers.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 28 Dec 2025 23:27:51 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46415558</link><dc:creator>barishnamazov</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46415558</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46415558</guid></item><item><title>New comment by elliotto in "Software engineers should be a little bit cynical"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;The author seems like a nice guy, but perhaps a bit naive regarding the efforts big tech companies go to to crush employees (&lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/High-Tech_Employee_Antitrust_Litigation" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/High-Tech_Employee_Antitrust_L...&lt;/a&gt;). They appear to be a staff level engineer at a big tech company - I don't know how much money they make, but I suspect it's an ungodly amount.&lt;p&gt;The organisation he works for is implicated in surveillance, monopoly exploitation, and current military action involving particularly unpopular wars. No one forced him into this role - he could have made less money elsewhere but decided not to. He has decided to be a cog in a larger, poorly functioning machine, and is handsomely rewarded for it. This sacrifice is, for many, a worthwhile trade.&lt;p&gt;If you don't want to engage with the moral ramifications of your profession, you are generally socially allowed to do so, provided the profession is above board. Unfortunately, you cannot then write a post trying to defend your position, saying that what I do is good, actually, meanwhile cashing your high 6-7 figure check. This is incoherent.&lt;p&gt;It is financially profitable to be a political actor within a decaying monopolist apparatus, but I don't need to accept that it's also a pathway to a well-lived life.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 28 Dec 2025 22:17:41 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46415077</link><dc:creator>elliotto</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46415077</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46415077</guid></item><item><title>New comment by jjice in "Last Year on My Mac: Look Back in Disbelief"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I don't mind how Liquid Glass looks at all. It's just insane how buggy the system has become. Even Messages will bug out, like deleting my first word if I type too fast after opening a conversation or auto scrolling and not letting me scroll down until I exit and re-enter.&lt;p&gt;Unacceptable for the premium you pay for Apple software. Unacceptable for any software one is paying for. I hope they get their shit together and start fixing before they continue adding new stuff. 26.2 doesn't inspire me that they're on that trajectory.&lt;p&gt;The thing that amazes me most is that everyone on the teams responsible is probably using their Apple devices and running into these same bugs!&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 28 Dec 2025 16:13:20 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46412078</link><dc:creator>jjice</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46412078</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46412078</guid></item><item><title>New comment by jasode in "C++ says “We have try... finally at home”"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;The submitted title is missing the salient keyword &lt;i&gt;"finally"&lt;/i&gt; that motivates the blog post.  The actual subtitle Raymond Chen wrote is:  &lt;i&gt;"C++ says “We have try…finally at home.”"&lt;/i&gt;&lt;p&gt;It's a snowclone based on the meme, &lt;i&gt;"Mom, can we get &lt;X&gt;?  No, we have &lt;X&gt; at home."&lt;/i&gt; :  &lt;a href="https://www.google.com/search?q=%22we+have+x+at+home%22+meme" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://www.google.com/search?q=%22we+have+x+at+home%22+meme&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;In other words, Raymond is saying... "We already have Java feature of 'finally' at home in the C++ refrigerator and it's called 'destructor'"&lt;p&gt;To continue the meme analogy, the kid's idea of &lt;X&gt; doesn't match mom's idea of &lt;X&gt; and disagrees that they're equivalent.   E.g. "Mom, can we order pizza? No, we have leftover casserole in the fridge."&lt;p&gt;So some kids would complain that C++ destructors RAII philosophy require creating a whole "class X{public:~X()}" which is sometimes inconvenient so it doesn't exactly equal "finally".&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 28 Dec 2025 10:00:45 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46409904</link><dc:creator>jasode</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46409904</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46409904</guid></item><item><title>New comment by levmiseri in "Replacing JavaScript with Just HTML"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;A missed opportunity to not have all of these examples inline. The page/blog-post would be so much more convincing if it utilized all of these HTML replacements instead (or in addition) to linking to codepen.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 28 Dec 2025 09:32:39 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46409716</link><dc:creator>levmiseri</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46409716</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46409716</guid></item><item><title>New comment by butz in "Rainbow Six Siege hacked as players get billions of credits and random bans"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Nice to see anti-cheats working and protecting Linux players from hacks, by preventing them from actually playing the game.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 28 Dec 2025 08:33:39 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46409448</link><dc:creator>butz</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46409448</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46409448</guid></item><item><title>New comment by Vincent_Yan404 in "Growing up in “404 Not Found”: China's nuclear city in the Gobi Desert"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Hi HN, OP here.&lt;p&gt;I grew up in "Factory 404," a secret nuclear industrial city in the Gobi Desert that officially didn't exist on public maps. This is a memoir about my childhood there.&lt;p&gt;It was a surreal place: we had elite scientists living next to laborers, a zoo in the middle of the desert, and distinct "communist" welfare, all hidden behind a classified code.&lt;p&gt;This is Part 1 of the story. I'm happy to answer any questions about life in a Chinese nuclear base!&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 28 Dec 2025 06:58:07 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46409061</link><dc:creator>Vincent_Yan404</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46409061</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46409061</guid></item><item><title>New comment by abetusk in "Calendar"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;The neatnik calendar is very nice. Others are talking about enhancements they've done and I've done my own, creating a pretty faithful JavaScript implementation with enhancements:&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/abetusk/neatocal" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://github.com/abetusk/neatocal&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://abetusk.github.io/neatocal/" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://abetusk.github.io/neatocal/&lt;/a&gt; (demo)&lt;p&gt;URL parameters can be used to alter behavior. Here's a highlight of some of them:&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://abetusk.github.io/neatocal/?layout=aligned-weekdays&amp;highlight_color=fee" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://abetusk.github.io/neatocal/?layout=aligned-weekdays&amp;...&lt;/a&gt; (weekend highlighted, aligned)&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://abetusk.github.io/neatocal/?start_month=7" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://abetusk.github.io/neatocal/?start_month=7&lt;/a&gt; (academic)&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://abetusk.github.io/neatocal/?start_month=6&amp;n_month=6" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://abetusk.github.io/neatocal/?start_month=6&amp;n_month=6&lt;/a&gt; (second half, 6 month)&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://abetusk.github.io/neatocal/?month_code=1%E6%9C%88,2%E6%9C%88,3%E6%9C%88,4%E6%9C%88,5%E6%9C%88,6%E6%9C%88,7%E6%9C%88,8%E6%9C%88,9%E6%9C%88,10%E6%9C%88,11%E6%9C%88,12%E6%9C%88&amp;weekday_code=%E6%97%A5,%E4%B8%80,%E4%BA%8C,%E4%B8%89,%E5%9B%9B,%E4%BA%94,%E5%85%AD" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://abetusk.github.io/neatocal/?month_code=1%E6%9C%88,2%...&lt;/a&gt; (chinese month and day)&lt;p&gt;There's also a data file option for more complex date notes.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 28 Dec 2025 06:50:18 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46409027</link><dc:creator>abetusk</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46409027</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46409027</guid></item><item><title>New comment by vlovich123 in "Rex is a safe kernel extension framework that allows Rust in the place of eBPF"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;As a lover of Rust, ooo boy does this sound like a bad idea. The Rust compiler is not guaranteed to always output safe code against malicious inputs given that there’s numerous known soundness bugs that allow exploiting this. Unless I’m missing something this is a security nightmare of an idea.&lt;p&gt;Also there’s reasons why eBPF programs aren’t allowed to run arbitrarily long and this just ignores that problem too.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 28 Dec 2025 06:17:27 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46408899</link><dc:creator>vlovich123</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46408899</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46408899</guid></item><item><title>New comment by subdavis in "Replacing JavaScript with Just HTML"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;The details / summary thing absolutely kills me. There’s basically nothing you can’t do with them.  Hiding and replacing markers is easy.  But every component library just pretends they don’t exist.&lt;p&gt;It even saves you the effort of all the aria control and expanded tags: these tags don’t need them.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 28 Dec 2025 01:48:32 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46407603</link><dc:creator>subdavis</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46407603</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46407603</guid></item><item><title>New comment by anonzzzies in "Say No to Palantir in the NHS"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Everyone should say no to palantir anywhere, especially outside the US.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 28 Dec 2025 00:31:28 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46407068</link><dc:creator>anonzzzies</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46407068</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46407068</guid></item><item><title>New comment by NiloCK in "How we lost communication to entertainment"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Being born in 83, I experienced the shift from "serious local nightly news program" into the 24 hr cable news platforms as a loss of focused, serious journalism.&lt;p&gt;Only much later did I read Understanding Media, Amusing Ourselves to Death, etc, and understand that the prior shift from print to the "serious local nightly new program" was itself a loss of focused, serious journalism.&lt;p&gt;For today's youth, Tik Tok is "the air we breath" - the de-facto standard against which the future will be judged. It's &lt;i&gt;horrifying&lt;/i&gt; to imagine what will be worse.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 28 Dec 2025 00:30:03 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46407060</link><dc:creator>NiloCK</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46407060</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46407060</guid></item></channel></rss>