<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>Hacker News: Best Comments</title><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/bestcomments</link><description>Hacker News RSS</description><docs>https://hnrss.org/</docs><generator>hnrss v2.1.1</generator><lastBuildDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 01:55:56 +0000</lastBuildDate><ns0:link href="https://hnrss.org/bestcomments" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item><title>New comment by elAhmo in "Apple AI chief John Giannandrea is retiring in spring 2026"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Siri is probably among the products which had the most exposure to users (probably a billion+ users throughout iPhone's history) without capturing that opportunity to actually do anything meaningful with the huge user base it got for free.&lt;p&gt;A decade and a half is insane timeline in tech industry, and huge majority of users use Siri the same way today as 15 years ago, setting a timer or an alarm clock.&lt;p&gt;If they had 0 improvements over these 15 years the situation wouldn't be much different than today.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 23:03:22 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46114686</link><dc:creator>elAhmo</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46114686</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46114686</guid></item><item><title>New comment by embedding-shape in "Mozilla's latest quagmire"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Firefox was seriously a better browser, not just "implements standards better". It ran faster, it had tabs (wow!) and at one point it got Firebug which let you have a console INSIDE the browser that showed information you could print with `console.log`, I kid you not.&lt;p&gt;It was a better browser through and through, maybe because MS slept on IE or maybe not, but in the end it isn't revisionist to say they beat MS's proverbial posterior because the browser was better.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 22:31:35 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46114263</link><dc:creator>embedding-shape</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46114263</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46114263</guid></item><item><title>New comment by eutropia in "Instagram chief orders staff back to the office five days a week in 2026"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Instagram chief orders quiet layoffs to please investors in 2026&lt;p&gt;fixed that title for you&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 21:27:20 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46113466</link><dc:creator>eutropia</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46113466</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46113466</guid></item><item><title>New comment by garciasn in "How to Attend Meetings – Internal guidelines from the New York Times"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I agree with each and every single slide in this presentation; I do. I also know that in each and every company I have ever worked for, none of this is going to fly. Especially, "Attending meetings is a choice." Just like paying taxes is a choice; got it.&lt;p&gt;---&lt;p&gt;For decades, I have been asking for agendas; I have asked for clarification on what to do to prepare; I have even suggested that we have solid outcomes. None of which are followed nor what anyone else wants.&lt;p&gt;Even as a leader at organizations where I can enforce this on my team, it makes absolutely no difference. Hell, Google Calendar (we use Workspace at my current org) doesn't even have solid support for good meeting invite commentary. And, even if it did, 99.99999% of folks wouldn't read any of it anyway.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 21:22:55 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46113419</link><dc:creator>garciasn</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46113419</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46113419</guid></item><item><title>New comment by rishabhaiover in "India orders smartphone makers to preload state-owned cyber safety app"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I'm shocked by people and state using the crutch of cyber crime or scams to push a totalitarian solution to a problem that is better solved by improved education and targeted campaigns against common security pitfalls.&lt;p&gt;I abhor any decision that robs even a grain of my individual freedom.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 18:51:51 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46111364</link><dc:creator>rishabhaiover</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46111364</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46111364</guid></item><item><title>New comment by zug_zug in "DeepSeek-v3.2: Pushing the frontier of open large language models [pdf]"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Well props to them for continuing to improve, winning on cost-effectiveness, and continuing to publicly share their improvements. Hard not to root for them as a force to prevent an AI corporate monopoly/duopoly.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 18:36:56 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46111149</link><dc:creator>zug_zug</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46111149</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46111149</guid></item><item><title>New comment by LanceH in "Games using anti-cheats and their compatibility with GNU/Linux or Wine/Proton"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Amongst the discussion of rootkits and anti-cheat, I would like to add that part of the reason it is necessary is caused by the game companies that took away the standard method of playing multiplayer -- players running their own servers.&lt;p&gt;It used to be pretty easy to just ban people from playing, now we're 100% reliant on their ability to do it.  So we have anti-cheat which roots our computer, and still doesn't 100% solve the problem.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 15:01:39 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46108253</link><dc:creator>LanceH</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46108253</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46108253</guid></item><item><title>New comment by wavemode in "Why xor eax, eax?"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&gt; CEO walking up behind my desk and pointing out that I'd done MOV AX, 0 when I could have done XOR AX, AX&lt;p&gt;Now that's what I call micromanagement.&lt;p&gt;(sorry couldn't resist)&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 14:51:06 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46108116</link><dc:creator>wavemode</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46108116</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46108116</guid></item><item><title>New comment by shevy-java in "Search tool that only returns content created before ChatGPT's public release"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&gt; This is a search tool that will only return content created before ChatGPT's first public release on November 30, 2022.&lt;p&gt;The problem is that Google's search engine - but, oddly enough, ALL search engines - got worse before that already. I noticed that search engines got worse several years before 2022. So, AI further decreased the quality, but the quality had a downwards trend already, as it was. There are some attempts to analyse this on youtube (also owned by Google - Google ruins our digital world); some explanations made sense to me, but even then I am not 100% certain why Google decided to ruin google search.&lt;p&gt;One key observation I made was that the youtube search, was copied onto Google's regular search, which makes no sense for google search. If I casually search for a video on youtube, I may be semi-interested in unrelated videos. But if I search on Google search for specific terms, I am not interested in crap such as "others also searched for xyz" - that is just ruining the UI with irrelevant information. This is not the only example, Google made the search results worse here and tries to confuse the user in clicking on things. Plus placement of ads. The quality really worsened.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 09:28:26 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46105297</link><dc:creator>shevy-java</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46105297</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46105297</guid></item><item><title>New comment by BrenBarn in "It’s been a very hard year"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;In contrast to others, I just want to say that I applaud the decision to take a moral stance against AI, and I wish more people would do that.  Saying "well you have to follow the market" is such a cravenly amoral perspective.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 07:56:28 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46104696</link><dc:creator>BrenBarn</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46104696</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46104696</guid></item><item><title>New comment by liendolucas in "Google Antigravity just deleted the contents of whole drive"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I love how a number crunching program can be deeply humanly "horrorized" and "sorry" for wiping out a drive. Those are still feelings reserved only for real human beings, and not computer programs emitting garbage. This is vibe insulting to anyone that don't understand how "AI" works.&lt;p&gt;I'm sorry for the person who lost their stuff but this is a reminder that in 2025 you STILL need to know what you are doing and if you don't then put your hands away from the keyboard if you think you can lose valuable data.&lt;p&gt;You simply don't vibe command a computer.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 07:33:43 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46104563</link><dc:creator>liendolucas</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46104563</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46104563</guid></item><item><title>New comment by AIorNot in "Is America's jobs market nearing a cliff?"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Well as a single datum:&lt;p&gt;After I got laid off in late 2023 I had a devil of a time finding work (despite having AI experience) to the point my unemployment ran out -&lt;p&gt;And I was 20 years as a dev and tech lead and full stack, (never had trouble finding work)  including stints as a leading EM and CTO, I’ve been an industry award winning innovation lead,a digital studio director, switching tech stacks and cloud certs all my career..mentoring juniors and doing podcasts and writing white papers etc, but peanuts - nothing&lt;p&gt;Getting ghosted by 25 year olds in interviews and doing rounds and  rounds and leetcode and all that but no success- for example I  had a 7 round interview with NBCUniversal in 2023 and then got ghosted (I probably doged a bullet since they had subsequent layoffs)&lt;p&gt;a 12 month stint with nothing - we lost our savings as my wife got laid off too&lt;p&gt;Since then I pivoted to AI and Gen AI startups- joining incubators and finally got some work or at least cofounded some AI startups- now money is tight and I dont have health insurance but at least I have a job… it sucks as a over 45 year old as I have so much experience but no one cares.. still dont have much grey hair so I can pass for 40 to get noticed&lt;p&gt;No one stable is hiring or your resume just goes to a dead letter queue or is lost in ether or lost amid all the ai generated resumes out there - young ML and PHds and people under 40 seem to be getting work in Gen AI but thats about it&lt;p&gt;networking is the only game left and most good recruiters I know got laid off too&lt;p&gt;At least I’ve built up production experience in agents and context engineering RL, pytorch, langchain/LangGraph, RAG, KGa, etc python, BAML, LLM and LLMops to add to my years of full stack work&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 06:52:12 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46104312</link><dc:creator>AIorNot</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46104312</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46104312</guid></item><item><title>New comment by Swizec in "It’s been a very hard year"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I’ve seen Picallilli’s stuff around and it looks extremely solid. But you can’t beat the market. You either have what they want to buy, or you don’t.&lt;p&gt;&gt; Landing projects for Set Studio has been extremely difficult, especially as we won’t work on product marketing for AI stuff, from a moral standpoint, but the vast majority of enquiries have been for exactly that&lt;p&gt;The market is speaking. Long-term you’ll find out who’s wrong, but the market can usually stay irrational for much longer than you can stay in business.&lt;p&gt;I think everyone in the programming education business is feeling the struggle right now. In my opinion this business died 2 years ago – &lt;a href="https://swizec.com/blog/the-programming-tutorial-seo-industry-is-dead/" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://swizec.com/blog/the-programming-tutorial-seo-industr...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 06:08:29 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46104058</link><dc:creator>Swizec</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46104058</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46104058</guid></item><item><title>New comment by magicalist in "AI just proved Erdos Problem #124"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;The overhyped tweet from the robinhood guy raising money for his AI startup is nicely brought into better perspective by Thomas Bloom (including that #124 is not from the cited paper, "Complete sequences of sets of integer powers "/BEGL96):&lt;p&gt;&gt; &lt;i&gt;This is a nice solution, and impressive to be found by AI, although the proof is (in hindsight) very simple, and the surprising thing is that Erdos missed it. But there is definitely precedent for Erdos missing easy solutions!&lt;/i&gt;&lt;p&gt;&gt; &lt;i&gt;Also this is not the problem as posed in that paper&lt;/i&gt;&lt;p&gt;&gt; &lt;i&gt;That paper asks a harder version of this problem. The problem which has been solved was asked by Erdos in a couple of later papers.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;p&gt;&gt; &lt;i&gt;One also needs to be careful about saying things like 'open for 30 years'. This does not mean it has resisted 30 years of efforts to solve it! Many Erdos problems (including this one) have just been forgotten about it, and nobody has seriously tried to solve it.&lt;/i&gt;[1]&lt;p&gt;And, indeed, Boris Alexeev (who ran the problem) agrees:&lt;p&gt;&gt; &lt;i&gt;My summary is that Aristotle solved "a" version of this problem (indeed, with an olympiad-style proof), but not "the" version.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;p&gt;&gt; &lt;i&gt;I agree that the [BEGL96] problem is still open (for now!), and your plan to keep this problem open by changing the statement is reasonable. Alternatively, one could add another problem and link them. I have no preference.&lt;/i&gt;[2]&lt;p&gt;Not to rain on the parade out of spite, it's just that this is neat, but not like, unusually neat compared to the last few months.&lt;p&gt;[1] &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/thomasfbloom/status/1995083348201586965" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://twitter.com/thomasfbloom/status/1995083348201586965&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;[2] &lt;a href="https://www.erdosproblems.com/forum/thread/124#post-1899" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://www.erdosproblems.com/forum/thread/124#post-1899&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 03:40:02 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46103249</link><dc:creator>magicalist</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46103249</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46103249</guid></item><item><title>New comment by 0xbadcafebee in "Advent of Sysadmin 2025"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Here's 12 Sysadmin/DevOps (they're synonyms now!) challenges, straight from the day job:&lt;p&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;  1.  Get a user to stop logging in as root.
  2.  Get all users to stop sharing the same login and password for all servers.
  3.  Get a user to upgrade their app's dependencies to versions newer than 2010.
  4.  Get a user to use configuration management rather than scp'ing config files from their laptop to the server.
  5.  Get a user to bake immutable images w/configuration rather than using configuration management.
  6.  Get a user to switch from Jenkins to GitHub Actions.
  7.  Get a user to stop keeping one file with all production secrets in S3, and use a secrets vault instead.
  8.  Convince a user (and management) you need to buy new servers, because although "we haven't had one go down in years", every one has faulty power supply, hard drive, network card, RAM, etc, and the hardware's so old you can't find spare parts.
  9.  Get management to give you the authority to force users to rotate their AWS access keys which are 8 years old.
  10. Get a user to stop using the aws root account's access keys for their application.
  11. Get a user to build their application in a container.
  12. Get a user to deploy their application without you.
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
After you complete each one, you get a glass of scotch. Happy Holidays!&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 03:10:22 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46103083</link><dc:creator>0xbadcafebee</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46103083</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46103083</guid></item><item><title>New comment by nico in "Writing a good Claude.md"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&gt; Claude often ignores CLAUDE.md&lt;p&gt;&gt; The more information you have in the file that's not universally applicable to the tasks you have it working on, the more likely it is that Claude will ignore your instructions in the file&lt;p&gt;Claude.md files can get pretty long, and many times Claude Code just stops following a lot of the directions specified in the file&lt;p&gt;A friend of mine tells Claude to always address him as “Mr Tinkleberry”, he says he can tell Claude is not paying attention to the instructions on Claude.md, when Claude stops calling him “Mr Tinkleberry” consistently&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 00:35:47 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46102048</link><dc:creator>nico</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46102048</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46102048</guid></item><item><title>New comment by deergomoo in "Advent of Code 2025"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&gt; You don't need a computer science background to participate - just a little programming knowledge and some problem solving skills will get you pretty far.&lt;p&gt;Every time I see this I wonder how many amateur/hobbyist programmers it sets up for disappointment. Unless your definition of “pretty far” is “a small number of the part ones”, it’s simply not true.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 30 Nov 2025 22:53:45 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46101274</link><dc:creator>deergomoo</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46101274</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46101274</guid></item><item><title>New comment by thomascgalvin in "Don't push AI down our throats"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I have a pixel watch, and my main use for it is setting reminders, like "reminder 3pm put the laundry in the dryer". It's worked fine since the day I bought it.&lt;p&gt;Last week, they pushed an update that broke all of the features on the watch unless I agreed to allow Google to train their AI on my content.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 30 Nov 2025 19:15:47 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46099488</link><dc:creator>thomascgalvin</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46099488</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46099488</guid></item><item><title>New comment by daft_pink in "Don't push AI down our throats"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;The real creepy thing is the way they force you to give up your data with these products.  If it were just useful add ons, it wouldn’t bother me, but the fact that Gemini requires you to turn activity history off for paid plans for the promise they won’t train on your data or allow a person to view your prompts is insanity.  If you’re paying $20 for Pro or 249.99 for Ultra, you should be able to get activity history without training or review or storing your data for several years.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 30 Nov 2025 18:44:31 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46099207</link><dc:creator>daft_pink</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46099207</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46099207</guid></item><item><title>New comment by notepad0x90 in "Windows drive letters are not limited to A-Z"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;The NT paths are how the object manager refers to things. For example the registry hive HKEY_LOCAL_MACHINE is an alias for \Registry\Machine&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://learn.microsoft.com/en-us/windows-hardware/drivers/kernel/registry-key-object-routines" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://learn.microsoft.com/en-us/windows-hardware/drivers/k...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;In this way, NT is similar to Unix in that many things are just files part of one global VFS layout (the object manager name space).&lt;p&gt;Paths that start with drive letters are called a "DOSPath" because they only exist for DOS compatibility. But unfortunately, even in kernel mode, different sub systems might still refer to a DOSPath.&lt;p&gt;Powershell also exposes various things as "drives", pretty sure you could create your own custom drive as well for your custom app. For example, by default there is the 'hklm:\' drive path:&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://learn.microsoft.com/en-us/powershell/scripting/samples/managing-windows-powershell-drives?view=powershell-7.5" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://learn.microsoft.com/en-us/powershell/scripting/sampl...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;Get-PSDrive/New-PSDrive&lt;p&gt;You can't access certificates in linux/bash as a file path for example, but you can in powershell/windows.&lt;p&gt;I highly recommend getting the NtObjectManager powershell module and exploring about:&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/googleprojectzero/sandbox-attacksurface-analysis-tools" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://github.com/googleprojectzero/sandbox-attacksurface-a...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;ls NtObject:\&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 30 Nov 2025 16:17:46 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46097879</link><dc:creator>notepad0x90</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46097879</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46097879</guid></item><item><title>New comment by mikeyk in "Paul Hegarty's updated CS193p SwiftUI course released by Stanford"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I took CS193P when it was first offered in 2007; one of my favorite classes at Stanford because it was so hands-on. At the time few people had iPhones, so everyone in the class got a free iPod Touch for development. My final project was a photo sharing app with a Polaroid shake to reveal mechanic… lightly influenced Instagram which Kevin and I built a few years later!&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 30 Nov 2025 15:13:15 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46097254</link><dc:creator>mikeyk</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46097254</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46097254</guid></item><item><title>New comment by xrd in "Migrating Dillo from GitHub"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I've been messing around with GitLab as a self hosted alternative for a few years. I do like it, but it is resource intensive!&lt;p&gt;For the past few days I've been playing with Forgejo (from the Codeberg people). It is fantastic.&lt;p&gt;The biggest difference is memory usage. GitLab is Ruby on Rails and over a dozen services (gitlab itself, then nginx, postgrest, prometheus, etc). Forgejo is written in go and is a single binary.&lt;p&gt;I have been running GitLab for several years (for my own personal use only!) and it regularly slowly starts to use up the entirety of the RAM on a 16GB VM. I have only been playing with Forgejo for a few days, but I am using only 300MB of the 8 GB of RAM I allocated, and that machine is running both the server and a runner (it is idle but...).&lt;p&gt;I'm really excited about Forgejo and dumping GitLab. The biggest difference I can see if that Forgejo does not have GraphQL support, but the REST API seems, at first glance, to be fine.&lt;p&gt;EDIT: I don't really understand the difference between gitea and forgejo. Can anyone explain? I see lots of directories inside the forgejo volume when I run using podman that clearly indicate they are the same under the hood in many ways.&lt;p&gt;EDIT 2: Looks like forgejo is a soft fork in 2022 when there were some weird things that happened to governance of the gitea project: &lt;a href="https://forgejo.org/compare-to-gitea/#why-was-forgejo-created" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://forgejo.org/compare-to-gitea/#why-was-forgejo-create...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 30 Nov 2025 15:07:59 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46097220</link><dc:creator>xrd</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46097220</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46097220</guid></item><item><title>New comment by qsort in "Advent of Code 2025"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I'm actually pleasantly surprised to see a 2025 edition, last year being the 10th anniversary and the LLM situation with the leaderboard were solid indications that it would have been a great time to wrap it up and let somebody else carry the torch.&lt;p&gt;It's only going to be 12 problems rather than 24 this year and there isn't going to be a gloabl leaderboard, but I'm still glad we get to take part in this fun Christmas season tradition, and I'm thankful for all those who put in their free time so that we can get to enjoy the problems. It's probably an unpopular stance, but I've never done Advent of Code for the competitive aspect, I've always just enjoyed the puzzles, so as far as I'm concerned nothing was really lost.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 30 Nov 2025 13:53:59 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46096662</link><dc:creator>qsort</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46096662</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46096662</guid></item><item><title>New comment by PaulRobinson in "Advent of Code 2025"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Advent of Code is one of the highlights of December for me.&lt;p&gt;It's sad, but inevitable, that the global leaderboard had to be pulled. It's also understandable that this year is just 12 days, so takes some pressure off.&lt;p&gt;If you've never done it before, I recommend it. Don't try and "win", just enjoy the problem solving and the whimsy.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 30 Nov 2025 13:52:21 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46096639</link><dc:creator>PaulRobinson</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46096639</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46096639</guid></item><item><title>New comment by jtrn in "Bazzite: Operating System for Linux gaming"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I have a special spot that gets extremely annoyed when I feel I have to spend a necessary time just figuring out what something is. The page suffers from "developer-brain" marketing, where they describe the technology used to build it (cloud-native images) rather than what the product actually is. Why not just lead with that it is a Linux distro/version focused on gaming. In the beginning, I thought it was new hardware, then I actually thought it was a streaming service. the website does a poor job of simply stating what it actually is. Then again, I might be stupid, but the problem is that a lot of people are stupid. And I guess many non-developers are going to have a hard time just figuring out what the hell this thing is. I’m probably being too cranky now, but the page reads like a combination of the worst from developers-speak combined with the rest of marketing-speak.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 30 Nov 2025 07:28:11 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46094613</link><dc:creator>jtrn</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46094613</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46094613</guid></item><item><title>New comment by collinmcnulty in "Datacenters in space aren't going to work"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;To say the quiet part out loud, I don't think any serious companies have any intention to build a data center in space. There is no benefit in actually trying this. There is however, benefit in &lt;i&gt;saying&lt;/i&gt; you'll do it to advance a narrative and distract from the problems terrestrial data centers are facing to an audience that mostly doesn't understand how heat transfer in a vacuum works.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 30 Nov 2025 05:43:43 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46094171</link><dc:creator>collinmcnulty</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46094171</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46094171</guid></item><item><title>New comment by rayiner in "Americans no longer see four-year college degrees as worth the cost"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;That's historical revisionism. The percentage of American adults over age 25 who have a college degree was only 20% as recently as 1990. When America was truly at the top of the world in the 1950s and 1960s, it was under 10%. A high fraction of college attendance is better correlated with the 21st century decline in America's situation.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 30 Nov 2025 04:31:22 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46093745</link><dc:creator>rayiner</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46093745</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46093745</guid></item><item><title>New comment by collinmcnulty in "Americans no longer see four-year college degrees as worth the cost"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;This view seems to be common, but I think it misses what incredible alchemy comes from making people who come in for “job training” (like I did) spend 4 years in close proximity with research, academic freedom, liberal arts, and at least an attempt at some kind of intellectual idealism separate from economic incentive. It’s peanut butter and chocolate that has served democracy and its people well by having a middle class that is not just productive, but truly educated. It’s weird and it has problems, but it’s also wonderful, and we should not try to sever the two so we can more “efficiently” crank out credentials.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 30 Nov 2025 04:15:19 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46093651</link><dc:creator>collinmcnulty</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46093651</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46093651</guid></item><item><title>New comment by jswelker in "Americans no longer see four-year college degrees as worth the cost"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Higher ed is like employer based health insurance in that they are both weird path dependent historical accidents.&lt;p&gt;People want cheap healthcare, and it got shoehorned into an odd employer fringe benefit system that really is not at all related healthcare in any intrinsic way.&lt;p&gt;People want job training, and it got shoehorned into extra departments at liberal arts universities intended as aristocrat finishing schools. Job training really has little to no relationship to liberal arts.&lt;p&gt;And now both those two systems are failing to deliver those benefits because those benefits which were initially afterthought add-ons have outgrown the institutions that were their hosts. It's akin to a parasitic vine that is now much larger than the tree it grew on and is crushing it under its weight. Both will die as a result.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 30 Nov 2025 03:37:46 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46093419</link><dc:creator>jswelker</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46093419</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46093419</guid></item><item><title>New comment by dherls in "Let go of StackOverflow; communities must take ownership"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Some of the alternatives that the author suggests (Slack, Discord, Matrix rooms) are so much worse to search for answers in. Stack overflow has many disadvantages, but it is extremely good at being a publicly searchable repository of answers to common questions&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 30 Nov 2025 01:12:29 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46092530</link><dc:creator>dherls</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46092530</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46092530</guid></item></channel></rss>