<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>Hacker News: Best Comments</title><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/bestcomments</link><description>Hacker News RSS</description><docs>https://hnrss.org/</docs><generator>hnrss v2.1.1</generator><lastBuildDate>Sun, 04 Jan 2026 00:06:08 +0000</lastBuildDate><ns0:link href="https://hnrss.org/bestcomments" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item><title>New comment by porcoda in "Total monthly number of StackOverflow questions over time"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Not a big surprise once LLMs came along: stack overflow developed some pretty unpleasant traits over time.  Everything from legitimate questions being closed for no good reason (or being labeled a duplicate even though they often weren’t), out of date answers that never get updated as tech changes, to a generally toxic and condescending culture amongst the top answerers.  For all their flaws, LLMs are so much better.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2026 23:01:51 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46482640</link><dc:creator>porcoda</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46482640</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46482640</guid></item><item><title>New comment by jjaksic in "Report: Microsoft kills official way to activate Windows 11/10 without internet"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;When Nadella took over from Ballmer, he steered Microsoft in a better direction for a while. But by now he's become a lot worse. The biggest software company can no longer produce good software and its products are actively hostile to users. Nadella cares only about one thing, which is shoving AI everywhere and to everyone, at any cost. The irony is that he knows nothing about AI, how to build capable models or how to build useful AI products, nor does he have people who do. AI is his Metaverse: something he's singularity focused on, to the point of neglecting everything else, without any idea what to actually do with it.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2026 19:34:17 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46480604</link><dc:creator>jjaksic</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46480604</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46480604</guid></item><item><title>New comment by incognito124 in "Report: Microsoft kills official way to activate Windows 11/10 without internet"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Thank you, Microsoft, for accelerating the advent of The Year of The Linux Desktop&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2026 19:18:46 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46480412</link><dc:creator>incognito124</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46480412</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46480412</guid></item><item><title>New comment by dubeux in "Trump says Venezuela’s Maduro captured after strikes"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I get slightly desperate realizing how people are lead to such naive discussions, even in a place with supposedly instructed, informed persons.
Maduro may be a dictator, a murderer, whatever. This has absolutely no relation with the reasons for US invading, bombing and killing Venezuelans, or whichever country. For about a century, US has been doing it all over the world, not because they wanna live in a better, peaceful world - quite the opposite, they've been doing it for supporting coups and stablishing dictatorships that favour their supremacy, their role as the most powerful country in the world.
Do you really, really believe Mr. Donald is very concerned about the lives of poor venezuelans? Or, just to stay in the region, he supports El Salvador dictator because he's a very nice fellow?&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2026 18:16:27 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46479744</link><dc:creator>dubeux</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46479744</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46479744</guid></item><item><title>New comment by xg15 in "Trump says Venezuela’s Maduro captured after strikes"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Yeah, I was mostly surprised about the brazenness of it all. So the plan is to take over the government, take over the oil industry, sell the oil and in infinite grace give the Venezuelans some part of it back (minus of course the "compensation" for the years in which US companies were kept out of the country)&lt;p&gt;And all that as &lt;i&gt;official doctrine&lt;/i&gt;, not even some secret strategy paper or covert ops campaign.&lt;p&gt;Edit: I had to chuckle at his "reviewing" of the Monroe doctrine as DONroe doctrine. There is "on the nose" and there is "punching someone in the face"...&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2026 17:56:10 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46479512</link><dc:creator>xg15</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46479512</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46479512</guid></item><item><title>New comment by guax in "Trump says Venezuela’s Maduro captured after strikes"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;"We're going to run the country until such time as we can do a safe, proper and judicious transition"&lt;p&gt;And then a few seconds later: "US oil companies will go into Venezuela"&lt;p&gt;Never the US has been so honest around so many lies in the same speech.&lt;p&gt;I am still curious about the whole side bar about Washington being now safest and free of crime.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2026 16:56:22 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46478843</link><dc:creator>guax</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46478843</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46478843</guid></item><item><title>New comment by guax in "Trump says Venezuela’s Maduro captured after strikes"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;A lot of Venezuelans are happy about it.&lt;p&gt;Maduro is not good for Venezuela.&lt;p&gt;The US should not be the decider of who stays in power on another country.&lt;p&gt;The president should not have the power to apprehend a countries president IN THEIR COUNTRY without a process thats more than just "I really want it".&lt;p&gt;The US is giving another clear message that it does not care about global order, just global control. We're back in the 70s.&lt;p&gt;There is ZERO concern of the current US administration about the welfare of Venezuelans, its a power play, if maduro played by the US rules, he would be in power regardless of crimes. Pinochet, The Brazilian regime are all here as testament to that.&lt;p&gt;I hope the power change turns out better for the Venezuelans. I hope this is a catalyst of change for a better government. Ideally one that does not sell itself to the US for legitimacy. I don't think that is the likely outcome.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2026 16:24:28 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46478426</link><dc:creator>guax</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46478426</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46478426</guid></item><item><title>New comment by mbix77 in "Trump says Venezuela’s Maduro captured after strikes"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;There is not an extreme amount of crime and violence. Years ago yes. But now it's a lot better. Source: living here.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2026 15:52:28 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46478024</link><dc:creator>mbix77</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46478024</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46478024</guid></item><item><title>New comment by ofalkaed in "Trump says Venezuela’s Maduro captured after strikes"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I just spent way too much time reading through this thread looking for a single post more concerned about Venezuela and its people than the poster's own politics. I gave up when I noticed I was only a 1/4 of the way through thread, should have started from the bottom.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2026 13:37:24 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46476456</link><dc:creator>ofalkaed</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46476456</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46476456</guid></item><item><title>New comment by boramalper in "Trump says Venezuela’s Maduro captured after strikes"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Two wrongs don’t make a right.&lt;p&gt;Regardless of your opinion on Maduro, you can still acknowledge that the head of a sovereign state being captured in an unannounced/unnamed military operation by a superpower is wrong from a principled standpoint, and that it’s destabilising a country with 30+ million people if not the entire region.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2026 13:37:22 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46476455</link><dc:creator>boramalper</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46476455</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46476455</guid></item><item><title>New comment by jacquesm in "Trump says Venezuela’s Maduro captured after strikes"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;It's funny how many people already see this as a book that is opened and closed on the same day. That's not how these things work. This is like the first stone of an avalanche. It could stop here, or it could roll on for quite a while. It will take months or even years to know whether or not the outcome here was desirable or not and what the final tally is.&lt;p&gt;Remember the 'Arab spring' and what came after.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2026 13:12:15 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46476197</link><dc:creator>jacquesm</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46476197</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46476197</guid></item><item><title>New comment by unionjack22 in "Trump says Venezuela’s Maduro captured after strikes"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Here's a trick I've learnt to get an authentic view of events like these, a nice way to parse through the keyboard warrior and ivory tower voices and noise is to hear what Venezuelans, the millions of Venezuelan migrants, and the citizens of neighboring countries who've had to reckon with the legacy of Chavez think about this. You can extend this to anything really with good results.&lt;p&gt;No valuable insight will be gleaned from chat boards and reddit in the immediate aftermath of these sorts of events.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2026 12:44:50 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46475929</link><dc:creator>unionjack22</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46475929</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46475929</guid></item><item><title>New comment by aqme28 in "Trump says Venezuela’s Maduro captured after strikes"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;A lot of talk about how the administration didn't even try to justify this, but I think that the administration actually believes they did justify it. They exist in some bubble completely un-tethered from reality. I don't know what that means for the future but it's terrifying.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2026 08:33:38 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46474125</link><dc:creator>aqme28</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46474125</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46474125</guid></item><item><title>New comment by zuminator in "Microsoft kills official way to activate Windows 11/10 without internet"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Microsoft is making Windows into the Nigerian Prince of operating systems. Classically, Nigerian Prince scams are so obvious that they weed out all the people smart enough to avoid being swindled, leaving the easy pickings to be plucked without much effort.&lt;p&gt;Windows is the same. By Microsoft removing all bypass measures that make it tolerable, their remaining user base will just end up being people who don't care about security and privacy, people who won't complain about being inundated with ads, AI, and bingware, people who have no idea that a modern operating system should be fast, customizable, and open. That 90% customer base is easy to fleece with 10% effort, so why bother with the 10% base that will require 90% effort?&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2026 06:35:39 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46473351</link><dc:creator>zuminator</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46473351</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46473351</guid></item><item><title>New comment by MindSpunk in "IPv6 just turned 30 and still hasn't taken over the world"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&gt; - I don't have a shortage of IPv4. Maybe my ISP or my VPN host do, I don't know. I have a roomy 10.0.0.0/8 to work with.&lt;p&gt;What happens when multiple devices in your /8 want to listen on port 80 and 443 on the public address? Only one of them can. Now you're running a proxy.&lt;p&gt;&gt; - Every host routable from anywhere on the Internet? No thanks. Maybe I've been irreparably corrupted by being behind NAT for too long but I like the idea of a gateway between my well kept garden and the jungle and my network topology being hidden.&lt;p&gt;It's called a firewall. You want a firewall. IPv6 also has a firewall. NAT is not a firewall. NAT is usually configured as part of your firewall, but is not a firewall.&lt;p&gt;&gt; - Stateless auto configuration. What ? No, no, I want my ducks neatly in a row, not wandering about. Again maybe my brain is rotten from years of DHCP usage but yes, I want stateful configuration and I want all devices on my network to automatically use my internal DNS server thank you very much.&lt;p&gt;DHCPv6&lt;p&gt;&gt; - My ISP gives me a /64, what am I supposed to do with that anyways?&lt;p&gt;What are you supposed to do with a /8? Do you have several million computers?&lt;p&gt;&gt; - What happens if my ISP decides to change my prefix ? How do my routing rules need to change? I have no idea.&lt;p&gt;What happens if your ISP changes your IPv4 address?&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2026 02:59:22 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46472360</link><dc:creator>MindSpunk</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46472360</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46472360</guid></item><item><title>New comment by ajnin in "IPv6 just turned 30 and still hasn't taken over the world"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I don't use IPv6 because it solves a problem that I don't have and it provides functionality that I don't want. And also because I don't understand it very well.&lt;p&gt;My points :&lt;p&gt;- I don't have a shortage of IPv4. Maybe my ISP or my VPN host do, I don't know. I have a roomy 10.0.0.0/8 to work with.&lt;p&gt;- Every host routable from anywhere on the Internet? No thanks. Maybe I've been irreparably corrupted by being behind NAT for too long but I like the idea of a gateway between my well kept garden and the jungle and my network topology being hidden.&lt;p&gt;- Stateless auto configuration. What ? No, no, I want my ducks neatly in a row, not wandering about. Again maybe my brain is rotten from years of DHCP usage but yes, I want stateful configuration and I want all devices on my network to automatically use my internal DNS server thank you very much.&lt;p&gt;- It's hard to remember IPv6 addresses. The prospect of reconfiguring all my router and firewall rules looks rather painful.&lt;p&gt;- My ISP gives me a /64, what am I supposed to do with that anyways?&lt;p&gt;- What happens if my ISP decides to change my prefix ? How do my routing rules need to change? I have no idea.&lt;p&gt;In short, so far, ignorance is bliss.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2026 02:26:25 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46472163</link><dc:creator>ajnin</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46472163</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46472163</guid></item><item><title>New comment by wewewedxfgdf in "Microsoft kills official way to activate Windows 11/10 without internet"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Microsoft could have made Windows:&lt;p&gt;able to run on any hardware&lt;p&gt;free for basic usage, paid for commercial usage&lt;p&gt;lightweight, simple, stripped of all cruft and extras&lt;p&gt;consistent in it's UI and cleaned up from 40 years of inconsistencies&lt;p&gt;But they didn't - so people are looking for alternatives.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2026 01:24:25 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46471753</link><dc:creator>wewewedxfgdf</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46471753</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46471753</guid></item><item><title>New comment by sylens in "2026 will be my year of the Linux desktop"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;If this wasn’t HN, I would swear that my personal recommendation algorithm has gotten Linux desktop-pilled and that’s why I’m seeing so many posts like these every day. But in reality I think there is a groundswell of momentum happening here, and with component prices rising, I only see this continuing as more people look to breathe new life into older hardware.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2026 00:30:55 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46471314</link><dc:creator>sylens</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46471314</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46471314</guid></item><item><title>New comment by roxolotl in "2026 will be my year of the Linux desktop"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;“start menus made with React Native, control-alt-delete menus that are actually just webviews”&lt;p&gt;Haven’t used windows in five years or so but I’ve kept hearing bad things. This really is the icing on the cake though. Yea the AI stuff is dumb but if a OS manufacturer can’t be bothered to interact with their own UI libraries to build native UIs something has gone horribly wrong.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2026 00:24:58 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46471257</link><dc:creator>roxolotl</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46471257</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46471257</guid></item><item><title>New comment by altairprime in "Daft Punk Easter Egg in the BPM Tempo of Harder, Better, Faster, Stronger?"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;This is thematically amazing when you consider what the song is about — the roboticization of the abducted band. (Music video:)&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://youtu.be/gAjR4_CbPpQ" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://youtu.be/gAjR4_CbPpQ&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;In this song, which is also chapter four of the movie Interstella 5000 movie (spoilers from here!), the knocked-out singers are scanned, parameterized, brainwashed, uploaded into The Matrix, and then used in the following songs of the movie-album to robotically mass produce music.&lt;p&gt;It makes &lt;i&gt;perfect&lt;/i&gt; sense that the BPM is 123.45 because that’s exactly the sort of thing you get when a manager  (who’s shown at the end!) just enters some numbers on the keyboard into the bpm field. They don’t keysmash the numpad; they just hit 123456789 until the field is full!&lt;p&gt;So not only does the song itself convey what some boss thinks is music, robotically beating at 123.45 bpm, but it is itself about being endlessly-rotating brainwashed-boring cogs in a pop music production industrial machine. I’m pretty sure the movie scene cuts and animations are timed specifically to the beats of the song, but knowing that they’re timed to a machine-specific bpm that a human would never select at random with a metronome?&lt;p&gt;Absolute genius.&lt;p&gt;I had no idea. Thanks for posting this.&lt;p&gt;EDIT: At 123.4567bpm, I think the track has precisely &lt;i&gt;0.2345&lt;/i&gt; seconds of silence before the first 'beat' of the song and actually has &lt;i&gt;456&lt;/i&gt; beats total, which is either numerological nonsense or pure genius by Daft Punk. Math elsethread :)&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 02 Jan 2026 22:39:57 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46470381</link><dc:creator>altairprime</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46470381</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46470381</guid></item><item><title>New comment by susam in "Publish on your own site, syndicate elsewhere"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Also, don't forget to set up an RSS or Atom feed for your website. Contrary to the recurring claim that RSS is dead, most of the traffic to my website still comes from RSS feeds, even in 2̶0̶2̶5̶ 2026!  In fact, one of my silly little games became moderately popular because someone found it in my RSS feed and shared it on HN. [1]&lt;p&gt;From the referer (sic) data in my web server logs (which is not completely reliable but still offers some insight), the three largest sources of traffic to my website are:&lt;p&gt;1. RSS feeds - People using RSS aggregator services as well as local RSS reader tools.&lt;p&gt;2. Newsletters - I was surprised to discover just how many tech newsletters there are on the Web and how active their user bases are. Once in a while, a newsletter picks up one of my silly or quirky posts, which then brings a large number of visits from its followers.&lt;p&gt;3. Search engines - Traffic from Google, DuckDuckGo, Bing and similar search engines. This is usually for specific tools, games and HOWTO posts available on my website that some visitors tend to return to repeatedly.&lt;p&gt;[1] &lt;a href="https://susam.net/from-web-feed-to-186850-hits.html" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://susam.net/from-web-feed-to-186850-hits.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 02 Jan 2026 21:39:10 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46469710</link><dc:creator>susam</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46469710</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46469710</guid></item><item><title>New comment by michaelt in "Fighting Fire with Fire: Scalable Oral Exams"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;&gt; We surveyed students before releasing grades to capture their experience. [...] Only 13% preferred the AI oral format. 57% wanted traditional written exams.  [...] 83% of students found the oral exam framework more stressful than a written exam.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;p&gt;[...]&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;&gt; Take-home exams are dead. Reverting to pen-and-paper exams in the classroom feels like a regression.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;p&gt;Yeah, not sure the conclusion of the article really matches the data.&lt;p&gt;Students were invited to talk to an AI. They did so, and having done so they expressed a clear preference for written exams - which can be taken under exam conditions to prevent cheating, something universities have hundreds of years of experience doing.&lt;p&gt;I know some universities started using the square wheel of online assessment during covid and I can see how this octagonal wheel &lt;i&gt;seems&lt;/i&gt; good if you've only ever seen a square wheel. But they'd be even better off with a circular wheel, which really doesn't need re-inventing.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 02 Jan 2026 20:47:19 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46469168</link><dc:creator>michaelt</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46469168</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46469168</guid></item><item><title>New comment by 10000truths in "IPv6 just turned 30 and still hasn't taken over the world"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;It's hard to adopt something that schools don't teach. I know someone who graduated from UCI with a CompSci degree with a specialization in networking, just before the COVID19 pandemic began. He recalled that the networking courses he took did not cover IPv6 at all, except to describe the address format (i.e. 128 bits, written as hexadecimal, colon-separated). Everything he learned about IPv6, he had to learn on his own or on the job. A standard that has been published for over two decades, heavily used for over a decade, and critical in the worldwide growth of the Internet, was treated as an afterthought by one of the premier universities in the US.&lt;p&gt;Obvious disclaimer: This is a sample size of 1, and an anecdote is not data, yada yada. I'm not involved in academia, and have no insight into the adoption of IPv6 in CompSci networking curricula on a broader level.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 02 Jan 2026 19:45:50 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46468577</link><dc:creator>10000truths</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46468577</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46468577</guid></item><item><title>New comment by Drybones in "What you need to know before touching a video file"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Nearly this entire HN comment section is upset about VLC being mentioned once and not recommended. If you can not understand why this very minor (but loud?) note was made, then you probably do not do any serious video encoding or you would know why it sucks today and is well past its prime. VLC is glorified because it was a video player that used to be amazing back in the day, but hasn't been for several years now. It is the Firefox of media players.&lt;p&gt;There is a reason why the Anime community has collectively has ditched VLC in favor of MPV and MPC-HC. Color reproduction, modern codec support, ASS subtitle rendering, and even audio codecs are janky or even broken on VLC. 98% of all Anime encode release playback problems are caused by the user using VLC.&lt;p&gt;We even have a dedicated pastebin on a quick run down of what is wrong: &lt;a href="https://rentry.co/vee-ell-cee" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://rentry.co/vee-ell-cee&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;And this pastebin doesn't even have all the issues. VLC has a long standing issue of not playing back 5.1 Surround sound Opus correctly or at all. VLC is still using FFmpeg 4.x. We're on FFmpeg 8.x these days&lt;p&gt;I can not even use VLC to take screenshots of videos I encode because the color rendering on everything is wrong. BT.709 is very much NOT new and predates VLC itself.&lt;p&gt;And you can say "VLC is easy to install and the UI is easy." Yeah so is IINA for macOS, Celluloid for Linux, and MPV.net for Windows which all use MPV underneath. Other better and easy video players exist today.&lt;p&gt;We are not in 2012 anymore. We are no longer just using AVC/H264 + AAC or AC-3 (Dolby Audio) MP4s for every video. We are playing back HEVC, VP9, and AV1 with HDR metadata in MKV/webm cnotainers with audio codecs like Opus or HE-AACv3 or TrueHD in surround channels, BT.2020 colorspaces. VLC's current release is made of libraries and FFmpeg versions that predate some of these codecs/formats/metadata types. Even the VLC 4.0 nightly alpha is not keeping up. 4.0 is several years late to releasing and when it does, it may not even matter.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 02 Jan 2026 19:20:10 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46468297</link><dc:creator>Drybones</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46468297</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46468297</guid></item><item><title>New comment by stared in "HPV vaccination reduces oncogenic HPV16/18 prevalence from 16% to &lt;1% in Denmark"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I would like to add:&lt;p&gt;- HPVs are extremely common: 80% of men and 90% of women will have at least one strain in their lives. Unless you plan to remain completely celibate, you are likely to contract a strain.&lt;p&gt;- Sooner is better, but vaccination can be done at any age. Guidelines often lag behind, but vaccination makes sense even if you are currently HPV-positive. While it won't clear an existing infection, it protects against different strains and reinfection (typically body removed HPV in 1-2 years). See: &lt;a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/38137661/" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/38137661/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;- HPV16 is responsible for a large number of throat cancers (around 50% in smokers and 80% in non-smokers!). This affects both men and women. Vaccinating men is important for their own safety and to reduce transmission to their partners.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 02 Jan 2026 13:24:07 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46464474</link><dc:creator>stared</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46464474</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46464474</guid></item><item><title>New comment by nxtfari in "I'm a developer for a major food delivery app"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Believability aside (I do think it’s believable personally) this is pretty much how “evil” (from outsider perspective) is done at every company, including mine. Inside it’s all sprint meetings, KPIs and terminology that are either intentionally or unintentionally designed to keep engineers far from thinking about impact on real people. It’s easy to convince a 25 year old whiz kid to optimize human assets, it’s just like Factorio and it feels good to see the number go up. In-jokes and dark humor fly and it all feels not real and just like a game. Sometimes on purpose by management, sometimes automatic as a coping mechanism. Defense (my field) is very much the same way.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 02 Jan 2026 08:16:42 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46462595</link><dc:creator>nxtfari</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46462595</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46462595</guid></item><item><title>New comment by mitchellh in "Why users cannot create Issues directly"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Note that this is an active discussion where we're trying to get to a point of clarity where we can promote to an issue (when it is actionable). The discussion is open and this is the system working as intended!&lt;p&gt;I want to clarify though that there isn't a known widespread "memory leak issue." You didn't say "widespread", but just in case that is taken by anyone else. :) To clarify, there are a few challenges here:&lt;p&gt;1. The report at hand seems to affect a very limited number of users (given the lack of reports and information about them). There are lots of X meme posts about Ghostty in the macOS "Force Close" window using a massive amount of RAM but that isn't directly useful because that window also reports all the RAM _child processes_ are using (e.g. if you run a command in your shell that consumes 100 GB of RAM, macOS reports it as Ghostty using 100 GB of RAM). And the window by itself also doesn't tell us what you were doing in Ghostty. It farms good engagement, though.&lt;p&gt;2. We've run Ghostty on Linux under Valgrind in a variety of configurations (the full GUI), we run all of Ghostty's unit tests under Valgrind in CI for every commit, and we've run Ghostty on macOS with the Xcode Instruments leak checker in a variety of configurations and we haven't yet been able to find any leaks. Both of these run fully clean. So, the "easy" tools can't find it.&lt;p&gt;3. Following point 1 and 2, no maintainer familiar with the codebase has ever seen leaky behavior. Some of us run a build of Ghostty, working full time in a terminal, for weeks, and memory is stable.&lt;p&gt;4. Our Discord has ~30K users, and within it, we only have one active user who periodically gets a large memory issue. They haven't been able to narrow this down to any specific reproduction and they aren't familiar enough with the codebase to debug it themselves, unfortunately. They're trying!&lt;p&gt;To be clear, I 100% believe that there is some kind of leak affecting some specific configuration of users. That's why the discussion is open and we're soliciting input. I even spent about an hour today on the latest feedback (posted earlier today) trying to use that information to narrow it down. No dice, yet.&lt;p&gt;If anyone has more info, we'd love to find this. :)&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 02 Jan 2026 05:56:40 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46461860</link><dc:creator>mitchellh</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46461860</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46461860</guid></item><item><title>New comment by ok123456 in "Why users cannot create Issues directly"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;100% agree.&lt;p&gt;If it's someone else's project, they have full authority to decide what is and isn't an issue. With large enough projects, you're going to have enough bad actors, people who don't read error messages, and just downright crazy people. Throw in people using AI for dubious purposes like CVE inflation, and it's even worse.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 02 Jan 2026 04:29:02 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46461421</link><dc:creator>ok123456</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46461421</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46461421</guid></item><item><title>New comment by pavlus in "A website to destroy all websites"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I've read your comment before visiting the site, and it got me wondering -- how bad can it be? Can it be worse than those acid green on red sites of the 90s-00s?&lt;p&gt;Imagine my surprise, when I opened the site and it looked and felt just like a museum or art exhibit. This was the literal feeling I had -- being at an art gallery, but online.&lt;p&gt;I guess, these comments tell more about the commenters, than TFA. We should remind ourselves to be more critical to the content we consume, regardless where it comes from.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 02 Jan 2026 00:27:22 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46459874</link><dc:creator>pavlus</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46459874</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46459874</guid></item><item><title>New comment by ralph84 in "BYD Sells 4.6M Vehicles in 2025, Meets Revised Sales Goal"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Auto manufacturing is low margin and capital intensive. BYD is valued as an auto manufacturer. Tesla is not.&lt;p&gt;Even all of that aside, the idea that foreign investors will be allowed to meaningfully participate in the upside of Chinese companies is questionable. Every Chinese company is one recapitalization away from zeroing out the common stock owned by foreigners. What are they gonna do, sue in Chinese court?&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2026 23:40:45 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46459483</link><dc:creator>ralph84</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46459483</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46459483</guid></item></channel></rss>