<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>Hacker News: Best Comments</title><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/bestcomments</link><description>Hacker News RSS</description><docs>https://hnrss.org/</docs><generator>hnrss v2.1.1</generator><lastBuildDate>Sun, 05 Oct 2025 00:31:20 +0000</lastBuildDate><ns0:link href="https://hnrss.org/bestcomments" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item><title>New comment by jcz_nz in "Asked to do something illegal at work? Here's what these software engineers did"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;At the very least, these folks need to have their names permanently attached to this atrocity. These weren’t decisions made by “a corporation” - these people sat across a meeting room table and actually concluded that targeting breast cancer patients was an acceptable means to an end.&lt;p&gt;Lori A. Beer was the CIO at the time.  Now at JP Morgan.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 04 Oct 2025 00:22:37 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45469309</link><dc:creator>jcz_nz</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45469309</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45469309</guid></item><item><title>New comment by jcz_nz in "Asked to do something illegal at work? Here's what these software engineers did"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;In 2010 WellPoint was found to be automatically targeting insurance policies of women with breast cancer for cancellation, using any pretext.   Angela Braly was the CEO at the time, now at ExxonMobile.  WellPoint was the second largest health insurer in the US at the time.
This required a lot of business analysis and software development - and people had to realize what this code was doing. I’m guessing bonuses were paid on the back of the “savings” this generated.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 04 Oct 2025 00:17:45 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45469276</link><dc:creator>jcz_nz</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45469276</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45469276</guid></item><item><title>New comment by HumblyTossed in "LoRA Without Regret"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;The name gets me every single time. Always think it’s going to be about radio LoRa&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2025 23:05:06 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45468827</link><dc:creator>HumblyTossed</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45468827</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45468827</guid></item><item><title>New comment by akagusu in "Jeff Bezos says AI is in a bubble but society will get 'gigantic' benefits"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;The big question is what "society" he is talking about? Is it the "society" that includes all people, or the "society" that includes only rich people?&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2025 22:44:10 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45468686</link><dc:creator>akagusu</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45468686</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45468686</guid></item><item><title>New comment by yjftsjthsd-h in "Inkjet printer with DRM-free ink will be launched via a crowdfunding campaign"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.crowdsupply.com/open-tools/open-printer" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://www.crowdsupply.com/open-tools/open-printer&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;&gt; Open Source&lt;p&gt;&gt; Open Printer will use the Creative Commons BY-NC-SA 4.0 license for all of its files, including electronics and mechanical design files, firmware code, and the bill of materials. We hope that people will be able to repair, upgrade, and contribute improvements to their printers.&lt;p&gt;It's a nice hope, but they've conveniently banned being able to pay someone else to make parts for you, which will make it harder. Also, not Open Source. (Shared Source is still better than proprietary, but it's not F/OSS.)&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2025 22:30:27 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45468592</link><dc:creator>yjftsjthsd-h</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45468592</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45468592</guid></item><item><title>New comment by daneel_w in "Offline card payments should be possible no later than 1 July 2026"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;&gt; "It's usually not said out loud, but cash is often considered to be dirty and criminal ..."&lt;/i&gt;&lt;p&gt;Are you sure this isn't impression you've gotten from isolated reactions involving a small number of individuals, perhaps just a single individual? I can't relate to the sentiment at all, having lived here for just over three decades and experiencing the popularity shift from cash to debit card. I can, in fact, not recall a single time ever that someone has divulged the opinion that they consider cash "dirty and criminal".&lt;p&gt;More than anything else the Swede's favor of debit card is the convenience. Second to that I would say is the security of not immediately losing funds if you misplace the card or it being stolen - it feels less risky carrying a debit card, in particular if you're the type who prefers having more than a few "tens" on you in case you'd need or want to buy something.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2025 21:35:29 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45468070</link><dc:creator>daneel_w</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45468070</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45468070</guid></item><item><title>New comment by g-mork in "Offline card payments should be possible no later than 1 July 2026"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;The EMV standard has long supported an offline transaction flow. AFAIK it was the default almost everywhere in Finland circa 2011, contactless there was almost always instantaneous. Digging into why that was compared to the invariable wait when using contactless in the UK revealed this flow.&lt;p&gt;The card has a variety of risk counters on it that allow it to securely decide whether an offline transaction can proceed, at least some of which are also exposed to the terminal which can have its own separate policy. I imagine internally the banks and payment gateways have a huge variety of internal related tuneables.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2025 21:34:41 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45468062</link><dc:creator>g-mork</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45468062</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45468062</guid></item><item><title>New comment by Etheryte in "Offline card payments should be possible no later than 1 July 2026"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Some context might be useful here. I spent some time living Sweden not too long ago and Swedes practically don't use cash. It's usually not said out loud, but cash is often considered to be dirty and criminal, to the point that most don't have any at all. Digital payments are very convenient and deeply integrated, so long as you have a local ID which allows you use the local payment system Swish etc.&lt;p&gt;This worked nicely until the tensions in Europe lead to more cyberattacks rolling in and suddenly you have people not being able to buy food, medicine, and so forth. Not too long after, there was a government advisory urging people to keep some cash reserves in case a larger cyberattack happens, but cultural habits at large are hard to change. This is of course a coarse simplification of the context, but might help understand this incentive a bit better.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2025 21:06:06 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45467771</link><dc:creator>Etheryte</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45467771</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45467771</guid></item><item><title>New comment by jinushaun in "ICE Wants to Build Out a 24/7 Social Media Surveillance Team"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;It’s pretty clear that ICE is the seed of a paramilitary force.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2025 20:07:37 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45467221</link><dc:creator>jinushaun</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45467221</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45467221</guid></item><item><title>New comment by simonw in "PEP 810 – Explicit lazy imports"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Love this. My &lt;a href="https://llm.datasette.io/" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://llm.datasette.io/&lt;/a&gt; CLI tool supports plugins, and people were complaining about really slow start times even for commands like "llm --help" - it turned out there were popular plugins that did things like import pytorch at the base level, so the entire startup was blocked on heavy imports.&lt;p&gt;I ended up adding a note to the plugin author docs suggesting lazy loading inside of functions - &lt;a href="https://llm.datasette.io/en/stable/plugins/advanced-model-plugins.html#tip-lazily-load-expensive-dependencies" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://llm.datasette.io/en/stable/plugins/advanced-model-pl...&lt;/a&gt; - but having a core Python language feature for this would be really nice.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2025 19:54:23 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45467095</link><dc:creator>simonw</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45467095</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45467095</guid></item><item><title>New comment by 0cf8612b2e1e in "LinkedIn sues software company allegedly scraping data from profiles"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Yeah, only Microsoft is allowed to indiscriminately scrape the web!&lt;p&gt;I somehow want both parties to lose.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2025 19:39:09 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45466941</link><dc:creator>0cf8612b2e1e</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45466941</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45466941</guid></item><item><title>New comment by blast in "Jeff Bezos says AI is in a bubble but society will get 'gigantic' benefits"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;He's (unsurprisingly) making an analogy to the dotcom bubble, which seems to me correct. There was a bubble, many non-viable companies got funded and died, and nevertheless the internet did eventually change everything.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2025 19:34:35 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45466890</link><dc:creator>blast</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45466890</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45466890</guid></item><item><title>New comment by jandrewrogers in "Anduril and Palantir battlefield communication system has flaws, Army memo says"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;What's the issue? Everything about this is normal and expected when prototyping new capabilities for DoD.&lt;p&gt;DoD intentionally pushes hard to get testable capabilities as early as possible to shorten feedback loops, understanding that features ancillary to the capability will be limited, stubbed out, or implemented using a stopgap that you would never use in production. This will all be cleaned up in the production implementation once everyone is happy with how the capability works. Basically an agile customer development approach, similar to what is used in startups.&lt;p&gt;In my experience, the fine-grained control and security features are &lt;i&gt;never&lt;/i&gt; implemented in the prototypes. This can be extremely fussy and slow development that isn't needed to evaluate capability. It also requires a lot of customer involvement, so they usually aren't willing to invest the time until they are satisfied that they want to move forward with the capability. The security architecture is demonstrably the kind of thing that can be mechanically added later so DoD takes the view that there is no development risk by not implementing it in the prototype.&lt;p&gt;There may be fair criticisms of the system but it looks like the article is going out of its way to mislead and misrepresent.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2025 16:38:49 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45464864</link><dc:creator>jandrewrogers</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45464864</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45464864</guid></item><item><title>New comment by BurningFrog in "Social anxiety isn't about being liked"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Perhaps this is controversial, but I think this is a mostly male way of expressing affection.&lt;p&gt;Women observing this sometimes conclude that men are horribly cruel to each other.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2025 16:35:04 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45464830</link><dc:creator>BurningFrog</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45464830</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45464830</guid></item><item><title>New comment by cortesoft in "Social anxiety isn't about being liked"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I hadn’t heard the word countersignaling before, but it matches something I had observed many years ago.&lt;p&gt;My closest groups of friends always make so much fun of each other. We make negative comments about the worst traits about each other, the things that we are most self-conscious about… yet every time my friends make fun of me for something I worry about, I actually feel better and more comfortable with myself.&lt;p&gt;When I thought about why, I realized it’s because of the hidden message behind the ridicule of my longtime friends; they are telling me, “we are keenly aware of the worst qualities about you, and we love you and want to spend time with you anyway.”&lt;p&gt;There is comfort in knowing you don’t have to hide your flaws to be accepted and loved.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2025 16:15:30 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45464604</link><dc:creator>cortesoft</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45464604</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45464604</guid></item><item><title>New comment by softwaredoug in "California needs to learn from Houston and Dallas about homelessness"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I think there's a crisis of ineffectiveness in Center-Left institutions&lt;p&gt;They are too deliberative, and take excessive time including voices of every stakeholder. So you don't just go do the "obvious thing". You cater to trying to listen to every voice in an effort to be as inclusive as possible. Committee after committee and an obsession with process. You can spend years placating NIMBYs and people living with their own alternate reality.&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile real people are suffering from lack of action.&lt;p&gt;This level of ineffectiveness just enables authoritarianism ("at least they get something done") and gets people to seek the private industry for their solutions.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2025 14:02:45 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45463154</link><dc:creator>softwaredoug</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45463154</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45463154</guid></item><item><title>New comment by DrScientist in "How Israeli actions caused famine in Gaza, visualized"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Sadly I think you are mistaken to paint it as an irrational Israel lashing out - that's too generous.&lt;p&gt;I think it's quite the opposite - there has been a very clear, cold, calculated strategy - which is to use the conflict as an cover for doing what some in the government have always wanted to do ( and been quite open about it ) - which is to create a greater Israel - drive out all Palestinians from the river to the sea ( Gaza and West Bank ), as well as push to the river in the north into Lebanon and take more of Syria.&lt;p&gt;Those in government understand the potential reputation loss - but see that as temporary and something that can be managed under the protection of the US, while viewing the gain of territory as permanent.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2025 09:32:11 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45460904</link><dc:creator>DrScientist</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45460904</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45460904</guid></item><item><title>New comment by mattlondon in "Fp8 runs ~100 tflops faster when the kernel name has "cutlass" in it"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Just in case anyone else parsed that sentence the same way as me, ati detected "quake" as the executable and changed things like texture quality etc to increase benchmark performance.  Some people discovered this after they renamed the executable to "quack" and the image quality improved but the benchmarks were lower, proving that the ati drivers "optimised" by reducing quality.&lt;p&gt;Ati did not rename quake to quack as I originally thought from this! :)&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2025 08:21:55 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45460415</link><dc:creator>mattlondon</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45460415</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45460415</guid></item><item><title>New comment by haunter in "Fp8 runs ~100 tflops faster when the kernel name has "cutlass" in it"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Heh. Does anyone remember when almost 25 years ago ATI (AMD) caught manipulating the Quake III benchmarks by renaming the executables to ‘quack’?&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://web.archive.org/web/20230929180112/https://techreport.com/review/how-atis-drivers-optimize-quake-iii/" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://web.archive.org/web/20230929180112/https://techrepor...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://web.archive.org/web/20011108190056/https://hardocp.com/reviews/vidcards/ati/8500/index5.html" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://web.archive.org/web/20011108190056/https://hardocp.c...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://web.archive.org/web/20011118183932/www.3dcenter.de/artikel/2001/10-24_a.php" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://web.archive.org/web/20011118183932/www.3dcenter.de/a...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2025 06:42:50 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45459778</link><dc:creator>haunter</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45459778</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45459778</guid></item><item><title>New comment by nulld3v in "Fp8 runs ~100 tflops faster when the kernel name has "cutlass" in it"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/triton-lang/triton/pull/7298#discussion_r2202281596" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://github.com/triton-lang/triton/pull/7298#discussion_r...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;&gt; By disassembly of ptxas, it is indeed hard-coded that they have logic like: strstr(kernel_name, "cutlass").&lt;p&gt;&gt; it is likely that, this is an unstable, experimental, aggressive optimization by NVIDIA, and blindly always enabling it may produce some elusive bugs.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2025 05:41:28 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45459397</link><dc:creator>nulld3v</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45459397</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45459397</guid></item><item><title>New comment by daemonologist in "I spent the day teaching seniors how to use an iPhone"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I have a couple of older relatives with Macs, and every time you fire them up for the first time in a while (these people might go several months without using their computer) the Apple ID sign-in nagging is &lt;i&gt;insane&lt;/i&gt;.  It'll pop up the same sign-in notification a dozen times and seems to lock up the settings app until you deal with it.  I usually think of myself as quite patient but when I see that little window it inspires strong feelings.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2025 04:47:11 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45459074</link><dc:creator>daemonologist</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45459074</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45459074</guid></item><item><title>New comment by rajaman0 in "OpenAI's H1 2025: $4.3B in income, $13.5B in loss"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Consumer brand quality is so massively underrated by tech people.&lt;p&gt;ChatGPT has a phenomenal brand. That's worth 100x more than "product stickiness". They have 700 million weekly users and growing much faster than Google.&lt;p&gt;I think your points on Google being well positioned are apt for capitalization reasons, but only one company has consumer mindshare on "AI" and its the one with "ai" in its name.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2025 02:22:55 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45458183</link><dc:creator>rajaman0</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45458183</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45458183</guid></item><item><title>New comment by avalys in "I spent the day teaching seniors how to use an iPhone"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;The iPhone - and macOS too - used to be a paragon of simplicity.&lt;p&gt;Today the setup experience on a brand-new iPhone or Mac is abysmal. Entering the same username and password multiple times - then sometimes a different username and password - competing notifications, irrelevant feature nags, a popup from some random product manager about their pet thingy. Permission questions from some meddlesome privacy team about the feature you just said you wanted to turn on. Uncertainty about whether you’ll break something irreparably by “skipping” the expected setup path. A choice of several inscrutable interface modes because no one has the balls to commit to a single solution. Just terrible.&lt;p&gt;I guess this is what happens without a dictator to tell people they’re fired for shipping garbage, and when a company worries about meeting quarterly KPIs rather than doing something great.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2025 02:11:28 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45458107</link><dc:creator>avalys</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45458107</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45458107</guid></item><item><title>New comment by rzzzwilson in "I spent the day teaching seniors how to use an iPhone"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;There's a quote from Bjarne Stroustrup showing it's not just Seniors having trouble:&lt;p&gt;I have always wished for my computer to be as easy to use as my telephone; my wish has come true because I can no longer figure out how to use my telephone.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2025 01:38:59 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45457844</link><dc:creator>rzzzwilson</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45457844</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45457844</guid></item><item><title>New comment by Zak in "Apple takes down ICE tracking apps after pressure from DOJ"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;This is exactly what's wrong with Apple's app store exclusivity. It's also what's wrong with mandatory notarization where regulations forbid that, and Google's plan to require developer verification.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2025 01:06:22 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45457567</link><dc:creator>Zak</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45457567</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45457567</guid></item><item><title>New comment by mrinterweb in "Apple takes down ICE tracking apps after pressure from DOJ"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Google is making it so sideloading APKs on Android is no longer possible. This is one of many great reasons why that should not happen.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2025 01:03:12 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45457544</link><dc:creator>mrinterweb</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45457544</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45457544</guid></item><item><title>New comment by saurik in "Apple takes down ICE tracking apps after pressure from DOJ"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;FWIW, everyone who claims that Apple &lt;i&gt;fundamentally needs&lt;/i&gt; the centralized ability to control apps on their platforms "for everyone's safety" -- despite how that obviously and repeatedly makes them become patsies for governments all over the world to enforce their censorship regimes -- are complicit in this stuff (in addition, of course, to the people who build it at Apple...).&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2025 00:57:24 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45457502</link><dc:creator>saurik</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45457502</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45457502</guid></item><item><title>New comment by DaiPlusPlus in "Apple takes down ICE tracking apps after pressure from DOJ"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Methinks this won’t be the last politically-motivated removal from Apple’s App Store; the more apps they remove then the more they weaken their own arguments about how a locked-in walled garden is in consumer interests.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2025 00:53:06 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45457474</link><dc:creator>DaiPlusPlus</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45457474</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45457474</guid></item><item><title>New comment by A_D_E_P_T in "How Israeli actions caused famine in Gaza, visualized"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Israel's response to Oct 7th has been a major blackpill.&lt;p&gt;Their strategy was, I think, as bad as it could &lt;i&gt;possibly&lt;/i&gt; be.  In fact, it really seemed, and still seems, like no strategy at all -- they lashed out wildly and extremely destructively, without a clear picture of what the post-war Gaza Strip will look like.&lt;p&gt;Hamas successfully baited Israel into a disproportionate response that killed tens of thousands, if not hundreds of thousands, which played directly into the dynamics of guerrilla warfare where a strong state's extreme actions against a weak opponent undermine its legitimacy.&lt;p&gt;Walking into such a trap tends to be a real world-historical blunder for any nation.&lt;p&gt;Yet, rather than adapting, Israel's network doubled down with censorship campaigns, crackdowns on protests, and weaponizing "anti-semitism" accusations to silence critics -- actions that have all backfired.  Now international support is collapsing, the EU is pushing sanctions, and the US is slowly distancing itself.  Israel's best option right now is to end the war as quickly as possible, and devote all of its efforts to repairing damaged relationships and mitigating the war's effects, before isolation accelerates to the level of sanctions similar to those imposed on South Africa.&lt;p&gt;I'll also note that it's interesting how all sides seem to have lost.  Hamas lost the shooting war, the people of Gaza have lost lives and livelihoods which may take more than a decade to rebuild, and Israel lost the information/media war so damn badly that it may genuinely not recover from this.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2025 00:09:43 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45457150</link><dc:creator>A_D_E_P_T</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45457150</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45457150</guid></item><item><title>New comment by nojs in "OpenAI's H1 2025: $4.3B in income, $13.5B in loss"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I think people are massively underestimating the money they will come from ads in the future.&lt;p&gt;They generated $4.3B in revenue without &lt;i&gt;any&lt;/i&gt; advertising program to monetise their 700 million weekly active users, most of whom use the free product.&lt;p&gt;Google earns essentially all of its revenue from ads, $264B in 2024. ChatGPT has more consumer trust than Google at this point, and numerous ways of inserting sponsored results, which they’re starting to experiment with with the recent announcement of direct checkout.&lt;p&gt;The biggest concern IMO is how good the open weight models coming out of China are, on consumer hardware. But as long as OpenAI remains the go-to for the average consumer, they’ll be fine.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2025 23:55:24 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45457037</link><dc:creator>nojs</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45457037</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45457037</guid></item></channel></rss>