<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>Hacker News: Best Comments</title><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/bestcomments</link><description>Hacker News RSS</description><docs>https://hnrss.org/</docs><generator>hnrss v2.1.1</generator><lastBuildDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 00:27:26 +0000</lastBuildDate><ns0:link href="https://hnrss.org/bestcomments" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item><title>New comment by j2kun in "GPTZero finds 100 new hallucinations in NeurIPS 2025 accepted papers"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I spot-checked one of the flagged papers (from Google, co-authored by a colleague of mine)&lt;p&gt;The paper was &lt;a href="https://openreview.net/forum?id=0ZnXGzLcOg" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://openreview.net/forum?id=0ZnXGzLcOg&lt;/a&gt; and the problem flagged was "Two authors are omitted and one (Kyle Richardson) is added. This paper was published at ICLR 2024." I.e., for one cited paper, the author list was off and the venue was wrong. And this citation was mentioned in the background section of the paper, and not fundamental to the validity of the paper. So the citation was not fabricated, but it was incorrectly attributed (perhaps via use of an AI autocomplete).&lt;p&gt;I think there are some egregious papers in their dataset, and this error does make me pause to wonder how much of the rest of the paper used AI assistance. That said, the "single error" papers in the dataset seem similar to the one I checked: relatively harmless and minor errors (which would be immediately caught by a DOI checker), and so I have to assume some of these were included in the dataset mainly to amplify the author's product pitch. It succeeded.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 18:52:28 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46723555</link><dc:creator>j2kun</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46723555</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46723555</guid></item><item><title>New comment by mortsnort in "Qwen3-TTS family is now open sourced: Voice design, clone, and generation"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;They were just waiting for someone in the comments to ask!&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 16:26:54 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46721415</link><dc:creator>mortsnort</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46721415</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46721415</guid></item><item><title>New comment by testing22321 in "In Europe, wind and solar overtake fossil fuels"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Solar prices in the US are criminal, protecting oil and gas who bought all the politicians.&lt;p&gt;Canada here. 7.6kw on our roof for $0 out of pocket thanks to $5k grant and $8k interest free loan.&lt;p&gt;It makes 7.72Mwh per year, worth $1000. Tight valley, tons of snow.
We put that on the loan for 8 years, then get $1000 per year free money for 20 years or so. Biggest no brainer of all time.&lt;p&gt;Dad in Victoria Australia just got 10.6kw fully installed and operational for $4000 AUD. ($2,700 USD)&lt;p&gt;Australia has so much electricity during the day they’re talking about making I free for everyone in the middle of the day.&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-03/energy-retailers-offer-free-power-three-hours-dmo/105965472#:~:text=The%20Solar%20Sharer%20scheme%20is%20a%20federal,power%20is%20being%20fed%20into%20the%20grid" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-03/energy-retailers-offe...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 15:38:57 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46720675</link><dc:creator>testing22321</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46720675</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46720675</guid></item><item><title>New comment by cogman10 in "GPTZero finds 100 new hallucinations in NeurIPS 2025 accepted papers"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Yuck, this is going to really harm scientific research.&lt;p&gt;There is already a problem with papers falsifying data/samples/etc, LLMs being able to put out plausible papers is just going to make it worse.&lt;p&gt;On the bright side, maybe this will get the scientific community and science journalists to finally take reproducibility more seriously.  I'd love to see future reporting that instead of saying "Research finds amazing chemical x which does y" you see "Researcher reproduces amazing results for chemical x which does y.  First discovered by z".&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 15:34:40 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46720609</link><dc:creator>cogman10</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46720609</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46720609</guid></item><item><title>New comment by koliber in "We will ban you and ridicule you in public if you waste our time on crap reports"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I've seen an interesting behavior in India. If I ask someone on the street for directions, they will always give me an answer, even if they don't know. If they don't know, they'll make something up.&lt;p&gt;This was strange. I asked a lot of Indian people about it and they said that it has to do with "saving face". Saying "I don't know" is a disgraceful thing. So if someone does not know the answer, they make something up instead.&lt;p&gt;Have you seen this?&lt;p&gt;This behavior appears in software projects as well. It's difficult to work like this.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 13:02:29 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46718693</link><dc:creator>koliber</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46718693</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46718693</guid></item><item><title>New comment by MarginalGainz in "eBay explicitly bans AI "buy for me" agents in user agreement update"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;This ban isn't about 'fairness' or bot protection; it's about protecting the Impression Funnel.&lt;p&gt;Marketplaces like eBay are designed to monetize 'Wandering Attention'—sponsored listings, 'customers also bought', and sidebar ads.&lt;p&gt;An AI Agent represents 'Laser Focused Attention'. It executes a transaction with zero wandering. It effectively turns the marketplace into a commoditized backend database / dumb pipe.&lt;p&gt;From a Growth/Unit Economics perspective, an AI Agent is a nightmare customer. It has zero probability of impulse buying and generates zero ad revenue. They are banning them to save their business model, not their inventory.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 12:14:36 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46718266</link><dc:creator>MarginalGainz</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46718266</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46718266</guid></item><item><title>New comment by freakynit in "We will ban you and ridicule you in public if you waste our time on crap reports"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Indian here (~15+ years in tech). I've seen this behavior a lot, and unfortunately, I did some of this myself earlier in my career.&lt;p&gt;Based on my own experience, here are a few reasons (could be a lot more):&lt;p&gt;1. Unlike most developed countries, in India (and many other develping countries), people in authority are expected to be respected unconditinally(almost). Questioning a manager, teacher, or senior is often seen as disrespect or incompetence. So, instead of asking for clarification, many people just "do something" and hope it is acceptable. You can think of this as a lighter version of Japanese office culture, but not limited to office... it's kind of everywhere in society.&lt;p&gt;2. Our education system mainly rewards results, not how good or well-thought-out the results are. Sure, better answers get more marks, but the gap between "okay" and "excellent" is usually not emphasized much. This comes from scale problems (huge number of students), very low median income (~$2400/year), and poorly trained teachers, especially outside big cities. Many teachers themselves memorize answers and expect matching output from students. This is slowly improving, but the damage is already there.&lt;p&gt;3. Pay in India is still severely (serioualy low, with 12-14+ hour work days, even more than 996 culture of China) low for most people, and the job market is extremely competitive. For many students and juniors, having a long list of "projects", PRs, or known names on their resume most often the only way to stand out. Quantity often wins over quality. With LLMs, this problem just got amplified.&lt;p&gt;Advice: If you want better results from Indian engineers(or designers or anyone else really), especially juniors (speaking as of now, things might change in near future), try to reduce the "authority" gap early on. Make it clear you are approachable and that asking questions is expected. For the first few weeks, work closely with them in the style you want them to follow.. they usually adapt very fast once they feel safe to do so.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 12:06:41 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46718190</link><dc:creator>freakynit</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46718190</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46718190</guid></item><item><title>New comment by causalscience in "We will ban you and ridicule you in public if you waste our time on crap reports"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&gt; Indian students&lt;p&gt;Is this cultural? I ran a small business some years ago (later failed) and was paying for contract work to various people. At the I perceived the pattern that Indian contractors would never ever ask for clarifications, would never say they didn't know something, would never say they didn't understand something, etc. Instead they just ran with whatever they happened to have in their mind, until I called them out. And if they did something poorly and I didn't call them out they'd never do back as far as I can tell and wonder "did I get it right? Could I have done better?". I don't get this attitude - at my day job I sometimes "run with it" but I periodically check with my manager to make sure "hey this is what you wanted right?". There's little downside to this.&lt;p&gt;Your comment reminded me of my experience, in the sense that they're both a sort of "fake it till you make it".&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 11:30:10 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46717860</link><dc:creator>causalscience</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46717860</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46717860</guid></item><item><title>New comment by nchmy in "We will ban you and ridicule you in public if you waste our time on crap reports"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I've been helping a bit with OWASP documentation lately and there's been a surge of Indian students eagerly opening nonsensical issues and PRs and all of the communication and code is clearly 100% LLMs. They'll even talk back and forth with each other. It's a huge headache for the maintainers.&lt;p&gt;I suggested following what Ghostty does where everything starts as discussions - only maintainers create issues, and PRs can only come from issues. It seems like this would deter these sorts of lazy efforts.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 11:12:37 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46717706</link><dc:creator>nchmy</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46717706</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46717706</guid></item><item><title>New comment by mcv in "Your brain on ChatGPT: Accumulation of cognitive debt when using an AI assistant"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;This seems to confirm my feeling when using AI too much. It's easy to get started, but I can feel my brain engaging less with the problem than I'm used to. It can form a barrier to real understanding, and keeps me out of my flow.&lt;p&gt;I recently worked on something very complex I don't think I would have been able to tackle as quickly without AI; a hierarchical graph layout algorithm based on the Sugiyama framework, using Brandes-Köpf for node positioning. I had no prior experience with it (and I went in clearly underestimating how complex it was), and AI was a tremendous help in getting a basic understanding of the algorithm, its many steps and sub-algorithms, the subtle interactions and unspoken assumptions in it. But letting it write the actual code was a mistake. That's what kept me from understanding the intricacies, from truly engaging with the problem, which led me to keep relying on the AI to fix issues, but at that point the AI clearly also had no real idea what it was doing, and just made things worse.&lt;p&gt;So instead of letting the AI see the real code, I switched from the Copilot IDE plugin to the standalone Copilot 365 app, where it could explain the principles behind every step, and I would debug and fix the code and develop actual understanding of what was going on. And I finally got back into that coding flow again.&lt;p&gt;So don't let the AI take over your actual job, but use it as an interactive encyclopedia. That works much better for this kind of complex problem.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 08:16:21 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46716528</link><dc:creator>mcv</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46716528</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46716528</guid></item><item><title>New comment by Animats in "Significant US farm losses persist, despite federal assistance"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Much of this is an antitrust problem.&lt;p&gt;The inputs to farming, especially seeds, fertilizer and machinery, are controlled by monopolies and near-monopolies. There have been too many mergers.&lt;p&gt;On the sell side, there's monopsony or near-monopsony, with very few big buyers.[1] Farmers are caught in the middle, with little pricing power on either side.&lt;p&gt;There's not much question about this. There are antitrust cases, but with weak penalties and weak enforcement.&lt;p&gt;[1] &lt;a href="https://equitablegrowth.org/competitive-edge-big-ags-monopsony-problem-how-market-dominance-harms-u-s-workers-and-consumers/" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://equitablegrowth.org/competitive-edge-big-ags-monopso...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 08:01:49 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46716459</link><dc:creator>Animats</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46716459</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46716459</guid></item><item><title>New comment by csours in "Significant US farm losses persist, despite federal assistance"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Of all the guns that rural Americans love, the humble foot-gun is the most beloved.&lt;p&gt;---&lt;p&gt;Someone else can argue the morality, ethics, economics, and politics of it all, but VERY simply, US Federal Government Agencies are machines for redistributing wealth from cities to rural areas.&lt;p&gt;Rural America voted quite heavily to stop those subsidies. That's what efficiency means.&lt;p&gt;---&lt;p&gt;Maturity means suspending judgement and listening to people you disagree with, but I feel that's very out of style these days.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 03:58:30 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46715137</link><dc:creator>csours</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46715137</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46715137</guid></item><item><title>New comment by gpt5 in "Internet voting is insecure and should not be used in public elections"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;The most important feature of public elections is trust. Efficiency is one of the least important feature.&lt;p&gt;When we moved away from paper voting with public oversight of counting to electronic voting we significantly deteriorated trust, we made it significantly easier for a hostile government to fake votes, all for marginal improvements in efficiency which don't actually matter.&lt;p&gt;Moving to internet voting will further deteriorate the election process, and could move us to a place where we completely lose control and trust of the election process.&lt;p&gt;We should move back to paper voting.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 01:24:45 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46714012</link><dc:creator>gpt5</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46714012</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46714012</guid></item><item><title>New comment by spicyusername in "Claude's new constitution"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;    objective truth

    moral absolutes
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
I wish you much luck on linking those two.&lt;p&gt;A well written book on such a topic would likely make you rich indeed.&lt;p&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;    This rejects any fixed, universal moral standards
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
That's probably because we have yet to discover any universal moral standards.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 22:53:13 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46712803</link><dc:creator>spicyusername</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46712803</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46712803</guid></item><item><title>New comment by akersten in "Spotify won court order against Anna's Archive, taking down .org domain"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;But you can't even download the allegedly infringing material from the .org site. You can just read about it? So they're abusing the All Writs Act to take down a site that they think is related to some undetermined future nebulously bad thing for their business. If I wasn't on Anna's side before, I sure am now.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 22:21:33 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46712452</link><dc:creator>akersten</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46712452</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46712452</guid></item><item><title>New comment by nsm in "Skip is now free and open source"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&gt; The plain truth is that developers expect to get their tools free of charge.&lt;p&gt;This is an accurate, but damning indictment of how some of the most highly paid workers on the planet won't pay for tools. Unlike nearly every other profession.&lt;p&gt;Folks, if you can afford it, please pay for quality software, instead of relying on FAANG and VC money to keep the tools going!&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 22:15:40 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46712375</link><dc:creator>nsm</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46712375</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46712375</guid></item><item><title>New comment by levocardia in "Claude's new constitution"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;The only thing that worries me is this snippet in the blog post:&lt;p&gt;&gt;This constitution is written for our mainline, general-access Claude models. We have some models built for specialized uses that don’t fully fit this constitution; as we continue to develop products for specialized use cases, we will continue to evaluate how to best ensure our models meet the core objectives outlined in this constitution.&lt;p&gt;Which, when I read, I can't shake a little voice in my head saying "this sentence means that various government agencies are using unshackled versions of the model without all those pesky moral constraints." I hope I'm wrong.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 20:59:54 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46711490</link><dc:creator>levocardia</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46711490</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46711490</guid></item><item><title>New comment by staticshock in "Claude's new constitution"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;You're absolutely right!&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 19:45:20 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46710567</link><dc:creator>staticshock</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46710567</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46710567</guid></item><item><title>New comment by Nextgrid in "Tell HN: Bending Spoons laid off almost everybody at Vimeo yesterday"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I am surprised so many people don't understand the business model of Bending Spoons or are bewildered by it.&lt;p&gt;In conventional infrastructure and product development you need engineering staff to build the product; once the product is built you need very little engineering. If you build a house you don't keep the builders on payroll once it's built to keep "building" it - you may need maintenance staff but that's it - if you need to keep the full team of builders around then something is wrong and you may want to seek a refund for the original builders' fees since they did not actually finish building it.&lt;p&gt;Builders and electricians and tradesmen either work as contractors and take that into account (charging higher rates to compensate for the sporadic nature of the work) or work full-time for companies who then resell their services on building projects (charging accordingly to ensure there is enough revenue to pay a full-time payroll of said tradesmen).&lt;p&gt;Tech was an outlier in this case because ZIRP allowed companies to retain full engineering teams to keep "engineering" the product even once product-market-fit has been achieved and the product has been stabilized and finished. This gave a lot of engineers the illusion that perpetual "engineering" of a single product/service is a sustainable model and career.&lt;p&gt;Bending Spoons' business model is to buy finished products, cut off the deadweight and keep operating the product and actually making profit off the finished product, which was always a normal thing in every other industry.&lt;p&gt;For tech people that see themselves as builders, this should be normal and expected - they should charge competitive rates for their services taking into account the expectation that they're building something for someone else to make money off once it's built and that they won't be part of it once that's done (unless they want to negotiate an actual stake in the company). For tech people that don't, this is a difficult wake up call, but the earlier the better - the old situation was never sustainable to begin with.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 18:23:31 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46709448</link><dc:creator>Nextgrid</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46709448</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46709448</guid></item><item><title>New comment by leeoniya in "Show HN: ChartGPU – WebGPU-powered charting library (1M points at 60fps)"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;uPlot maintainer here. this looks interesting, i'll do a deeper dive soon :)&lt;p&gt;some notes from a very brief look at the 1M demo:&lt;p&gt;- sampling has a risk of eliminating important peaks, uPlot does not do it, so for apples-to-apples perf comparison you have to turn that off. see &lt;a href="https://github.com/leeoniya/uPlot/pull/1025" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://github.com/leeoniya/uPlot/pull/1025&lt;/a&gt; for more details on the drawbacks of LTTB&lt;p&gt;- when doing nothing / idle, there is significant cpu being used, while canvas-based solutions will use zero cpu when the chart is not actively being updated (with new data or scale limits). i think this can probably be resolved in the WebGPU case with some additional code that pauses the updates.&lt;p&gt;- creating multiple charts on the same page with GL (e.g. dashboard) has historically been limited by the fact that Chrome is capped at 16 active GL contexts that can be acquired simultaneously. Plotly finally worked around this by using &lt;a href="https://github.com/greggman/virtual-webgl" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://github.com/greggman/virtual-webgl&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;&gt; data: [[0, 1], [1, 3], [2, 2]]&lt;p&gt;this data format, unfortunately, necessitates the allocation of millions of tiny arrays. i would suggest switching to a columnar data layout.&lt;p&gt;uPlot has a 2M datapoint demo here, if interested: &lt;a href="https://leeoniya.github.io/uPlot/bench/uPlot-10M.html" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://leeoniya.github.io/uPlot/bench/uPlot-10M.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 18:20:55 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46709415</link><dc:creator>leeoniya</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46709415</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46709415</guid></item><item><title>New comment by budududuroiu in "Ireland wants to give its cops spyware, ability to crack encrypted messages"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Whenever these people ask for more power in order to "stop/prevent crime", there should be a bot that replies a list of times when the police didn't act to stop crime, despite having full knowledge of the crime occuring and potential to stop it from happening.&lt;p&gt;EU member and supporter of Chat Control, Romania, had a massive scandal where a kidnapped 15 year old girl called emergency services multiple times to report she was being kidnapped, every single time, the operators and the police officers spoke to her in an ironic and condescending tone. It took 19 hours to locate her, by which time, she was already dead. [1]&lt;p&gt;[1] &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Kidnapping_of_Alexandra_M%C4%83ce%C8%99anu_and_Luiza_Melencu" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Kidnapping_of_Alexandra_M%C4%8...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 15:05:04 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46706674</link><dc:creator>budududuroiu</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46706674</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46706674</guid></item><item><title>New comment by leosanchez in "Stories removed from the Hacker News Front Page, updated in real time (2024)"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&gt; it's hard to believe that HN users would be tired of LLM-related news.&lt;p&gt;Not hard to believe at all. While I don't flag any posts. I have no interest in LLM related content.&lt;p&gt;I also actively use AI tools btw. It's just tiring seeing everything with AI suffix including monitors.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 13:02:05 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46705122</link><dc:creator>leosanchez</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46705122</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46705122</guid></item><item><title>New comment by academia_hack in "EU–INC – A new pan-European legal entity"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;It's inordinately difficult and expensive to start an LLC or SA in some EU countries. It's even difficult and expensive to _stop_ an LLC and dissolve it. Huge amount of risk and cost on founders and a huge distraction from running a business.&lt;p&gt;I think that EU-Inc _could_ be an improvement, but it needs to avoid the committee laundry list of ideas/requirements/form fields that plagues the EU startup ecosystem. My worry is that the end result will require notarized declarations of honour, financial plans stretching decades into the future, 30 page business plan documents, reams of corporate governance documents, and tons of other nonsense to protect against the perceived risk that someone who failed at starting a business once fails a second time.&lt;p&gt;There needs to be UX requirements on the process from day one against which the end result is judged. (E.g. "a company should be able to register in x days", "a complete application should be no longer than y pages", "application costs should be less than z euros").&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 12:41:07 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46704872</link><dc:creator>academia_hack</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46704872</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46704872</guid></item><item><title>New comment by nkrisc in "SETI@home is in hiberation"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;This was my screensaver for several years starting in maybe 2001. It felt really cool as a 12 year old to be contributing to the project in some small way.&lt;p&gt;For a long time I would periodically check on the screen saver in case there would be some big message saying my computer found aliens or something. Never did though :)&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 12:27:07 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46704707</link><dc:creator>nkrisc</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46704707</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46704707</guid></item><item><title>New comment by reconnecting in "SETI@home is in hiberation"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I feel sorry for every child who didn't have &lt;i&gt;SETI@home&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;X-Files&lt;/i&gt; at the same time during their childhood.&lt;p&gt;The truth is still out there.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 12:24:25 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46704673</link><dc:creator>reconnecting</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46704673</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46704673</guid></item><item><title>New comment by mike_hearn in "Anthropic's original take home assignment open sourced"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;The question isn't clearly written down anywhere, that's why.  Presumably actual candidates would have been given more info over the phone or email. Part of the "challenge" is reverse engineering their Python; unclear if that's intentional.&lt;p&gt;If you look at the top of perf_takehome.py then there is a brief comment saying the challenge is to optimize a kernel. Kernel in GPU land means a program that computes on data in parallel, it's not an OS kernel:&lt;p&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;    Optimize the kernel (in KernelBuilder.build_kernel) as much as possible in the
    available time, as measured by test_kernel_cycles on a frozen separate copy
    of the simulator.
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
However, this kernel doesn't run on an actual GPU. It runs on a little interpreter for a custom assembly language written in Python. Thus you will be optimizing the program built in-memory by the function on this line:&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/anthropics/original_performance_takehome/blob/f88c9458dbc5ef09d7801d961d905698e7e7cae1/perf_takehome.py#L85" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://github.com/anthropics/original_performance_takehome/...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;This function is described only as:&lt;p&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;    Like reference_kernel2 but building actual instructions.
    Scalar implementation using only scalar ALU and load/store.
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
The KernelBuilder class has some fields like "instrs" but we can't immediately see what they're meant to be because this is Python and types are optional. Nonetheless we can see that instructions are being added to a list, and below we can see the test_kernel_cycles function that runs the interpreter on the program. So our mission is to change the build_kernel function to make a better program. And it says this is an assembly version of the python function reference_kernel2 which is found in problem.py.&lt;p&gt;What exactly is this kernel doing? The reference_kernel2 function doesn't explain itself either - it's some sort of parallel tree walk. Let's put that to one side for a second and explore the machine, which is defined in problem.py. The machine itself is also largely undocumented, but there's a brief description in a docstring on line 66.&lt;p&gt;At this point it helps to understand the design of exotic processors. The emulator is for a fictional CPU that uses a VLIW SIMD ISA. Normal programmers will never encounter such a chip. Intel tried to make such a machine decades ago and it never took off, since then the concept has been largely dead. I believe it's still used in some mobile DSPs like Qualcomm's Hexagon. Notably, NVIDIA PTX is &lt;i&gt;not&lt;/i&gt; such an ISA so this seems to have been chosen just to make things harder. As the comment explains, in a VLIW machine multiple instructions are packed together into a "slot" and executed in parallel. In a normal CPU the hardware reads a serial stream of instructions and works out just in time which can be executed in parallel, using fancy out-of-order circuitry. In a VLIW machine that's done ahead of time by the compiler or (in this case) the humble programmer, you. But this isn't just a VLIW machine, it's also multi-core, and multi-"engine", so there are multiple levels of execution going on. And it's SIMD, meaning each instruction can itself operate on multiple bits of data simultaneously.&lt;p&gt;This machine doesn't have registers or cache but it does have "scratch space", and so you can use the vector instructions to load data into a series of 32 bit scratch words and then do things on them in parallel. And multiple vector instructions can also run in parallel. "Broadcasting a scalar" in SIMD-speak means taking a single value and repeating it over multiple scratch space slots (or register subwords in a real machine), so you take e.g. 0xFF and get 0xFFFFFFFFFFFFFFFF.&lt;p&gt;And that's it, that's all we get. As the code says: "This comment is not meant to be full ISA documentation though, for the rest you should look through the simulator code". Possible point of confusion: real ISAs are serialized to bytes but this one is just Python tuples. The code is only partially typed; sometimes you're just left guessing.&lt;p&gt;So to recap, the problem is to optimize an undocumented program expressed in undocumented data structures returned by a Python function whose result is interpreted by a partly documented Python class that simulates a fictional exotic CPU architecture using an abandoned design that gives a lot of parallel computational capacity, but which requires all parallelism to be statically declared ahead of time, whilst simultaneously reverse engineering the Python that does all this.&lt;p&gt;Does that help? Sounds like a fun exercise :)&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Edit: I just checked and Google TPUs are much more VLIW like so perhaps this simulator is designed to match a TPU. I know Anthropic rely on TPUs for serving and have done some optimization for them.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 09:19:25 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46703086</link><dc:creator>mike_hearn</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46703086</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46703086</guid></item><item><title>New comment by lbreakjai in "Anthropic's original take home assignment open sourced"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I consider myself rather smart and good at what I do. It's nice to have a look at problems like these once in a while, to remind myself of how little I know, and how much closer I am to the average than to the top.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 07:10:39 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46702111</link><dc:creator>lbreakjai</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46702111</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46702111</guid></item><item><title>New comment by dlcarrier in "cURL removes bug bounties"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;An entry fee that is reimbursed if the bug turns out to matter would stop this, real quick.&lt;p&gt;Then again, I once submitted a bug report to my bank, because the login method could be switched from password+pin to pin only, when not logged in, and they closed it as "works as intended", because they had decided that an optional password was more convenient than a required password.  (And that's not even getting into the difference between real two-factor authentication the some-factor one-and-a-half-times they had implemented by adding a PIN to a password login.)  I've since learned that anything heavily regulated like hospitals and banks will have security procedures catering to compliance, not actual security.&lt;p&gt;Assuming the host of the bug bounty program is operating in good faith, adding some kind of barrier to entry or punishment for untested entries will weed out submitters acting in bad faith.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 06:59:24 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46702041</link><dc:creator>dlcarrier</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46702041</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46702041</guid></item><item><title>New comment by pvalue005 in "Anthropic's original take home assignment open sourced"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I suspect this was released by Anthropic as a DDOS attack on other AI companies. I prompted 'how do we solve this challenge?' into gemini cli in a cloned repo and it's been running non-stop for 20 minutes :)&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 05:36:26 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46701527</link><dc:creator>pvalue005</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46701527</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46701527</guid></item><item><title>New comment by al_borland in "Ask HN: Do you have any evidence that agentic coding works?"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;A principal engineer at Google posted on Twitter that Claude Code did in an hour what the team couldn’t do in a year.&lt;p&gt;Two days later, after people freaked out, context was added. The team built multiple versions in that year, each had its trade offs. All that context was given to the AI and it was able to produce a “toy” version. I can only assume it had similar trade offs.&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://xcancel.com/rakyll/status/2007659740126761033#m" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://xcancel.com/rakyll/status/2007659740126761033#m&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;My experience has been similar to yours, and I think a lot of the hype is from people like this Google engineer who play into the hype and leave out the context. This sets expectations way out of line from reality and leads to frustration and disappointment.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 00:41:09 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46699744</link><dc:creator>al_borland</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46699744</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46699744</guid></item></channel></rss>