<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>Hacker News: Best Comments</title><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/bestcomments</link><description>Hacker News RSS</description><docs>https://hnrss.org/</docs><generator>hnrss v2.1.1</generator><lastBuildDate>Sat, 15 Nov 2025 00:20:09 +0000</lastBuildDate><ns0:link href="https://hnrss.org/bestcomments" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item><title>New comment by dijit in "Being poor vs. being broke"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Even this does a poor job of explaining being poor.&lt;p&gt;The constant open loop on everything you own, terrified to discard anything even if its broken because there are components that might be useful to fix something else; the constant churn of second-hand (and cheap/disposable) things that are already close to death before they come into your possession and- crucially: the crushing weight of knowing that any financial roadbump is existential.&lt;p&gt;As the author mentions, a £50 fine might as well be £50,000- its unpayable, and leads to a sort of doom-spiral of lending to avoid worse consequences. Easily you can end up in unmanageable debt, in rare cases prison, its not uncommon to have the few worthwhile items you own being seized by bailifs to recoup debts, treasured heirlooms that cannot be replaced and have little monetary value so they do no impact to your debt. The hoarding of canned goods to avoid being unable to eat.&lt;p&gt;It’s hard to convey this, and what it does to your mentality- I am now built mentally to think quite fiscally conservative and do not take debts or put savings into investments like my peers. I am well off but a fraction of what I could have been had I not has this mentality.&lt;p&gt;You have to live it to understand it, but I wouldn’t wish it on anyone, its a tarpit and getting out of it without someone handing you a branch (and if you no longer have the strength to pull yourself out) then you’ll be stuck in it forever.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 18:06:41 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45929705</link><dc:creator>dijit</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45929705</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45929705</guid></item><item><title>New comment by the__alchemist in "AGI fantasy is a blocker to actual engineering"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I will go meta into what you posted here: That people are classifying themselves as "AI skeptics". Many people are treating this in terms of tribal conflict and identity politics. On HN, we can do better! IMO the move is drop the politics, and discuss things on their technical merits. If we do talk about it as a debate, we can do it when with open minds, and intellectual honesty.&lt;p&gt;I think much of this may be a reaction to the hype promoted by tech CEOs and media outlets. People are seeing through their lies and exaggerations, and taking positions like "AI/LLMs have no values or uses", then using every argument they hear as a reason why it is &lt;i&gt;bad&lt;/i&gt; in a broad sense. For example: Energy and water concerns. That's my best guess about the concern you're braced against.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 15:01:36 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45927408</link><dc:creator>the__alchemist</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45927408</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45927408</guid></item><item><title>New comment by andy99 in "I think nobody wants AI in Firefox, Mozilla"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;The existence of the features doesn’t bother me. It’s the constant nagging about them. I can’t use a google product without being harassed to the point of not being able to work by offers to “help me write” or whatever.&lt;p&gt;Having the feature on a menu somewhere would be fine. The problem is the confluence of new features now becoming possible, and companies no longer building software for their users but as vehicles to push some agenda. Now we’re seeing this in action.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 14:51:44 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45927274</link><dc:creator>andy99</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45927274</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45927274</guid></item><item><title>New comment by transcriptase in "I think nobody wants AI in Firefox, Mozilla"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Nobody wants anything from Mozilla except Firefox/Thunderbird to be high-performance alternatives to Chrome/Outlook with fewer restrictions on extensions.&lt;p&gt;That’s it. The rest is just activism and kids playing in a sandbox with non-profit money to pad out their resume with whatever topical keywords might land them their next gig.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 14:26:17 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45926961</link><dc:creator>transcriptase</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45926961</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45926961</guid></item><item><title>New comment by everdrive in "I think nobody wants AI in Firefox, Mozilla"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Does anyone want AI in anything? I can see the value of navigating to an LLM and asking specific questions, but generally speaking I don't want that just running / waiting on my machine as I open a variety of applications. It's a huge waste of resources and for most normal people is an edge case.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 14:23:42 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45926926</link><dc:creator>everdrive</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45926926</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45926926</guid></item><item><title>New comment by simonw in "AGI fantasy is a blocker to actual engineering"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Tip for AI skeptics: skip the data center water usage argument. At this point I think it harms your credibility - numbers like "millions of liters of water annually" (from the linked article) sound scary when presented without context, but if you compare data centers to farmland or even golf courses they're minuscule.&lt;p&gt;Other energy usage figures, air pollution, gas turbines, CO2 emissions etc are fine - but if you complain about water usage I think it risks discrediting the rest of your argument.&lt;p&gt;(Aside from that I agree with most of this piece, the "AGI" thing is a huge distraction.)&lt;p&gt;UPDATE an hour after posting this: I may be making an ass of myself here in that I've been arguing in this thread about comparisons between data center usage and agricultural usage of water, but that comparison doesn't hold as data centers often use potable drinking water that wouldn't be used in agriculture or for many other industrial purposes.&lt;p&gt;I still think the way these numbers are usually presented - as scary large "gallons of water" figures with no additional context to help people understand what that means - is an anti-pattern.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 14:21:42 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45926914</link><dc:creator>simonw</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45926914</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45926914</guid></item><item><title>New comment by 3ln00b in "Kubernetes Ingress Nginx is retiring"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;How do you people even keep up with this? I'm going back to cybersecurity after trying DevOps for a year, it's not for me. I miss my sysadmin days, things were simple back then and worked. Maybe I'm just getting old and my cognitive abilities are declining. It seems to me that the current tech scene doesn't reward simple.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 04:19:24 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45923809</link><dc:creator>3ln00b</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45923809</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45923809</guid></item><item><title>New comment by atlintots in "Disrupting the first reported AI-orchestrated cyber espionage campaign"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I might be crazy, but this just feels like a marketing tactic from Anthropic to try and show that their AI can be used in the cybersecurity domain.&lt;p&gt;My question is, how on earth does does Claude Code even "infiltrate" databases or code from one account, based on prompts from a different account? What's more, it's doing this to what are likely enterprise customers ("large tech companies, financial institutions, ... and government agencies"). I'm sorry but I don't see this as some fancy AI cyberattack, this is a security failure on Anthropic's part and that too at a very basic level that should never have happened at a company of their caliber.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2025 22:11:54 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45921319</link><dc:creator>atlintots</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45921319</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45921319</guid></item><item><title>New comment by habibur in "Rust in Android: move fast and fix things"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;    5 million Rust LOC 
    One potential memory safety vulnerability found 
    Rust is 0.2 vuln per 1 MLOC.

    Compared to 
    C and C++ : 1,000 memory safety vulnerabilities per MLOC. 

&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
Key take.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2025 21:56:48 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45921143</link><dc:creator>habibur</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45921143</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45921143</guid></item><item><title>New comment by BinaryPie in "Zed is our office"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I generally like what Zed is trying to become. However, all of these features and blog posts are frustraing when they struggle to keep basic editor features stable. Edit a file outside of the editor? It's not going to show up in the project pane or the git diff. Need to work inside a container because it's 2025 and we don't need to clutter our local machine with 100s of dependencies and env managers... well now all the AI stuff is broken. ACP sounds cool until you realize every single CLI in existence works better.&lt;p&gt;My wish is that Zed gets the core working correctly 100% of the time before moving on to expanding feature sets. For now I'm back in NeoVIM because it always works the first time....&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/zed-industries/zed/issues/38109" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://github.com/zed-industries/zed/issues/38109&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;Hopefully soon I can give it another shot at full time usage.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2025 18:34:46 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45918650</link><dc:creator>BinaryPie</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45918650</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45918650</guid></item><item><title>New comment by mothballed in "Hemp ban hidden inside government shutdown bill"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Even the legal weed state senators were voting for this.&lt;p&gt;It is mostly about shifting profits from mom and pop, low regulation hemp industry to wealthy corporations that own dispensaries that have gargantuan regulatory costs that gatekeep out most the competition.  This ensures profits are captured by the wealthy rather than small family type setups.&lt;p&gt;Wealthy former hemp companies will shift to the "legal" weed market, while the mom and pops will get completely wiped out.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2025 17:10:55 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45917448</link><dc:creator>mothballed</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45917448</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45917448</guid></item><item><title>New comment by saghm in "Steam Machine"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;My theory for a bit now has been that Valve is playing the long game in trying to make SteamOS a mainstay gaming platform as an alternative to Windows, and that the hardware products are essentially a way of breaking into that market. Even a few years ago, the idea of a custom Linux distro based on Arch Linux with both a built-in full desktop mode and a lower-powered gaming mode that you could switch between on a handheld device would have sounded kind of crazy, but now we're at the point where it's fully supported on more than one vendor's hardware. This seems like it could be a similar play in the traditional desktop space; if they can prove that the concept is viable, maybe other vendors will come out with similar products that come with SteamOS by default. All of this insulates them from having to worry about the long-term sustainability of making money from game sales on Windows, and if it works out, they wouldn't even necessarily have to continue making hardware indefinitely.&lt;p&gt;I don't pretend to have any insight into whether this theory is correct beyond that it seems to track with what they've been doing lately, or any expertise to make claims about whether it will work or not. In a lot of ways, this might just be a projection of my desires as a gamer who enjoys not having had to boot into Windows to play something for quite a few years at this point. I do hope that maybe they're just crazy enough to not only try this, but pull it off though!&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2025 16:15:24 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45916678</link><dc:creator>saghm</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45916678</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45916678</guid></item><item><title>New comment by hamdingers in "Tesla Is Recalling Cybertrucks Again"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&gt; how did this pass safety standards&lt;p&gt;In the US, the safety standards consider only the occupants of the car. The safety of pedestrians, cyclists, and occupants of other cars are not considered. This was looking like it would change but with the current administration I doubt it.&lt;p&gt;The Cybertruck is not legal in Europe and anywhere else with actual safety standards.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2025 16:02:46 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45916517</link><dc:creator>hamdingers</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45916517</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45916517</guid></item><item><title>New comment by 0xbadcafebee in "We cut our Mongo DB costs by 90% by moving to Hetzner"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&gt; Here's how we managed to cut our costs by 90%&lt;p&gt;You could cut your MongoDB costs by 100% by not using it ;)&lt;p&gt;&gt; without sacrificing performance or reliability.&lt;p&gt;You're using a single server in a single datacenter. MongoDB Atlas is deployed to VMs on 2-3 AZs. You don't have close to the same reliability. (I'm also curious why their M40 instance costs $1000, when the Pricing Calculator (&lt;a href="https://www.mongodb.com/pricing" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://www.mongodb.com/pricing&lt;/a&gt;) says M40 is $760/month? Was it the extra storage?)&lt;p&gt;&gt; We're building Prosopo to be resilient to outages, such as the recent massive AWS outage, so we use many different cloud providers&lt;p&gt;This means you're going to have multiple outages, AND incur more cross-internet costs. How does going to Hetzner make you more resilient to outages? You have one server in one datacenter. Intelligent, robust design at one provider (like AWS) is way more resilient, and intra-zone transfer is cheaper than going out to the cloud ($0.02/GB vs $0.08/GB). You do not have a centralized or single point of failure design with AWS. They're not dummies; plenty of their services are operated independently per region. But they do expect you to use their infrastructure intelligently to avoid &lt;i&gt;creating&lt;/i&gt; a single point of failure. (For example, during the AWS outage, my company was in us-east-1, and we never had any issues, because we didn't depend on calling AWS APIs to continue operating. Things already running continue to run.)&lt;p&gt;I get it; these "we cut bare costs by moving away from the cloud" posts are catnip for HN. But they usually don't make sense. There's only a few circumstances where you really have to transfer out a lot of traffic, or need very large storage, where cloud pricing is just too much of a premium. The whole point of using the cloud is to use it as a competitive advantage. Giving yourself an extra role (sysadmin) in addition to your day job (developer, data scientist, etc) and more maintenance tasks (installing, upgrading, patching, troubleshooting, getting on-call, etc) with lower reliability and fewer services, isn't an advantage.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2025 15:58:47 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45916469</link><dc:creator>0xbadcafebee</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45916469</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45916469</guid></item><item><title>New comment by TheOtherHobbes in "Britain's railway privatization was an abject failure"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;This is incorrect. The biggest accidents - Potters Bar, Hatfield, Southall - happened in the years immediately after privatisation, before passenger numbers had grown much.&lt;p&gt;The problem was more that - in typical privatised fashion - the industry was treated as a cash grab, and property speculation and other side quests got more management attention than running a safe railway.&lt;p&gt;That first incarnation was so bad it was quickly nuked, and replaced with the hybrid arrangement we have today, which has a much better safety record, but is still comically expensive and inefficient.&lt;p&gt;And franchises very clearly have improved, so that's incorrect too. Delays and cancellations are down across the network, and that's before the system is reintegrated.&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/business/ng-interactive/2025/oct/13/most-of-great-britains-major-rail-operators-are-back-in-public-hands-is-it-working" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://www.theguardian.com/business/ng-interactive/2025/oct...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;The biggest disaster of privatisation was the loss of more than a century of engineering and management culture and knowledge. The UK invented tilting train technology, and it was &lt;i&gt;given away&lt;/i&gt; to foreign corporations instead of being licensed and exploited in the UK.&lt;p&gt;This is the pattern behind all UK privatisation. Foreign countries and shareholders benefited hugely, while prices of essential services exploded, and service quality degraded.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2025 15:33:39 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45916092</link><dc:creator>TheOtherHobbes</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45916092</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45916092</guid></item><item><title>New comment by dkersten in "GPT-5.1: A smarter, more conversational ChatGPT"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I don’t want more conversational, I want more to the point. Less telling me how great my question is, less about being friendly, instead I want more cold, hard, accurate, direct, and factual results.&lt;p&gt;It’s a machine and a tool, not a person and definitely not my friend.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2025 15:32:54 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45916076</link><dc:creator>dkersten</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45916076</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45916076</guid></item><item><title>New comment by graemep in "Britain's railway privatization was an abject failure"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;It implies railways were les safe post privatisation. This is misleading. There were more accidents and deaths, but that was because of a huge increase in miles travelled. Deaths per billion kilometers fell consistently before and after privatisation.&lt;p&gt;A lot of the problems lie in tracks and their maintenance, and the tracks were re-nationalised many years ago. It is not efficiently run (see HS2!).&lt;p&gt;They are expensive, but that is partly because rail workers are well paid. Train drivers can be paid as much as aircraft pilots. Their ability and willingness to strike affects both costs and people's willingness to rely on public transport.&lt;p&gt;The big constraint is lack of subsidies. it probably makes little difference whether the system is privately owned but tightly regulated, or publicly owned so much as willingness to subsidise it. This is also shown by the failure of franchises taken back into public ownership to improve.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2025 14:15:26 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45915129</link><dc:creator>graemep</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45915129</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45915129</guid></item><item><title>New comment by frustracean in "Blender Lab"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;If anyone else is having trouble loading the CSS for the page, go to &lt;a href="https://www.blender.org/wp-content/themes/bthree/style.css?x78892" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://www.blender.org/wp-content/themes/bthree/style.css?x...&lt;/a&gt; to be Captcha'd by Cloudflare - it should load fine after that.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2025 14:07:47 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45915036</link><dc:creator>frustracean</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45915036</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45915036</guid></item><item><title>New comment by joshmn in "Checkout.com hacked, refuses ransom payment, donates to security labs"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;It’s notable that there were ShinyHunters members arrested by the FBI a few years ago. I was in prison with Sebastian Raoult, one of them. We talked quite a bit.&lt;p&gt;The level of persistence these guys went through to phish at scale is astounding—which is how they gained most of their access. They’d otherwise look up API endpoints on GitHub and see if there were any leaked keys (he wasn’t fond of GitHub's automated scanner).&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.justice.gov/usao-wdwa/pr/member-notorious-international-hacking-crew-sentenced-prison" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://www.justice.gov/usao-wdwa/pr/member-notorious-intern...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2025 13:11:12 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45914502</link><dc:creator>joshmn</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45914502</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45914502</guid></item><item><title>New comment by throwaway2037 in "Checkout.com hacked, refuses ransom payment, donates to security labs"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I love this part (no trolling from me):&lt;p&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;    &gt; We are sorry. We regret that this incident has caused worry for our partners and people. We have begun the process to identify and contact those impacted and are working closely with law enforcement and the relevant regulators. We are fully committed to maintaining your trust.
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
I know there will by a bunch of cynics who say that an LLM or a PR crisis team wrote this post... but if they did, hats off.  It is powerful and moving.  This guys really falls on his sword / takes it on the chin.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2025 10:08:35 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45913010</link><dc:creator>throwaway2037</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45913010</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45913010</guid></item><item><title>New comment by iamcalledrob in "Meta replaces WhatsApp for Windows with web wrapper"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;As the person who designed and fought for this app, I am a bit sad about the change.&lt;p&gt;The native app was by no means perfect, but it felt like a real productivity tool that was trying to be respectful of it's environment.&lt;p&gt;I've come to the conclusion that native desktop apps are just not viable from large companies, even if there is headcount. The problem is coordination cost.&lt;p&gt;If you want to launch new features and experiments here, there and everywhere, then the coordination complexity increases nonlinearly with the number of platforms.&lt;p&gt;If you can sustain a more deliberate, low churn pace of development then it's workable. Features can be well defined and then implemented by the platform team as they see fit. But if you want a more fast-paced, "just in time" style of development, you need to coordinate with every team for every change... wouldn't it be nice to just write web code and be done?&lt;p&gt;Even Microsoft are building this way these days.&lt;p&gt;This is why ironically small companies seem more able to support native apps than large ones. The more "stuff" that's being worked on concurrently, the harder it is to support multiple platforms.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2025 09:06:00 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45912564</link><dc:creator>iamcalledrob</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45912564</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45912564</guid></item><item><title>New comment by rom1v in "Android developer verification: Early access starts"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I want to be able to install apps from alternative app stores like F-Droid and receive automatic updates, without requiring Google's authorization for app publication.&lt;p&gt;Manually installing an app via adb must, of course, be permitted. But that is not sufficient.&lt;p&gt;&gt; Keeping users safe on Android is our top priority.&lt;p&gt;Google's mandatory verification is not about security, but about control (they want to forbid apps like ReVanced that could reduce their advertising revenue).&lt;p&gt;When SimpleMobileTools was sold to a shady company (&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=38505229"&gt;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=38505229&lt;/a&gt;), the new owner was able to push any user-hostile changes they wanted to all users who had installed the original app through Google Play (that's the very reason why the initial app could be sold in the first place, to exploit a large, preexisting user base that had the initial version installed).&lt;p&gt;That was not the case on F-Droid, which blocked the new user-hostile version and recommended the open source fork (Fossify Apps). (see also this comment: &lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45410805"&gt;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45410805&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2025 08:46:26 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45912425</link><dc:creator>rom1v</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45912425</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45912425</guid></item><item><title>New comment by cambaceres in "Project Euler"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;12 years ago I was a failed computer science student, wasting my time on drugs. Having failed so many classes I did not see any future at all, and I was considering killing myself to get out of the anxiety and stress.
My confidence regarding programming etc was 0.&lt;p&gt;I decided to apply for a junior developer job. I got an interview and to prepare for an interview I found this site, Project Euler. I did ten or so tasks.&lt;p&gt;The interview started out pretty bad, they asked me some technical questions which I did not give good answers to, and I saw that they where not impressed. Then they wanted me to solve two programming problems on a white board. Imagine the relief I felt when both of these questions where from the ones that I solved on Project Euler a couple of days before! I nailed them and the interviewers where clearly impressed. In the end they hired me and motivated it with that although I lack a lot of theory I am obviously a very good coder haha.&lt;p&gt;Anyway, that was what I needed, when I got this job I quit the drugs and got my act together. 12 years later I live a confortable life as a freelancer and have even managed to build my own SaaS with paying customers! Thank you Project Euler.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2025 07:25:49 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45911812</link><dc:creator>cambaceres</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45911812</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45911812</guid></item><item><title>New comment by Ey7NFZ3P0nzAe in "Steam Machine"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&gt; Install your own apps, or even another operating system. Who are we to tell you how to use your computer?&lt;p&gt;I'm so happy to read this&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2025 05:57:28 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45911243</link><dc:creator>Ey7NFZ3P0nzAe</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45911243</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45911243</guid></item><item><title>New comment by josephcsible in "Android 16 QPR1 is being pushed to the Android Open Source Project"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Android 16 QPR1 rolled out in binary-only form to phones that are blessed by Google over two months ago, and it's only just now that they bothered to actually release the source of their open-source operating system.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2025 05:20:09 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45911015</link><dc:creator>josephcsible</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45911015</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45911015</guid></item><item><title>New comment by somenameforme in "Valve is about to win the console generation"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&gt; Most consoles are sold at a loss&lt;p&gt;You're thinking of 'back in the day.' The original XBox's video card was worth more than they sold the entire system for, and the PS3 was a complete beast of computation (even if not entirely inappropriate for games...)! But in modern times (PS4 gen onward) consoles have become relatively vanilla midrange computers designed with the intent of turning profit on the hardware as quickly as possible.&lt;p&gt;The hardware cost of the PS4 was less than it's retail price from day 0 [1], and they began making a profit per unit shortly thereafter. Similarly the PS5 also reached profit per unit in less than a year. [2] XBox models from the PS4 gen onward are conspicuously similar as well.&lt;p&gt;[1] - &lt;a href="https://tech.yahoo.com/general/article/2013-11-19-ps4-costs-381-to-make-according-to-hardware-teardown.html" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://tech.yahoo.com/general/article/2013-11-19-ps4-costs-...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;[2] - &lt;a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/4/22609150/sony-playstation-5-ps5-loss-profit" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://www.theverge.com/2021/8/4/22609150/sony-playstation-...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2025 03:44:54 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45910349</link><dc:creator>somenameforme</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45910349</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45910349</guid></item><item><title>New comment by twodave in "My dad could still be alive, but he's not"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I feel this, but in reverse. My son could be dead, but he’s not. He was born on the floor of a trailer park apartment, not breathing. His birth mother’s partner called 911, who dispatched an ambulance. All rescue units for his zone were already busy. An ambulance returning from the nearby hospital to another zone heard the call over the radio and happened to be passing by. The hospital was expecting a DOA, but the paramedics (HEROES) managed to get him breathing again on the way. He’s 11 now, and he is the source of all kinds of trouble and joy. Our home would be very different without him.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2025 03:41:26 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45910323</link><dc:creator>twodave</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45910323</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45910323</guid></item><item><title>New comment by thisislife2 in "Android developer verification: Early access starts"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I don't buy this argument at all that this specific implementation is under pressure from the government - if the problem is indeed malware getting access to personal data, then the very obvious solution is to ensure that such personal data is not accessible by apps in the first place! Why should apps have access to a user's SMS / RCS? (Yeah, I know it makes onboarding / verification easy and all, if an app can access your OTP. But that's a minor convenience that can be sacrificed if it's also being used for scams by malware apps).&lt;p&gt;But that kind of privacy based security model is anathema to Google because its whole business model is based on violating its users' privacy. And that's why they have come with such convoluted implementation that further give them control over a user's device. Obviously some government's too may favour such an approach as they too can then use Google or Apple to exert control over their citizens (through censorship or denial of services).&lt;p&gt;Note also that while they are not completely removing sideloading (for now) they are introducing further restrictions on it, including gate-keeping by them. This is just the &lt;i&gt;"boil the frog slowly"&lt;/i&gt; approach. Once this is normalised, they will make a move to prevent sideloading completely, again, in the future.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2025 02:54:03 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45909950</link><dc:creator>thisislife2</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45909950</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45909950</guid></item><item><title>New comment by Normal_gaussian in "Valve is about to win the console generation"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Valve certainly won't win it, but they're bringing the heat where it wasn't before.&lt;p&gt;SteamOS is the important part here - if it is proven to be a good console experience (which the deck has basically proven already) then licensing of the OS to other manufacturers will put a lot of pressure on integrated h/w s/w manufacturers.&lt;p&gt;Unlike the handheld format, the tvbox console is fairly easy to manufacture and is tolerant of a lot of spec and price variety. Any slip up by Sony and Microsoft in specs and price will result in steam machine variants carving away market share, which could force more frequent console releases.&lt;p&gt;The steam machine will almost certainly come in at a higher price point than the PS5, but with no 'online' subscription charge and reasonably priced storage upgrades we may see these revenue streams disappear from the next console generation in order to compete.&lt;p&gt;SteamOS isn't perfect, and the variety inherent in the platform that is a strength is also a weakness. The core markets for Nintendo and for Sony aren't going anywhere.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2025 02:51:14 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45909928</link><dc:creator>Normal_gaussian</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45909928</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45909928</guid></item><item><title>New comment by svat in "Android developer verification: Early access starts"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;From the very first announcement of this, Google has hinted that they were doing this under pressure from the governments in a few countries. (I don't remember the URL of the first announcement, but &lt;a href="https://android-developers.googleblog.com/2025/08/elevating-android-security.html" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://android-developers.googleblog.com/2025/08/elevating-...&lt;/a&gt; is from 2025-August-25 and mentions “These requirements go into effect in Brazil, Indonesia, Singapore, and Thailand”.) The “Why verification is important” section of this blog post goes into a bit more detail (see also the &lt;i&gt;We are designing this flow specifically to resist coercion, ensuring that users aren't tricked into bypassing these safety checks while under pressure from a scammer&lt;/i&gt;), but ultimately the point is:&lt;p&gt;there &lt;i&gt;cannot&lt;/i&gt; exist an easy way for a typical non-technical user to install “unverified apps” (whatever that means), because the governments of countries where such scams are widespread will hold Google responsible.&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile this very fact seems fundamentally unacceptable to many, so there will be no end to this discourse IMO.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2025 01:33:26 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45909348</link><dc:creator>svat</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45909348</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45909348</guid></item></channel></rss>