<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>Hacker News: Best Comments</title><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/bestcomments</link><description>Hacker News RSS</description><docs>https://hnrss.org/</docs><generator>hnrss v2.1.1</generator><lastBuildDate>Thu, 31 Jul 2025 02:10:18 +0000</lastBuildDate><ns0:link href="https://hnrss.org/bestcomments" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item><title>New comment by jacobedawson in "Study mode"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;An underrated quality of LLMs as study partner is that you can ask "stupid" questions without fear of embarrassment. Adding in a mode that doesn't just dump an answer but works to take you through the material step-by-step is magical. A tireless, capable, well-versed assistant on call 24/7 is an autodidact's dream.&lt;p&gt;I'm puzzled (but not surprised) by the standard HN resistance &amp; skepticism. Learning something online 5 years ago often involved trawling incorrect, outdated or hostile content and attempting to piece together mental models without the chance to receive immediate feedback on intuition or ask follow up questions. This is leaps and bounds ahead of that experience.&lt;p&gt;Should we trust the information at face value without verifying from other sources? Of course not, that's part of the learning process. Will some (most?) people rely on it lazily without using it effectively? Certainly, and this technology won't help or hinder them any more than a good old fashioned textbook.&lt;p&gt;Personally I'm over the moon to be living at a time where we have access to incredible tools like this, and I'm impressed with the speed at which they're improving.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 29 Jul 2025 22:34:39 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44729042</link><dc:creator>jacobedawson</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44729042</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44729042</guid></item><item><title>New comment by czhu12 in "Study mode"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I'll personally attest: LLM's have been absolutely incredible to self learn new things post graduation. It used to be that if you got stuck on a concept, you're basically screwed. Unless it was common enough to show up in a well formed question on stack exchange, it was pretty much impossible, and the only thing you can really do is keep paving forward and hope at some point, it'll make sense to you.&lt;p&gt;Now, everyone basically has a personal TA, ready to go at all hours of the day.&lt;p&gt;I get the commentary that it makes learning too easy or shallow, but I doubt anyone would think that college students would learn better if we got rid of TA's.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 29 Jul 2025 17:27:28 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44726074</link><dc:creator>czhu12</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44726074</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44726074</guid></item><item><title>New comment by skibz in "Copyparty – Turn almost any device into a file server"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;The author of this tool uploaded a YouTube video demonstrating it a few days ago: &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=15_-hgsX2V0" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=15_-hgsX2V0&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;At one point in his demo, he uploads a file but terminates the upload more or less halfway. Then he begins downloading the file - which only progresses to the point it had been uploaded, and subsequently stalls indefinitely. And, finally, he finishes uploading the file (which gracefully resumes) and the file download (which is still running) seamlessly completes.&lt;p&gt;I found that particularly impressive.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 28 Jul 2025 15:14:17 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44711691</link><dc:creator>skibz</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44711691</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44711691</guid></item><item><title>New comment by zaik in "Debian switches to 64-bit time for everything"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Celebrate 100 years since complete ipv6 adoption.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 28 Jul 2025 11:46:03 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44709887</link><dc:creator>zaik</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44709887</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44709887</guid></item><item><title>New comment by zaptheimpaler in "VPN use surges in UK as new online safety rules kick in"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Basically every new law, piece of news or media I see coming from the UK paints a picture of a beat-down, cynical &amp; scared society that's complacent to or in support of increasing surveillance and control by the government. Like maybe Adolescence or basically any mention of the NHS. The crimes they cite like child grooming or terrorism/hate being incited sound pretty terrible too, but I wonder why the UK specifically is taking action - is the issue bigger there, or are they just more aware of and willing to act on it.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 28 Jul 2025 05:54:54 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44707618</link><dc:creator>zaptheimpaler</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44707618</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44707618</guid></item><item><title>New comment by WarOnPrivacy in "EU age verification app to ban any Android system not licensed by Google"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;In the case of Android, genuine means:&lt;/i&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;    The operating system was licensed by Google
    The app was downloaded from the Play Store (thus requiring a Google account)
    Device security checks have passed
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;i&gt;While there is value to verify device security,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;this strongly ties the app to many Google properties and services,&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;because those checks won't pass on an aftermarket Android OS&lt;/i&gt;&lt;p&gt;The issue is being raised here: &lt;a href="https://github.com/eu-digital-identity-wallet/av-app-android-wallet-ui/issues/10"&gt;https://github.com/eu-digital-identity-wallet/av-app-android...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;    I would like to strongly urge to abandon this plan. 
    Requiring a dependency on American tech giants for age verification
    further deepens the EU's dependency on America and the USA's
    control over the internet. 
    Especially in the current political climate I hope I do not have
    to explain how undesirable and dangerous that is.
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
As a resident of the aforementioned political climate, I find their concerns to be reasonable.&lt;p&gt;There are a number of comments in that same thread that indicate a mandate to utilize Google services may run afoul of EU member nations' integrity and privacy laws.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 27 Jul 2025 23:03:47 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44705507</link><dc:creator>WarOnPrivacy</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44705507</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44705507</guid></item><item><title>New comment by samrus in "4k NASA employees opt to leave agency through deferred resignation program"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I understand wanting to make the organization more efficient, but i don't think this is what's happening here. I think this is the classic republican strat of gutting federal agencies, pointing to the inefficiencies caused by the loss of institutional knowledge, and using that as an excuse to privatize to their friends.&lt;p&gt;The fact that Elon's DOGE suggested these cuts lines up&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 27 Jul 2025 14:33:10 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44701607</link><dc:creator>samrus</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44701607</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44701607</guid></item><item><title>New comment by thunderbong in "What went wrong for Yahoo"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&gt; In 1998, Yahoo turned down the opportunity to acquire Google for $1 million. Yahoo made six acquisitions that year, spending $107.3 million.&lt;p&gt;&gt; In 2002, Google offered to sell again for $1 billion. Yahoo hesitated and Google raised its price to $3 billion. Yahoo declined at the higher price. Google went on to become a trillion dollar company.&lt;p&gt;&gt; Yahoo attempted to acquire Facebook for $1 billion in 2006, but Mark Zuckerberg turned down the offer. Had Yahoo increased its offer by just $100 million, Facebook’s board would have forced Zuckerberg to take it. Facebook also became a trillion dollar company.&lt;p&gt;In inclined to believe that neither would have become trillion dollar companies if they had been acquired by Yahoo.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 26 Jul 2025 18:50:54 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44696197</link><dc:creator>thunderbong</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44696197</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44696197</guid></item><item><title>New comment by tempestn in "Do not download the app, use the website"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;At AutoTempest we resisted making an app for years, because anything that a hypothetical app could do, we could do with the website. And in my opinion, when searching for cars, it's more convenient to be in your browser where you can easily open new tabs, bookmark results, etc.&lt;p&gt;And for years, it was our most requested feature, by far. We had instructions for how to pin the site to your home screen, and would explain to users how the website does everything an app can do. Still, constant requests for an app. Finally we relented and released one, and very quickly around half our mobile traffic moved to the app without us really trying to nudge people at all.&lt;p&gt;People just really like apps! I think it suits our mental model of different tools for different uses. We've also found that app users are much more engaged than website users, but of course much of that will be selection bias. Still, I can see how having your app on someone's home screen could provide a significant boost to retention, compared to a website they're liable to forget. For us now, that's the main benefit we see. Certainly don't use any additional data, though I won't argue that other companies don't.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 26 Jul 2025 06:31:41 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44691882</link><dc:creator>tempestn</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44691882</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44691882</guid></item><item><title>New comment by codingdave in "It's time for modern CSS to kill the SPA"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;SPAs make sense when your users have long sessions in your app. When it is worth the pain to load a large bundle in exchange for having really small network requests after the load.&lt;p&gt;Smooth transitions are a nice side effect, but not the reason for an SPA. The core argument of the article, that client-side routing is a solution for page transitions, is a complete misunderstanding of what problems SPAs solve. So absolutely, if you shared that misunderstanding of SPAs and used them to solve the wrong problem, this article is 100% correct.&lt;p&gt;But SPAs came about in the days of jQuery, not React. You'd have a complex app, and load up a giant pile of jQuery spaghetti, which would then treat each div of your app is its own little mini-app, with lots of small network requests keeping everything in sync. It solved a real problem, of not wanting to reload all that code every time a user on an old browser, with a slow connection, changed some data. jQuery made it feasible to do SPAs instead.&lt;p&gt;Later, React and other frameworks made it less spaghetti-like. And it really took off. Often, for sketchy reasons. But the strongest argument for SPAs remains using them as a solution to provide a single-load of a large code bundle, that can be cached, to provide minimal network traffic subsequent to the load when the expected session time of a user is long enough to be worth the trouble of the complexity of an SPA.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 25 Jul 2025 21:43:36 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44688842</link><dc:creator>codingdave</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44688842</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44688842</guid></item><item><title>New comment by stan_kirdey in "Windsurf employee #2: I was given a payout of only 1% what my shares where worth"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Engineers: always negotiate for higher base salaries. In the vast majority of cases—especially during acquihires—your equity will be worth little or nothing. Founders and VCs still get paid; employees rarely do.&lt;p&gt;Don't just accept promises. Ask for the 409A valuation, liquidation preferences, and pay bands. If a company won’t provide transparency, that’s your signal.&lt;p&gt;Equity is a lottery ticket. Salary is money in the bank.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 25 Jul 2025 19:54:08 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44687627</link><dc:creator>stan_kirdey</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44687627</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44687627</guid></item><item><title>New comment by voxleone in "The future is not self-hosted"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Self-hosting isn't just about tech choices — it's about *who controls access to knowledge*.&lt;p&gt;During the Enlightenment, owning a physical copy of a book meant intellectual freedom. You didn’t rent ideas; you had them. Today, most digital knowledge is hosted, locked, or streamed — *leased from platforms*, not owned. We’re in fact drifting into *digital feudalism*, where access to culture, tools, and even history depends on gatekeepers.&lt;p&gt;In a perfect world this should go beyond market logic. It’s not just a question of what's sustainable or profitable. It's about *civic autonomy*. If the infrastructure of knowledge is centralized, then so is control over thought.&lt;p&gt;Self-hosting may not be for everyone, but *distributed, open systems are essential* to preserving a democratic and durable digital commons.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 25 Jul 2025 19:23:03 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44687266</link><dc:creator>voxleone</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44687266</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44687266</guid></item><item><title>New comment by keithwinstein in "Why MIT switched from Scheme to Python (2009)"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;This story has been reposted many times, and I think GJS's remarks (as recorded by Andy Wingo) are super-interesting as always, but this is really not a great account of "why MIT switched from Scheme to Python."&lt;p&gt;Source: I worked with GJS (I also know Alexey and have met Andy Wingo), and I took 6.001, my current research still has us referring to SICP on a regular basis, and in 2006 Kaijen Hsiao and I were the TAs for what was &lt;i&gt;basically&lt;/i&gt; the first offering of the class that quasi-replaced it (6.01) taught by Leslie Kaelbling, Hal Abelson, and Jacob White.&lt;p&gt;I would defer to lots of people who know the story better than me, but here's my understanding of the history. When the MIT EECS intro curriculum was redesigned in the 1980s, there was a theory that an EECS education should start with four "deep dives" into the four "languages of engineering." There were four 15-unit courses, each about one of these "languages":&lt;p&gt;- 6.001: Structure and Interpretation of Computer Programs (the "procedural" language, led by Abelson and Sussman)&lt;p&gt;- 6.002: Circuits and Electronics ("structural" language)&lt;p&gt;- 6.003: Signals and Systems ("functional" language)&lt;p&gt;- 6.004: Computation Structures ("architectural" language)&lt;p&gt;These were intellectually deep classes, although there was pain in them, and they weren't universally beloved. 6.001 wasn't really &lt;i&gt;about&lt;/i&gt; Scheme; I think a lot of the point of using Scheme (as I understood it) is that the language is so minimalist and so beautiful that even this first intro course can be &lt;i&gt;about&lt;/i&gt; fundamental concepts of computer science without getting distracted by the language. This intro sequence lasted until the mid-2000s, when enrollment in EECS ("Course 6") declined after the dot-com crash, and (as would be expected, and I think particularly worrisome) the enrollment drop was greater among demographic groups that EECS was eager to retain. My understanding circa 2005 is that there was a view that EECS had broadened in its applications, and that beginning the curriculum with four "deep dives" was offputting to students who might not be as sure that they wanted to pursue EECS and might not be aware of all the cool places they could go with that education (e.g. to robotics, graphics, biomedical applications, genomics, computer vision, NLP, systems, databases, visualization, networking, HCI, ...).&lt;p&gt;I wasn't in the room where these decisions were made, and I bet there were multiple motivations for these changes, but I understood that was part of the thinking. As a result, the EECS curriculum was redesigned circa 2005-7 to de-emphasize the four 15-unit "deep dives" and replace them with two 12-unit survey courses, each one a survey of a bunch of cool places that EECS could go. The "6.01" course (led by Kaelbling, Abelson, and White) was about robots, control, sensing, statistics, probabilistic inference, etc., and students did projects where the robot drove around a maze (starting from an unknown position) and sensed the walls with little sonar sensors and did Bayesian inference to figure out its structure and where it was. The "6.02" course was about communication, information, compression, networking, etc., and eventually the students were supposed to each get a software radio and build a Wi-Fi-like system (the software radios proved difficult and, much later, I helped make this an acoustic modem project).&lt;p&gt;The goal of these classes (as I understood) was to expose students to a broad range of all the cool stuff that EECS could do and to let them get there sooner (e.g. two classes instead of four) -- keep in mind this was in the wake of the dot-com crash when a lot of people were telling students that if they majored in computer science, they were going to end up programming for an insurance company at a cubicle farm before their job was inevitably outsourced to a low-cost-of-living country.&lt;p&gt;6.01 used Python, but in a very different way than 6.001 "used" Scheme -- my recollection is that the programming work in 6.01 (at least circa 2006) was minimal and was only to, e.g., implement short programs that drove the robot and averaged readings from its sonar sensors and made steering decisions or inferred the robot location. It was nothing like the big programming projects in 6.001 (the OOP virtual world, the metacircular evaluator, etc.).&lt;p&gt;So I don't think it really captures it to say that MIT "switched from Scheme to Python" -- I think the MIT EECS intro sequence switched from four deep-dive classes to two survey ones, and while the first "deep dive" course (6.001) had included a lot of programming, the first of the new survey courses only had students write pretty small programs (e.g. "drive the robot and maintain equal distance between the two walls") where the simplest thing was to use a scripting language where the small amount of necessary information can be taught by example. But it's not like the students &lt;i&gt;learned&lt;/i&gt; Python in that class.&lt;p&gt;My (less present) understanding is that &gt;a decade after this 2006-era curricular change, the department has largely deprecated the idea of an EECS core curriculum, and MIT CS undergrads now go through something closer to a conventional CS0/CS1 sequence, similar to other CS departments around the country (&lt;a href="https://www.eecs.mit.edu/changes-to-6-100a-b-l/" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://www.eecs.mit.edu/changes-to-6-100a-b-l/&lt;/a&gt;). But all of that is long after the change that Sussman and Wingo are talking about here.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 25 Jul 2025 19:14:15 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44687148</link><dc:creator>keithwinstein</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44687148</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44687148</guid></item><item><title>New comment by edent in "Google's shortened goo.gl links will stop working next month"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;About 60k academic citations about to die - &lt;a href="https://scholar.google.com/scholar?start=90&amp;q=%22https://goo.gl/%22&amp;hl=en&amp;as_sdt=0,5" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://scholar.google.com/scholar?start=90&amp;q=%22https://goo...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;Countless books with irrevocably broken references - &lt;a href="https://www.google.com/search?q=%22://goo.gl%22&amp;sca_upv=1&amp;sca_upv=1&amp;tbs=cdr:1,cd_min:2010,cd_max:2024,bkt:b&amp;tbm=bks" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://www.google.com/search?q=%22://goo.gl%22&amp;sca_upv=1&amp;sc...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;And for what? The cost of keeping a few TB online and a little bit of CPU power?&lt;p&gt;An absolute act of cultural vandalism.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 25 Jul 2025 14:59:31 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44683928</link><dc:creator>edent</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44683928</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44683928</guid></item><item><title>New comment by mzitelli in "Visa and Mastercard: The global payment duopoly (2024)"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Brazil central bank introduced Pix a few years ago. It took over the country as the public basic infrastructure for money transfer. Totally free and instantaneous transactions between people and companies, available to all banks.&lt;p&gt;Then, just last week, the US presidency launched an investigation considering Pix an unfair trade practice against the US.&lt;p&gt;Actions like that may show the current direction of the US government is aligned on preserving status quo. But still, I wonder how impactful a public digital infrastructure for the dollar would be.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 24 Jul 2025 22:20:58 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44677016</link><dc:creator>mzitelli</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44677016</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44677016</guid></item><item><title>New comment by sReinwald in "Itch.io: Update on NSFW Content"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;This is a deeply concerning development, though not an entirely surprising one. While I sympathize with itch.io's position - being caught between their creators and their payment processors - the broader implications here are alarming.&lt;p&gt;Payment processors have effectively become unelected censorship boards with the power to strangle entire categories of &lt;i&gt;legal&lt;/i&gt; content by threatening to cut off the economic infrastructure that platforms depend on. The fact that a single advocacy campaign can pressure Visa/Mastercard/PayPal into forcing platforms to remove legal adult content should concern anyone who values free expression online.&lt;p&gt;The fundamental issue isn't whether you personally approve of adult games or specific content - it's that a handful of payment companies now wield veto power over what legal content can exist in the digital economy. This represents a massive concentration of censorial authority in the hands of unaccountable corporate entities that face no meaningful democratic oversight.&lt;p&gt;We've seen this pattern repeatedly: PayPal blocking VPN providers over "piracy concerns," Visa suspending payments to adult sites, and now this coordinated pressure campaign. Each time, legal content gets effectively banned not through legislation or courts, but through corporate policy decisions made behind closed doors.&lt;p&gt;By inserting themselves as moral arbiters for the digital economy and free expression on the internet, these processors are creating a very strong case for being designated as common carriers or being subjected to much stricter public utility regulation. When payment infrastructure becomes as essential as electricity or telephone service for participating in the digital economy, treating these companies as neutral utilities rather than editorial boards becomes not just reasonable but necessary.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 24 Jul 2025 07:47:26 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44668093</link><dc:creator>sReinwald</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44668093</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44668093</guid></item><item><title>New comment by K0balt in "Show HN: Tinder but it's only pictures of my wife and I can only swipe right"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;This is great.&lt;p&gt;I set it up and was conspicuously swiping in bed.  My wife is all hey, what are you doing? I’m all nothing.. put the phone down on the dresser.&lt;p&gt;No, let me see your phone etc. I relent, she opens the app with sulphur smoldering in her nostrils lol, then she starts poking around, and we have been having a really great night since.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 24 Jul 2025 07:09:12 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44667831</link><dc:creator>K0balt</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44667831</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44667831</guid></item><item><title>New comment by littlecranky67 in "AI overviews cause massive drop in search clicks"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Here is the experience when clicking a link on mobile:&lt;p&gt;* Page loads, immediately when I start scrolling and reading a popup trying to get tracking consent&lt;p&gt;* If I am lucky, there is a "necessary only". When unlucky I need to click "manage options" and first see how to reject all tracking&lt;p&gt;* There is a sticky banner on top/bottom taking 20-30% of my screen upselling me a subscription or asking me to install their app. Upon pressing the tiny X in the corner it takes 1-2 seconds to close or multiple presses as I am either missing the x or because there is a network roundtrip&lt;p&gt;* I scroll down a screen and get a popup overlay asking me to signup for their service or newsleter, again messing with the x to close&lt;p&gt;* video or other flashy adds in the content keep bugging me&lt;p&gt;This is btw. usually all before I even established if the content is what I was looking for, or is at any way useful to me (often it is not).&lt;p&gt;If you use AI or Kagi summarizr, you get ad-free, well-formatted content without any annoyance.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 24 Jul 2025 06:40:29 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44667666</link><dc:creator>littlecranky67</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44667666</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44667666</guid></item><item><title>New comment by mattlutze in "How to Firefox"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I am surprised how many people have so many problems with Firefox.&lt;p&gt;I've never felt impeded by loading speeds, and my ADHD regularly has me forgetting to restart it, to the tune of 100+ tabs open across multiple desktops. My wimply little MacBook Pro doesn't seem to mind.&lt;p&gt;The only downside I've found is that, because so many people just default to "Chrome or nothing," there's occasionally sites that have bugs because, like was the case in the 90s with Internet Explorer, the site developers took the idiomatic Chrome way of building a feature instead of something universal.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 22 Jul 2025 13:00:03 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44646335</link><dc:creator>mattlutze</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44646335</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44646335</guid></item><item><title>New comment by nomel in "What went wrong inside recalled Anker PowerCore 10000 power banks?"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I work in manufacturing in the US. Incoming quality control, for Chinese vendors, is &lt;i&gt;necessarily&lt;/i&gt; set up with zero-trust. This isn't a "trust but verify" sort of thing, it's strictly "do not trust". Assume that, at every step of the chain, there will be a lie: change of process, material change, collected data, and that the product being given to you is even yours (delivering a knockoff at the final step, and reselling yours on the gray market).&lt;p&gt;This is all common knowledge, proven by example after example that it's &lt;i&gt;necessary&lt;/i&gt; to have zero trust. It's truly an adversarial system. All the extra engineering effort for IQC is still cheaper. And, there's rarely an alternative to the amazing manufacturing ecosystem that is China.&lt;p&gt;After tracking down several of these types of issues, it appears that the Chabuduo mindset [1] is a very real thing.&lt;p&gt;[1] &lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=32465780"&gt;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=32465780&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 21 Jul 2025 20:57:02 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44640329</link><dc:creator>nomel</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44640329</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44640329</guid></item><item><title>New comment by yegle in "What went wrong inside recalled Anker PowerCore 10000 power banks?"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;FWIW this has caused a big storm in China. The root of the issue is known to be caused by the battery cell vendor Amprius changing the battery design w/o notifying the power bank manufacturers. AFAIKT Amprius lost the 3C certification (a certification in China) because of this incident.&lt;p&gt;This is one of the Chinese reports on the issue: 
&lt;a href="https://m.thepaper.cn/newsDetail_forward_31048287" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://m.thepaper.cn/newsDetail_forward_31048287&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;Excerpt from the report above (translated using Google):&lt;p&gt;&gt; The Paper learned from an insider that Anker Innovations' battery cell supplier is already a leading battery cell supplier in the industry, and did not inform customers after it changed materials. In addition to Anker Innovations, the supplier also cooperates with leading power bank brands, so the impact is huge. Although Anker Innovations did not name the supplier, an insider pointed out that the supplier was Amprius.&lt;p&gt;UPDATE:&lt;p&gt;There's an exclusive interview by 36kr with one of Anker's VPs:&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://m.36kr.com/p/3365435892680709" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://m.36kr.com/p/3365435892680709&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 21 Jul 2025 19:58:01 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44639759</link><dc:creator>yegle</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44639759</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44639759</guid></item><item><title>New comment by npsomaratna in "“Dynamic programming” is not referring to “computer programming”"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Sri Lankan here. I used to compete in the IOI (International Olympiad in Informatics), back in the '90s.&lt;p&gt;I aced the competition in Sri Lanka, but I failed to win a medal the first time I competed internationally. I solved several problems with recursion, but these failed to complete within the strict time limits allowed.&lt;p&gt;One of the contestants from another country told me: "You needed dynamic programming to solve problems 1 and 5." I then spent the next year trying to figure out what dynamic programming was. The folks over here weren't familiar with the term. In fact, I was often asked "did you mean dynamic memory allocation?"&lt;p&gt;After a while, I managed to find a book that talked about dynamic programming, and I was like "Oh, it's recursion + storing results" and "Ah, you can also do this iteratively in certain circumstances"&lt;p&gt;Bottom line, armed with this new knowledge, I ended up winning a gold medal at IOI 2001. Fun times.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 21 Jul 2025 05:34:38 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44632078</link><dc:creator>npsomaratna</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44632078</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44632078</guid></item><item><title>New comment by layer8 in "The bewildering phenomenon of declining quality"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Many comments here are arguing that quality has actually gone up over the past decades. However, a common experience for me is that I own something of good quality from 5/10/15 years ago and now buy the successor model from the same brand, but the product has gotten worse, being cheaper made. And I have a hard time finding a replacement that matches the quality of the old version. It’s a regularly reoccurring frustration.&lt;p&gt;My suspicion is that when products are successful and mature but reach market saturation, profit growth pressure leads to cutting some corners on every iteration, and hence to a slow decline in quality over the years.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 20 Jul 2025 11:42:47 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44624220</link><dc:creator>layer8</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44624220</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44624220</guid></item><item><title>New comment by ijk in "Valve confirms credit card companies pressured it to delist certain adult games"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;One factor is the ongoing campaigns from number of moral crusading groups who lobby them to cut off payment processing for things they don't approve of. NCOSE has been working for decades on the project, and targeting credit card companies has been a successful tactic for them for a decade or so.&lt;p&gt;[1] &lt;a href="https://www.eff.org/deeplinks/2020/12/visa-and-mastercard-are-trying-dictate-what-you-can-watch-pornhub" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://www.eff.org/deeplinks/2020/12/visa-and-mastercard-ar...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;[2] &lt;a href="https://www.newsweek.com/why-visa-mastercard-being-blamed-onlyfans-banning-explicit-content-pornography-1621570" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://www.newsweek.com/why-visa-mastercard-being-blamed-on...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;[3] &lt;a href="https://scholarworks.iu.edu/dspace/bitstreams/761eb6c3-9377-4ced-9287-5733293063bf/download" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://scholarworks.iu.edu/dspace/bitstreams/761eb6c3-9377-...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 19 Jul 2025 00:50:45 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44611517</link><dc:creator>ijk</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44611517</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44611517</guid></item><item><title>New comment by thr0waway001 in "Anthropic tightens usage limits for Claude Code without telling users"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&gt; One user, who asked not to be identified, said it has been impossible to advance his project since the usage limits came into effect.&lt;p&gt;Vibe limit reached. Gotta start doing some thinking.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 17 Jul 2025 22:06:08 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44598772</link><dc:creator>thr0waway001</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44598772</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44598772</guid></item><item><title>New comment by twalkz in "ChatGPT agent: bridging research and action"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;The "spreadsheet" example video is kind of funny: guy talks about how it normally takes him 4 to 8 hours to put together complicated, data-heavy reports. Now he fires off an agent request, goes to walk his dog, and comes back to a downloadable spreadsheet of dense data, which he pulls up and says "I think it got 98% of the information correct... I just needed to copy / paste a few things. If it can do 90 - 95% of the time consuming work, that will save you a ton of time"&lt;p&gt;It feels like either finding that 2% that's off (or dealing with 2% error) will be the time consuming part in a lot of cases. I mean, this is nothing new with LLMs, but as these use cases encourage users to input more complex tasks, that are more integrated with our personal data (and at times money, as hinted at by all the "do task X and buy me Y" examples), "almost right" seems like it has the potential to cause a lot of headaches. Especially when the 2% error is subtle and buried in step 3 of 46 of some complex agentic flow.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 17 Jul 2025 17:27:06 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44595791</link><dc:creator>twalkz</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44595791</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44595791</guid></item><item><title>New comment by idle_zealot in "Where's Firefox going next?"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I know there are plenty of more serious issues people have with Mozilla's direction and focus, but patronizing stuff like this really grinds my gears.&lt;p&gt;&gt; Which animal best represents your Firefox browsing style? [List of emoji animals]&lt;p&gt;The marketing/PR trend of speaking to communities as though they're kindergartners is distracting and off-putting. This is the most egregious part but the whole post has a similar tone.&lt;p&gt;I'll note that I'm not saying outreach should necessarily be professional or devoid of fun/humor. There's just a sterile, saccharine way about Mozilla's community engagement that evokes artificiality.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 16 Jul 2025 06:43:48 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44579387</link><dc:creator>idle_zealot</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44579387</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44579387</guid></item><item><title>New comment by lsy in "LLM Inevitabilism"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I think two things can be true simultaneously:&lt;p&gt;1. LLMs are a new technology and it's hard to put the genie back in the bottle with that. It's difficult to imagine a future where they don't continue to exist in some form, with all the timesaving benefits and social issues that come with them.&lt;p&gt;2. Almost three years in, companies investing in LLMs have not yet discovered a business model that justifies the massive expenditure of training and hosting them, the majority of consumer usage is at the free tier, the industry is seeing the first signs of pulling back investments, and model capabilities are plateauing at a level where most people agree that the output is trite and unpleasant to consume.&lt;p&gt;There are many technologies that have seemed inevitable and seen retreats under the lack of commensurate business return (the supersonic jetliner), and several that seemed poised to displace both old tech and labor but have settled into specific use cases (the microwave oven). Given the lack of a sufficiently profitable business model, it feels as likely as not that LLMs settle somewhere a little less remarkable, and hopefully less annoying, than today's almost universally disliked attempts to cram it everywhere.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 15 Jul 2025 05:33:27 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44568114</link><dc:creator>lsy</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44568114</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44568114</guid></item><item><title>New comment by somenameforme in "The new literalism plaguing today’s movies"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Fun fact: movie sales, in terms of tickets sold, peaked in 2002. [1] All the 'box office records' since then are the result of charging way more to a continually plummeting audience size.&lt;p&gt;And this is highly relevant for things like this. People often argue that if movies were so bad then people would stop watching them, unaware that people actually have stopped watching them!&lt;p&gt;Even for individual movies. For all the men-in-spandex movies, the best selling movie (by tickets sold) in modern times is Titanic, 27 years ago.&lt;p&gt;[1] - &lt;a href="https://www.the-numbers.com/market/" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://www.the-numbers.com/market/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 15 Jul 2025 04:23:05 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44567805</link><dc:creator>somenameforme</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44567805</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44567805</guid></item><item><title>New comment by pm90 in "Cognition (Devin AI) to Acquire Windsurf"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I think the amount of turmoil around these deals is giving more weight to the possibility that we’re in a massive bubble thats quite divorced from any kind of fundamentals. Sooner or later the bubbles gonna burst.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 14 Jul 2025 19:38:52 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44564397</link><dc:creator>pm90</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44564397</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=44564397</guid></item></channel></rss>