<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>Hacker News: Best Comments</title><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/bestcomments</link><description>Hacker News RSS</description><docs>https://hnrss.org/</docs><generator>hnrss v2.1.1</generator><lastBuildDate>Sun, 04 Jan 2026 23:52:43 +0000</lastBuildDate><ns0:link href="https://hnrss.org/bestcomments" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item><title>New comment by mike_hearn in "Lessons from 14 Years at Google"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;&gt; If the Google culture was at all obsessed about helping users, I wonder why Google UX always sucked so much and in particularly in the recent years seem to be getting even worse.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;p&gt;There was no beancounter takeover and it never was so obsessed. I worked there from 2006-2014 in engineering roles and found this statement was particularly jarring: &lt;i&gt;"User obsession means spending time in support tickets, talking to users, watching users struggle, asking “why” until you hit bedrock"&lt;/i&gt;&lt;p&gt;When I worked on user facing stuff (Maps, Gmail, Accounts) I regularly read the public user support forums and ticket queues looking for complaints, sometimes I even took part in user threads to get more information. What I learned was:&lt;p&gt;• Almost nobody else in engineering did this.&lt;p&gt;• I was considered weird for doing it.&lt;p&gt;• It was viewed negatively by managers and promo committees.&lt;p&gt;• An engineer talking directly to users was considered especially weird and problematic.&lt;p&gt;• The products did always have serious bugs that had escaped QA and monitoring.&lt;p&gt;In theory there were staff paid to monitor these forums, but in practice the eng managers paid little attention to them - think "user voice" reports once a quarter, that sort of thing. Partly that's because they weren't technical and often struggled to work out whether a user complaint was just noise or due to a genuine bug in the product, something often obvious to an engineer, so stuff didn't get escalated properly.&lt;p&gt;This general disconnection from the outside world was pervasive. When I joined the abuse team in 2010 I was surprised to discover that despite it having existed for many years, only one engineer was bothering to read spammer forums where they talked to each other, and he was also brand new to the team. He gave me his logins and we quickly discovered spammers had found bugs in the accounts web servers they were using to blow past the antispam controls, without this being visible from any monitoring on our side. We learned many other useful things by doing this kind of "abuser research". But it was, again, very unusual. The team until that point had been dominated by ML-heads who just wanted to use it as a testing ground for model training.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 04 Jan 2026 18:38:04 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46490826</link><dc:creator>mike_hearn</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46490826</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46490826</guid></item><item><title>New comment by hansmayer in "Lessons from 14 Years at Google"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Not looking to dismiss the authors long tenure at a major tech company like Google, but the first point kind of stuck like a sore thumb. If the Google culture was at all obsessed about helping users, I wonder why Google UX always sucked so much and in particularly in the recent years seem to be getting even worse. Every single one of their services is a pain to use, with unnecessary steps, clicks - basically everything you are trying to do needs a click of sorts. Recently I was writing an e-mail and noticed I misspelled the e-mail address of the recipient, which I rarely do. So, I should just be able to click the address and edit it quickly, right? Wrong - now you have a popup menu and inside of it you have to search for "edit e-mail" option. Most of the rest of his lessons while valuable in  their own right, are not  something I would put under the headline of "after X years at &lt;insert-major-tech-company&gt;", as they do not quite seem to be  that different from lessons you pick up at other companies ? I´d more interested to hear about how the culture was impacted when the bean-counters took over and started entshittifying the company for both the users and the employees too.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 04 Jan 2026 18:06:50 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46490497</link><dc:creator>hansmayer</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46490497</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46490497</guid></item><item><title>New comment by unsungNovelty in "The Unbearable Joy of Sitting Alone in a Café"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Too many negative comments here. This is just someone discovering something new and sharing it very excitedly.&lt;p&gt;Almost 6-7 years ago, I read about a 30min challenge to sit upright without doing anything in a chair challenge. That changed how I think about distractions. If I had written about it, there surely will be people who would just like here say... &lt;i&gt;What is so crazy about it? I do that all the time...&lt;/i&gt;&lt;p&gt;To me, this post is someone's joy and curiosity shared through a well written piece. Everybody discover certain things at different stages of their lives. What's so bad about that?&lt;p&gt;Was able to bring a smile on my face. A good post. :)&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 04 Jan 2026 17:06:02 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46489861</link><dc:creator>unsungNovelty</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46489861</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46489861</guid></item><item><title>New comment by simonw in "Web development is fun again"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Something I like about our weird new LLM-assisted world is the number of people I know who are coding again, having mostly stopped as they moved into management roles or lost their personal side project time to becoming parents.&lt;p&gt;AI assistance means you can get something useful done in half an hour, or even &lt;i&gt;while&lt;/i&gt; you are doing other stuff. You don't need to carve out 2-4 hours to ramp up any more.&lt;p&gt;If you have significant previous coding experience - even if it's a few years stale - you can drive these things extremely effectively. Especially if you have management experience, quite a lot of which transfers to "managing" coding agents (communicate clearly, set achievable goals, provide all relevant context.)&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 04 Jan 2026 15:32:58 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46488894</link><dc:creator>simonw</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46488894</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46488894</guid></item><item><title>New comment by Aurornis in "Total monthly number of StackOverflow questions over time"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&gt; I disagree with most comments that the brusque moderation is the cause of SO's problems, though it certainly didn't help. SO has had poor moderation from the beginning.&lt;p&gt;I was an early SO user and I don’t agree with this.&lt;p&gt;The moderation was always there, but from my perspective it wasn’t until the site really pushed into branching out and expanding Stack Exchange across many topics to become a Quora style competitor that the moderation started taking on a life of its own. Stack Overflow moderator drama felt constant in the later 2010s with endless weird drama spilling across Twitter, Reddit, and the moderator’s personal blogs. That’s about the same time period where it felt like the moderation team was more interested in finding reasons to exercise their moderation power than in maintaining an interesting website.&lt;p&gt;Since about 2020 every time I click a Stack Overflow link I estimate there’s a 50/50 chance that the question I clicked on would be marked as off topic or closed or something before anyone could answer it. Between the moderator drama and the constant bait-and-switch feeling of clicking on SO links that didn’t go anywhere the site just felt more exhausting than helpful.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 04 Jan 2026 02:34:48 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46484235</link><dc:creator>Aurornis</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46484235</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46484235</guid></item><item><title>New comment by erikig in "Total monthly number of StackOverflow questions over time"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;The various admonitions to publish to a personal blog, while encouraging, don't really get at the 0xfaded's request which I'd summarize as follows:&lt;p&gt;With no one asking questions these technical questions publicly, where, how and on what public platform will technical people find the problems that need solving so they can exercise their creativity for the benefit of all?&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 04 Jan 2026 01:10:17 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46483704</link><dc:creator>erikig</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46483704</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46483704</guid></item><item><title>New comment by yakattak in "The suck is why we're here"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&gt; Because I don’t write a daily blog to crank out a post every day. If that was the point, I’d have switched to AI long ago already. I write a daily blog to make sure I remember how to think.&lt;p&gt;I feel like this will get missed by the general public. What’s the point in generating writing or generating art if it gives next to zero feelings of accomplishment?&lt;p&gt;I could generate some weird 70s sci fi art, make an Instagram profile around that, barrage the algorithm with my posts and rack up likes. The likes will give that instant dopamine but it will never fill that need of accomplishing something.&lt;p&gt;I like LLMs to get me to reword something, since I struggle with that. But just like in programming I focus it on a specific sentence or two. Otherwise why am I doing it?&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 04 Jan 2026 01:01:15 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46483645</link><dc:creator>yakattak</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46483645</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46483645</guid></item><item><title>New comment by 0xfaded in "Total monthly number of StackOverflow questions over time"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I once published a method for finding the closest distance between an ellipse and a point on SO: &lt;a href="https://stackoverflow.com/questions/22959698/distance-from-given-point-to-given-ellipse#answer-46007540" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://stackoverflow.com/questions/22959698/distance-from-g...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;I consider it the most beautiful piece of code I've ever written and perhaps my one minor contribution to human knowledge. It uses a method I invented, is just a few lines, and converges in very few iterations.&lt;p&gt;People used to reach out to me all the time with uses they had found for it, it was cited in a PhD and apparently lives in some collision plugin for unity. Haven't heard from anyone in a long time.&lt;p&gt;It's also my test question for LLMs, and I've yet to see my solution regurgitated. Instead they generate some variant of Newtons method, ChatGPT 5.2 gave me an LM implementation and acknowledged that Newtons method is unstable (it is, which is why I went down the rabbit hole in the first place.)&lt;p&gt;Today I don't know where I would publish such a gem. It's not something I'd bother writing up in a paper, and SO was the obvious place were people who wanted an answer to this question would look. Now there is no central repository, instead everyone individually summons the ghosts of those passed in loneliness.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 04 Jan 2026 00:47:15 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46483541</link><dc:creator>0xfaded</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46483541</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46483541</guid></item><item><title>New comment by johnfn in "Total monthly number of StackOverflow questions over time"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Some comments:&lt;p&gt;- This is a really remarkable graph. I just didn't realize how thoroughly it was over for SO. It stuns me as much as when Encyclopædia Britannica stopped selling print versions a mere 9 years after the publication of Wikipedia, but at an even faster timescale.&lt;p&gt;- I disagree with most comments that the brusque moderation is the cause of SO's problems, though it certainly didn't help. SO has had poor moderation from the beginning. The fundamental value proposition of SO is getting an answer to a question; if you can the same answer faster, you don't need SO. I suspect that the gradual decline, beginning around 2016, is due to growth in a number of other sources of answers. Reddit is kind of a dark horse here, as I began seeing answers on Google to more modern technical questions link to a Reddit thread frequently along with SO from 2016 onwards. I also suspect Discord played a part, though this is harder to gauge; I certainly got a number of answers to questions for, e.g., Bun, by asking around in the Bun Discord, etc. The final nail in the coffin is of course LLMs, which can offer a SO-level answer to a decent percentage of questions instantly. (The fact that the LLM doesn't insult you is just the cherry on top.)&lt;p&gt;- I know I'm beating a dead horse here, but what happens now? Despite stratification I mentioned above, SO was by far the leading source of high quality answers to technical questions. What do LLMs train off of now? I wonder if, 10 years from now, LLMs will still be answering questions that were answered in the halcyon 2014-2020 days of SO better than anything that came after? Or will we find new, better ways to find answers to technical questions?&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 04 Jan 2026 00:39:04 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46483491</link><dc:creator>johnfn</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46483491</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46483491</guid></item><item><title>New comment by Alupis in "Total monthly number of StackOverflow questions over time"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;People in this thread are missing another key component in the decline of StackOverflow - the more experienced you become, the less useful it is.&lt;p&gt;The harder the problem, the less engagement it gets. People who spend hours working on your issue are rewarded with a single upvote. Meanwhile, "how do I concat a string" gets dozens or hundreds of upvotes.&lt;p&gt;The incentive/reward structure punished experienced folks with challenging/novel questions.&lt;p&gt;Pair that with the toxic moderation and trigger-happy close-votes, you get a zombie community with little new useful content.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2026 23:39:05 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46483019</link><dc:creator>Alupis</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46483019</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46483019</guid></item><item><title>New comment by etamponi in "Total monthly number of StackOverflow questions over time"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I spent the last 14 days chasing an issue with a Spark transform. Gemini and Claude were exceptionally good at giving me answers that looked perfectly reasonable: none of them worked, they were almost always completely off-road.&lt;p&gt;Eventually I tried with something else, and found a question on stackoverflow, luckily with an answer. That was the game changer and eventually I was able to find the right doc in the Spark (actually Iceberg) website that gave me the final fix.&lt;p&gt;This is to say that LLMs might be more friendly. But losing SO means that we're getting an idiot friendly guy with a lot of credible but wrong answers in place of a grumpy and possibly toxic guy which, however, actually answered our questions.&lt;p&gt;Not sure why someone is thinking this is a good thing.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2026 23:13:43 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46482769</link><dc:creator>etamponi</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46482769</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46482769</guid></item><item><title>New comment by porcoda in "Total monthly number of StackOverflow questions over time"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Not a big surprise once LLMs came along: stack overflow developed some pretty unpleasant traits over time.  Everything from legitimate questions being closed for no good reason (or being labeled a duplicate even though they often weren’t), out of date answers that never get updated as tech changes, to a generally toxic and condescending culture amongst the top answerers.  For all their flaws, LLMs are so much better.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2026 23:01:51 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46482640</link><dc:creator>porcoda</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46482640</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46482640</guid></item><item><title>New comment by geerlingguy in "The Most Popular Blogs of Hacker News in 2025"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I've gotten a ton out of this community (much of the time research I've done in the past year stems from various comments and articles I found here), and regarding:&lt;p&gt;"Jeff started out as a blogger, and he still treats his blog readers as first-class citizens. He structures his articles to fit the text medium rather than just lazily scraping dialog from his videos. You can read his post about upgrading storage on his Mac mini and not even realize it’s adapted from a video."&lt;p&gt;For most of my favorite projects, I write the blog post _first_, then adapt that to a YouTube script. I still consider the written word to be vastly superior to video form.&lt;p&gt;But the videos earn an income (about 1/2 what I earned as a software dev, but it's sustainable and lets me do whatever projects I like), whereas the blog has earned maybe a few thousand dollars with Amazon Affiliate links each year (it covers the hosting, at least, and gives a little extra cash, but I try to keep the blog as "old school web" as possible.&lt;p&gt;Just finished upgrading it to Hugo today! (After being on Drupal for 16 years)&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2026 20:04:17 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46480959</link><dc:creator>geerlingguy</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46480959</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46480959</guid></item><item><title>New comment by jjaksic in "Report: Microsoft kills official way to activate Windows 11/10 without internet"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;When Nadella took over from Ballmer, he steered Microsoft in a better direction for a while. But by now he's become a lot worse. The biggest software company can no longer produce good software and its products are actively hostile to users. Nadella cares only about one thing, which is shoving AI everywhere and to everyone, at any cost. The irony is that he knows nothing about AI, how to build capable models or how to build useful AI products, nor does he have people who do. AI is his Metaverse: something he's singularity focused on, to the point of neglecting everything else, without any idea what to actually do with it.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2026 19:34:17 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46480604</link><dc:creator>jjaksic</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46480604</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46480604</guid></item><item><title>New comment by incognito124 in "Report: Microsoft kills official way to activate Windows 11/10 without internet"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Thank you, Microsoft, for accelerating the advent of The Year of The Linux Desktop&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2026 19:18:46 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46480412</link><dc:creator>incognito124</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46480412</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46480412</guid></item><item><title>New comment by dubeux in "Trump says Venezuela’s Maduro captured after strikes"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I get slightly desperate realizing how people are lead to such naive discussions, even in a place with supposedly instructed, informed persons.
Maduro may be a dictator, a murderer, whatever. This has absolutely no relation with the reasons for US invading, bombing and killing Venezuelans, or whichever country. For about a century, US has been doing it all over the world, not because they wanna live in a better, peaceful world - quite the opposite, they've been doing it for supporting coups and stablishing dictatorships that favour their supremacy, their role as the most powerful country in the world.
Do you really, really believe Mr. Donald is very concerned about the lives of poor venezuelans? Or, just to stay in the region, he supports El Salvador dictator because he's a very nice fellow?&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2026 18:16:27 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46479744</link><dc:creator>dubeux</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46479744</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46479744</guid></item><item><title>New comment by xg15 in "Trump says Venezuela’s Maduro captured after strikes"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Yeah, I was mostly surprised about the brazenness of it all. So the plan is to take over the government, take over the oil industry, sell the oil and in infinite grace give the Venezuelans some part of it back (minus of course the "compensation" for the years in which US companies were kept out of the country)&lt;p&gt;And all that as &lt;i&gt;official doctrine&lt;/i&gt;, not even some secret strategy paper or covert ops campaign.&lt;p&gt;Edit: I had to chuckle at his "reviewing" of the Monroe doctrine as DONroe doctrine. There is "on the nose" and there is "punching someone in the face"...&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2026 17:56:10 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46479512</link><dc:creator>xg15</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46479512</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46479512</guid></item><item><title>New comment by guax in "Trump says Venezuela’s Maduro captured after strikes"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;"We're going to run the country until such time as we can do a safe, proper and judicious transition"&lt;p&gt;And then a few seconds later: "US oil companies will go into Venezuela"&lt;p&gt;Never the US has been so honest around so many lies in the same speech.&lt;p&gt;I am still curious about the whole side bar about Washington being now safest and free of crime.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2026 16:56:22 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46478843</link><dc:creator>guax</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46478843</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46478843</guid></item><item><title>New comment by guax in "Trump says Venezuela’s Maduro captured after strikes"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;A lot of Venezuelans are happy about it.&lt;p&gt;Maduro is not good for Venezuela.&lt;p&gt;The US should not be the decider of who stays in power on another country.&lt;p&gt;The president should not have the power to apprehend a countries president IN THEIR COUNTRY without a process thats more than just "I really want it".&lt;p&gt;The US is giving another clear message that it does not care about global order, just global control. We're back in the 70s.&lt;p&gt;There is ZERO concern of the current US administration about the welfare of Venezuelans, its a power play, if maduro played by the US rules, he would be in power regardless of crimes. Pinochet, The Brazilian regime are all here as testament to that.&lt;p&gt;I hope the power change turns out better for the Venezuelans. I hope this is a catalyst of change for a better government. Ideally one that does not sell itself to the US for legitimacy. I don't think that is the likely outcome.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2026 16:24:28 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46478426</link><dc:creator>guax</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46478426</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46478426</guid></item><item><title>New comment by mbix77 in "Trump says Venezuela’s Maduro captured after strikes"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;There is not an extreme amount of crime and violence. Years ago yes. But now it's a lot better. Source: living here.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2026 15:52:28 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46478024</link><dc:creator>mbix77</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46478024</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46478024</guid></item><item><title>New comment by ofalkaed in "Trump says Venezuela’s Maduro captured after strikes"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I just spent way too much time reading through this thread looking for a single post more concerned about Venezuela and its people than the poster's own politics. I gave up when I noticed I was only a 1/4 of the way through thread, should have started from the bottom.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2026 13:37:24 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46476456</link><dc:creator>ofalkaed</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46476456</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46476456</guid></item><item><title>New comment by boramalper in "Trump says Venezuela’s Maduro captured after strikes"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Two wrongs don’t make a right.&lt;p&gt;Regardless of your opinion on Maduro, you can still acknowledge that the head of a sovereign state being captured in an unannounced/unnamed military operation by a superpower is wrong from a principled standpoint, and that it’s destabilising a country with 30+ million people if not the entire region.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2026 13:37:22 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46476455</link><dc:creator>boramalper</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46476455</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46476455</guid></item><item><title>New comment by jacquesm in "Trump says Venezuela’s Maduro captured after strikes"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;It's funny how many people already see this as a book that is opened and closed on the same day. That's not how these things work. This is like the first stone of an avalanche. It could stop here, or it could roll on for quite a while. It will take months or even years to know whether or not the outcome here was desirable or not and what the final tally is.&lt;p&gt;Remember the 'Arab spring' and what came after.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2026 13:12:15 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46476197</link><dc:creator>jacquesm</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46476197</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46476197</guid></item><item><title>New comment by unionjack22 in "Trump says Venezuela’s Maduro captured after strikes"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Here's a trick I've learnt to get an authentic view of events like these, a nice way to parse through the keyboard warrior and ivory tower voices and noise is to hear what Venezuelans, the millions of Venezuelan migrants, and the citizens of neighboring countries who've had to reckon with the legacy of Chavez think about this. You can extend this to anything really with good results.&lt;p&gt;No valuable insight will be gleaned from chat boards and reddit in the immediate aftermath of these sorts of events.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2026 12:44:50 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46475929</link><dc:creator>unionjack22</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46475929</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46475929</guid></item><item><title>New comment by aqme28 in "Trump says Venezuela’s Maduro captured after strikes"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;A lot of talk about how the administration didn't even try to justify this, but I think that the administration actually believes they did justify it. They exist in some bubble completely un-tethered from reality. I don't know what that means for the future but it's terrifying.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2026 08:33:38 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46474125</link><dc:creator>aqme28</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46474125</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46474125</guid></item><item><title>New comment by MindSpunk in "IPv6 just turned 30 and still hasn't taken over the world"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&gt; - I don't have a shortage of IPv4. Maybe my ISP or my VPN host do, I don't know. I have a roomy 10.0.0.0/8 to work with.&lt;p&gt;What happens when multiple devices in your /8 want to listen on port 80 and 443 on the public address? Only one of them can. Now you're running a proxy.&lt;p&gt;&gt; - Every host routable from anywhere on the Internet? No thanks. Maybe I've been irreparably corrupted by being behind NAT for too long but I like the idea of a gateway between my well kept garden and the jungle and my network topology being hidden.&lt;p&gt;It's called a firewall. You want a firewall. IPv6 also has a firewall. NAT is not a firewall. NAT is usually configured as part of your firewall, but is not a firewall.&lt;p&gt;&gt; - Stateless auto configuration. What ? No, no, I want my ducks neatly in a row, not wandering about. Again maybe my brain is rotten from years of DHCP usage but yes, I want stateful configuration and I want all devices on my network to automatically use my internal DNS server thank you very much.&lt;p&gt;DHCPv6&lt;p&gt;&gt; - My ISP gives me a /64, what am I supposed to do with that anyways?&lt;p&gt;What are you supposed to do with a /8? Do you have several million computers?&lt;p&gt;&gt; - What happens if my ISP decides to change my prefix ? How do my routing rules need to change? I have no idea.&lt;p&gt;What happens if your ISP changes your IPv4 address?&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2026 02:59:22 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46472360</link><dc:creator>MindSpunk</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46472360</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46472360</guid></item><item><title>New comment by ajnin in "IPv6 just turned 30 and still hasn't taken over the world"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I don't use IPv6 because it solves a problem that I don't have and it provides functionality that I don't want. And also because I don't understand it very well.&lt;p&gt;My points :&lt;p&gt;- I don't have a shortage of IPv4. Maybe my ISP or my VPN host do, I don't know. I have a roomy 10.0.0.0/8 to work with.&lt;p&gt;- Every host routable from anywhere on the Internet? No thanks. Maybe I've been irreparably corrupted by being behind NAT for too long but I like the idea of a gateway between my well kept garden and the jungle and my network topology being hidden.&lt;p&gt;- Stateless auto configuration. What ? No, no, I want my ducks neatly in a row, not wandering about. Again maybe my brain is rotten from years of DHCP usage but yes, I want stateful configuration and I want all devices on my network to automatically use my internal DNS server thank you very much.&lt;p&gt;- It's hard to remember IPv6 addresses. The prospect of reconfiguring all my router and firewall rules looks rather painful.&lt;p&gt;- My ISP gives me a /64, what am I supposed to do with that anyways?&lt;p&gt;- What happens if my ISP decides to change my prefix ? How do my routing rules need to change? I have no idea.&lt;p&gt;In short, so far, ignorance is bliss.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2026 02:26:25 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46472163</link><dc:creator>ajnin</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46472163</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46472163</guid></item><item><title>New comment by wewewedxfgdf in "Microsoft kills official way to activate Windows 11/10 without internet"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Microsoft could have made Windows:&lt;p&gt;able to run on any hardware&lt;p&gt;free for basic usage, paid for commercial usage&lt;p&gt;lightweight, simple, stripped of all cruft and extras&lt;p&gt;consistent in it's UI and cleaned up from 40 years of inconsistencies&lt;p&gt;But they didn't - so people are looking for alternatives.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2026 01:24:25 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46471753</link><dc:creator>wewewedxfgdf</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46471753</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46471753</guid></item><item><title>New comment by sylens in "2026 will be my year of the Linux desktop"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;If this wasn’t HN, I would swear that my personal recommendation algorithm has gotten Linux desktop-pilled and that’s why I’m seeing so many posts like these every day. But in reality I think there is a groundswell of momentum happening here, and with component prices rising, I only see this continuing as more people look to breathe new life into older hardware.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2026 00:30:55 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46471314</link><dc:creator>sylens</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46471314</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46471314</guid></item><item><title>New comment by roxolotl in "2026 will be my year of the Linux desktop"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;“start menus made with React Native, control-alt-delete menus that are actually just webviews”&lt;p&gt;Haven’t used windows in five years or so but I’ve kept hearing bad things. This really is the icing on the cake though. Yea the AI stuff is dumb but if a OS manufacturer can’t be bothered to interact with their own UI libraries to build native UIs something has gone horribly wrong.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2026 00:24:58 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46471257</link><dc:creator>roxolotl</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46471257</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46471257</guid></item></channel></rss>