<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>Hacker News: Best Comments</title><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/bestcomments</link><description>Hacker News RSS</description><docs>https://hnrss.org/</docs><generator>hnrss v2.1.1</generator><lastBuildDate>Mon, 20 Oct 2025 23:53:24 +0000</lastBuildDate><ns0:link href="https://hnrss.org/bestcomments" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item><title>New comment by tantalor in "The scariest "user support" email I've ever received"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&gt; as ChatGPT confirmed when I asked it to analyze it&lt;p&gt;lol we are so cooked&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 20 Oct 2025 21:36:00 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45649704</link><dc:creator>tantalor</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45649704</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45649704</guid></item><item><title>New comment by seanhunter in "J.P. Morgan's OpenAI loan is strange"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;What a weird analysis.&lt;p&gt;A company that has revenues and is extremely well-capitalized gets debt finance. That is not news. That is totally commonplace. "Shouldn't all their capital come from investors?" No. Companies at all stages typically use a mixture of debt and equity finance.&lt;p&gt;His EV calculation is completely flawed also.  Debt finance is typically senior to equity in recovery at bankruptcy, so when JPMC do this analysis (and believe me they did this analysis) they are not assuming 0% recovery. They are thinking it is most likely in a bankruptcy that they get some x&gt;0% recovery.&lt;p&gt;Finally, banks don't think about their relationship with a multi-billion-dollar company in terms of the ROI on a single revolving credit. (even though this will in all likelihood be very profitable for JPMC). They think about how giving this revolving credit makes it more likely they get advisory on any future bond issuance and I-banking work when OpenAI want to do takeovers, and a foot in the door at IPO time etc.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 20 Oct 2025 20:06:27 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45648617</link><dc:creator>seanhunter</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45648617</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45648617</guid></item><item><title>New comment by 0x5345414e in "AWS Multiple Services Down in us-east-1"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;This is having a direct impact on my wellbeing. I was at Whole Foods in Hudson Yards NYC and I couldn’t get the prime discount on my chocolate bar because the system isn’t working. Decided not to get the chocolate bar. Now my chocolate levels are way too low.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 20 Oct 2025 18:04:41 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45647080</link><dc:creator>0x5345414e</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45647080</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45647080</guid></item><item><title>New comment by indoordin0saur in "AWS Multiple Services Down in us-east-1"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Seems like major issues are still ongoing. If anything it seems &lt;i&gt;worse&lt;/i&gt; than it did ~4 hours ago. For reference I'm a data engineer and it's Redshift and Airflow (AWS managed) that is FUBAR for me.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 20 Oct 2025 16:31:11 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45645786</link><dc:creator>indoordin0saur</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45645786</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45645786</guid></item><item><title>New comment by time0ut in "AWS Multiple Services Down in us-east-1"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Interesting day. I've been on an incident bridge since 3AM. Our systems have mostly recovered now with a few back office stragglers fighting for compute.&lt;p&gt;The biggest miss on our side is that, although we designed a multi-region capable application, we could not run the failover process because our security org migrated us to Identity Center and only put it in us-east-1, hard locking the entire company out of the AWS control plane. By the time we'd gotten the root credentials out of the vault, things were coming back up.&lt;p&gt;Good reminder that you are only as strong as your weakest link.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 20 Oct 2025 13:44:18 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45643848</link><dc:creator>time0ut</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45643848</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45643848</guid></item><item><title>New comment by JCM9 in "AWS Multiple Services Down in us-east-1"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;US-East-1 is more than just a normal region. It also provides the backbone for other services, including those in other regions. Thus simply being in another region doesn’t protect you from the consistent us-east-1 shenanigans.&lt;p&gt;AWS doesn’t talk about that much publicly, but if you press them they will admit in private that there are some pretty nasty single points of failure in the design of AWS that can materialize if us-east-1 has an issue. Most people would say that means AWS isn’t truly multi-region in some areas.&lt;p&gt;Not entirely clear yet if those single points of failure were at play here, but risk mitigation isn’t as simple as just “don’t use us-east-1” or “deploy in multiple regions with load balancing failover.”&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 20 Oct 2025 12:45:59 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45643276</link><dc:creator>JCM9</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45643276</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45643276</guid></item><item><title>New comment by miki123211 in "DeepSeek OCR"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Text tokens are quantized and represent subword units, vision tokens only exist in the embedding space.&lt;p&gt;The way text tokenization works in LLMs is that you have a "lookup table" of (small) token ids to (large) vector embeddings. To pass text to the LLM, you split it at token boundaries, convert strings to token ids, and then construct the "context", a matrix where each row is a vector taken from that lookup table.&lt;p&gt;Transmitting text token sequences can be relatively efficient, you just transmit the token IDs themselves[1]. They're small integers (~100k possible token ids is typical for large models). Transmitting the actual embeddings matrix would be far less efficient, as embeddings often consist of thousands of floating point numbers.&lt;p&gt;Images are encoded differently. After some basic preprocessing, image data is passed straight to a neural- network-based image encoder. That encoder encodes the image into vectors, which are then appended to the context. There are no token ids, there's no lookup table, we go straight from image data to token embeddings.&lt;p&gt;This means transmitting image tokens cannot be done as efficiently, as you'd have to transmit the embeddings themselves. Even though an image is encoded in fewer tokens, the most efficient representation of those tokens takes more bytes.&lt;p&gt;You can think of a text token as an integer between 0 and n, which we know how to map to a vector. This means you have `n` possible choices of tokens. In contrast, an image token is an array of m floating point numbers (the vector itself), each of which can take on many possible values. This means the "token space" of vision tokens is actually much larger.&lt;p&gt;There's also the issue of patterns. Text tokens correspond directly to a contiguous span of UTF-8 bytes, and most tokenizers won't create tokens that span word boundaries. This means they can't encode global patterns efficiently. You can't have a "Hamlet's monologue" or "the text that follows is in Spanish" token.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 20 Oct 2025 11:13:17 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45642598</link><dc:creator>miki123211</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45642598</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45642598</guid></item><item><title>New comment by padjo in "AWS Multiple Services Down in us-east-1"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Planning for an AWS outage is a complete waste of time and energy for most companies. Yes it does happen but very rarely to the tune of a few hours every 5-10 years. I can almost guarantee that whatever plans you have won’t get you fully operational faster than just waiting for AWS to fix it.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 20 Oct 2025 10:13:38 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45642182</link><dc:creator>padjo</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45642182</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45642182</guid></item><item><title>New comment by JCM9 in "AWS Multiple Services Down in us-east-1"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Have a meeting today with our AWS account team about how we’re no longer going to be “All in on AWS” as we diversify workloads away. Was mostly about the pace of innovation on core services slowing and AWS being too far behind on AI services so we’re buying those from elsewhere.&lt;p&gt;The AWS team keeps touting the rock solid reliability of AWS as a reason why we shouldn’t diversify our cloud. Should be a fun meeting!&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 20 Oct 2025 10:09:16 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45642146</link><dc:creator>JCM9</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45642146</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45642146</guid></item><item><title>New comment by jacquesm in "AWS Multiple Services Down in us-east-1"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Every week or so we interview a company and ask them if they have a fall-back plan in case AWS goes down or their cloud account disappears. They always have this deer-in-the-headlights look. 'That can't happen, right?'&lt;p&gt;Now imagine for a bit that it will never come back up. See where that leads you. The internet got its main strengths from the fact that it was completely decentralized. We've been systematically eroding that strength.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 20 Oct 2025 10:05:03 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45642107</link><dc:creator>jacquesm</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45642107</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45642107</guid></item><item><title>New comment by jpalomaki in "Major AWS Outage Happening"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;When AWS is down, everybody knows it. People don’t really question your hosting choice. It’s the IBM of cloud era.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 20 Oct 2025 09:13:07 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45641689</link><dc:creator>jpalomaki</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45641689</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45641689</guid></item><item><title>New comment by stepri in "AWS Multiple Services Down in us-east-1"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;“Based on our investigation, the issue appears to be related to DNS resolution of the DynamoDB API endpoint in US-EAST-1. We are working on multiple parallel paths to accelerate recovery.”&lt;p&gt;It’s always DNS.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 20 Oct 2025 09:07:40 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45641627</link><dc:creator>stepri</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45641627</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45641627</guid></item><item><title>New comment by littlecranky67 in "AWS Multiple Services Down in us-east-1"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Just a couple of days ago in this HN thread [0] there were quite some users claiming Hetzner is not an options as their uptime isn't as good as AWS, hence the higher AWS pricing is worth the investment. Oh, the irony.&lt;p&gt;[0]: &lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45614922"&gt;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45614922&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 20 Oct 2025 09:07:19 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45641625</link><dc:creator>littlecranky67</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45641625</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45641625</guid></item><item><title>New comment by amadeoeoeo in "AWS Multiple Services Down in us-east-1"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Oh no... may be LaLiga found out pirates hosting on AWS?&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 20 Oct 2025 08:20:21 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45641213</link><dc:creator>amadeoeoeo</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45641213</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45641213</guid></item><item><title>New comment by nikolay in "AWS Multiple Services Down in us-east-1"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Choosing us-east-1 as your primary region is good, because when you're down, everybody's down, too. You don't get this luxury with other US regions!&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 20 Oct 2025 07:57:12 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45641031</link><dc:creator>nikolay</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45641031</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45641031</guid></item><item><title>New comment by krackers in "DeepSeek OCR"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;The paper is more interesting than just another VLM for OCR, they start talking about compression and stuff. E.g. there is this quote&lt;p&gt;&gt;Our work represents an initial exploration into the boundaries of vision-text compression, investigating how many vision tokens are required to decode  text tokens. The preliminary results are encouraging: DeepSeek-OCR achieves near-lossless OCR compression at approximately 10× ratios, while 20× compression still retains 60% accuracy.&lt;p&gt;(I guess you could say a picture token is worth 10 textual tokens...)&lt;p&gt;Could someone explain to a noob what the information-theoretic intuition is here? Why does this work, is it that text tokens are still too "granular"/repetitive and don't come close to the ideal entropy coding? Or is switching to vision tokens escaping the limitation of working "one word-ish at a time", allowing you to get closer to entropy (similar to the way that arithmetic encoding does compared to huffman codes)?&lt;p&gt;And then they start talking about handling long-context by literally(?) downscaling images, forming a correspondence between information loss in the textual domain and the image domain.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 20 Oct 2025 06:57:27 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45640720</link><dc:creator>krackers</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45640720</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45640720</guid></item><item><title>New comment by jddj in "United MAX Hit by Falling Object at 36,000 Feet"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Go for a scroll up &lt;a href="https://neal.fun/space-elevator/" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://neal.fun/space-elevator/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 19 Oct 2025 22:20:23 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45638559</link><dc:creator>jddj</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45638559</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45638559</guid></item><item><title>New comment by bawolff in "Novo Nordisk's Canadian Mistake"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Typically when people get fired for something like this they are just the scapegoat.&lt;p&gt;A failure like this isn't just one dude forgetting, its a system failure where policies and checks failed. If it is solely up to one person that is a failure in and of itself.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 19 Oct 2025 21:52:44 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45638371</link><dc:creator>bawolff</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45638371</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45638371</guid></item><item><title>New comment by rahimnathwani in "Novo Nordisk's Canadian Mistake"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;AIUI, because they let the patent expire, the drug was not subject to price regulation by the government. So they could charge whatever.&lt;p&gt;And during most of that time, they were still protected by 'data exclusivity' which means that any generic producer could not get approved without doing their own clinical trials, until 8 years had passed.&lt;p&gt;So they gave up some period of exclusivity in return for being able to charge a higher price when they still had a monopoly.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 19 Oct 2025 21:34:54 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45638230</link><dc:creator>rahimnathwani</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45638230</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45638230</guid></item><item><title>New comment by jzebedee in "Novo Nordisk's Canadian Mistake"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&gt; Prof. Michael Hoffman from Toronto put me on to the Canadian Patent Database, where you can find that Novo did file a patent there for semaglutide. . .but the last time they paid the annual maintenance fee on it was 2018!&lt;p&gt;&gt; You can even find a letter where their lawyers send a refund request for the 2017 maintenance fee ($250) because Novo apparently wanted some more time to see if they wanted to pay it.&lt;p&gt;&gt; On the same date in 2019, the office sent a letter saying that “The fee payable to maintain the rights accorded by the above patent was not received by the prescribed due date. . .”&lt;p&gt;&gt; By that time it was $450 with the late fee added, but that was apparently too much for Novo. They had a one year grace period to make it up, and apparently never did, so their patent lapsed in Canada. And as the Canadian authorities remind them, “Once a patent has lapsed it cannot be revived”.&lt;p&gt;Impressive failure for "the second-largest semaglutide market in the world."&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 19 Oct 2025 21:24:37 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45638127</link><dc:creator>jzebedee</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45638127</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45638127</guid></item><item><title>New comment by brosco in "Doing well in your courses: Andrej's advice for success (2013)"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I have a tip for following lectures (or any technical talk, really) that I've been meaning to write about for a while.&lt;p&gt;As you follow along with the speaker, try to predict what they will say next. These can be either local or global predictions. Guess what they will write next, or what will be on the next slide. With some practice (and exposure to the subject area) you can usually get it right. Also try to keep track of how things fit into the big picture. For example in a math class, there may be a big theorem that they're working towards using lots of smaller lemmas. How will it all come together?&lt;p&gt;When you get it right, it will feel like you are figuring out the material on your own, rather than having it explained to you. This is the most important part.&lt;p&gt;If you can manage to stay one step ahead of the lecturer, it will keep you way more engaged than trying to write everything down. Writing puts you one step behind what the speaker is saying. Because of this, I usually don't take any notes at all. It obviously works better when lecture notes are made available, but you can always look at the textbook.&lt;p&gt;People often assume that I have read the material or otherwise prepared for lectures, seminars, etc., because of how closely I follow what the speaker is saying. But really most talks are quite logical, and if you stay engaged it's easy to follow along. The key is to not zone out or break your concentration, and I find this method helps me immensely.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 19 Oct 2025 17:41:32 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45636152</link><dc:creator>brosco</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45636152</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45636152</guid></item><item><title>New comment by raincole in "Replacement.ai"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;It's actually an extremely good analogy (but in the opposite way of what you imply), as you don't own your job or your wife. Banning AI for job security is like banning dildos because they make men feel insecure.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 19 Oct 2025 17:16:12 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45635905</link><dc:creator>raincole</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45635905</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45635905</guid></item><item><title>New comment by echelon_musk in "Comparing the power consumption of a 30 year old refrigerator to a new one"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&gt; &lt;i&gt;Comparing the power consumption of a [broken] 30 year old refrigerator to a brand new one&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 19 Oct 2025 16:11:45 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45635305</link><dc:creator>echelon_musk</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45635305</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45635305</guid></item><item><title>New comment by ErikCorry in "RFCs: Blueprints of the Internet"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Forgotten? No mention of why we should think they are forgotten outside the headline.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 19 Oct 2025 16:02:09 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45635205</link><dc:creator>ErikCorry</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45635205</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45635205</guid></item><item><title>New comment by everdrive in "Replacement.ai"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;[flagged]&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 19 Oct 2025 15:56:21 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45635149</link><dc:creator>everdrive</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45635149</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45635149</guid></item><item><title>New comment by TechSquidTV in "Replacement.ai"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Personal belief, but robots coming for your jobs is not a valid argument against robots. If robots can do a job better and/or faster, they should be the ones doing the jobs. Specialization is how we got to the future.&lt;p&gt;So the problem isn't robots, it's the structure of how we humans rely on jobs for income. I don't necessarily feel like it's the AI company's problem to fix either.&lt;p&gt;This is what government is for, and not to stifle innovation by banning AI but by preparing society to move forward.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 19 Oct 2025 15:12:51 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45634750</link><dc:creator>TechSquidTV</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45634750</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45634750</guid></item><item><title>New comment by allturtles in "Replacement.ai"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;This is a brilliant piece of satire. "A Modest Proposal" for the AI age.&lt;p&gt;The leader bios are particularly priceless. "While working for 12 years as the Director of HR for a multinational, Faith realized that firing people gave her an almost-spiritual high. Out of the office, Faith coaches a little league softball team and looks after her sick mother - obligations she looks forward to being free of!"&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 19 Oct 2025 14:42:33 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45634510</link><dc:creator>allturtles</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45634510</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45634510</guid></item><item><title>New comment by darthoctopus in "Replacement.ai"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;that &lt;i&gt;is&lt;/i&gt; the point of Luddism! the original Luddite movement was not ipso facto opposed to progress, but rather to the societal harm caused by society-scale economic obsolescence. the entire history of technology is &lt;i&gt;also&lt;/i&gt; powerful business interests smearing this movement as being intrinsically anti-progress, rather than directly addressing these concerns…&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 19 Oct 2025 14:33:06 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45634424</link><dc:creator>darthoctopus</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45634424</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45634424</guid></item><item><title>New comment by sincerely in "Replacement.ai"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I kind of get it, but at the same time...isn't "we made a machine to do something that people used to do" basically the entire history of of technology? It feels like somehow we should have figured out how to cope with the "but what about the old jobs" problem&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 19 Oct 2025 14:26:22 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45634372</link><dc:creator>sincerely</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45634372</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45634372</guid></item><item><title>New comment by aantix in "Friendship Begins at Home"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I've been pretty harsh on myself over the years.&lt;p&gt;I started carrying around a photo of myself as a kid.  I'm sitting against a wall, by a pillar, at our state capital.  My eyes are shut.  I was kind of a shy kid.&lt;p&gt;When I start to get frustrated and talk to myself in that short, abrasive, condescending tone, I think of that photo and of myself, as still that kid.&lt;p&gt;It helps me to be more compassionate towards myself in those moments.  I'm still that shy kid trying to make sense of the world.&lt;p&gt;I'm 47.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 19 Oct 2025 05:01:56 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45632158</link><dc:creator>aantix</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45632158</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45632158</guid></item></channel></rss>