<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>Hacker News: Best Comments</title><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/bestcomments</link><description>Hacker News RSS</description><docs>https://hnrss.org/</docs><generator>hnrss v2.1.1</generator><lastBuildDate>Sun, 19 Oct 2025 00:18:27 +0000</lastBuildDate><ns0:link href="https://hnrss.org/bestcomments" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item><title>New comment by CGamesPlay in "IDEs we had 30 years ago and lost (2023)"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;(Article is from 2023, so the title should be updated to say "32 years ago", or something)&lt;p&gt;The biggest loss in TUIs is the latest wave of asynchronous frameworks, which bring the joy of dropped keypresses to the terminal.&lt;p&gt;In any TUI released before the year 2000, if you press a key when the system wasn't ready, the key would just wait until the system was ready. Many TUIs today still do this, but increasingly frequently (with the modern "web-inspired" TUI frameworks), the system will be ready to take your keypress, and discard it because the async dialog box hasn't registered its event listener yet.&lt;p&gt;Other than that antipattern, TUIs are doing great these days. As for terminal IDEs, Neovim has never been more featureful, with LSPs and other plugins giving all the features this article discusses. I guess it isn't a mouse-driven TUI, so the author wouldn't be interested, but still.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 18 Oct 2025 14:58:01 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45627903</link><dc:creator>CGamesPlay</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45627903</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45627903</guid></item><item><title>New comment by blahgeek in "./watch"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&gt; taking inspiration from command-line interfaces&lt;p&gt;IMO the take away from command-line interfaces is compact, precise and minimal design. In a transitional shell prompt like #~$, each character has its meaning. Merely copying these symbols to a watch face is the exact opposite spirit of command like interfaces.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 18 Oct 2025 12:42:52 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45626902</link><dc:creator>blahgeek</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45626902</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45626902</guid></item><item><title>New comment by conartist6 in "Second Chances on YouTube"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Won't be available to anyone terminated for copyright stuff.&lt;p&gt;Woooow what a huge dick move.&lt;p&gt;That's the one massively imbalanced power dynamic that I hear people really fear losing their livelihood to for no good reason, and they're leaving it there to terrorize and ruin livelihoods for future generations.&lt;p&gt;I put up a video of a funeral service for my grandma and like 5 minutes later I was getting threatening legalese mail about my channel by cancelled forever because some record label has a recording of a thousand year old hymn and they don't give a shit about threatening people with no legal basis at all&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 18 Oct 2025 11:48:06 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45626590</link><dc:creator>conartist6</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45626590</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45626590</guid></item><item><title>New comment by michael1999 in "Claude Skills are awesome, maybe a bigger deal than MCP"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;We're doing something like this internally.  Our monorepo context files were much too big, so we built a progressive tree of fragments to load up for different tasks.&lt;p&gt;I am struck by how much these kinds of context documents resemble normal developer documentation, but actually useful and task-oriented.  What was the barrier to creating these documents before?&lt;p&gt;Three theories on why this is so different:&lt;p&gt;1) The feedback loop was too long.  If you wrote some docs, you might never learn if they were any good.  If you did, it might be years later.  And if you changed them, doing an A/B test was impractical.  Now, you can write up a context markdown, ask Claude to do something, and iterate in minutes.&lt;p&gt;2) The tools can help build them.  Building good docs was always hard.  Especially if you take the time to include examples, urls, etc. that make the documentation truly useful.  These tools reduce this cost.&lt;p&gt;3) Many programmers are egotists.  Documentation that helps other people doesn't generate internal motivation.  But documentation that allows you to better harness a computer minion to your will is attractive.&lt;p&gt;Any other theories?&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 17 Oct 2025 22:54:18 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45623083</link><dc:creator>michael1999</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45623083</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45623083</guid></item><item><title>New comment by PaulRobinson in "4Chan Lawyer publishes Ofcom correspondence"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Not quite.&lt;p&gt;Ofcom in their reply make their point clear: "The [Online Safety] Act explicitly grants Ofcom the legal authority to regulate online safety for individuals in the United Kingdom [...]"&lt;p&gt;They are stating that companies operating in the UK and providing services to UK individuals, are required to conform with UK regulations in relation to those services, under UK law.&lt;p&gt;As an American business, you can choose to ignore that, but that has consequences if any of your board of directors ever sets foot in the UK.&lt;p&gt;The US does this, and US lawyers understand this. If I open an online poker and sports bookmaking site in the UK (where such sites are completely legal), and take business from all over the United States thereby breaking federal law, I can expect to be met at the plane door the next time I take a shopping trip to NYC. Arguing that my servers and my business are located in the UK is not going to impress the federal judge I'd appear in front of in the morning. Stating the US laws against my activities have a snowball's chance in hell of being enforced in the UK is surely going to risk me being charged with contempt.&lt;p&gt;The Online Safety Act is ridiculous on many levels, but in the same way that Google does certain things in relation to Tiananmen Square searches in China, and every tech company engages in regulatory alignment for the entire Middle East, the UK has asked that US companies do certain things in the jurisdiction of the UK. I'd argue, less harmful and egregious things in some respects.&lt;p&gt;Should the UK do this? No, probably not. I think it will just make VPN software vendors richer, and UK citizens - particularly children - barely any safer.&lt;p&gt;Are Ofcom claiming jurisdiction in the US? No, they're claiming jurisdiction in the UK. Which, I hasten to add &lt;i&gt;they are legally required to do by the Online Safety Act&lt;/i&gt;, by the government they are an agency of. If they didn't, the government would literally be breaking its own law.&lt;p&gt;TIL that 4chan's lawyer is about as grown up, mature and able to engage in critical thinking about the law as the people who post on his client's site.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 17 Oct 2025 21:12:36 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45622144</link><dc:creator>PaulRobinson</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45622144</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45622144</guid></item><item><title>New comment by crazygringo in "Exploring PostgreSQL 18's new UUIDv7 support"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&gt; &lt;i&gt;Using UUIDv7 is generally discouraged for security when the primary key is exposed to end users in external-facing applications or APIs. The main issue is that UUIDv7 incorporates a 48-bit Unix timestamp as its most significant part, meaning the identifier itself leaks the record's creation time... Experts recommend using UUIDv7 only for internal keys and exposing a separate, truly random UUIDv4 as an external identifier.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;p&gt;So this basically defeats the entire performance improvement of UUIDv7. Because anything coming from the user will need to look up a UUIDv4, which means every new row needs to create an extra random UUIDv4 which gets inserted into a &lt;i&gt;second&lt;/i&gt; B-tree index, which recreates the very performance problem UUIDv7 is supposedly solving.&lt;p&gt;In other words, you can only use UUIDv7 for rows that &lt;i&gt;never&lt;/i&gt; need to be looked up by &lt;i&gt;any&lt;/i&gt; data coming from the user. And maybe that exists sometimes for certain data in JOINs... but it seems like it might be more the exception than the rule, and you never know when an internal ID might need to become an external one in the future.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 17 Oct 2025 21:03:56 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45622045</link><dc:creator>crazygringo</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45622045</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45622045</guid></item><item><title>New comment by branon in "GOG has had to hire private investigators to track down IP rights holders"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I like GOG a lot but it's wild to me that their GOG Galaxy client doesn't work on Linux! A lot of gamers who care about preservation and availability are spending money with Valve because Steam's DRM is mostly inoffensive and the Linux support is so good.&lt;p&gt;The addressable market segment of people who play PC games and also care about DRM-free accessibility would be larger if GOG's launcher ran on Linux and targeted Linux users. It seems like a logical overlap to me.&lt;p&gt;Valve is eating GOG's lunch in this segment but it could easily change. Sure it might be small but it's bigger than ever, still growing, and seems to fit GOG's mission.&lt;p&gt;I would definitely start repurchasing my Steam games DRM-free on GOG if only they provided a launcher with the tooling necessary to download &amp; run them on my system.&lt;p&gt;As things stand now, and for all the good GOG does... it's not enough to be DRM-free but only distribute Windows installers. You've just outsourced the DRM scheme to Microsoft. If the software doesn't run on a DRM-free OS, the job is only halfway done.&lt;p&gt;And in the meantime, GOG's product is tragically subject to piracy, (I believe) partially enabled by their decision to _only_ package games for the OS upon which most piracy traditionally takes place! :( I hope this could be offset by packaging for a crowd with more ideological overlap.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 17 Oct 2025 19:30:07 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45620990</link><dc:creator>branon</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45620990</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45620990</guid></item><item><title>New comment by ctoth in "OpenAI Needs $400B In The Next 12 Months"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;His "$400B in next 12 months" claim treats OpenAI as paying construction costs upfront. But OpenAI is leasing capacity as operating expense - Oracle finances and builds the data centers [1]. This is like saying a tenant needs $5M cash because that's what the building cost to construct.&lt;p&gt;The Oracle deal structure: OpenAI pays ~$30B/year in rental fees starting fiscal 2027/2028 [2], ramping up over 5 years as capacity comes online. Not "$400B in 12 months."&lt;p&gt;The deals are structured as staged vendor financing:
- NVIDIA "invests" $10B per gigawatt milestone, gets paid back through chip purchases [3]
- AMD gives OpenAI warrants for 160M shares (~10% equity) that vest as chips deploy [4]
- As one analyst noted: "Nvidia invests $100 billion in OpenAI, which then OpenAI turns back and gives it back to Nvidia" [3]&lt;p&gt;This is circular vendor financing where suppliers extend credit betting on OpenAI's growth. It's unusual and potentially fragile, but it's not "OpenAI needs $400B cash they don't have."&lt;p&gt;Zitron asks: "Does OpenAI have $400B in cash?"&lt;p&gt;The actual question: "Can OpenAI grow revenue from $13B to $60B+ to cover lease payments by 2028-2029?"&lt;p&gt;The first question is nonsensical given deal structure. The second is the actual bet everyone's making.&lt;p&gt;His core thesis - "OpenAI literally cannot afford these deals therefore fraud" - fails because he fundamentally misunderstands how the deals work. The real questions are about execution timelines and revenue growth projections, not about OpenAI needing hundreds of billions in cash right now.&lt;p&gt;There's probably a good critical piece to write about whether these vendor financing bets will pay off, but this isn't it.&lt;p&gt;[1] &lt;a href="https://www.cnbc.com/2025/09/23/openai-first-data-center-in-500-billion-stargate-project-up-in-texas.html" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://www.cnbc.com/2025/09/23/openai-first-data-center-in-...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;[2] &lt;a href="https://w.media/openai-to-rent-4-5-gw-of-data-center-power-from-oracle-in-us-30-billion-deal/" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://w.media/openai-to-rent-4-5-gw-of-data-center-power-f...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;[3] &lt;a href="https://www.cnbc.com/2025/09/22/nvidia-openai-data-center.html" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://www.cnbc.com/2025/09/22/nvidia-openai-data-center.ht...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;[4] &lt;a href="https://techcrunch.com/2025/10/06/amd-to-supply-6gw-of-compute-capacity-to-openai-in-chip-deal-worth-tens-of-billions/" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://techcrunch.com/2025/10/06/amd-to-supply-6gw-of-compu...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 17 Oct 2025 18:37:22 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45620292</link><dc:creator>ctoth</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45620292</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45620292</guid></item><item><title>New comment by ekjhgkejhgk in "Andrej Karpathy – It will take a decade to work through the issues with agents"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;The interview which I've watched recently with Rich Sutton left me with the impression that AGI is not just a matter of adding more 9s.&lt;p&gt;The interviewer had an idea that he took for granted: that to understand language you have to have a model of the world. LLMs seem to udnerstand language therefore they've trained a model of the world. Sutton rejected the premise immediately. He might be right in being skeptical here.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 17 Oct 2025 18:28:51 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45620183</link><dc:creator>ekjhgkejhgk</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45620183</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45620183</guid></item><item><title>New comment by cosmicgadget in "4Chan Lawyer publishes Ofcom correspondence"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;From the attorney's post:&lt;p&gt;&gt; The infinite character of that power was most famously summed up by English lawyer Sir Ivor Jennings, who once said that “if Parliament enacts that smoking in the streets of Paris is an offence, then it is an offence”. This line is taught to every first-year English law student.&lt;p&gt;Initially this seems like disrespect for another country's sovereignty. But really the crucial thing is:&lt;p&gt;&gt; We explained to the UK that the Online Safety Act had a snowball’s chance in hell of being enforced in the United States&lt;p&gt;Ofcom has to go through the motions of telling 4chan they can't smoke in Paris because of the (very on-brand) nanny law.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 17 Oct 2025 18:09:32 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45619922</link><dc:creator>cosmicgadget</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45619922</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45619922</guid></item><item><title>New comment by Imnimo in "Andrej Karpathy – It will take a decade to work through the issues with agents"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&gt;What takes the long amount of time and the way to think about it is that it’s a march of nines. Every single nine is a constant amount of work. Every single nine is the same amount of work. When you get a demo and something works 90% of the time, that’s just the first nine. Then you need the second nine, a third nine, a fourth nine, a fifth nine. While I was at Tesla for five years or so, we went through maybe three nines or two nines. I don’t know what it is, but multiple nines of iteration. There are still more nines to go.&lt;p&gt;I think this is an important way of understanding AI progress. Capability improvements often look exponential on a particular fixed benchmark, but the difficulty of the next step up is also often exponential, and so you get net linear improvement with a wider perspective.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 17 Oct 2025 18:09:10 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45619916</link><dc:creator>Imnimo</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45619916</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45619916</guid></item><item><title>New comment by earlyriser in "The Rapper 50 Cent, Adjusted for Inflation"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Conversions to Nickelback, Poundz, Los Pesos, DJ Euro and Yen.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 17 Oct 2025 17:40:06 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45619531</link><dc:creator>earlyriser</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45619531</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45619531</guid></item><item><title>New comment by lanewinfield in "The Rapper 50 Cent, Adjusted for Inflation"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;hi, i made this. thank you for posting.&lt;p&gt;unfortunately due to the government shutdown, the BLS inflation data for September 2025 is delayed from October 15 (as it normally is) until October 24[1], so please check back then to see if he is &gt;109 Cent.&lt;p&gt;assuming future stability, the site will automatically update on the 15th of every month.&lt;p&gt;[1] &lt;a href="https://www.bls.gov/bls/092025-cpi-reschedule-notice.htm" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://www.bls.gov/bls/092025-cpi-reschedule-notice.htm&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 17 Oct 2025 17:26:07 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45619352</link><dc:creator>lanewinfield</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45619352</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45619352</guid></item><item><title>New comment by xp84 in "EVs are depreciating faster than gas-powered cars"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Sub-Headline from this article: "Plummeting resale values are threatening to derail the world’s transition to electric transportation."&lt;p&gt;Alternative take: "EVs now easy to afford for the 80% of Americans who don't have $50-90k to spend on an EV!"&lt;p&gt;This year I bought a 2022 EV with 16k miles. A luxury brand. The sticker price when new was $79,000. I paid $35k. It was an off-lease vehicle so if anyone took a bath, it was the bank. I would never in a million years spend 80 grand on a car but now I have a great EV.&lt;p&gt;Battery life is not a huge concern. Any more than timing belts/chains, transmissions, etc. can be dauntingly costly repairs for cars with 150k miles or more.&lt;p&gt;I also have a gas car which I love (spouse drives the electric for a much greater commute) so I'm no EV absolutist. But this whole premise is stupid. EV adoption has had 2 main blockers: 1. only rich people had justification to buy them until recently, and 2. Charging space for people who don't have their own private garage.&lt;p&gt;Now #1 is no longer a factor. This is a GOOD thing.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 17 Oct 2025 17:15:13 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45619225</link><dc:creator>xp84</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45619225</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45619225</guid></item><item><title>New comment by riazrizvi in "4Chan Lawyer publishes Ofcom correspondence"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;More odious nannying by silly civil servants. If Britain is to restore cultural leadership it needs to move policy away from this horrible trend of policing what people say and think, and focus its energy on better policing what people do.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 17 Oct 2025 17:09:53 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45619150</link><dc:creator>riazrizvi</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45619150</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45619150</guid></item><item><title>New comment by AdamJacobMuller in "Ask HN: How to stop an AWS bot sending 2B requests/month?"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&gt; I've tried 30X redirects (which it follows)&lt;p&gt;301 response to a selection of very large files hosted by companies you don't like.&lt;p&gt;When their AWS instances start downloading 70000 windows ISOs in parallel, they might notice.&lt;p&gt;Hard to do with cloudflare but you can also tar pit them. Accept the request and send a response, one character at a time (make sure you uncork and flush buffers/etc), with a 30 second delay between characters.&lt;p&gt;700 requests/second with say 10Kb headers/response. Sure is a shame your server is so slow.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 17 Oct 2025 16:38:48 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45618776</link><dc:creator>AdamJacobMuller</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45618776</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45618776</guid></item><item><title>New comment by bunderbunder in "EVs are depreciating faster than gas-powered cars"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&gt; You can just buy new, for the same or lower price&lt;p&gt;But, like the article says, new EVs are selling for about &lt;i&gt;twice&lt;/i&gt; as much as a 2-year-old used vehicle of the same make and model. That's a very very far cry from "same or lower price".&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 17 Oct 2025 16:36:38 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45618730</link><dc:creator>bunderbunder</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45618730</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45618730</guid></item><item><title>New comment by kemayo in "EVs are depreciating faster than gas-powered cars"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&gt; For Tesla owners in the U.S., their 2023 Model Ys are worth 42% less than what they paid two years ago&lt;p&gt;I want to suggest that there are recent reasons why Tesla, as a brand, has &lt;i&gt;specifically&lt;/i&gt; gotten a bit less popular that are unrelated to the entire EV category. (It's Elon. He's the reason.)&lt;p&gt;That said, to the extent the result holds true for the entire category, I'd suspect it's because EVs are still fairly immature. It's like "resale value of desktop PCs falling rapidly" back in the 90s, when the field was advancing quickly enough that buying used was genuinely a bad idea.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 17 Oct 2025 16:21:23 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45618525</link><dc:creator>kemayo</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45618525</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45618525</guid></item><item><title>New comment by nostrademons in "EVs are depreciating faster than gas-powered cars"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Causality could be reversed here.  In markets where technology advances quickly and prices drop, there is very little market for used goods, because why would you buy a 4-year-old whatever when you can get a new one that's twice as good for half the price?  You see this in computers, smartphones, TVs, and solar panels (outside of the U.S, where prices are kept artificially high by tariffs).  People almost never buy used because there's no reason to.  You can just buy new, for the same or lower price, and get something way better.&lt;p&gt;Instead of threatening to derail the EV transition, lack of resale value might be &lt;i&gt;evidence of&lt;/i&gt; the EV transition, particularly when coupled with quickly growing overall sales of EVs globally.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 17 Oct 2025 16:15:35 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45618442</link><dc:creator>nostrademons</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45618442</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45618442</guid></item><item><title>New comment by xena in "Ask HN: How to stop an AWS bot sending 2B requests/month?"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Main author of Anubis here. Have CloudFlare return a HTTP 200 response instead of a rejection at non-200. That makes the bots stop hammering until they get a 200 response.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 17 Oct 2025 16:12:50 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45618404</link><dc:creator>xena</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45618404</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45618404</guid></item><item><title>New comment by chaps in "You did no fact checking, and I must scream"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I've done a fair amount of data-intensive fact checking for journalism articles and have had fact checking done on my own data-intensive reporting.&lt;p&gt;Couple things:&lt;p&gt;1. Fact checkers are not paid enough to do what they do. They're usually freelancers and they're usually financially struggling. The dynamics of that are difficult to say the least.&lt;p&gt;2. Editors change things last minute without informing the journalist whose name the piece is in. It's really not fun to receive threats of lawsuit from a powerful government agency because your editor added something that you never would have added. Once told an editor in-writing three times not to add something and he did it right before publishing.&lt;p&gt;It sucks being a journalist. Donate to your local investigative newsroom.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 17 Oct 2025 15:24:00 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45617829</link><dc:creator>chaps</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45617829</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45617829</guid></item><item><title>New comment by white-moss in "Ruby core team takes ownership of RubyGems and Bundler"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Really appreciate Matz stepping up to take on this difficult situation.
As a Japanese developer, I’ve been worried about the direction things were going, so it’s reassuring to see this.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 17 Oct 2025 12:52:41 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45616177</link><dc:creator>white-moss</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45616177</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45616177</guid></item><item><title>New comment by sebiw in "Ruby core team takes ownership of RubyGems and Bundler"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I think this is the right move. Thank you to Ruby Core and Matz for stepping up and providing stability to the language and community as a whole.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 17 Oct 2025 12:21:30 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45615909</link><dc:creator>sebiw</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45615909</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45615909</guid></item><item><title>New comment by rightbyte in "Migrating from AWS to Hetzner"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;What is old is new again.&lt;p&gt;My employer is so conservative and slow that they are forerunning this Local Cloud Edge Our Basement thing by just not doing anything.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 17 Oct 2025 12:21:18 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45615906</link><dc:creator>rightbyte</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45615906</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45615906</guid></item><item><title>New comment by adamcharnock in "Migrating from AWS to Hetzner"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I cannot overstate the performance improvement of deploying onto bare metal. We typically see a doubling of performance, as well as extremely predictable baseline performance.&lt;p&gt;This is down to several things:&lt;p&gt;- Latency - having your own local network, rather than sharing some larger datacenter network fabric, gives around of order of magnitude reduced latency&lt;p&gt;- Caches – right-sizing a deployment for the underlying hardware, and so actually allowing a modern CPU to do its job, makes a huge difference&lt;p&gt;- Disk IO – Dedicated NVMe access is _fast_.&lt;p&gt;And with it comes a whole bunch of other benefits:&lt;p&gt;- Auto-scalers becomes less important, partly because you have 10x the hardware for the same price, partly because everything runs 2x the speed anyway, and partly because you have a fixed pool of hardware. This makes the whole system more stable and easier to reason about.&lt;p&gt;- No more sweating the S3 costs. Put a 15TB NVMe drive in each server and run your own MinIO/Garage cluster (alongside your other workloads). We're doing about 20GiB/s sustained on a 10 node cluster, 50k API calls per second (on S3 that is $20-$250 _per second_ on API calls!).&lt;p&gt;- You get the same bill every month.&lt;p&gt;- UPDATE: more benefits - cheap fast storage, run huge Postgresql instances at minimal cost, less engineering time spend working around hardware limitations and cloud vagaries.&lt;p&gt;And, if chose to invest in the above, it all costs 10x less than AWS.&lt;p&gt;Pitch: If you don't want to do this yourself, then we'll do it for you for half the price of AWS (and we'll be your DevOps team too):&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://lithus.eu" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://lithus.eu&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;Email: adam@ above domain&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 17 Oct 2025 12:16:07 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45615867</link><dc:creator>adamcharnock</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45615867</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45615867</guid></item><item><title>New comment by lisperforlife in "Migrating from AWS to Hetzner"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I think you can get much farther with dedicated servers. I run a couple of nodes on Hetzner. The performance you get from a dedicated machine even if it is a 3 year old machine that you can get on server auction is absolutely bonkers and cannot be compared to VMs. The thing is that most of the server hardware is focused towards high core count, low clock speed processors that optimize for I/O rather than compute. It is overprovisioned by all cloud providers. Even the I/O part of  the disk is crazy. It uses all sorts of shenanigans to get a drive that sitting on a NAS and emulating a local disk. Most startups do not need the hyper virtualized, NAS based drive. You can go much farther and much more cost-effectively with dedicated server rentals from Hetzner. I would love to know if they are any north-american (particularly canadian) companies that can compete with price and  the quality of service like Hetzner. I know  of OVH but I would love to know others in the same space.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 17 Oct 2025 10:34:50 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45615090</link><dc:creator>lisperforlife</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45615090</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45615090</guid></item><item><title>New comment by swiftcoder in "Ask HN: How to stop an AWS bot sending 2B requests/month?"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Making the obviously-abusive bot prohibitively expensive is one way to go, if you control the terminating server.&lt;p&gt;gzip bomb is good if the bot happens to be vulnerable, but even just slowing down their connection rate is often sufficient - waiting just 10 seconds before responding with your 404 is going to consume ~7,000 ports on their box, which should be enough to crash most linux processes (nginx + mod-http-echo is a really easy way to set this up)&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 17 Oct 2025 06:59:35 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45614001</link><dc:creator>swiftcoder</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45614001</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45614001</guid></item><item><title>New comment by omcnoe in "Meow.camera"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;These feeders are part of a stray cat control program in China, aiming to both feed &amp; neuter stray cat populations there.&lt;p&gt;There have been some distasteful incidents of online groups organizing to try and harm/kill specific cats famous through this feeder program. China lacks animal welfare laws to protect these cats, it's not a crime. So people have taken to identifying these abusers and reporting them to their employer, university etc. Abusers have been fired and expelled over such cases. Governments overseas whose citizens participate in such online abuse groups need to be doing more. Membership in online animal abuse groups needs to be criminalized.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 17 Oct 2025 06:25:17 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45613829</link><dc:creator>omcnoe</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45613829</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45613829</guid></item><item><title>New comment by sib in "How I bypassed Amazon's Kindle web DRM"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I have more than 100 books that I &lt;i&gt;bought with actual money&lt;/i&gt; on Apple's iBooks (or whatever it was called back in 2010-2012). I no longer use an iPad and would like to be able to read them on my Kindle. Because of DRM, I can't. I'm all for supporting authors and the various editors, etc., but I feel like I've already done that in this case.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 17 Oct 2025 00:08:40 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45612120</link><dc:creator>sib</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45612120</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45612120</guid></item><item><title>New comment by dannyobrien in "How I bypassed Amazon's Kindle web DRM"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Fun fact: this is one of the few situations in the US where a prosecutor could claim that this is &lt;i&gt;criminal&lt;/i&gt; speech  (though I hope and trust they would not, and if it did it would get thrown out by any court respecting the First Amendment).&lt;p&gt;Not a civil issue, like libel or fraud, but the sort of talk that can get a policeman to come and drag you off to jail. If you've ever wondered why DRM is so roundly hated by engineers of a certain age, it's because not only it dumb makework that they are required to implement, not only is it extremely irritating to discover it interfering with your own computer, but if you &lt;i&gt;do&lt;/i&gt; effectively point out how dumb, irritating, and eminently circumventable it is, they made it against the law to even tell anyone.&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.eff.org/press/releases/licensing-scheme-fair-uses-and-other-speech-violates-first-amendment-eff-argues" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://www.eff.org/press/releases/licensing-scheme-fair-use...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 16 Oct 2025 23:26:42 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45611895</link><dc:creator>dannyobrien</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45611895</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45611895</guid></item></channel></rss>