<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>Hacker News: Best Comments</title><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/bestcomments</link><description>Hacker News RSS</description><docs>https://hnrss.org/</docs><generator>hnrss v2.1.1</generator><lastBuildDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 01:21:27 +0000</lastBuildDate><ns0:link href="https://hnrss.org/bestcomments" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item><title>New comment by dts in "Anthropic acquires Bun"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;A lot of people seem confused about this acquisition because they think of Bun as a node.js compatible bundler / runtime and just compare it to Deno / npm. But I think its a really smart move if you think of where Bun has been pushing into lately which is a kind of cloud-native self contained runtime (S3 API, SQL, streaming, etc). For an agent like Claude Code this trajectory is really interesting as you are creating a runtime where your agent can work inside of cloud services as fluently as it currently does with a local filesystem. Claude will be able to leverage these capabilities to extend its reach across the cloud and add more value in enterprise use cases&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 20:52:05 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46126685</link><dc:creator>dts</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46126685</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46126685</guid></item><item><title>New comment by stack_framer in "OpenAI declares 'code red' as Google catches up in AI race"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I can generate $20 billion in ARR this year too! I just need you to give me $100 billion and allow me to sell each of your dollars for 0.2 dollars.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 20:38:29 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46126517</link><dc:creator>stack_framer</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46126517</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46126517</guid></item><item><title>New comment by Jarred in "Anthropic acquires Bun"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I work on Bun.&lt;p&gt;Happy to answer any questions&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 20:28:51 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46126387</link><dc:creator>Jarred</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46126387</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46126387</guid></item><item><title>New comment by strickjb9 in "The Junior Hiring Crisis"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Adding to this: it's not just that the apprenticeship ladder is gone—it's that nobody wants to deal with juniors who spit out AI code they don't really understand.&lt;p&gt;In the past, a junior would write bad code and you'd work with them to make it better. Now I just assume they're taking my feedback and feeding it right back to the LLM. Ends up taking more of my time than if I'd done it myself. The whole mentorship thing breaks down when you're basically collaborating with a model through a proxy.&lt;p&gt;I think highly motivated juniors who actually want to learn are still valuable. But it's hard to get past "why bother mentoring when I could just use AI directly?"&lt;p&gt;I don't have answers here. Just thinking maybe we're not seeing the end of software engineering for those of us already in it—but the door might be closing for anyone trying to come up behind us.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 19:08:21 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46125216</link><dc:creator>strickjb9</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46125216</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46125216</guid></item><item><title>New comment by andrewl-hn in "Anthropic acquires Bun"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I’ll be honest, while I have my doubts about the match of interests and cohesion between an AI company and a JS runtime company I have to say this is the single best acquisition announcement blog post I’ve seen in 20 years or so.&lt;p&gt;Very direct, very plain and detailed. They cover all the bases about the why, the how, and what to expect. I really appreciate it.&lt;p&gt;Best of luck to the team and hopefully the new home will support them well.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 18:28:07 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46124566</link><dc:creator>andrewl-hn</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46124566</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46124566</guid></item><item><title>New comment by da_grift_shift in "Garry Tan claims Zoho will be out of business due to vibe coding"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;"NFTs show relatively small groups of tens of thousands of people can work together collectively for a common good"  - Garry Tan, 23 March 2022&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://x.com/garrytan/status/1506769562468958210" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://x.com/garrytan/status/1506769562468958210&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;"If you own an NFT..." you are an innovator among innovators. - Garry Tan, 30 September 2021 [quote tweet]&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://x.com/garrytan/status/1443460589049704450" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://x.com/garrytan/status/1443460589049704450&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;Web3 vs Earlier incarnations technology adoption curve [image tweet]&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://x.com/garrytan/status/1521530531568963584" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://x.com/garrytan/status/1521530531568963584&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;"airdrops going mainstream could truly upend some % of the centralized ad-based economy of Web2" - Garry Tan, 25 Dec 2021&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://x.com/garrytan/status/1474826162408808448" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://x.com/garrytan/status/1474826162408808448&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 13:49:16 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46121153</link><dc:creator>da_grift_shift</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46121153</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46121153</guid></item><item><title>New comment by messe in "Rootless Pings in Rust"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&gt; It turns out you can create a UDP socket with a protocol flag, which allows you to send the ping rootless&lt;p&gt;This is wrong, despite the Rust library in question's naming convention. You're not creating a UDP socket. You're creating an IP (AF_INET), datagram socket (SOCK_DGRAM), using protocol ICMP (IPPROTO_ICMP). The issue is that the rust library apparently conflates datagram and UDP, when they're not the same thing.&lt;p&gt;You can do the same in C, by calling socket(2) with the above arguments. It hinges on Linux allowing rootless pings from the GIDs in&lt;p&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;  $ sysctl net.ipv4.ping_group_range
  net.ipv4.ping_group_range = 999 59999
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
EDIT: s/ICMP4/ICMP/g&lt;p&gt;EDIT2: more spelling mistakes&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 09:33:12 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46119375</link><dc:creator>messe</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46119375</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46119375</guid></item><item><title>New comment by densh in "Apple Releases Open Weights Video Model"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&gt; As a blind person, AI has changed my life.&lt;p&gt;Something one doesn't see in news headlines. Happy to see this comment.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 08:44:08 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46119040</link><dc:creator>densh</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46119040</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46119040</guid></item><item><title>New comment by devinprater in "Apple Releases Open Weights Video Model"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Apple has a video understanding model too. I can't wait to find out what accessibility stuff they'll do with the models. As a blind person, AI has changed my life.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 08:34:44 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46118991</link><dc:creator>devinprater</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46118991</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46118991</guid></item><item><title>New comment by bcrosby95 in "What will enter the public domain in 2026?"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;The length of copyright is absurd.  Corporations have hijacked a concept that should exist on human timescales.&lt;p&gt;Ideally, a child could legally provide their own spin on IP they consumed by the time they reach adulthood.  But also, people need to make a living.&lt;p&gt;I actually think the original 14+14 year copyright is the right balance.  It gives people time to make their profits, but also guarantees the right of people to tweak and modify content they consume within their lifetime.  It's a balanced time scale rather than one that exists solely to serve mega corporations giving them the capability to hold cultural icons hostage.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 07:54:32 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46118773</link><dc:creator>bcrosby95</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46118773</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46118773</guid></item><item><title>New comment by imcrs in "Instagram chief orders staff back to the office five days a week in 2026"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;It's not about productivity at all. These same companies were commissioning studies during Covid that told their analysts "look how productive our employees are now that they are working from home!"&lt;p&gt;It's about crushing labor.&lt;p&gt;WFH forces employers to compete. It gives a lot of power to employees, because they can apply for far more roles, work fewer hours, moonlight for multiple companies, etc, apply for other jobs during work hours, etc. These companies know that white collar workers are not fungible. Their intellectual workers are genuinely very difficult to replace and produce a lot of value.&lt;p&gt;For talent that isn't fungible, it's RTO. For talent that is fungible, offshoring.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 05:32:25 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46117935</link><dc:creator>imcrs</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46117935</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46117935</guid></item><item><title>New comment by Arainach in "What will enter the public domain in 2026?"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;To avoid the advent calendar, this may be more useful:&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/2026_in_public_domain" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/2026_in_public_domain&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 03:50:51 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46117301</link><dc:creator>Arainach</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46117301</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46117301</guid></item><item><title>New comment by elAhmo in "John Giannandrea to retire from Apple"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Siri is probably among the products which had the most exposure to users (probably a billion+ users throughout iPhone's history) without capturing that opportunity to actually do anything meaningful with the huge user base it got for free.&lt;p&gt;A decade and a half is insane timeline in tech industry, and huge majority of users use Siri the same way today as 15 years ago, setting a timer or an alarm clock.&lt;p&gt;If they had 0 improvements over these 15 years the situation wouldn't be much different than today.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 23:03:22 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46114686</link><dc:creator>elAhmo</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46114686</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46114686</guid></item><item><title>New comment by embedding-shape in "Mozilla's latest quagmire"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Firefox was seriously a better browser, not just "implements standards better". It ran faster, it had tabs (wow!) and at one point it got Firebug which let you have a console INSIDE the browser that showed information you could print with `console.log`, I kid you not.&lt;p&gt;It was a better browser through and through, maybe because MS slept on IE or maybe not, but in the end it isn't revisionist to say they beat MS's proverbial posterior because the browser was better.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 22:31:35 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46114263</link><dc:creator>embedding-shape</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46114263</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46114263</guid></item><item><title>New comment by wosined in "India orders smartphone makers to preload state-owned cyber safety app"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Sounds so authoritarian. Luckily, in the UK you only have to scan your face and ID   to access cat photos.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 21:37:23 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46113588</link><dc:creator>wosined</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46113588</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46113588</guid></item><item><title>New comment by kkolybacz in "Instagram chief orders staff back to the office five days a week in 2026"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;"We're also offering the option to transfer from the MPK to SF office for those people whose commute would be the same or better with that change."&lt;p&gt;So wait, you'll be able to switch offices even though your team might be in the second one? 
What's the benefit of working remote from your team but next to random, noisy people?&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 21:28:03 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46113474</link><dc:creator>kkolybacz</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46113474</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46113474</guid></item><item><title>New comment by eutropia in "Instagram chief orders staff back to the office five days a week in 2026"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Instagram chief orders quiet layoffs to please investors in 2026&lt;p&gt;fixed that title for you&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 21:27:20 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46113466</link><dc:creator>eutropia</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46113466</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46113466</guid></item><item><title>New comment by garciasn in "How to Attend Meetings"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I agree with each and every single slide in this presentation; I do. I also know that in each and every company I have ever worked for, none of this is going to fly. Especially, "Attending meetings is a choice." Just like paying taxes is a choice; got it.&lt;p&gt;---&lt;p&gt;For decades, I have been asking for agendas; I have asked for clarification on what to do to prepare; I have even suggested that we have solid outcomes. None of which are followed nor what anyone else wants.&lt;p&gt;Even as a leader at organizations where I can enforce this on my team, it makes absolutely no difference. Hell, Google Calendar (we use Workspace at my current org) doesn't even have solid support for good meeting invite commentary. And, even if it did, 99.99999% of folks wouldn't read any of it anyway.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 21:22:55 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46113419</link><dc:creator>garciasn</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46113419</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46113419</guid></item><item><title>New comment by MonkeyClub in "India orders smartphone makers to preload state-owned cyber safety app"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&gt; I'm shocked&lt;p&gt;India is currently run by a nationalist regime headed by the so called "butcher of Gujarat"[1], there isn't much that would shock me wrt to that lot's totalitarian tendencies.&lt;p&gt;[1] &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Public_image_of_Narendra_Modi" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Public_image_of_Narendra_Modi&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 21:05:28 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46113202</link><dc:creator>MonkeyClub</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46113202</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46113202</guid></item><item><title>New comment by rishabhaiover in "India orders smartphone makers to preload state-owned cyber safety app"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I'm shocked by people and state using the crutch of cyber crime or scams to push a totalitarian solution to a problem that is better solved by improved education and targeted campaigns against common security pitfalls.&lt;p&gt;I abhor any decision that robs even a grain of my individual freedom.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 18:51:51 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46111364</link><dc:creator>rishabhaiover</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46111364</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46111364</guid></item><item><title>New comment by zug_zug in "DeepSeek-v3.2: Pushing the frontier of open large language models [pdf]"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Well props to them for continuing to improve, winning on cost-effectiveness, and continuing to publicly share their improvements. Hard not to root for them as a force to prevent an AI corporate monopoly/duopoly.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 18:36:56 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46111149</link><dc:creator>zug_zug</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46111149</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46111149</guid></item><item><title>New comment by glenstein in "The Penicillin Myth"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;In my opinion, we're possessed by a cultural epidemic of think pieces doing rich and nuanced science history, but wrongly framed in the form of correcting "myths" that, in their substance amount to quibblings over narrative emphasis. It's easy to get taken in by the framing because it truly is enlightening, and the argument goes down so smooth because its embedded in a rich, curious, and fascinating scientific history that otherwise embodies best practices I would happily celebrate.&lt;p&gt;But the key details about the story of penicillin are that a moldy plate showed bacteria-free clearing, Fleming saw it, isolated the mold, proved its germ-killing filtrate and published the finding, which is the heart of the story and which is not a myth.&lt;p&gt;I'm sure it's true enough that St Mary's windows were usually kept shut to keep pathogens in and contaminants out, that London's August 1928 cold snap would have slowed staph growth, that Fleming's first notes Or 8 weeks later than the actual event, and that a modern plate seeded with bacteria first will not produce the celebrated halo unless the mold is given a head start. The article makes much of the fact that today’s researchers cannot reproduce the famous halo if they add staph first, yet that difficulty rebuts a sequence Fleming never claimed to have used.&lt;p&gt;These points are significant, even fascinating, yet the article inflates them into a strobe-lit "MYTH" banner, turning normal human imprecision about times and temperatures into evidence of wholesale fiction, which abuses the ordinary friction of any retrospective account and punishes the story for the very human messiness that makes it instructive.&lt;p&gt;The window quibble, the incubator gap, and the replication protocol do not touch the central, uncontested fact that chance contamination plus observational curiosity gave medicine its first antibiotic.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 18:16:48 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46110840</link><dc:creator>glenstein</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46110840</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46110840</guid></item><item><title>New comment by keepamovin in "Cartographers have been hiding illustrations inside Switzerland’s maps (2020)"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;When I was a cartographer in the 1500s I used to hide dragons, sea serpents and the occasional heretical inscription in the blank bits, because at least back then the Holy Roman Emperor had the decency to pretend he didn’t notice as long as the tax broders were correct.&lt;p&gt;Now look at us: the Swiss federal cartographers, salaried, pensioned, triple-proofread, still cannot resist smuggling a naked woman and a cheeky marmot into the official topography. And the admisntration? They wait until the perpetrator has safely retired on full index-linked benefits, then solemnly announce the marmot will be "removed in the next revision cycle, pending environmental-impact assessment of the pixel."&lt;p&gt;This is what passes for rebellion inside the European regulatory state: a rodent drawn at 1:25 000 scale that offends precisely no one and will be erased by a civil servant who wasn’t even born when it was sketched. Truly the revolutionary spirit of our continent has been reduced to a change-request ticket with fourteen mandatory approvers and a carbon-copy to Bern.&lt;p&gt;I fill in another compliance form and weep for the age when men risked the stake for a badly drawn leviathan.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 17:51:44 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46110519</link><dc:creator>keepamovin</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46110519</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46110519</guid></item><item><title>New comment by RoddaWallPro in "Google, Nvidia, and OpenAI"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;"advertising would make ChatGPT a better product."&lt;p&gt;And with that, I will never read anything this guy writes again :)&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 16:58:57 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46109774</link><dc:creator>RoddaWallPro</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46109774</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46109774</guid></item><item><title>New comment by LanceH in "Games using anti-cheats and their compatibility with GNU/Linux or Wine/Proton"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Amongst the discussion of rootkits and anti-cheat, I would like to add that part of the reason it is necessary is caused by the game companies that took away the standard method of playing multiplayer -- players running their own servers.&lt;p&gt;It used to be pretty easy to just ban people from playing, now we're 100% reliant on their ability to do it.  So we have anti-cheat which roots our computer, and still doesn't 100% solve the problem.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 15:01:39 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46108253</link><dc:creator>LanceH</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46108253</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46108253</guid></item><item><title>New comment by wavemode in "Why xor eax, eax?"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&gt; CEO walking up behind my desk and pointing out that I'd done MOV AX, 0 when I could have done XOR AX, AX&lt;p&gt;Now that's what I call micromanagement.&lt;p&gt;(sorry couldn't resist)&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 14:51:06 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46108116</link><dc:creator>wavemode</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46108116</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46108116</guid></item><item><title>New comment by BrenBarn in "It’s been a very hard year"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;In contrast to others, I just want to say that I applaud the decision to take a moral stance against AI, and I wish more people would do that.  Saying "well you have to follow the market" is such a cravenly amoral perspective.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 07:56:28 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46104696</link><dc:creator>BrenBarn</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46104696</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46104696</guid></item><item><title>New comment by liendolucas in "Google Antigravity just deleted the contents of whole drive"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I love how a number crunching program can be deeply humanly "horrorized" and "sorry" for wiping out a drive. Those are still feelings reserved only for real human beings, and not computer programs emitting garbage. This is vibe insulting to anyone that don't understand how "AI" works.&lt;p&gt;I'm sorry for the person who lost their stuff but this is a reminder that in 2025 you STILL need to know what you are doing and if you don't then put your hands away from the keyboard if you think you can lose valuable data.&lt;p&gt;You simply don't vibe command a computer.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 07:33:43 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46104563</link><dc:creator>liendolucas</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46104563</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46104563</guid></item><item><title>New comment by Swizec in "It’s been a very hard year"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I’ve seen Picallilli’s stuff around and it looks extremely solid. But you can’t beat the market. You either have what they want to buy, or you don’t.&lt;p&gt;&gt; Landing projects for Set Studio has been extremely difficult, especially as we won’t work on product marketing for AI stuff, from a moral standpoint, but the vast majority of enquiries have been for exactly that&lt;p&gt;The market is speaking. Long-term you’ll find out who’s wrong, but the market can usually stay irrational for much longer than you can stay in business.&lt;p&gt;I think everyone in the programming education business is feeling the struggle right now. In my opinion this business died 2 years ago – &lt;a href="https://swizec.com/blog/the-programming-tutorial-seo-industry-is-dead/" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://swizec.com/blog/the-programming-tutorial-seo-industr...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 06:08:29 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46104058</link><dc:creator>Swizec</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46104058</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46104058</guid></item><item><title>New comment by nico in "Writing a good Claude.md"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&gt; Claude often ignores CLAUDE.md&lt;p&gt;&gt; The more information you have in the file that's not universally applicable to the tasks you have it working on, the more likely it is that Claude will ignore your instructions in the file&lt;p&gt;Claude.md files can get pretty long, and many times Claude Code just stops following a lot of the directions specified in the file&lt;p&gt;A friend of mine tells Claude to always address him as “Mr Tinkleberry”, he says he can tell Claude is not paying attention to the instructions on Claude.md, when Claude stops calling him “Mr Tinkleberry” consistently&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 00:35:47 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46102048</link><dc:creator>nico</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46102048</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46102048</guid></item></channel></rss>