<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>Hacker News: Best Comments</title><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/bestcomments</link><description>Hacker News RSS</description><docs>https://hnrss.org/</docs><generator>hnrss v2.1.1</generator><lastBuildDate>Sun, 26 Oct 2025 00:10:59 +0000</lastBuildDate><ns0:link href="https://hnrss.org/bestcomments" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item><title>New comment by diegof79 in "React vs. Backbone in 2025"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I worked with Backbone, Angular 1, Ember, and then React.&lt;p&gt;The article overlooks the problems that made React popular:&lt;p&gt;- Composition: Composing components is easier and more efficient in React. Backbone’s render function assumes "this.$el" is mounted and available in the DOM. That makes composition difficult: you cannot simply nest one component inside another without managing the DOM lifecycle of subcomponents. You don’t need 1.000 components to feel the pain.&lt;p&gt;- Event handling: You can’t pass an event handler as a string, so the events object must be paired with the selector to locate the element. Any structural changes require updating selectors or managing unique IDs.&lt;p&gt;- State management: Re-rendering components when state changes becomes messy in Backbone fairly quickly. That mess is why Angular 1 gained popularity. React simplifies this further by enforcing a one-directional state flow.&lt;p&gt;- Efficient DOM updates: Even if you implement composition and state management ad hoc, you still must update the DOM efficiently to avoid layout thrashing and related issues. React isn’t immune, but these problems are typically easier to handle.&lt;p&gt;- Other features: Implementing useful capabilities from scratch, like lazy loading parts of components (for example, suspense) or building hybrid apps with server-side rendering, requires significant work.&lt;p&gt;I'll argue that nowadays, if you want to use vanilla JS with templating support, lit-html (not the full framework, just the template part) is a much better choice than Backbone.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 25 Oct 2025 15:29:26 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45704636</link><dc:creator>diegof79</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45704636</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45704636</guid></item><item><title>New comment by picardo in "React vs. Backbone in 2025"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&gt; For massive apps with 1,000 components on the same page, maybe React's complexity is justified. But what the other 99% of apps?&lt;p&gt;The number of components is not the only yardstick of complexity. Most of the complexity in building a UI comes from state management and how state changes are propagated across the store and the UI.&lt;p&gt;I worked with Backbone for many years, and I can distinctly recall the hours of frustration I had debugging a UI because it was freezing due to cascading state changes. That was because we were using Backbone Store, which had bidirectional data flow, and when one updated the store, it would trigger a change to the UI, which would change the state store, which would change the UI, etc.&lt;p&gt;You could argue that the real innovation of React was "unidirectional data flow," but React team made Flux architecture central to the framework, making it easier to adopt good practices, whereas Backbone remained store agnostic and even encouraged Backbone Store which used the observer pattern for many years. I think you should choose a framework that allows you to fall into the Pit of Success, and React was that framework at the time, and for my money, it still is.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 25 Oct 2025 12:14:11 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45703288</link><dc:creator>picardo</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45703288</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45703288</guid></item><item><title>New comment by ceronman in "Meet the real screen addicts: the elderly"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;The elderly, the kids, the teenagers, the adults. Screen addiction is a pandemic. The biggest one humanity has ever seen.&lt;p&gt;The richest, most powerful organizations are spending billions every month to make it more addictive, to reach more people.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 25 Oct 2025 07:51:38 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45702078</link><dc:creator>ceronman</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45702078</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45702078</guid></item><item><title>New comment by sevg in "Key IOCs for Pegasus and Predator Spyware Removed with iOS 26 Update"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;The article doesn’t define “IOC”, so if (like me) you didn’t know the abbreviation: Indicators Of Compromise.&lt;p&gt;(They actually do use the expanded form in the article, just without some parentheses afterwards on the first usage of the phrase.)&lt;p&gt;Maybe everyone but me knows the abbreviation, but in case it helps _someone_ out there!&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 25 Oct 2025 05:55:02 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45701621</link><dc:creator>sevg</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45701621</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45701621</guid></item><item><title>New comment by Neywiny in "Study: MRI contrast agent causes harmful metal buildup in some patients"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;This is very interesting to see on here. My mother was the dissenting vote on an FDA panel on this. There are articles about it. I'll copy her words (as reported by something but seems legit)&lt;p&gt;&gt; She said that the FDA's plan doesn't go far enough.&lt;p&gt;&gt; "It's hard to dismiss an anecdotal report when you are the anecdote. When a patient is finally tested and found to have gadolinium retention, there's no FDA-approved antidote. So what does the patient do?"&lt;p&gt;And I want to reiterate that she was "the" no not "a" no. I don't know if her vote alone is what's caused more research into this. But it's probably the thing I brag about her the most. Even though everybody else said it was fine or abstained, she stood strong. If you look up the articles from the time of the panel (2017) you'll see a lot of articles about this panel and how she was the sole no vote. Included in that was a public post from Chuck Norris praising her. He was going to come out to meet us but I think it was a bad Texas hurricane season so that fell through&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 24 Oct 2025 22:37:58 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45699820</link><dc:creator>Neywiny</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45699820</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45699820</guid></item><item><title>New comment by bsimpson in "The Swift SDK for Android"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;The most important question for every cross platform framework is what happens to the UI?&lt;p&gt;Adobe products (both the Creative Suite, and their Flex Builder environment for Flash app) had their own design system that felt foreign on every platform it shipped on.  If you wanted something that felt native, you had to reimplement e.g. Apple Aqua in Flash yourself.&lt;p&gt;Flutter goes out of its way to do that work for you, aiming for a "Cupertino" theme that looks-and-feels pixel-perfect on iOS.&lt;p&gt;React Native tries to delegate to platform primitives for complex widgets, so scroll views still feel like Apple's when on Apple's platform.&lt;p&gt;Just about every top-level comment here is talking about that in one way or another; yet the blog post doesn't mention it at all.&lt;p&gt;It's possible that Apple/Swift's mindshare among developers will lead to a significant number of apps shipping the Swift version for Android even if it means using Apple's UI, simply because they can't be bothered to make something bespoke for Android.  Then again, Apple takes so much pride in its design language that it might not be willing to implement anything that feels good on a platform they don't own.  If they were to ship an API-compatible widget toolkit, it might e.g. use intentionally bad spring physics to remind you you aren't on an iPhone.&lt;p&gt;I wonder how big the community part of this is.  Is this an open source project of non-Apple people who are trying to break Apple's platform out of its walled garden?  Is a lot of it funded by Apple?  Ultimately, that's going to shape a lot of how this plays out.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 24 Oct 2025 22:08:17 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45699600</link><dc:creator>bsimpson</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45699600</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45699600</guid></item><item><title>New comment by teo_zero in "First convex polyhedron found that can't pass through itself"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Misleading title. Other shapes have been well known for years, like a sphere. The novelty here is the first &lt;i&gt;polyhedron&lt;/i&gt; that can't pass through itself.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 24 Oct 2025 22:01:20 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45699544</link><dc:creator>teo_zero</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45699544</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45699544</guid></item><item><title>New comment by WillAdams in "Public Montessori programs strengthen learning outcomes at lower costs: study"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;My children attended Montessori schools, and it really is a wonderful system.&lt;p&gt;I would really like to see an extension of this learning method up through high school --- the closest thing I'm aware of was a school I attended in Mississippi for a couple of years --- classes were divided between academic and social, social classes (homeroom, phys ed, social studies, &amp;c.) were attended at one's age, while academic classes (reading, math, science, geography, history, &amp;c.) were by ability (with a limit on no more than 4 grades ahead up to 8th grade) --- after 8th grade that was removed and students were allowed to take any classes.&lt;p&gt;Some of the faculty were accredited as faculty at a local college, and where warranted, either professors travelled from there to the school, or students travelled to the college for classes --- it wasn't uncommon for students to graduate high school and simultaneously be awarded a college degree.&lt;p&gt;Apparently, the system was deemed unfair because it accorded a benefit to the students who were able to take advantage of it, with no commensurate compensation for those who were not, so the Miss. State Supreme Court dismantled it.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 24 Oct 2025 18:57:30 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45697940</link><dc:creator>WillAdams</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45697940</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45697940</guid></item><item><title>New comment by brandall10 in "'Attention is all you need' coauthor says he's 'sick' of transformers"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Attention is all he needs.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 24 Oct 2025 17:36:37 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45697059</link><dc:creator>brandall10</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45697059</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45697059</guid></item><item><title>New comment by dekhn in "'Attention is all you need' coauthor says he's 'sick' of transformers"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;The way I look at transformers is: they have been one of the most fertile inventions in recent history.  Originally released in 2017, in the subsequent 8 years they completely transformed (heh) multiple fields, and at least partially led to one Nobel prize.&lt;p&gt;realistically, I think the valuable idea is probabilistic graphical models- of which transformers is an example- combining probability with sequences, or with trees and graphs- is likely to continue to be a valuable area for research exploration for the foreseeable future.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 24 Oct 2025 17:11:58 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45696753</link><dc:creator>dekhn</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45696753</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45696753</guid></item><item><title>New comment by riotnrrd in "Counter-Strike's player economy is in a freefall"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I used to work at Valve -- on the CS:GO team, no less -- although I left nearly a decade ago.  I don't know what prompted this change but I have some suspicions.  Even when I was there and the loot box system was new to CS:GO, there were concerns that a lot of trading was happening outside of the marketplace. The trading happened elsewhere because you can't have more than $300 in your Steam wallet (more than this would trigger some banking regulations that Valve wanted to avoid), so anything more valuable than that had to happen on 3rd party sites.&lt;p&gt;We didn't want this for three reasons: we'd lose out on the marketplace cut (10% of all sales I think?); we didn't want people grinding the game to earn money from rare drops; and finally because 3rd party trading ended up creating a lot of scams and therefore angry players.&lt;p&gt;At the time, we didn't see any way around it: we couldn't prevent people "gifting" items to each other, and despite omniscience and omnipotence in the game and Marketplace, we weren't confident that we could rejigger the drop rates and rarities to lower the maximum perceived value of the fanciest knife to be under the $300 limit.&lt;p&gt;I suspect that the CS:GO team finally decided to do something about it and chose this.  If the team is anything like I left it, they probably modeled this extensively (we had data on nearly every game ever played in CS:GO and complete Marketplace data), and discussed the change with the TF2 and DOTA teams, who also have to deal with this, and decided that the short-term fury of a small fraction of the playerbase was worth it. I wonder if TF2 and DOTA are having similar problems and, if so, whether this change will be rolled out for those games, too.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 24 Oct 2025 16:52:16 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45696488</link><dc:creator>riotnrrd</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45696488</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45696488</guid></item><item><title>New comment by bjackman in "Asahi Linux Still Working on Apple M3 Support, M1n1 Bootloader Going Rust"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;The actual update: &lt;a href="https://asahilinux.org/2025/10/progress-report-6-17/" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://asahilinux.org/2025/10/progress-report-6-17/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 24 Oct 2025 16:09:15 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45696042</link><dc:creator>bjackman</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45696042</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45696042</guid></item><item><title>New comment by agentcoops in "Counter-Strike's player economy is in a freefall"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I waded through some Tik Tok comment threads on this change and it was so eye-opening: there are a shocking number of people without disposable income who were seriously investing in CS items, thinking it was a retirement portfolio. I fear the crypto era has lead to even further diminished financial literacy at large… Blessed be compound interest and financial regulation.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 24 Oct 2025 14:54:59 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45695284</link><dc:creator>agentcoops</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45695284</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45695284</guid></item><item><title>New comment by JohnMakin in "Poker fraud used X-ray tables, high-tech glasses and NBA players"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;“just play better poker” like that’s an easy thing to do in a game of chance and incomplete information, with variance having years or decades long tails. not to mention it’s an unsolved game, so “better” poker doesn’t even really have a set definition and depends on tons of variables. and they literally knew what hole cards were coming - that’s vastly more of an edge than playing “better poker” than someone.&lt;p&gt;Besides the fact they were often targeting pros - this was reported on and known by LA area pros for at least two years now. why the FBI decided to act now is weird to me. I can’t stress enough that in the pro scene this was common knowledge. years old podcast clips are coming up talking about it.&lt;p&gt;source: &lt;a href="https://sports.yahoo.com/nba/breaking-news/article/professional-gambler-matthew-berkey-called-out-rigged-chauncey-billups-poker-game-2-years-before-coachs-arrest-184422377.html" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://sports.yahoo.com/nba/breaking-news/article/professio...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 24 Oct 2025 13:39:56 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45694521</link><dc:creator>JohnMakin</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45694521</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45694521</guid></item><item><title>New comment by optionalsquid in "Typst 0.14"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;There's usually some confusion about this, so to clarify in advance:&lt;p&gt;- The Typst online editor is proprietary: &lt;a href="https://typst.app" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://typst.app&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;- The Typst compiler/CLI is open source: &lt;a href="https://github.com/typst/typst" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://github.com/typst/typst&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;I hear that the online editor is quite good, but personally I've only ever used the CLI.&lt;p&gt;I originally picked up Typst as yet another replacement for PowerPoint (replacing my use of Marp), but have since used it for a poster and some minor text documents. And I've been very happy the results. I know that a lot of people love using LaTeX for that kind of thing, and with good reasons, but I always forgot most of the details between my (occasional) use of LaTeX, while I've found Typst to be very easy to return to&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 24 Oct 2025 13:20:44 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45694338</link><dc:creator>optionalsquid</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45694338</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45694338</guid></item><item><title>New comment by upofadown in "Debian Technical Committee overrides systemd change"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;This part seems fairly editorial:&lt;p&gt;&gt;Debian Policy still cites the FHS, even though the FHS has gone unmaintained for more than a decade.&lt;p&gt;What ongoing maintenance would a file system standard require? A successful standard of that type would have to remain static unless there was a serious issue to address. Regular changes are what the standard was intended to combat in the first place.&lt;p&gt;&gt;The specification was not so much finished as abandoned after FHS 3.0 was released...&lt;p&gt;OK.&lt;p&gt;&gt;...though there is a slow-moving effort to revive and revise the standard as FHS 4.0, it has not yet produced any results.&lt;p&gt;So it is not abandoned then. A slow moving process is exactly what you would want for the maintenance of a file system standard.&lt;p&gt;&gt;Meanwhile, in the absence of a current standard, systemd has spun off its file-hierarchy documentation to the Linux Userspace API (UAPI) Group as a specification. LWN covered that development in August, related to Fedora's search for an FHS successor.&lt;p&gt;Ah. Systemd/Fedora want a standard that they can directly control without interference from others.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 24 Oct 2025 12:14:02 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45693843</link><dc:creator>upofadown</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45693843</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45693843</guid></item><item><title>New comment by Bengalilol in "Counter-Strike's player economy is in a freefall"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Any market maker, such as Valve, is free to establish the rules of its own "reality".&lt;p&gt;I understand your analysis, and I certainly failed to mention that point, but making the overall value less attractive to speculators is not evidence of being "rotten to the core".&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 24 Oct 2025 07:35:14 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45691930</link><dc:creator>Bengalilol</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45691930</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45691930</guid></item><item><title>New comment by Bengalilol in "Counter-Strike's player economy is in a freefall"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I bet this is an on-purpose move by Valve, and I view this as a sane action. [1]&lt;p&gt;Having a game where some players only play in order to win money is, for sure, a no go. If the game is fun, then players will keep on playing it. It may also keep some money thirsty (sometimes very toxic) people at the gates.&lt;p&gt;It is also smoothing players' frustration and shopping-spree habits in order to obtain a rare item. If you have the ability to trade N rare items for another rare item then you quite surely may obtain any cosmetic item you want for a much lower investment (less boxes to open). The 'grey market' will adapt to this new value.&lt;p&gt;That's also a lesson on how a closed economy (and open ones too, to some extent) can collapse based on a single actor controlling the rules. That's fair to learn.&lt;p&gt;[1] EDIT: and probably a preemptive protection for any future legal threat (as some countries tend to prohibit money gambling in games)&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 24 Oct 2025 07:21:22 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45691834</link><dc:creator>Bengalilol</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45691834</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45691834</guid></item><item><title>New comment by barrell in "Roc Camera"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I also used to be really (really really) into photography. Personally, I’ve stopped taking pictures because of the stigma around a camera.&lt;p&gt;Everyone, me more than most, doesn’t want their picture taken, or to be in the background of other photos. When someone can take thousands of pictures an hour, and upload them all to some social media site to be permanently stored… idk it’s shifted from a way to capture a moment to feeling like you’re being survieled.&lt;p&gt;A bit hyperbolic, but it’s the best way to describe what I’m feeling&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 24 Oct 2025 06:49:25 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45691630</link><dc:creator>barrell</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45691630</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45691630</guid></item><item><title>New comment by jeswin in "Roc Camera"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I am actually willing to support DIY camera efforts, but if you're semi-serious about taking pictures, this just wouldn't work. First, Raspberry Pi (I'm guessing this is a CM4/CM5) is a disaster for a camera board. Nobody wants a 20s boot every time you want to take a picture, cameras need to be near instantaneous. And you can't keep it on either, because the RPi can't really sleep. There are boards that can actually sleep, but with fewer sensor options.&lt;p&gt;Now moving on to the sensor (IMX 519 - Arducam?) - it's tinier than the tiniest sensor found on phones. If you really want to have decent image quality, you should look at Will Whang's OneInchEye and Four-thirds eye (&lt;a href="https://www.willwhang.dev/" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://www.willwhang.dev/&lt;/a&gt;). 4/3 Eye uses IMX294 which is currently the only large sensor which has Linux support (I think he upstreamed it) and MIPI. All the other larger sensors use interfaces like SLVS which are impossible to connect to.&lt;p&gt;If anyone's going to attempt a serious camera, they need to do two things. Use at least a 1 inch sensor, and a board which can actually sleep (which means it can't be the RPi). This would mean a bunch of difficult work, such as drivers to get these sensors to work with those boards. The Alice Camera  (&lt;a href="https://www.alice.camera/" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://www.alice.camera/&lt;/a&gt;) is a better attempt and probably uses the IMX294 as well. The most impressive attempt however is Wenting Zhang's Sitina S1 - (&lt;a href="https://rangefinderforum.com/threads/diy-full-frame-digital-camera-released-on-github.4817105" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://rangefinderforum.com/threads/diy-full-frame-digital-...&lt;/a&gt;). He used a full frame Kodak CCD Sensor.&lt;p&gt;There is a market for a well made camera like the Fuji X-Half. It doesn't need to have a lot of features, just needs to have ergonomics and take decent pictures. Stuff like proofs are secondary to what actually matters - first it needs to take good pictures, which the IMX 519 is going to struggle with.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 24 Oct 2025 06:13:30 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45691385</link><dc:creator>jeswin</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45691385</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45691385</guid></item><item><title>New comment by peteforde in "Roc Camera"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I used to be really (really really) into photography. I respect anyone working hard on a physical product, but this misses the mark on every front I can think of.&lt;p&gt;The real issue that photographers grapple with, emotionally and financially, is that pictures have become so thoroughly commodified that nobody assigns them cultural value anymore. They are the thumbnail you see before the short video clip starts playing.&lt;p&gt;Nobody has ever walked past a photograph because they can't inspect its digital authenticity hash. This is especially funny to me because I used to struggle with the fact that people looking at your work don't know or care what kind of camera or process was involved. They don't know if I spent two hours zoomed in removing microscopic dust particles from the scanning process after a long hike to get a single shot at 5:30am, or if it was just the 32nd of 122 shots taken in a burst by someone holding up an iPad Pro Max at a U2 concert.&lt;p&gt;This all made me sad for a long time, but I ultimately came to terms with the fact that my own incentives were perverse; I was seeking the external gratification of getting likes just like everyone else. If you can get back to a place where you're taking photographs or making music or doing 5 minute daily synth drills for your own happiness with no expectation of external validity, you will be far happier taking that $399 and buying a Mamiya C330.&lt;p&gt;This video is about music, but it's also about everything worth doing for the right reasons. &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=NvQF4YIvxwE" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=NvQF4YIvxwE&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 24 Oct 2025 05:26:02 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45691069</link><dc:creator>peteforde</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45691069</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45691069</guid></item><item><title>New comment by uvaursi in "Counter-Strike's player economy is in a freefall"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Remember back in the day when we just downloaded skin packs from some random Geocities website with obnoxious red text on black background and after going through the install.txt written in broken English/Italian, lo and behold your AK47 now had a proper arctic camo skin and it was so much cooler?&lt;p&gt;What was wrong with that? Doesn’t gaben have enough money for his super yachts and sword collections?&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 24 Oct 2025 05:21:40 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45691042</link><dc:creator>uvaursi</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45691042</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45691042</guid></item><item><title>New comment by somenameforme in "Apple loses UK App Store monopoly case, penalty might near $2B"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I find headlines like this much more appropriate when placed in terms of days of revenue: "Apple loses UK App Store monopoly case, penalty might near 2 days of revenue!"&lt;p&gt;For somebody that makes the median income, of about $50k, this is a fine of $273 for years of largescale systematic abusive behavior, done for profit.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 24 Oct 2025 05:00:31 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45690937</link><dc:creator>somenameforme</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45690937</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45690937</guid></item><item><title>New comment by corysama in "Computer science courses that don't exist, but should (2015)"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&gt; CSCI 3300: Classical Software Studies&lt;p&gt;Alan Kay, my favorite curmudgeon, spent decades trying to remind us we keep reinventing concepts that were worked out in the late 70s and he’s disappointed we’ve been running in circles ever since. He’s still disappointed because very few programmers are ever introduced to the history of computer science in the way that artists study the history of art or philosophers the history of philosophy.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 24 Oct 2025 03:14:16 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45690371</link><dc:creator>corysama</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45690371</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45690371</guid></item><item><title>New comment by adrr in "Counter-Strike's player economy is in a freefall"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Gambling mechanics for anyone under 18 should be banned.  Children can't buy lottery tickets or hit tables in Vegas.  Its crazy they can buy loot boxes that real life value.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 24 Oct 2025 01:43:15 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45689806</link><dc:creator>adrr</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45689806</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45689806</guid></item><item><title>New comment by leshokunin in "Counter-Strike's player economy is in a freefall"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I play CS. This is good. The gambling economy and the creator economy of people pumping their marketplaces and gambling sites is really toxic. It extracts money from kids, all for a nice skin. Making them more affordable is going to make this more fair and sensible.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 24 Oct 2025 01:27:22 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45689685</link><dc:creator>leshokunin</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45689685</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45689685</guid></item><item><title>New comment by jihadjihad in "/dev/null is an ACID compliant database"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;In a similar vein, this is one of the most interesting things I’ve come across on HN over the years:&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.linusakesson.net/programming/pipelogic/index.php" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://www.linusakesson.net/programming/pipelogic/index.php&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;Past HN post: &lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=15363029"&gt;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=15363029&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 24 Oct 2025 01:25:14 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45689668</link><dc:creator>jihadjihad</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45689668</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45689668</guid></item><item><title>New comment by apricot13 in "When is it better to think without words?"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;This is one of those things that you don't really tend to think about (pun not intended!) until you experience a change in your thinking or meet someone who thinks like you do!&lt;p&gt;&gt; If we can avoid the compression step, and do the manipulations directly in the high-dimensional, non-linguistic, conceptual space, we can move much faster&lt;p&gt;With my neurodivergent brain I've always conducted my thoughts in an "uncompressed format" and then eternally struggled to confine it all into words. Only then for people to misinterpret and question it. They might get caught up in the first sentence when the end of the paragraph is where you need to be!&lt;p&gt;That's why when you meet someone who thinks like you the depth of conversation and thinking you can achieve together is vast and also incredibly liberating! Your no longer limited by words in same way.&lt;p&gt;Since becoming ill I've suffered badly with brainfog. The cutesy name for a cruel experience. Sometimes there's no memories to draw on when your thinking, the cupboards are bare. You can't leap from thought to thought because they disappear before you get there or after like a cursed platformer. You might be able to grab hold of the thought but you can't reach inside or read it. It's all wrong somehow like when your suddenly convinced a word is spelt wrong even though you know it's right. You can't maintain focus long enough to finish your train of thought.&lt;p&gt;Even that subconscious processing is affected I used to prime my brain with information all day and instead of waking up with the solution I'll wake up frustrated but not knowing why. Just the vague notion that I failed at something that used to come so easily.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 24 Oct 2025 00:40:09 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45689360</link><dc:creator>apricot13</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45689360</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45689360</guid></item><item><title>New comment by gpm in "Apple loses UK App Store monopoly case, penalty might near $2B"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;As long as Apple requires they make use of those services for me to install software on the computer I bought, and they prevent others from producing equivalent competing devices via patents (i.e. government granted monopolies), zero.&lt;p&gt;It's not that it's not worth something, it's that they're abusing their patents and monopoly to extract further compensation after I already bought the device.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2025 23:39:51 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45688899</link><dc:creator>gpm</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45688899</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45688899</guid></item><item><title>New comment by mktemp-d in "Trump pardons convicted Binance founder"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Your forget to insert the part where the President asks the convicted defendant if they want to finance their pardon with Klarna or Affirm in the Presidential Library's checkout page&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2025 23:25:39 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45688760</link><dc:creator>mktemp-d</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45688760</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45688760</guid></item></channel></rss>