<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>Hacker News: Best Comments</title><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/bestcomments</link><description>Hacker News RSS</description><docs>https://hnrss.org/</docs><generator>hnrss v2.1.1</generator><lastBuildDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 23:50:06 +0000</lastBuildDate><ns0:link href="https://hnrss.org/bestcomments" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item><title>New comment by wewewedxfgdf in "State of the Windows: What is going on with Windows 11?"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;State of Windows?&lt;p&gt;It's so out of touch, people hate it.&lt;p&gt;People want a simple, clean, minimal, consistent OS that does not have anyone's interests first except the user. Windows 11 is a very, very long way from this.&lt;p&gt;Honestly Windows 95 is closer to ideal than Windows 11.&lt;p&gt;The state of Windows is: disaster.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 22:25:01 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46772423</link><dc:creator>wewewedxfgdf</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46772423</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46772423</guid></item><item><title>New comment by internetter in "Fedora Asahi Remix is now working on Apple M3"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I would just like to point out that Michael Reeves (the poster, no relation to youtuber) is a high schooler who has also found numerous high impact vulnerabilities in Apple software. Immensely talented.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 18:30:02 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46769560</link><dc:creator>internetter</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46769560</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46769560</guid></item><item><title>New comment by softwaredoug in "France Aiming to Replace Zoom, Google Meet, Microsoft Teams, etc."</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Americans fail to appreciate a few things about our economy&lt;p&gt;1. We have a large homgoneous market where you can build a product and it’s expected it can succeed for hundreds of millions of Americans&lt;p&gt;2. EU is the easiest second market, and another step change of hundreds of millions of customers in a somewhat unified market&lt;p&gt;3. there’s not an easy 3rd economy that replaces EUs wealth, population, and comfort with English + technology&lt;p&gt;When we piss everyone off in the EU tech company growth gets kneecapped and limited to US / Canada. Theres not an easy market to expand to without much deeper focus on that specific market and its needs, for much fewer returns.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 17:48:48 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46768949</link><dc:creator>softwaredoug</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46768949</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46768949</guid></item><item><title>New comment by abixb in "Google AI Overviews cite YouTube more than any medical site for health queries"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Heavy Gemini user here, another observation: Gemini cites lots of "AI generated" videos as its primary source, which creates a closed loop and has the potential to debase shared reality.&lt;p&gt;A few days ago, I asked it some questions on Russia's industrial base and military hardware manufacturing capability, and it wrote a very convincing response, except the video embedded at the end of the response was an AI generated one. It might have had actual facts, but overall, my trust in Gemini's response to my query went DOWN after I noticed the AI generated video attached as the source.&lt;p&gt;Countering debasement of shared reality and NOT using AI generated videos as sources should be a HUGE priority for Google.&lt;p&gt;YouTube channels with AI generated videos have exploded in sheer quantity, and I think majority of the new channels and videos uploaded to YouTube might actually be AI; "Dead internet theory," et al.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 15:27:34 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46766802</link><dc:creator>abixb</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46766802</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46766802</guid></item><item><title>New comment by orev in "After two years of vibecoding, I'm back to writing by hand"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;It’s like weightlifting: sure you can use a forklift to do it, but if the goal is to build up your own strength, using the forklift isn’t going to get you there.&lt;p&gt;This is the ultimate problem with AI in academia. We all inherently know that “no pain no gain” is true for physical tasks, but the same is true for learning. Struggling through the new concepts is essentially the point of it, not just the end result.&lt;p&gt;Of course this becomes a different thing outside of learning, where delivering results is more important in a workplace context. But even then you still need someone who does the high level thinking.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 14:26:07 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46766020</link><dc:creator>orev</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46766020</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46766020</guid></item><item><title>New comment by recursivedoubts in "After two years of vibecoding, I'm back to writing by hand"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;AI is incredibly dangerous because it &lt;i&gt;can&lt;/i&gt; do the simple things very well, which prevents new programmers from learning the simple things ("Oh, I'll just have AI generate it") which then prevents them from learning the middlin' and harder and meta things at a visceral level.&lt;p&gt;I'm a CS teacher, so this is where I see a huge danger right now and I'm explicit with my students about it: you HAVE to write the code.  You CAN'T let the machines write the code.  Yes, they can write the code: you are a student, the code isn't hard yet.  But you HAVE to write the code.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 14:05:52 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46765774</link><dc:creator>recursivedoubts</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46765774</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46765774</guid></item><item><title>New comment by crjohns648 in "Things I've learned in my 10 years as an engineering manager"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&gt; A good manager is more like a transparent umbrella. They protect the team from unnecessary stress and pressure, but don’t hide reality from them.&lt;p&gt;I'm absolutely going to steal this metaphor going forward.&lt;p&gt;Being a "transparent umbrella" does require knowing the personalities of your reports, some people do get distracted when they think higher-up decisions or unhappiness are going to affect their team. Most people, however, really appreciate the transparency. It helps them feel more in control when they know what is happening around them, and when things do change they can tie it back to something that was said previously.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 13:25:04 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46765340</link><dc:creator>crjohns648</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46765340</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46765340</guid></item><item><title>New comment by mahdi7d1 in "Iran's internet blackout may become permanent, with access for elites only"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I've been moderately happy this morning to find out I can open hackernews. Also Gmail is working. After attempting to get bridges using email and configuring an dozen of them I got 100% connection but then it disconnected without me being able to connect to anything.
I would assume some sort of tunneling must be possible cause the services available are varied and not limited to a few websites (We only had access to Google Search for about a week and nothing before that) now even Nintendo Store opened to my complete surprise.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 06:54:57 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46762620</link><dc:creator>mahdi7d1</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46762620</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46762620</guid></item><item><title>New comment by anigbrowl in "The '3.5% rule': How a small minority can change the world (2019)"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;(2019)&lt;p&gt;Chenoweth has backed off her previous conclusions in recent years, observing that nonviolent protest strategies have dramatically declined in effectiveness as governments have adjusted their tactics of repression and messaging. See eg &lt;a href="https://www.harvardmagazine.com/2025/07/erica-chenoweth-democracy-data-harvard" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://www.harvardmagazine.com/2025/07/erica-chenoweth-demo...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;One current example of messaging can be seen in the reflexive dismissal  by the current US government and its propagandists of any popular opposition as 'paid protesters'. Large attendance at Democratic political rallies during the 2024 election was dismissed as being paid for by the campaign, any crowd protesting government policy is described as either a rioting or alleged to be financed by George Soros or some other boogeyman of the right. This has been going on for years; the right simply refuses to countenance the possibility of legitimate organic opposition, while also being chronically unable to provide any evidence for their claims.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 25 Jan 2026 22:25:21 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46759139</link><dc:creator>anigbrowl</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46759139</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46759139</guid></item><item><title>New comment by messe in "Yes, It's Fascism"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;This should not have been flagged off the front page.&lt;p&gt;I really worry for the people in the US, but I'm hopeful it's hegemony is ending.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 25 Jan 2026 21:55:58 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46758778</link><dc:creator>messe</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46758778</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46758778</guid></item><item><title>New comment by Kaibeezy in "Yes, It's Fascism"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;If you are debating whether to read this article, read it. It’s comprehensive and precise, and although political in substance, not political in form — test-fitting an imprecise definition. The fact it also reaches a firm conclusion (spoiler alert right there in the title) is depoliticized by allowing for malleable application. A benchmark article I will now go share elsewhere.&lt;p&gt;What’s left to talk about? How to react. How it ends. Where we likely go from there. Where we &lt;i&gt;should&lt;/i&gt; go.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 25 Jan 2026 20:55:57 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46758113</link><dc:creator>Kaibeezy</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46758113</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46758113</guid></item><item><title>New comment by simonw in "First, make me care"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;This is something I find fascinating about TikTok: on that platform you literally get a few seconds to catch the attention of your audience before they skip to the next video.&lt;p&gt;You can't just find one hook that works and reuse it forever because people will get bored of it - including if that hook is heavily used by other accounts.&lt;p&gt;This makes TikTok a fascinating brute-force attack on human psychology, with literally millions of people all trying to find the right hooks to catch attention and constantly evolving and iterating on them as the previous hooks stop being effective.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 25 Jan 2026 20:18:29 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46757744</link><dc:creator>simonw</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46757744</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46757744</guid></item><item><title>New comment by kjellsbells in "ICE using Palantir tool that feeds on Medicaid data"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;FWIW, people here illegally are already not eligible for Medicaid, [0] so it's hard to see why ICE having access to a roster of Medicaid enrollees would help them with their stated mission of enforcing removal orders.&lt;p&gt;Then again, we have ICE shooting American citizens in the streets, so I guess the law is whatever they decide it is, not least because our legislative branch is uninterested in laws.&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.congress.gov/crs_external_products/IF/PDF/IF11912/IF11912.4.pdf" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://www.congress.gov/crs_external_products/IF/PDF/IF1191...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 25 Jan 2026 20:17:06 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46757734</link><dc:creator>kjellsbells</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46757734</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46757734</guid></item><item><title>New comment by tasty_freeze in "ICE using Palantir tool that feeds on Medicaid data"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;It reminds me of when Eric Schmidt, then CEO of google, tried that argument about people's worry of google collecting so much personal data. Some media outlet then published a bunch of personal information about Schmidt they had gathered using only google searches, including where he lives, his salary, his political donations, and where his kids went to school. Schmidt was not amused.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 25 Jan 2026 19:47:41 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46757487</link><dc:creator>tasty_freeze</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46757487</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46757487</guid></item><item><title>New comment by steve1977 in "ICE using Palantir tool that feeds on Medicaid data"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Also always keep in mind that what is legal today might be illegal tomorrow. This includes things like your ethnicity, religion, sexual orientation and much more.&lt;p&gt;You don't know today on which side of legality you will be in 10 years, even if your intentions are harmless.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 25 Jan 2026 18:28:53 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46756681</link><dc:creator>steve1977</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46756681</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46756681</guid></item><item><title>New comment by eoskx in "ICE using Palantir tool that feeds on Medicaid data"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Glad to see this post didn't get flagged like the one that was posted yesterday on a similar topic about ICE data mining and user tracking.&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46748336"&gt;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46748336&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 25 Jan 2026 18:10:11 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46756472</link><dc:creator>eoskx</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46756472</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46756472</guid></item><item><title>New comment by simonw in "ICE using Palantir tool that feeds on Medicaid data"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Any time I see people say "I don't see why I should care about my privacy, I've got nothing to hide" I think about how badly things can go if the wrong people end up in positions of power.&lt;p&gt;The classic example here is what happens when someone is being stalked by an abusive ex-partner who works in law enforcement and has access to those databases.&lt;p&gt;This ICE stuff is that scaled up to a multi-billion dollar federal agency with, apparently, no accountability for following the law at all.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 25 Jan 2026 17:56:37 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46756340</link><dc:creator>simonw</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46756340</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46756340</guid></item><item><title>New comment by hn_throwaway_99 in "FAA institutes nationwide drone no-fly zones around ICE operations"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;One of the hallmarks of authoritarianism is to have laws that are virtually impossible to &lt;i&gt;not&lt;/i&gt; break.&lt;p&gt;I hope this gets tested in court and declared unconstitutional for being overly vague and arbitrary. For example, Montana used to have some maximum speed limits that were just "reasonable and prudent", but they were eventually rejected by courts as being too vague (what's prudent to you may not be prudent to someone else). This is similar, in that the FAA has a no fly zone but they don't actually publish what it is.&lt;p&gt;Catch-22 and 1984 weren't supposed to be instruction manuals.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 25 Jan 2026 17:50:20 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46756278</link><dc:creator>hn_throwaway_99</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46756278</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46756278</guid></item><item><title>New comment by dayofthedaleks in "FAA institutes nationwide drone no-fly zones around ICE operations"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Bubble of protection is 3000 feet laterally and 1000 feet vertically. From the article:&lt;p&gt;“Unlike traditional Temporary Flight Restrictions, the NOTAM does not provide geographic coordinates, activation times, or public notification when the restriction is in effect near a specific location. Instead, the restricted airspace moves with DHS assets, meaning the no-fly zone can appear wherever ICE or other DHS units operate.”&lt;p&gt;“In practical terms, a drone operator flying legally in a public area could unknowingly enter restricted airspace if an ICE convoy passes within the protected radius.”&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 25 Jan 2026 17:33:14 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46756085</link><dc:creator>dayofthedaleks</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46756085</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46756085</guid></item><item><title>New comment by wmeredith in "White House alters arrest photo of ICE protester, says "the memes will continue""</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;There's been a lot of talk on HN about generative AI and how it will be weaponized to scam people and politically for propoganda. That reality got here very quickly.&lt;p&gt;Secretary of Homeland Security Kristi Noem posted a photo of Nekima Levy Armstrong, a Minnesota civil rights attorney, being arrested at a political protest. A half hour later, the official White House X account posted an altered version in which Armstrong’s face was manipulated to make it appear that she was crying.&lt;p&gt;Wild to see this tech get adopted so fast and so unapologetically used.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 25 Jan 2026 16:58:19 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46755736</link><dc:creator>wmeredith</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46755736</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46755736</guid></item><item><title>New comment by avalys in "A macOS app that blurs your screen when you slouch"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;You can measure my productivity by how slouched I am.&lt;p&gt;Sitting up straight at my desk, chair locked, perfect posture? I’m doing nothing, maybe looking through System Preferences to change the system highlight color.&lt;p&gt;Sliding down in my chair like jelly, with my shoulders where my butt should be and my head resting on the lumbar support? I’m building the next iPhone and it’ll be done by 2 AM.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 25 Jan 2026 16:58:19 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46755735</link><dc:creator>avalys</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46755735</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46755735</guid></item><item><title>New comment by bargle0 in "A flawed paper in management science has been cited more than 6k times"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;If you’re the same Sean Luke I’m thinking of:&lt;p&gt;I was an undergraduate at the University of Maryland when you were a graduate student there in the mid nineties. A lot of what you had to say shaped the way I think about computer science. Thank you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 25 Jan 2026 15:50:59 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46755114</link><dc:creator>bargle0</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46755114</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46755114</guid></item><item><title>New comment by SeanLuke in "A flawed paper in management science has been cited more than 6k times"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I developed and maintain a large and very widely used open source agent-based modeling toolkit.  It's designed to be very highly efficient: that's its calling card. But it's old: I released its first version around 2003 and have been updating it ever since.&lt;p&gt;Recently I was made aware by colleagues of a publication by authors of a new agent-based modeling toolkit in a different, hipper programming language.  They compared their system to others, including mine, and made kind of a big checklist of who's better in what, and no surprise, theirs came out on top.  But digging deeper, it quickly became clear that they didn't understand how to run my software correctly; and in many other places they bent over backwards to cherry-pick, and made a lot of bold and completely wrong claims.  Correcting the record would place their software far below mine.&lt;p&gt;Mind you, I'm VERY happy to see newer toolkits which are better than mine -- I wrote this thing over 20 years ago after all, and have since moved on.  But several colleagues demanded I do so.  After a lot of back-and-forth however, it became clear that the journal's editor was too embarrassed and didn't want to require a retraction or revision.  And the authors kept coming up with excuses for their errors.  So the journal quietly dropped the complaint.&lt;p&gt;I'm afraid that this is very common.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 25 Jan 2026 15:31:11 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46754905</link><dc:creator>SeanLuke</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46754905</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46754905</guid></item><item><title>New comment by layer8 in "A flawed paper in management science has been cited more than 6k times"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Labeling people as villains (as opposed to condemning acts), in particular those you don’t know personally, is almost always an unhelpful oversimplification of reality. It obscures the root causes of why the bad things are happening, and stands in the way of effective remedy.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 25 Jan 2026 12:39:43 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46753607</link><dc:creator>layer8</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46753607</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46753607</guid></item><item><title>New comment by goldenarm in "Google confirms 'high-friction' sideloading flow is coming to Android"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Sideloading is a neologism to scare users and lawmakers, it just means "Installing software" and should be a basic right.&lt;p&gt;Also software installation in Android has been high friction for a while. Installing an APK on my phone is at least 10 clicks.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 25 Jan 2026 11:51:51 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46753268</link><dc:creator>goldenarm</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46753268</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46753268</guid></item><item><title>New comment by 0xcb0 in "Deutsche Telekom is throttling the internet"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Telekom is a bunch of strange folks.
I lately was not able to send mails, from my private mail servrr to my fathers telekom mail. After investigation I found out my server got blocked. After a decade of working.
I mailed them, and they told me to register my mailserver with them. I shall tell them what mails I will send from there and about what content. I couldn’t believe my eyes. 
Sure, thats how mail was supposed to work. Register with every mail server in the world, before you can send mail.&lt;p&gt;Their mail excerpt:
This system has not sent any e-mail to our customers for a long time.
For security reasons our systems will only accept e-mails from such IP
addresses after a check of setup and information about these systems.&lt;p&gt;Please give us details about this system and the company using it,
tell us all about the sending domain, what type of e-mail will be sent
and especially if you or your customer want to send newsletter give us
detailed information on how recipients e-mail addresses had been
acquired. Who in person is responsible for e-mail sent from this
system (MTA)?&lt;p&gt;Please be advised that only technically proper configured and very well
maintained systems are qualified for a reset of reputation and please
see our FAQ section 4.1 (Requirements for smooth access to our e-mail
exchanges &lt;&lt;a href="https://postmaster.t-online.de/index.en.html#t4.1" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://postmaster.t-online.de/index.en.html#t4.1&lt;/a&gt;&gt;):&lt;p&gt;"There must be a domain and website with direct contact information
easily deducible from the delivering IP's hostname (FQDN)."&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 25 Jan 2026 11:00:45 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46752954</link><dc:creator>0xcb0</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46752954</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46752954</guid></item><item><title>New comment by flowerthoughts in "A flawed paper in management science has been cited more than 6k times"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&gt; This doesn’t mean that the authors of that paper are bad people!&lt;p&gt;&gt; We should distinguish the person from the deed. We all know good people who do bad things&lt;p&gt;&gt; They were just in situations where it was easier to do the bad thing than the good thing&lt;p&gt;I can't believe I just read that. What's the bar for a bad person if you haven't passed it at "it was simply easier to do the bad thing?"&lt;p&gt;In this case, it seems not owning up to the issues is the bad part. That's a choice they made. Actually, multiple choices at different times, it seems. If you keep choosing the easy path instead of the path that is right for those that depend on you, it's easier for me to just label you a bad person.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 25 Jan 2026 10:36:18 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46752788</link><dc:creator>flowerthoughts</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46752788</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46752788</guid></item><item><title>New comment by onli in "Google confirms 'high-friction' sideloading flow is coming to Android"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I don't see any iOS advantage with the apps anymore. That was maybe true in the very beginning, during the gold rush time of the app store. But not since then. In which category are there better iOS apps? Browsers? No, strictly worse. Youtube app? No, worse. Texting? Worse or equal (Whatsapp). Podcast client? I assume worse, since there is no Antenna Pod. Social media apps? The iOS variants of those apps are afaik in no way better. What else is there, where is the advantage?&lt;p&gt;Also, while the Play store is an equally ad-riddled and unsearchable hellhole, at least Android does have with F-Droid a high quality alternative. iOS has nothing.&lt;p&gt;But sure, removing the F-Droid advantage can only hurt Android, the direction of your comment still stands.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 25 Jan 2026 09:13:56 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46752200</link><dc:creator>onli</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46752200</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46752200</guid></item><item><title>New comment by AlotOfReading in "Google confirms 'high-friction' sideloading flow is coming to Android"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Google's long term strategy with Android is baffling to me. Apple has had better mobile hardware for years. Apple has higher consumer trust. Apple has better app selection (for most people). Apple has been increasingly implementing the core features that differentiate Android devices, like USB-C and RCS. Every Android user lost to the increasing iOS market share is another customer Google has to pay exorbitant fees to a competitor to access.&lt;p&gt;And Google's strategy is to continue removing differentiating features from Android that &lt;i&gt;also&lt;/i&gt; help them mitigate the threat of antitrust? Surely the marginal revenue from the inconsequential number of sideloading users isn't attractive enough to justify that kind of strategic blunder.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 25 Jan 2026 07:08:12 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46751542</link><dc:creator>AlotOfReading</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46751542</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46751542</guid></item><item><title>New comment by princevegeta89 in "Adoption of EVs tied to real-world reductions in air pollution: study"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;No surprises.&lt;p&gt;No matter how we look at it, EVs are much friendlier and safer to the environment. Some people argue the source of electricty can be contested against because that involves fossil fuel burning again, but in today's world we are rapidly moving away from it and towards nuclear/hydel/wind methods for generating power.&lt;p&gt;I hope ICE cars completely become a thing of the past in the next couple of decades to come.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 25 Jan 2026 02:01:43 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46749919</link><dc:creator>princevegeta89</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46749919</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46749919</guid></item></channel></rss>