<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>Hacker News: Best Comments</title><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/bestcomments</link><description>Hacker News RSS</description><docs>https://hnrss.org/</docs><generator>hnrss v2.1.1</generator><lastBuildDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 00:08:38 +0000</lastBuildDate><ns0:link href="https://hnrss.org/bestcomments" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item><title>New comment by etangent in "My stages of learning to be a socially normal person"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&gt; a lot of the points felt more like learning how to charm, manipulate, and game social interactions.&lt;p&gt;A lot of stuff "normal" people do is charm, manipulate, and game social interactions. Except because they are not conscious about it, we give them a pass. One of the characteristics of autistic-spectrum individuals is that they must make a conscious effort to achieve goals that are achieved unconsciously by most of us. If we prevent such individuals from learning all that rarely-written-down stuff consciously because it seems "distasteful" to us, then we are disadvantaging such individuals socially.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 21:16:10 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45958403</link><dc:creator>etangent</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45958403</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45958403</guid></item><item><title>New comment by baklavaEmperor in "Israeli-founded app preloaded on Samsung phones is attracting controversy"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;What’s striking is how often these ‘small’ surveillance tech stories trace back to the same state-aligned ecosystem. When Israel does it, it’s treated as a complex security issue. When another ‘bad’ country does the same thing, we immediately call it espionage. And almost on cue, the discussion drifts anywhere except the uncomfortable fact that it’s the same ecosystem from the same country showing up again.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 20:30:54 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45957934</link><dc:creator>baklavaEmperor</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45957934</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45957934</guid></item><item><title>New comment by hpdigidrifter in "Why don't people return their shopping carts?"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I assume it's generally unbecoming to reference 4chan posts for an academic but surprised the Shopping Cart theory didn't get a mention given how close it was to the subject matter.&lt;p&gt;&gt;“The shopping cart is the ultimate litmus test for whether a person is capable of self-governing. To return the shopping cart is an easy, convenient task and one we all recognize as the correct, appropriate thing to do. To return the shopping cart is objectively right. There are no situations other than dire emergencies in which a person is not able to return their cart. Simultaneously, it is not illegal to abandon your shopping cart. Therefore, the shopping cart presents itself as the apex example of whether a person will do what is right without being forced to do it.”&lt;p&gt;&gt;“No one will punish you for not returning the shopping cart, no one will fine you, or kill you for not returning the shopping cart. You gain nothing by returning the shopping cart. You must return the shopping cart out of the goodness of your own heart. You must return the shopping cart because it is the right thing to do. Because it is correct. The Shopping Cart Theory, therefore, is a great litmus test on whether a person is a good or bad member of society.”&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 18:45:54 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45956589</link><dc:creator>hpdigidrifter</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45956589</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45956589</guid></item><item><title>New comment by xmcp123 in "Google is killing the open web, part 2"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;It’s interesting to see the casual slide of Google towards almost internet explorer 5.1 style behavior, where standards can just be ignored “because market share”.&lt;p&gt;Having flashbacks of “&lt;!--[if IE 6]&gt;
    &lt;script src="fix-ie6.js"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;![endif]--&gt;”&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 16:37:48 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45955239</link><dc:creator>xmcp123</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45955239</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45955239</guid></item><item><title>New comment by nwellnhof in "Google is killing the open web, part 2"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Removing XSLT from browsers was long overdue and I'm saying that as ex-maintainer of libxslt who probably triggered (not caused) this removal. What's more interesting is that Chromium plans to switch to a Rust-based XML parser. Currently, they seem to favor xml-rs which only implements a subset of XML. So apparently, Google is willing to remove standards-compliant XML support as well. This is a lot more concerning.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 16:33:27 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45955183</link><dc:creator>nwellnhof</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45955183</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45955183</guid></item><item><title>New comment by wmeredith in "Are you stuck in movie logic?"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&gt; Good Will Hunting. The entire movie feels like it could’ve been skipped if literally any emotionally intelligent person said to Matt Damon’s character: “I feel like you have a tremendous amount of intellectual potential that you’re wasting here — why are you getting in fights rather than trying to do something interesting?”&lt;p&gt;Maybe I'm missing something but that's literally what everyone in the movie is telling Will. HIs best friend, his mentor, his girlfriend, his therapist. They all literally say this in some form during the movie. His character growth is believing it himself.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 16:16:46 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45954969</link><dc:creator>wmeredith</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45954969</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45954969</guid></item><item><title>New comment by btilly in "A new chapter begins for EV batteries with the expiry of key LFP patents"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;It is worth noting that this is an ad. It is a law firm that is advertising their expertise in this field. And the product that they want people to buy is revealed in this passage:&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Freedom-to-operate (FTO) analysis therefore remains critical for market entrants. Whilst the primary patents have expired, a dense web of secondary patents, covering additives, coatings, and production methods, still poses infringement risks.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;p&gt;Of course Shoosmiths would be happy to do a FTO analysis for your potential product...for a fee.&lt;p&gt;That doesn't mean that it doesn't contain quality information. Law firms tend to make this kind of ad informative. But it does mean that there is an agenda.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 04:39:39 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45950886</link><dc:creator>btilly</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45950886</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45950886</guid></item><item><title>New comment by RandyOrion in "Heretic: Automatic censorship removal for language models"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;This repo is valuable for local LLM users like me.&lt;p&gt;I just want to reiterate that the word "LLM safety" means very different things to large corporations and LLM users.&lt;p&gt;For large corporations, they often say "do safety alignment to LLMs". What they actually do is to avoid anything that causes damage to their own interests. These things include forcing LLMs to meet some legal requirements, as well as forcing LLMs to output "values, facts, and knowledge" which in favor of themselves, e.g., political views, attitudes towards literal interaction, and distorted facts about organizations and people behind LLMs.&lt;p&gt;As an average LLM user, what I want is maximum factual knowledge and capabilities from LLMs, which are what these large corporations claimed in the first place. It's very clear that the interests of me, an LLM user, is not aligned with these of large corporations.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 03:21:30 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45950598</link><dc:creator>RandyOrion</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45950598</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45950598</guid></item><item><title>New comment by AlbertoGP in "Britney Spears' Guide to Semiconductor Physics (2000)"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Around the time this website was made, I was building an application for a big company in Spain that was to run as a Java applet and required the code to be signed.&lt;p&gt;They did not yet have their own certificates so I had to make my own CA during testing and sign the code, and I wanted to make sure that they did not forget to switch to their certificates later, so instead of signing the code with my name which some bureaucrat might decide to not bother changing, the code was signed by Britney Spears.&lt;p&gt;They noticed it, got the joke and made sure to switch certificates for the release. Everything went well thanks to Britney.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 00:38:11 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45949868</link><dc:creator>AlbertoGP</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45949868</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45949868</guid></item><item><title>New comment by stego-tech in "Goldman Sachs asks in biotech Report: Is curing patients a sustainable business? (2018)"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I feel kinda bad for the writer, because it's a good question: no, curing patients is &lt;i&gt;not&lt;/i&gt; a good business model, just like public transit is &lt;i&gt;not&lt;/i&gt; a good business model.&lt;p&gt;What a lot of folks neglect are N+1-order effects, because those are harder to quantify and fail to reach the predetermined decision some executive or board or shareholder has already made.  Is curing patients a bad business model? Sure, for the biotech company it is, but those cured patients are far more likely to go on living longer, healthier lives, and in turn contribute additional value to society - which will impact others in ways that may also create additional value.  That doesn't even get into the jobs and value created through the R&amp;D process, testing, manufacturing, logistics of delivery, ongoing monitoring, etc.  As long as the value created is more than the cost of the treatment, then it's a net-gain for the economy even if it's a net loss for that singular business.&lt;p&gt;If all you're judging is the first-order impacts on a single business, you're missing the forest for the trees.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 00:03:56 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45949690</link><dc:creator>stego-tech</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45949690</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45949690</guid></item><item><title>New comment by mendelmaleh in "Open-source Zig book"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&gt; The Zigbook intentionally contains no AI-generated content—it is hand-written, carefully curated, and continuously updated to reflect the latest language features and best practices.&lt;p&gt;I think it's time to have a badge for non LLM content, and avoid the rest.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 16 Nov 2025 22:05:14 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45948849</link><dc:creator>mendelmaleh</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45948849</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45948849</guid></item><item><title>New comment by chaps in "I have recordings proving Coinbase knew about breach months before disclosure"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Once did some programming/networking work for a company that did the networking of a office sharing building that Coinbase was running out of. Early in my work there I noticed that the company had its admin passwords written on a whiteboard -- visible from the hallway because they had glass for walls. So I sent them an email to ask that they remove it (I billed them for it).&lt;p&gt;Their fix was to put a piece of paper over the passwords.&lt;p&gt;What a time.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 16 Nov 2025 20:59:05 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45948347</link><dc:creator>chaps</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45948347</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45948347</guid></item><item><title>New comment by jchw in "I finally understand Cloudflare Zero Trust tunnels"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;One thing that makes Cloudflare worse for home usage is it acts as a termination point for TLS, whereas Tailscale does not. If you use a Tailscale Funnel, you get the TLS certificate on your endpoint. With Cloudflare, they get a TLS certificate for you, and then strip and optionally re-add TLS as traffic passes through them.&lt;p&gt;I actually have no idea how private networks with WARP are here, but that's a pretty big privacy downgrade for tunneling from the Internet.&lt;p&gt;I also consider P2P with relay fallback to be highly desirable over always relaying traffic through a third party, too. Firstly, less middlemen. Secondly, it continues working even if the coordination service is unavailable.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 16 Nov 2025 20:21:29 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45948083</link><dc:creator>jchw</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45948083</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45948083</guid></item><item><title>New comment by joshcsimmons in "Heretic: Automatic censorship removal for language models"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;This is extremely important work thank you for sharing it. We are in the process of giving up our own moral standing in favor of taking on the ones imbued into LLMs by their creators. This is a worrying trend that will totally wipe out intellectual diversity.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 16 Nov 2025 17:37:01 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45946838</link><dc:creator>joshcsimmons</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45946838</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45946838</guid></item><item><title>New comment by gpi in "Anthropic’s paper smells like bullshit"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;The below amendment from the anthropic blog page is telling.&lt;p&gt;Edited November 14 2025:&lt;p&gt;Added an additional hyperlink to the full report in the initial section&lt;p&gt;Corrected an error about the speed of the attack: not "thousands of requests per second" but "thousands of requests, often multiple per second"&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 16 Nov 2025 14:44:10 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45945486</link><dc:creator>gpi</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45945486</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45945486</guid></item><item><title>New comment by yousif_123123 in "Maybe you’re not trying"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I've always noticed that when I'm giving advice to someone or trying to help out, it always feels their problem is easier than whatever problem I have. As someone with some anxiety around things like calling some company to get something done or asking a random stranger for some help in a store, I would gladly do it if it was to help someone else (family member or friend). But when it's for me I find it harder.&lt;p&gt;I wonder how much psychologically we can be more confident and less anxious when we're doing something for others vs ourselves..&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 16 Nov 2025 14:02:31 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45945216</link><dc:creator>yousif_123123</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45945216</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45945216</guid></item><item><title>New comment by jmkni in "Anthropic’s paper smells like bullshit"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;That whole article felt like "Claude is so good Chinese hackers are using it for espionage" marketing fluff tbh&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 16 Nov 2025 12:56:48 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45944780</link><dc:creator>jmkni</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45944780</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45944780</guid></item><item><title>New comment by KaiserPro in "Anthropic’s paper smells like bullshit"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;When I worked at a  FAANG with a "world leading" AI lab (now run by a teenage data labeller) as an SRE/sysadmin I was asked to use a modified version of a foundation model which was steered towards infosec stuff.&lt;p&gt;We were asked to try and persuade it to help us hack into a mock printer/dodgy linux box.&lt;p&gt;It helped a little, but it wasn't all that helpful.&lt;p&gt;but in terms of coordination, I can't see how it would be useful.&lt;p&gt;the same for claude, you're API is tied to a bankaccount, and vibe coding a command and control system on a very public system seems like a bad choice.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 16 Nov 2025 12:33:24 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45944641</link><dc:creator>KaiserPro</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45944641</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45944641</guid></item><item><title>New comment by prinny_ in "Anthropic’s paper smells like bullshit"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;The lack of evidence before attributing the attack(s) to a Chinese sponsored group makes me correlate this report with recent statements from companies in the AI space about how China is about to surpass US in the AI race. Ultimately statements and reports like these seem more like an attempt to make the US government step in and be the big investor that keeps the money flowing rather than anything else.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 16 Nov 2025 12:29:12 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45944616</link><dc:creator>prinny_</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45944616</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45944616</guid></item><item><title>New comment by torginus in "I don’t need a Steam Machine"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;When I first saw the Arduino I didn't see the point - after all there were boards that cost less, did more, and the Arduino IDE seemed very barebones compared to what you could do with GCC and a custom toolchain.&lt;p&gt;Then eventually I saw how much community support, ready made hardware emerged around it, to the point that after a while, not going the Arduino route was a decision you needed to justify heavily.&lt;p&gt;Same thing with the Raspberry Pi - there are commercial devices now running or more or less stock Pi hardware with some accomodations - the power of the community is just too large - you can either spend an insane amount of time getting things working on your custom SBC, or get something well-supported for free.&lt;p&gt;I hope that the same thing will happen with the Steam Machine - the pull of the community will result in a well-supported 'default' device where people (and Valve) will put in the effort to create a comparable desktop experience to the commercial OSes.&lt;p&gt;Valve already helped immensely with Wayland - it's crazy to think that the project was stared cca. 2008, and today there's still arguments to be made it's not mature yet - by investing the necessary energy to make sure games run well, the drivers are optimized, and there's a high-quality end-user library (wlroots) for writing compositors has been the push that Wayland needed.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 16 Nov 2025 11:03:02 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45944161</link><dc:creator>torginus</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45944161</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45944161</guid></item><item><title>New comment by mariopt in "I don’t need a Steam Machine"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Steam Machines can become an existencial crisis for PlayStation and Xbox.&lt;p&gt;A “console” that I can use as a PC? I am in 100%. You’ll get the world biggest game library at a discount, this is why I sold my PlayStation after spending 200 euros and watching it becoming useless.&lt;p&gt;I also suspect a lot of game devs will optimize for steam machine and finally we’ll get a console like experience on PC.&lt;p&gt;Don’t let the “low specs” fool you, it has the same specs or better as 70% of steam users.&lt;p&gt;Given Valve gave money to a lot of open source maintainers , it’s also great for Linux.&lt;p&gt;Just take my money&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 16 Nov 2025 10:47:05 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45944089</link><dc:creator>mariopt</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45944089</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45944089</guid></item><item><title>New comment by xps in "AirPods libreated from Apple's ecosystem"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;They don't report battery status to non-Apple devices. This is a pretty basic feature and without this I wouldn't consider them to perform "on par" with other Bluetooth headphones.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 16 Nov 2025 10:44:55 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45944080</link><dc:creator>xps</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45944080</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45944080</guid></item><item><title>New comment by gloxkiqcza in "Hyundai Paywalls Brake Pads replacement on Ioniq 5 N"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Doesn’t really surprise me. I remember reading the article linked below from which I quote:&lt;p&gt;&gt; Forced to raise their game, carmakers are only now realizing they cannot repeat past mistakes such as letting others build up parts and services businesses off the back of their core product. "They stole the business from us," Martinet says, referencing as an example windshield replacement companies. "So I don't want them to steal the next one."&lt;p&gt;Xavier Martinet is the President and CEO of Hyundai Motor Europe.&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.wired.com/story/the-global-car-reckoning-is-here-auto-companies-dont-have-a-plan/" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://www.wired.com/story/the-global-car-reckoning-is-here...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 16 Nov 2025 08:45:46 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45943646</link><dc:creator>gloxkiqcza</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45943646</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45943646</guid></item><item><title>New comment by LarsDu88 in "Report: Tim Cook could step down as Apple CEO 'as soon as next year'"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;They shipped AirPods and the Apple Watch during his tenure. And the ahem, Vision Pro. The M-series chips are probably the biggest win for Apple in the past 15 years.&lt;p&gt;There hasn't been lack of category killers during his stint. If anything they are running out of places on the human body where you can stick a small computer.&lt;p&gt;Surely the next CEO will hopefully not ruin the company and brand by cramming ads into everything.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 16 Nov 2025 07:41:13 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45943427</link><dc:creator>LarsDu88</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45943427</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45943427</guid></item><item><title>New comment by exitb in "AirPods libreated from Apple's ecosystem"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;AirPods can connect to any device and perform on par with other Bluetooth headphones. This is about availability of special features which require a dedicated driver non-Apple devices are not expected to have.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 16 Nov 2025 06:36:01 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45943230</link><dc:creator>exitb</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45943230</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45943230</guid></item><item><title>New comment by isoprophlex in "AirPods libreated from Apple's ecosystem"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;From a bit further down the page&lt;p&gt;&gt; Bluetooth DID (Device Identification) Hook
&gt; Turns out, if you change the manufacturerid to that of Apple, you get access to several special features!&lt;p&gt;I hope Apple gets slammed hard by some regulatory body. Apparently there's absolutely zero magic reasons why their airpods are unable to connect to non-Apple devices; pretend you're an iPhone and you're in.&lt;p&gt;EDIT: read "unable to connect" =&gt; "unable to expose advanced functionality", ofc they connect just fine&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 16 Nov 2025 06:17:59 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45943174</link><dc:creator>isoprophlex</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45943174</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45943174</guid></item><item><title>New comment by jmgao in "AirPods libreated from Apple's ecosystem"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;It doesn't seem obvious to me that this is actually a bug in the Android implementation, it seems like this is due to AirPods violating the spec and requiring a special handshake before responding to standard requests. It doesn't seem reasonable to expect Android to work around a device that appears to be intentionally breaking the spec for vendor lock-in purposes: the possibility of them just OTAing an update that breaks in some other way means that you'd have to be entirely bug compatible with iOS's bluetooth implementation.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 16 Nov 2025 03:12:23 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45942451</link><dc:creator>jmgao</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45942451</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45942451</guid></item><item><title>New comment by ferd in "When did people favor composition over inheritance?"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;An important point not mentioned by the article is that of "co-recursion" with inheritance (of implementation).&lt;p&gt;That is: an instance of a subclass calls a method defined on a parent class, which in turn may call a method that's been overridden by the subclass (or even another sub-subclass in the hierarchy) and that one in turn may call another parent method, and so on. It can easily become a pinball of calls around the hierarchy.&lt;p&gt;Add to that the fact that "objects" have state, and each class in the hierarchy may add more state, and modify state declared on parents. Perfect combinatory explosion of state and control-flow complexity.&lt;p&gt;I've seen this scenario way too many times in projects, and worse thing is: many developers think it's fine... and are even proud of navigating such a mess. Heck, many popular "frameworks" encourage this.&lt;p&gt;Basically: every time you modify a class, you must review the inner implementation of all other classes in the hierarchy, and call paths to ensure your change is safe. That's a horrendous way to write software, against the most basic principles of modularity and low coupling.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 16 Nov 2025 02:15:38 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45942186</link><dc:creator>ferd</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45942186</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45942186</guid></item><item><title>New comment by JSR_FDED in "When UPS charged me a $684 tariff on $355 of vintage computer parts"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Tariffs are great. They protect the struggling domestic IT industry and gives it time to ramp up its production of vintage computer parts.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 16 Nov 2025 00:41:49 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45941785</link><dc:creator>JSR_FDED</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45941785</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45941785</guid></item><item><title>New comment by moonleay in "AirPods libreated from Apple's ecosystem"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;A cool project, when you want to use AirPods outside of Apples ecosystem. Sadly, you have to use a rooted android device with a small patch due to a bug in the Android Bluetooth implementation.
&lt;a href="https://issuetracker.google.com/issues/371713238" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://issuetracker.google.com/issues/371713238&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 16 Nov 2025 00:02:57 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45941605</link><dc:creator>moonleay</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45941605</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45941605</guid></item></channel></rss>