<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>Hacker News: Best Comments</title><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/bestcomments</link><description>Hacker News RSS</description><docs>https://hnrss.org/</docs><generator>hnrss v2.1.1</generator><lastBuildDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 00:29:53 +0000</lastBuildDate><ns0:link href="https://hnrss.org/bestcomments" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item><title>New comment by tenpoundhammer in "GPT-5.2"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I have been using chatGPT a ton over the last months and paying the subscription. Used it for coding, news, stock analysis, daily problems, and a whatever I could think of. I decided to give Gemini a go when version three came out to great reviews. Gemini handles every single one of my uses cases much better and consistently gives better answers. This is especially true for situations were searching the web for current information is important, makes sense that google would be better. Also OCR is phenomenal chatgpt can't read my bad hand writing but Gemini can easily. Only downsides are in the polish department, there are more app bugs and I usually have to leave the happen or the session terminates. There are bugs with uploading photos. The biggest complaint is that all links get inserted into google search and then I have to manipulate them when they should go directly to the chosen website, this has to be some kind of internal org KPI nonsense. Overall, my conclusion is that ChatGPT has lost and won't catch up because of the search integration strength.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 20:39:33 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46236826</link><dc:creator>tenpoundhammer</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46236826</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46236826</guid></item><item><title>New comment by tedsanders in "GPT-5.2"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Yep, the point we wanted to make here is that GPT-5.2's vision is better, not perfect. Cherrypicking a perfect output would actually mislead readers, and that wasn't our intent.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 18:44:01 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46235267</link><dc:creator>tedsanders</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46235267</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46235267</guid></item><item><title>New comment by n4r9 in "The highest quality codebase"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I think we have different opinions on what's fun and what's boring!&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 16:27:58 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46233446</link><dc:creator>n4r9</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46233446</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46233446</guid></item><item><title>New comment by celeritascelery in "iPhone Typos? It's Not Just You – The iOS Keyboard Is Broken [video]"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I have had this conversation with several people. I feel like I used to be able to type with a fairly low error rate on a smaller screen with old iPhones. Now I feel that it is constant exercise in frustration as I will hit a letter and the keyboard will decide to pick the letter next to it. It is evolving backwards.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 16:02:08 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46233057</link><dc:creator>celeritascelery</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46233057</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46233057</guid></item><item><title>New comment by mort96 in "Helldivers 2 on-disk size 85% reduction"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;The negativity towards this is wild. A company followed relatively widely accepted industry practice (lots and lots of other games also have huge sizes on disk for the exact same reason), then eventually they decided to do their own independent testing to check whether said common practice actually makes things better or not in their case, found that it didn't, so they reversed it. In addition, they wrote up some nice technical articles on the topic, helping to change the old accepted industry wisdom.&lt;p&gt;This seems great to me. Am I crazy? This feels like it should be Hacker News's bread and butter, articles about "we moved away from Kubernetes/microservices/node.js/serverless/React because we did our own investigation and found that the upsides aren't worth the downsides" tend to do really well here. How is this received so differently?&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 15:58:11 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46232985</link><dc:creator>mort96</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46232985</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46232985</guid></item><item><title>New comment by nabla9 in "Rubio stages font coup: Times New Roman ousts Calibri"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I think we all can agree that Comic Sans MS reflects the current US government best, both spiritually and aesthetically.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 11:41:57 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46230177</link><dc:creator>nabla9</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46230177</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46230177</guid></item><item><title>New comment by LucasFonts in "Rubio stages font coup: Times New Roman ousts Calibri"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Our studio, LucasFonts, designed Calibri. Here are our CEO Luc(as) de Groot’s thoughts on the matter:&lt;p&gt;The decision to abandon Calibri on the grounds of it being a so-called “wasteful diversity font” is both amusing and regrettable. Calibri was specifically designed to enhance readability on modern computer screens and was selected by Microsoft in 2007 to replace Times New Roman as the default font in the Office suite. There were sound reasons for moving away from Times: Calibri performs exceptionally well at small sizes and on standard office monitors, whereas serif fonts like Times New Roman tend to appear more distorted. While serif fonts are well-suited to high-resolution displays, such as those found on modern smartphones, on typical office screens the serifs introduce unnecessary visual noise and can be particularly problematic for users with impaired vision, such as older adults.&lt;p&gt;Professional typography can be achieved with both serif and sans-serif fonts. However, Times New Roman—a typeface older than the current president—presents unique challenges. Originally crafted in Great Britain for newspaper printing, Times was optimised for paper, with each letterform meticulously cut and tested for specific sizes. In the digital era, larger size drawings were repurposed as models, resulting in a typeface that appears too thin and sharp when printed at high quality.&lt;p&gt;Serif fonts are often perceived as more traditional, but they are also more demanding to use effectively. While a skilled typographer can, in theory, produce excellent results with Times, using it in its default digital form is not considered professional practice.&lt;p&gt;Calibri, by contrast, incorporates extensive spacing adjustments and language-specific refinements. The digital version of Times New Roman, developed in the early days of computing, offers only minimal kerning and letter-pair adjustments. This is especially evident in words set in all capitals—such as “CHICAGO”—where the spacing is inconsistent: the letters “HIC” are tightly packed, while “CAG” are spaced too far apart. Microsoft cannot rectify these issues without altering the appearance of existing documents.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 10:02:44 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46229533</link><dc:creator>LucasFonts</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46229533</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46229533</guid></item><item><title>New comment by satvikpendem in "Vibe coding is mad depressing"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;This article is not about vibe coding per se, it's about not having strong boundaries between you as the developer, and your client. You should not be allowing the client to dictate how you work, much less them having the permissions to merge in code. This was true before AI too, where clients might say, do X this way, and you should simply say no, because they are paying for &lt;i&gt;your&lt;/i&gt; expertise*. It's like hiring a plumber then trying to tell them how to fix the toilet.&lt;p&gt;*as an aside, this reminds me of the classic joke where the client asks for the price list for a developer's services:&lt;p&gt;I do it: $500&lt;p&gt;I do it, but you watch: $750&lt;p&gt;I do it, and you help: $1,000&lt;p&gt;You do it yourself: $5,000&lt;p&gt;You start it, and you want me to finish it: $10,000&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 04:18:44 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46227607</link><dc:creator>satvikpendem</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46227607</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46227607</guid></item><item><title>New comment by doctoboggan in "How Google Maps allocates survival across London's restaurants"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;It's always annoyed me that zooming in on a building will not reliably show the business that operates there. I understand that at low zoom levels you may need to filter what is displayed based on the high density, but when I zoom in I want to see everything that is there. Sometimes I am forced to go to street view to read the sign, then type the company name into the search box to force the business marker to show up and get clickable.&lt;p&gt;I've found Apple Maps is a little better in this regard. They show a higher density of business markers at any given zoom level.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 00:28:19 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46226092</link><dc:creator>doctoboggan</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46226092</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46226092</guid></item><item><title>New comment by brokenmachine in "Valve: HDMI Forum Continues to Block HDMI 2.1 for Linux"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Reading a standards spec to understand what the device you paid for does?&lt;p&gt;Straight to jail!&lt;p&gt;Pirating the entire internet to train your AI?&lt;p&gt;That's fair use.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 22:34:47 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46224924</link><dc:creator>brokenmachine</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46224924</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46224924</guid></item><item><title>New comment by pinkmuffinere in "Rubio stages font coup: Times New Roman ousts Calibri"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;When I read the headline i thought “well obviously they don’t mean Marco Rubio, there must be some famous publicist or something”. Cannot believe it actually was Marco Rubio, lol&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 22:30:35 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46224867</link><dc:creator>pinkmuffinere</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46224867</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46224867</guid></item><item><title>New comment by roenxi in "Australia begins enforcing world-first teen social media ban"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Well, yes but the other problem is this is putting authoritarians in charge of more stuff. I had a comment comparing this to allowing people to eat too much food and that is literally where the logical outcome of this sort of thinking goes - it happens in practice, that isn't some sort of theoretical risk. The more the government decides what people can and can't want to do the worse the potential gets when they make mistakes. And this is further normalising the government making decisions about speech where they have every incentive and tendency to shut down people who tell inconvenient and important truths.&lt;p&gt;The risks are not worth the rewards of half-heatedly trying to stop kids communicating with other kids. They're still going to bully each other and what have you. They're still going to develop unrealistic expectations. They're probably even still going to use social media in practice.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 21:41:07 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46224269</link><dc:creator>roenxi</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46224269</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46224269</guid></item><item><title>New comment by indymike in "Australia begins enforcing world-first teen social media ban"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Father of five here, and founder of a social media marketing company (exited).   Our kids are up against problems we didn't have during the great expansion of social. The three big things:&lt;p&gt;1. State level actors and well funded not for profits are fighting an information war to influence our kids. And they are very good at it. Down to having troll farms to talk one on one. Every time something new happens in the world, my younger kids ask me about what they saw on Tik-Tok and their initial understanding is shaped by a well funded actor, and is often completely a false narrative. The solution is be open and talk about it with your kids.&lt;p&gt;2. Criminals are even better at social than state level actors. They are smooth. And they are on platforms you wouldn't expect - like games. And criminals aren't all about fraud. They sell drugs, they try to physically steal in real life from your kids,they'll try to get your kids to do something embarrasing and blackmail them with it, and even can be human traffickers. Again, the solution is be open and talk about it with your kids - and make sure they know it's ok to ask, and it's especially ok if you think I shouldn't share this with Dad or they person is saying not to show your parents.&lt;p&gt;3. Sexual predators are even better at social than the criminals. The difference is that the predators can't hide behind national borders so they are very careful. Same solution as $#2, but this one is really tough because when your kids come to you about it, they may have shared something with the predator that the predator is using to extort them into hooking up. Don't attack or blame your kid, focus on making sure the predator never gets to them&lt;p&gt;I do not believe for a minute that social media was good for my kids as they grew up, but I'm not sure that you can even begin to fix it the way AU is trying to - regulating speech, association using prohibition is dipping a colander in the river to filter the silt.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 21:04:31 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46223824</link><dc:creator>indymike</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46223824</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46223824</guid></item><item><title>New comment by zmmmmm in "Australia begins enforcing world-first teen social media ban"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;A lot of the criticism is based on the concept that it won't be technically watertight. But the key is that it doesn't have to be watertight to work. Social media is all about network effects. Once most kids are on there, everyone has to be on there. If you knock the percentage down far enough, you break the network effect to the point where those who don't want to don't feel pressured to. If that is all it does, it's a benefit.&lt;p&gt;My concerns about this are that it will lead to&lt;p&gt;(a) normalising people uploading identification documents and hence lead to people becoming victims of scams. This won't be just kids - scammers will be challenging all kinds of people including vulnerable elderly people saying "this is why we need your id". People are going to lose their entire life savings because of this law.&lt;p&gt;(b) a small fraction of kids branching off into fringe networks that are off the radar and will take them to very dark places very quickly.&lt;p&gt;Because it's politically unattractive, I don't think enough attention has been given to the harms that will flow from these laws.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 21:02:51 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46223802</link><dc:creator>zmmmmm</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46223802</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46223802</guid></item><item><title>New comment by gabriel666smith in "Gundam is just the same as Jane Austen but happens to include giant mech suits"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;"It is a truth universally acknowledged that a single man in possession of a good fortune must be in want of a robot suit to ride around and fight things with."&lt;p&gt;I was visiting Jane Austen's House Museum last year and it always gives me pleasure to see how wildly popular her work remains. There always seem to be tourists there visiting from all over the world. That is really heartening.&lt;p&gt;She was very innovative. Maybe even underrated as a craftsperson at the sentence level. My favourite trick that I believe she invented is slipping from prose into a soft Iambic pentameter, essentially unnoticed. Lots of people have copied that from her.&lt;p&gt;And class-pressure narratives will never not be relevant to people's lives. She's a very very humane storyteller in that respect.&lt;p&gt;I am slightly biased - she's my great aunt (x 6). Used to find that embarrassing but now I feel quite proud.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 19:58:15 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46222858</link><dc:creator>gabriel666smith</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46222858</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46222858</guid></item><item><title>New comment by kscarlet in "Is it a bubble?"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;The line right after this is much worse:&lt;p&gt;&gt; Coding performed by AI is at a world-class level, something that wasn’t so just a year ago.&lt;p&gt;Wow, finance people certainly don't understand programming.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 19:20:54 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46222269</link><dc:creator>kscarlet</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46222269</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46222269</guid></item><item><title>New comment by ethin in "Valve: HDMI Forum Continues to Block HDMI 2.1 for Linux"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;We really need to just force all standards organizations to release their standards for free. No making you pay $300 or whatever for a standard. (The PCI SIG makes you pay like $5000 for access to the PCIe standard...)&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 18:47:12 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46221748</link><dc:creator>ethin</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46221748</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46221748</guid></item><item><title>New comment by dang in "Israel used Palantir technologies in pager attack in Lebanon"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;All: before commenting here, please verify that you're feeling something different—&lt;i&gt;quite&lt;/i&gt; different—from anger and a desire to fight this war. That is not what HN is for, and destroys what it is for.&lt;p&gt;This site is for curious, thoughtful, respectful, and &lt;i&gt;kind&lt;/i&gt; interaction—most of all with those you may disagree with, regardless of how bad they are or you feel they are.&lt;p&gt;If that's not possible, it's ok not to post. We'd rather have a thread with no comments than a thread with aggressive comments, let alone nationalistic or religious flamewar. There is far too much aggression in the thread below, which is is understandable, but please don't add more. It provides a fleeting sensation of relief, but then it just makes everything worse.&lt;p&gt;Note this, from &lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/newsguidelines.html"&gt;https://news.ycombinator.com/newsguidelines.html&lt;/a&gt;: "&lt;i&gt;Comments should get more thoughtful and substantive, not less, as a topic gets more divisive.&lt;/i&gt;"&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 18:32:28 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46221528</link><dc:creator>dang</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46221528</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46221528</guid></item><item><title>New comment by sp4cec0wb0y in "Is it a bubble?"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&gt; In many advanced software teams, developers no longer write the code; they type in what they want, and AI systems generate the code for them.&lt;p&gt;What a wild and speculative claim. Is there any source for this information?&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 18:26:13 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46221430</link><dc:creator>sp4cec0wb0y</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46221430</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46221430</guid></item><item><title>New comment by feb012025 in "Australia begins enforcing world-first teen social media ban"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I feel like everyone in this thread is assuming this is a good faith move by Australia to help kids in school and with socialization.&lt;p&gt;I think phones and social media are harmful, but I get the sense there's a political motive behind this. We've been hearing politicians complain for years that they're losing the youth when it comes to long-standing foreign policy positions, etc... And suddenly they ban social media. Rahm Emanuel is campaigning for the same thing in America.&lt;p&gt;I don't believe they're overly concerned with "helping the kids" unfortunately&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 18:24:07 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46221402</link><dc:creator>feb012025</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46221402</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46221402</guid></item><item><title>New comment by jsheard in "Valve: HDMI Forum Continues to Block HDMI 2.1 for Linux"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;No, the issue here is that the HDMI 2.1 NDA is so strict that releasing an open source implementation is forbidden no matter how much you pay them. AMD has access to the specs, they've implemented it in hardware and in their closed source Windows driver, but they're not allowed to add it to their open source Linux driver.&lt;p&gt;Nvidia does support HDMI 2.1 on Linux since their driver is closed source (but that causes its own problems). Maybe AMD could compromise by releasing a minimal binary blob which only exposes the HDMI 2.1 implementation and nothing else.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 17:56:07 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46220995</link><dc:creator>jsheard</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46220995</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46220995</guid></item><item><title>New comment by chrismorgan in "Size of Life"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;The dynamic soundscape is delightful, as it subtly adds instruments and musical texture as you progress. And going back down the scale regresses it to simple again. Smoothly done.&lt;p&gt;It reminded me of Operation Neptune (1991): each level starts with just one channel, probably percussion, and as you progress through the rooms it adds and removes more channels or sometimes switches to a different section of music. It is unfortunately all sharp cuts, no attempts at smoothing or timing instrument entry and exit. A couple of samples: &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=S0LNaatyoQk" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=S0LNaatyoQk&lt;/a&gt; is an hour of gameplay revelling in “the dynamic and sometimes beautiful music of Operation Neptune” using a Roland MT-32 MIDI synthesiser; and &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=wPxEdQ4wx9s&amp;list=PL3FC048B134B3D9D8&amp;index=8" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=wPxEdQ4wx9s&amp;list=PL3FC048B13...&lt;/a&gt; is the PCM files used on some platforms (if you want to compare that track with the MT-32, it starts at 28 minutes).&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 17:29:37 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46220623</link><dc:creator>chrismorgan</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46220623</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46220623</guid></item><item><title>New comment by cs702 in "Size of Life"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Beautiful.&lt;/i&gt; It's clearly a labor of love.&lt;p&gt;The authors deserve our support. Buy them a coffee via the provided link.&lt;p&gt;Thank you for sharing this on HN.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 17:17:26 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46220449</link><dc:creator>cs702</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46220449</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46220449</guid></item><item><title>New comment by mongrelion in "DeepSeek uses banned Nvidia chips for AI model, report says"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I recommend everyone to watch GamersNexus' documentary on the NVIDIA AI GPU black market.
They explain how companies like DeepSeek can get a hold of chips that are otherwise banned by the US government to export to China&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=1H3xQaf7BFI" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=1H3xQaf7BFI&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 17:03:23 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46220255</link><dc:creator>mongrelion</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46220255</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46220255</guid></item><item><title>New comment by jll29 in "Show HN: Gemini Pro 3 imagines the HN front page 10 years from now"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;AI professor here. I know this page is a joke, but in the interest of accuracy, a terminological comment: we don't call it a "hallucination" if a model complies exactly with what a prompt asked for and produces a prediction, exactly as requested.&lt;p&gt;Rater, "hallucinations" are spurious replacements of factual knowledge with fictional material caused by the use of statistical process (the pseudo random number generator used with the "temperature" parameter of neural transformers): token prediction without meaning representation.&lt;p&gt;[typo fixed]&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 12:24:58 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46216933</link><dc:creator>jll29</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46216933</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46216933</guid></item><item><title>New comment by tzury in "Rust in the kernel is no longer experimental"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;  &gt; Mike: rachel and i are no longer dating
  &gt;
  &gt; rachel: mike that's a horrible way of telling people we're married
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
from the meme section on that page.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 07:29:10 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46215090</link><dc:creator>tzury</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46215090</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46215090</guid></item><item><title>New comment by sho_hn in "Rust in the kernel is no longer experimental"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I absolutely understand the sentiment, but LWN is a second-to-none publication that on this rare occasion couldn't resist the joke, and also largely plays to an audience who will immediately understand that it's tongue-in-cheek.&lt;p&gt;Speaking as a subscriber of about two decades who perhaps wouldn't have a career without the enormous amount of high-quality education provided by LWN content, or at least a far lesser one: Let's forgive.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 04:06:35 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46213974</link><dc:creator>sho_hn</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46213974</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46213974</guid></item><item><title>New comment by arilotter in "Rust in the kernel is no longer experimental"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;This title is moderately clickbait-y and comes with a subtle implication that Rust might be getting removed from the kernel. IMO it should be changed to "Rust in the kernel is no longer experimental"&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 03:47:43 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46213850</link><dc:creator>arilotter</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46213850</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46213850</guid></item><item><title>New comment by WalterBright in "So you want to speak at software conferences?"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Some things I've learned over the years:&lt;p&gt;1. do not show a slide full of code. The font will be too small to read. Nobody will read it&lt;p&gt;2. don't read your slides to the audience. The audience can read&lt;p&gt;3. don't talk with your back to the audience&lt;p&gt;4. make your font as big as practical&lt;p&gt;5. 3 bullet points is ideal&lt;p&gt;6. add a picture now and then&lt;p&gt;7. don't bother with a copyright notice on every slide. It gets really old. Besides, you want people to steal your presentation!&lt;p&gt;8. avoid typing in code as part of the presentation, most of the time it won't work and it's boring watching somebody type&lt;p&gt;9. render the presentation as a pdf file, so any device can display it&lt;p&gt;10. email a copy of your presentation to the conference coordinator beforehand, put a copy on your laptop, and phone, and on a usb stick in your pocket. Arriving at the show without your presentation can be very embarrassing!&lt;p&gt;11. the anxiety goes away&lt;p&gt;12. don't worry about it. You're not running for President! Just have some fun with it&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 00:05:44 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46212412</link><dc:creator>WalterBright</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46212412</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46212412</guid></item><item><title>New comment by thomasm6m6 in "Show HN: Gemini Pro 3 imagines the HN front page 10 years from now"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Here it is: &lt;a href="https://sw.vtom.net/hn35/news.html" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://sw.vtom.net/hn35/news.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;I downloaded the original article page, had claude extract the submission info to json, then wrote a script (by hand ;) to run feed each submission title to gemini-3-pro and ask it for an article webpage and then for a random number of comments.&lt;p&gt;I was impressed by some of the things gemini came up with (or found buried in its latent space?). Highlights:&lt;p&gt;"You’re probably reading this via your NeuralLink summary anyway, so I’ll try to keep the entropy high enough to bypass the summarizer filters."&lt;p&gt;"This submission has been flagged by the Auto-Reviewer v7.0 due to high similarity with "Running DOOM on a Mitochondria" (2034)."&lt;p&gt;"Zig v1.0 still hasn't released (ETA 2036)"&lt;p&gt;The unprompted one-shot leetcode, youtube, and github clones&lt;p&gt;Nature: "Content truncated due to insufficient Social Credit Score or subscription status" / "Buy Article PDF - $89.00 USD" / "Log in with WorldCoin ID"&lt;p&gt;"Gemini Cloud Services (formerly Bard Enterprise, formerly Duet AI, formerly Google Brain Cloud, formerly Project Magfi)"&lt;p&gt;Github Copilot attempts social engineering to pwn the `sudo` repo&lt;p&gt;It made a Win10 "emulator" that goes only as far as displaying a "Windows Defender is out of date" alert message&lt;p&gt;"dang_autonomous_agent: We detached this subthread from &lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=8675309"&gt;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=8675309&lt;/a&gt; because it was devolving into a flame war about the definition of 'deprecation'."&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 23:33:43 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46212180</link><dc:creator>thomasm6m6</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46212180</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46212180</guid></item></channel></rss>