<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>Hacker News: Best Comments</title><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/bestcomments</link><description>Hacker News RSS</description><docs>https://hnrss.org/</docs><generator>hnrss v2.1.1</generator><lastBuildDate>Sat, 04 Oct 2025 00:20:54 +0000</lastBuildDate><ns0:link href="https://hnrss.org/bestcomments" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item><title>New comment by avalys in "I spent the day teaching seniors how to use an iPhone"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;The iPhone - and macOS too - used to be a paragon of simplicity.&lt;p&gt;Today the setup experience on a brand-new iPhone or Mac is abysmal. Entering the same username and password multiple times - then sometimes a different username and password - competing notifications, irrelevant feature nags, a popup from some random product manager about their pet thingy. Permission questions from some meddlesome privacy team about the feature you just said you wanted to turn on. Uncertainty about whether you’ll break something irreparably by “skipping” the expected setup path. A choice of several inscrutable interface modes because no one has the balls to commit to a single solution. Just terrible.&lt;p&gt;I guess this is what happens without a dictator to tell people they’re fired for shipping garbage, and when a company worries about meeting quarterly KPIs rather than doing something great.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2025 02:11:28 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45458107</link><dc:creator>avalys</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45458107</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45458107</guid></item><item><title>New comment by saurik in "Apple takes down ICE tracking apps after pressure from DOJ"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;FWIW, everyone who claims that Apple &lt;i&gt;fundamentally needs&lt;/i&gt; the centralized ability to control apps on their platforms "for everyone's safety" -- despite how that obviously and repeatedly makes them become patsies for governments all over the world to enforce their censorship regimes -- are complicit in this stuff (in addition, of course, to the people who build it at Apple...).&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2025 00:57:24 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45457502</link><dc:creator>saurik</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45457502</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45457502</guid></item><item><title>New comment by Animats in "How Israeli actions caused famine in Gaza, visualized"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;“Israel has built the most efficient starvation machine you can imagine.”&lt;/i&gt;&lt;p&gt;There's political opposition to this within Israel. Here's what happened to an elected member of the Knesset who spoke out against the cruelty in Gaza.[1] He was forcibly removed from the podium of the Knesset.&lt;p&gt;[1] &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=UzDxV7jnAos" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=UzDxV7jnAos&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2025 18:15:23 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45453320</link><dc:creator>Animats</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45453320</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45453320</guid></item><item><title>New comment by rubzah in "How Israeli actions caused famine in Gaza, visualized"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;There is simply no excuse for blocking the entry of food into a region wholesale. For that alone they should, at the very least, be an outcast in the international community. But here we are.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2025 10:57:19 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45448156</link><dc:creator>rubzah</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45448156</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45448156</guid></item><item><title>New comment by corry in "I only use Google Sheets"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Always overlooked point in these pro/anti-spreadsheet discussions:&lt;p&gt;A spreadsheet gives you a DB, a quickly and easily customized UI, and iterative / easy-to-debug data processing all in a package that everyone in the working world already understands. AND with a freedom that allows the creator to do it however they want. AND it's fairly portable.&lt;p&gt;You can build incredible things in spreadsheets. I remain convinced that it's the most creative and powerful piece of software we have available, especially so for people who can't code.&lt;p&gt;With that power and freedom comes downsides, sure; and we can debate the merits of it being online, or whether this or that vendor is preferable; but my deep appreciation for spreadsheets remains undiminished by these mere trifles.&lt;p&gt;It's the best authoring tool we've ever devised.&lt;p&gt;EDIT TO ADD: the only other thing that seems to 'rhyme' with spreadsheets in the same way is: HyperCard. Flexible workbench that let you stitch together applications, data, UX, etc. RIP HyperCard, may you be never forgotten.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 13:11:56 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45437297</link><dc:creator>corry</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45437297</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45437297</guid></item><item><title>New comment by the_duke in "Sora 2"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I haven't seen comments regarding a big factor here:&lt;p&gt;It seems like OpenAI is trying to turn Sora into a social network - TikTok but AI.&lt;p&gt;The webapp is heavily geared towards consumption, with a feed as the entry point, liking and commenting for posts, and user profiles having a prominent role.&lt;p&gt;The creation aspect seems about as important as on Instagram, TikTok etc - easily available, but not the primary focus.&lt;p&gt;Generated videos are very short, with minimal controls. The only selectable option is picking between landscape and portrait mode.&lt;p&gt;There is no mention or attempt to move towards long form videos, storylines, advanced editing/controls/etc, like others in this space (eg Google Flow).&lt;p&gt;Seems like they want to turn this into AITok.&lt;p&gt;Edit: regarding accurate physics ... check out these two videos below...&lt;p&gt;To be fair, Veo fails miserably with those prompts also.&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://sora.chatgpt.com/p/s_68dc32c7ddb081919e0f38d8e006163d" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://sora.chatgpt.com/p/s_68dc32c7ddb081919e0f38d8e006163...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://sora.chatgpt.com/p/s_68dc3339c26881918e45f61d9312e955" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://sora.chatgpt.com/p/s_68dc3339c26881918e45f61d9312e95...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;Veo:&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://veo-balldrop.wasmer.app/ballroll.mp4" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://veo-balldrop.wasmer.app/ballroll.mp4&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://veo-balldrop.wasmer.app/balldrop.mp4" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://veo-balldrop.wasmer.app/balldrop.mp4&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;Couldn't help but mock them a little, here is a bit of fun... the prompt adherence is pretty good, at least.&lt;p&gt;NOTE: there are plenty of quite impressive videos being posted, and a lot of horrible ones also.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2025 19:37:24 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45430197</link><dc:creator>the_duke</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45430197</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45430197</guid></item><item><title>New comment by scrlk in "Boeing has started working on a 737 MAX replacement"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;To add to this &amp; the Jobs interview - an oil industry proverb: a healthy oil company has a geologist in charge, a mature one has an engineer in charge, a declining one has an accountant in charge, and a dying one has a lawyer in charge.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2025 18:41:12 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45429423</link><dc:creator>scrlk</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45429423</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45429423</guid></item><item><title>New comment by nostrademons in "Boeing has started working on a 737 MAX replacement"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;It'll be interesting to see if they still &lt;i&gt;can&lt;/i&gt; design and build a new ground-up airplane design.  The last all-new design was the 787, initiated in 2003 and launched in 2009, and its design was fraught with problems.  Before then was the 777 in the early 90s (pre-McDonnell takeover), and the 757/767 in the early 80s.&lt;p&gt;There's a phenomena that ofter occurs with large organizations where once their markets mature, everybody who &lt;i&gt;can&lt;/i&gt; build a product end-to-end leaves or gets forced out, leaving only people with highly specialized maintenance skillsets.  The former group has no work to do, after all, so why should the company keep them around?  But then if the market ecosystem shifts, and a new product is necessary, they no longer have the capacity to build ground-up new products.  All those people have left, and won't come anywhere near the company.&lt;p&gt;Steve Jobs spoke eloquently about this phenomena in an old interview:&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=K1WrHH-WtaA" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=K1WrHH-WtaA&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2025 18:08:42 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45428997</link><dc:creator>nostrademons</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45428997</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45428997</guid></item><item><title>New comment by mrkeen in "Comprehension debt: A ticking time bomb of LLM-generated code"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;This was a pre-existing problem, even if reliance on LLMs is making it worse.&lt;p&gt;Naur (&lt;a href="https://gwern.net/doc/cs/algorithm/1985-naur.pdf" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://gwern.net/doc/cs/algorithm/1985-naur.pdf&lt;/a&gt;) called it "theory building":&lt;p&gt;&gt; The death of a program happens when the programmer team possessing its theory is dissolved. A dead program may
continue to be used for execution in a computer and to produce useful results. The actual state of death becomes visible when demands for modifications of the program cannot be intelligently answered. Revival of a program is the rebuilding of its theory by a new programmer team.&lt;p&gt;Lamport calls it "programming ≠ coding", where programming is "what you want to achieve and how" and coding is telling the computer how to do it.&lt;p&gt;I strongly agree with all of this.  Even if your dev team skipped any kind of theory-building or modelling phase, they'd still passively absorb some of the model while typing the code into the computer.  I think that it's this last resort of &lt;i&gt;incidental&lt;/i&gt; model building that the LLM replaces.&lt;p&gt;I suspect that there is a strong correlation between programmers who don't think that there needs to be a model/theory, and those who are reporting that LLMs are speeding them up.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2025 11:53:07 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45424366</link><dc:creator>mrkeen</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45424366</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45424366</guid></item><item><title>New comment by CaptainOfCoit in "iRobot Founder: Don't Believe the AI and Robotics Hype"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;One quote that really stood out to me:&lt;p&gt;&gt; Rodney: The robots—they’re not embodied. I always say about a physical robot, the physical appearance makes a promise about what it can do. The Roomba was this little disc on the floor. It didn’t promise much—you saw it and thought, that’s not going to clean the windows. But you can imagine it cleaning the floor. But the human form sort of promises it can do anything a human can. And that’s why it’s so attractive to people—it’s selling a promise that is amazing.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2025 01:35:54 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45421019</link><dc:creator>CaptainOfCoit</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45421019</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45421019</guid></item><item><title>New comment by cjflog in "Ask HN: What are you working on? (September 2025)"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Currently a one-man side project:&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://laboratory.love" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://laboratory.love&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;Last year PlasticList discovered that 86% of food products they tested contain plastic chemicals—including 100% of baby food tested. The EU just lowered their "safe" BPA limit by 20,000x. Meanwhile, the FDA allows levels 100x higher than what Europe considers safe.&lt;p&gt;This seemed like a solvable problem.&lt;p&gt;Laboratory.love lets you crowdfund independent testing of specific products you actually buy. Think Consumer Reports meets Kickstarter, but focused on detecting endocrine disruptors in your yogurt, your kid's snacks, whatever you're curious about.&lt;p&gt;Here's how it works: Find a product (or suggest one), contribute to its testing fund, get detailed lab results when testing completes. If a product doesn't reach its funding goal within 365 days, automatic refund. All results are published openly. Laboratory.love uses the same methodology as PlasticList.org, which found plastic chemicals in everything from prenatal vitamins to ice cream. But instead of researchers choosing what to test, you do.&lt;p&gt;The bigger picture: Companies respond to market pressure. Transparency creates that pressure. When consumers have data, supply chains get cleaner.&lt;p&gt;Technical details: Laboratory.love works with ISO 17025-accredited labs, test three samples from different production lots, detect chemicals down to parts per billion. The testing protocol is public.&lt;p&gt;So far a couple dozen products have received some funding, six products have been fully funded (five product results published, the sixth is at the lab as I write this!)&lt;p&gt;You can browse products, add your own, or just follow specific items you're curious about: &lt;a href="https://laboratory.love" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://laboratory.love&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2025 21:10:22 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45418794</link><dc:creator>cjflog</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45418794</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45418794</guid></item><item><title>New comment by simonw in "Claude Sonnet 4.5"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I had access to a preview over the weekend, I published some notes here: &lt;a href="https://simonwillison.net/2025/Sep/29/claude-sonnet-4-5/" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://simonwillison.net/2025/Sep/29/claude-sonnet-4-5/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;It's very good - I think probably a tiny bit better than GPT-5-Codex, based on vibes more than a comprehensive comparison (there are plenty of benchmarks out there that attempt to be more methodical than vibes).&lt;p&gt;It particularly shines when you try it on &lt;a href="https://claude.ai/" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://claude.ai/&lt;/a&gt; using its brand new Python/Node.js code interpreter mode. Try this prompt and see what happens:&lt;p&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;  Checkout https://github.com/simonw/llm and run the tests with
  
  pip install -e '.[test]'
  pytest
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
I then had it iterate on a pretty complex database refactoring task, described in my post.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2025 18:23:52 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45417062</link><dc:creator>simonw</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45417062</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45417062</guid></item><item><title>New comment by fuzz_junket in "Google appears to have deleted its political ad archive for the EU"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Archivist here. Google is not an archive. Neither is Tumblr or Flickr or any other platform that might delete your content at any time. They're companies and it's their job to make money. This is why my profession exists. We don't make money, which is why we're not well funded, but we have a whole lot of training, technical knowledge, and professional ethics around saving information and making it accessible. If you want to preserve your records, talk to an archivist because you can't assume some faceless corporation will do it for you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2025 12:40:34 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45412988</link><dc:creator>fuzz_junket</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45412988</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45412988</guid></item><item><title>New comment by eterm in "What if I don't want videos of my hobby time available to the world?"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I wonder if it's a generational or cultural difference present in the comments here.&lt;p&gt;I am sympathetic to the author, and I also find video a bit invasive of privacy in a way that photos aren't.&lt;p&gt;I therefore find the (obviously common) attitude that videos are just "something you need to accept" quite alien, but I wonder how much of that attitude is just comments coming from a younger generation that have grown up with the idea that they're recorded all the time.&lt;p&gt;I'm old enough thankfully to have grown up without video being present, that's probably not true for someone 10 years younger than me.&lt;p&gt;There's also a big difference in my mind between, "You might be filmed on occassion" and, "A recording of this goes up on youtube every single week".&lt;p&gt;With the former you can still reasonably anonymous, with the latter you risk becoming a side character in someone elses' parasocial relationship.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2025 12:03:49 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45412654</link><dc:creator>eterm</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45412654</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45412654</guid></item><item><title>New comment by marc_abonce in "F-Droid and Google’s developer registration decree"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&gt; F-Droid is different. It distributes apps that have been validated to work for the user’s interests, rather than for the interests of the app’s distributors.&lt;p&gt;F-Droid's curation saved me at least once when I wanted to upgrade my Simple™ apps and couldn't find them in F-Droid anymore, which led me to learn that SimpleMobileTools was sold to a company that closed sourced the apps[1] and that there's a free fork called Fossify[2].&lt;p&gt;Had I installed these through Google Play, they wouldn't have cared about this particular change and I would've gotten whatever random upgrades the new owners pushed.&lt;p&gt;Each app store's policies have their pros and cons, but that's why it's so important to have a diversity of marketplaces.&lt;p&gt;[1] &lt;a href="https://github.com/SimpleMobileTools/General-Discussion/issues/241" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://github.com/SimpleMobileTools/General-Discussion/issu...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;[2] &lt;a href="https://github.com/FossifyOrg" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://github.com/FossifyOrg&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2025 06:15:12 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45410805</link><dc:creator>marc_abonce</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45410805</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45410805</guid></item><item><title>New comment by anilgulecha in "F-Droid and Google’s developer registration decree"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;F-droid has been stellar in steering the alternative app store environment over the past 15 years or so, and I'd heed their call on this.&lt;p&gt;A small call to any googler on the thread - put your support towards this internally. I understand the internal dynamics, and it may seem current option is best amongst imperfect choices, but in this case F-droid is right in that closing out anonymous (but good) software is a line crossed with peril for any open ecosystem. Today it's play store, tomorrow it will be the web, and that will have a significant negative impact on Google.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2025 05:48:11 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45410665</link><dc:creator>anilgulecha</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45410665</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45410665</guid></item><item><title>New comment by PessimalDecimal in "The AI coding trap"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&gt; I would love to see an anti-AI take that doesn't hinge on the idea that technology forces people to be lazy/careless/thoughtless.&lt;p&gt;The article sort of goes sideways with this idea but pointing out that AI coding robs you a deep understanding of the code it produces is a valid and important criticism of AI coding.&lt;p&gt;A software engineer's primary job isn't producing code, but producing a functional software system. Most important to that is the extremely hard to convey "mental model" of how the code works and an expertise of the domain it works in. Code is a derived asset of this mental model. And you will never know code as well as a reader and you would have as the author for anything larger than a very small project.&lt;p&gt;There are other consequences of not building this mental model of a piece of software. Reasoning at the level of syntax is proving to have limits that LLM-based coding agents are having trouble scaling beyond.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 28 Sep 2025 16:30:01 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45405638</link><dc:creator>PessimalDecimal</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45405638</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45405638</guid></item><item><title>New comment by shredprez in "The AI coding trap"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I would love to see an anti-AI take that doesn't hinge on the idea that technology forces people to be lazy/careless/thoughtless.&lt;p&gt;The plan-build-test-reflect loop is equally important when using an LLM to generate code, as anyone who's seriously used the tech knows: if you yolo your way through a build without thought, it will collapse in on itself quickly. But if you DO apply that loop, you get to spend much more time on the part I personally enjoy, architecting the build and testing the resultant experience.&lt;p&gt;&gt; While the LLMs get to blast through all the fun, easy work at lightning speed, we are then left with all the thankless tasks&lt;p&gt;This is, to me, the root of one disagreement I see playing out in every industry where AI has achieved any level of mastery. There's a divide between people who enjoy the physical experience of the work and people who enjoy the mental experience of the work. If the thinking bit is your favorite part, AI allows you to spend nearly all of your time there if you wish, from concept through troubleshooting. But if you like the doing, the typing, fiddling with knobs and configs, etc etc, all AI does is take the good part away.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 28 Sep 2025 16:04:52 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45405383</link><dc:creator>shredprez</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45405383</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45405383</guid></item><item><title>New comment by armchairhacker in "When I say “alphabetical order”, I mean “alphabetical order”"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I agree with Microsoft/Google/KDE's order. The author's situation is extremely rare, and the situation where someone wants "10" to be before "9" is far more common. Moreover, desktops don't label this sorting "alphabetical" (E: and it would really be "lexicographic"*), they label it "by name" (an informal criteria), so technically they're not lying.&lt;p&gt;&gt; I miss the time when computers did what you told them to, instead of trying to read your mind.&lt;p&gt;You may be looking at that time through rose-tinted glasses. I don't like when computers &lt;i&gt;lie&lt;/i&gt; to me either, but "mind-reading" is really helpful in ways we take for granted, like autosave. Desktops can have an option to sort files truly alphabetically, but the more common case should always be the default; that's the definition of "intuitive".&lt;p&gt;* &lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45404022#45405279"&gt;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45404022#45405279&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 28 Sep 2025 15:57:25 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45405300</link><dc:creator>armchairhacker</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45405300</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45405300</guid></item><item><title>New comment by jqpabc123 in "Privacy Badger is a free browser extension made by EFF to stop spying"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Privacy Badger doesn’t block ads unless they happen to be tracking you; in fact, one of our goals is to incentivize advertisers to adopt better privacy practices.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;p&gt;There is an easy solution to this --- it is called "context sensitive" advertising. And the idea is simple --- ads are prioritized based on what you're currently viewing, not your viewing history (aka "personalized ads").&lt;p&gt;What's wrong with "personalized ads"?  They are fundamentally rooted in the past --- and the past is often no longer relevant.  Just because I searched for a car last week doesn't mean I haven't bought one already --- so why am I seeing auto ads when I search for pet supplies?. But if I'm currently looking at an auto dealers web site, the odds are pretty good that I'm still interested in buying one.&lt;p&gt;What's wrong with advertisers? Without any real proof, they have bought into this vision of advertising that is illogical, ineffective and simply not true in many cases --- the idea that personal browsing history is a good indicator of the future.&lt;p&gt;In the process, they have surrendered their ad budgets to a "black box" process that they have no insight into or control over and can be easily manipulated against them.&lt;p&gt;So why do I care?  Because we *all* pay a price for this.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 28 Sep 2025 13:25:29 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45404178</link><dc:creator>jqpabc123</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45404178</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45404178</guid></item><item><title>New comment by firefoxd in "A WebGL game where you deliver messages on a tiny planet"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;The font? The art style? The fluidity on a mobile device? It's fantastic.&lt;p&gt;I wasn't able to deliver packages but I was too mesmerized to be mad about that. Beautiful game. Kudos.&lt;p&gt;Edit: I did figure it out and completed all the deliveries. So many potential. It reminds me a bit of Sky by thatgamecompany&lt;p&gt;Edit 2: for the author, I noticed several players approached me and tried to communicate. Please explore games like Journey (thatgamecompany) to see different ways people communicate without chatting. People can help each other, veterans can guide newbies all without using words. Every time I met a player in the game back in the days, they sent me a heartfelt message.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 27 Sep 2025 16:36:27 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45397294</link><dc:creator>firefoxd</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45397294</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45397294</guid></item><item><title>New comment by mr-karan in "Typst: A Possible LaTeX Replacement"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;It's great to see Typst getting more visibility. We migrated a real-world workload to it a couple of years back: generating and e-mailing 1.5M+ PDFs daily at my org, Zerodha.&lt;p&gt;Our previous pipeline was LaTeX-based (first pdflatex, then lualatex), but we were constantly fighting cryptic memory errors on large documents and huge Docker image sizes that slowed down boot times of our ephemeral workers.&lt;p&gt;Switching to Typst was a massive win for us. The single static binary resulted in tiny images and faster boot times. More importantly, the performance gains were huge. Overall compile times were ~3–4× faster than LaTeX. On really large documents (2000+ pages, mostly tables), Typst compiles in ~1 minute vs. ~18 minutes with lualatex.&lt;p&gt;Beyond performance, the better developer experience and good error messages was a nice bonus too.&lt;p&gt;We wrote a detailed post about the entire architecture - from the job orchestration with Nomad to the S3 optimizations and the Typst migration in particular. If you're curious, you can read it here: &lt;a href="https://zerodha.tech/blog/1-5-million-pdfs-in-25-minutes" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://zerodha.tech/blog/1-5-million-pdfs-in-25-minutes&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 27 Sep 2025 09:59:47 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45394479</link><dc:creator>mr-karan</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45394479</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45394479</guid></item><item><title>New comment by RobKohr in "US cities pay too much for buses"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;"Federal funding typically covers 80% of bus purchases, with agencies responsible for the remainder."&lt;p&gt;Well, there is your answer. The one making the purchase isn't the one primarily paying for the purchase. This makes them less sensitive to pricing.&lt;p&gt;Kinda like how expensive healthcare is since it is paid for by insurance.&lt;p&gt;Or how you don't care how much you put on your plate or what you choose to eat at an all you can eat buffet.&lt;p&gt;The second you detach the consumer from the price of something, even through an intermediary such as health insurance, that is when they stop caring about how much something costs, and so the price jumps.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 26 Sep 2025 19:11:14 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45389953</link><dc:creator>RobKohr</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45389953</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45389953</guid></item><item><title>New comment by aftergibson in "Britain to introduce compulsory digital ID for workers"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;A secure, optional digital ID could be useful. But not in today’s UK. Why? Because the state has already shown it can’t be trusted with our data.&lt;p&gt;- Snoopers’ Charter (Investigatory Powers Act 2016): ISPs must keep a year’s worth of records of which websites you visit. More than 40 agencies—from MI5 to the Welsh Ambulance Service—can request it. MI5 has already broken the rules and kept data it shouldn’t have.&lt;p&gt;- Encryption backdoors: Ministers can issue “Technical Capability Notices” to force tech firms to weaken or bypass end-to-end encryption.&lt;p&gt;- Online Safety Act: Expands content-scanning powers that experts warn could undermine privacy for everyone.&lt;p&gt;- Palantir deals: The government has given £1.5 billion+ in contracts to a US surveillance firm that builds predictive-policing tools and runs the NHS’s new Federated Data Platform. Many of those deals are secret.&lt;p&gt;- Wall-to-wall cameras: Millions of CCTV cameras already make the UK one of the most surveilled countries in the world.&lt;p&gt;A universal digital ID would plug straight into this ecosystem, creating an always-on, uniquely identified record of where you go and what you do. Even if paper or card options exist on paper, smartphone-based systems will dominate in practice, leaving those without phones excluded or coerced.&lt;p&gt;I’m not against digital identity in principle. But until the UK government proves it can protect basic privacy—by rolling back mass data retention, ending encryption backdoor demands, and enforcing genuine oversight—any national digital ID is a surveillance power-grab waiting to happen.&lt;p&gt;I'm certain it's worked well in other countries, but I have zero trust in the UK government to handle this responsibility.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 26 Sep 2025 11:52:27 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45385420</link><dc:creator>aftergibson</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45385420</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45385420</guid></item><item><title>New comment by codeulike in "No reachable chess position with more than 218 moves"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;They dont really spell it out but they mean "from this position the player has 218 possible legal moves to choose from"&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 26 Sep 2025 06:51:47 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45383525</link><dc:creator>codeulike</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45383525</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45383525</guid></item><item><title>New comment by donmcronald in "Evanston orders Flock to remove reinstalled cameras"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Even though it's become commonplace in the last 20 years, I'm still shocked to see how companies can pretty much ignore the law, do whatever they want, and have everyone involved shielded from any kind of significant consequences.&lt;p&gt;In situations like this, I think the person at the top of the chain that told employees to perform the illegal installations should be arrested and charged.  On top of that, the company should be fined into bankruptcy.  If the directors knew about it any companies they're involved with shouldn't be allowed to conduct future business in the municipality (or state).&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 26 Sep 2025 05:24:17 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45382972</link><dc:creator>donmcronald</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45382972</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45382972</guid></item><item><title>New comment by txrx0000 in "ChatControl: EU wants to scan all private messages, even in encrypted apps"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Dear citizens of the EU:&lt;p&gt;If this gets pushed through, you will gradually lose control of your government much like how the people of the UK already lost control of theirs.&lt;p&gt;What are you going to do when the government's interests inevitably drift out of alignment with yours? Start a political movement? You will have the police knocking on your door for criticizing the establishment.&lt;p&gt;Start a revolution? You have no weapons. You can't even organize a resistance because all channels of communication are monitored.&lt;p&gt;You have neither the pen nor the sword. There is no longer an incentive for the government to serve you, and so it eventually won't.&lt;p&gt;No amount of protest will recover the freedom you once had. You're heading towards a society where everyone feels oppressed but no one can do anything about it.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2025 20:06:25 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45378256</link><dc:creator>txrx0000</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45378256</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45378256</guid></item><item><title>New comment by SirensOfTitan in "ChatGPT Pulse"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;My pulse today is just a mediocre rehash of prior conversations I’ve had on the platform.&lt;p&gt;I tried to ask GPT-5 pro the other day to just pick an ambitious project it wanted to work on, and I’d carry out whatever physical world tasks it needed me to, and all it did was just come up with project plans which were rehashes of my prior projects framed as its own.&lt;p&gt;I’m rapidly losing interest in all of these tools. It feels like blockchain again in a lot of weird ways. Both will stick around, but fall well short of the tulip mania VCs and tech leaders have pushed.&lt;p&gt;I’ve long contended that tech has lost any soulful vision of the future, it’s just tactical money making all the way down.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2025 17:29:20 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45375992</link><dc:creator>SirensOfTitan</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45375992</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45375992</guid></item><item><title>New comment by neom in "ChatGPT Pulse"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Just connect everything folks, we'll proactively read everything, all the time, and you'll be a 10x human, trust us friends, just connect everything...&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2025 17:18:29 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45375792</link><dc:creator>neom</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45375792</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45375792</guid></item><item><title>New comment by haolez in "ChatControl: EU wants to scan all private messages, even in encrypted apps"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I think the challenge for society here is not to simply reject attempts like this, but how to prevent them from being pushed over and over until a specific context allows it to be approved.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2025 16:20:49 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45374802</link><dc:creator>haolez</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45374802</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45374802</guid></item></channel></rss>