<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>Hacker News: Best Comments</title><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/bestcomments</link><description>Hacker News RSS</description><docs>https://hnrss.org/</docs><generator>hnrss v2.1.1</generator><lastBuildDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 23:58:13 +0000</lastBuildDate><ns0:link href="https://hnrss.org/bestcomments" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item><title>New comment by chaps in "Police Said They Surveilled Woman Who Had an Abortion for Her 'Safety.'"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;A lot of folk tried to justify the situation as being not as bad as it sounded, citing the official narrative as a source of truth.&lt;p&gt;It's amazing to me that people will still trust police narratives.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 16:24:13 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45505173</link><dc:creator>chaps</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45505173</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45505173</guid></item><item><title>New comment by observationist in "Microsoft is plugging more holes that let you use Windows 11 without MS account"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Companies that cannot run their businesses responsibly at scale should not be allowed to run their business at that scale.&lt;p&gt;If Microsoft can't do it, if Apple, Google, Facebook, X , OpenAI can't do it, then maybe we shouldn't allow companies to operate at scales which inevitably lead to widespread consumer harm.&lt;p&gt;They should be required to provide human customer service, with some sort of legal liability to ensure their products perform as advertised, without an end-user having to spend tens or hundreds of hours chasing down a solution, spending thousands of dollars on a lawyer, and all the rest of the hassle.&lt;p&gt;This is a legislation and regulation issue - the data barons are exploiting the effective absence of any accountability for harms they casually inflict on the public, ranging from gotcha situations like the OP to viral self harm trends among kids to mass surveillance and commercial invasion of privacy.&lt;p&gt;Pirate everything, support open source, pay content creators directly.&lt;p&gt;If they want to have billions of users, they damn well better be able to handle each and every one of those users in a commercially responsible fashion, or they have no business operating at that scale. We should be done with the "oops, we're too big and we make too much money to care that we just casually wrecked your life, oh well!" If the solution is to force users to have to buy a new PC, or a new phone, or create a new account, or anything in that vein, it's almost intentional, and casually malicious.&lt;p&gt;It's not like these companies don't know what they're doing, they can simply afford not to care. Until there's regulation and accountability that's more expensive than ignoring the consumer casualties, things will continue to get worse.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 16:00:04 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45504830</link><dc:creator>observationist</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45504830</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45504830</guid></item><item><title>New comment by wseqyrku in "Who needs Git when you have 1M context windows?"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;"Who needs git when [..]"&lt;p&gt;No matter how that sentence ends, I weep for our industry.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 15:39:05 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45504527</link><dc:creator>wseqyrku</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45504527</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45504527</guid></item><item><title>New comment by Night_Thastus in "Microsoft is plugging more holes that let you use Windows 11 without MS account"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;My biggest annoyance is that I specifically bought a Windows 11 license, from the MS store, using my MS account. I did this because I assumed that if something went wrong, I would always be able to recover it. I could never 'lose' the key if it was tied to my account.&lt;p&gt;Well unfortunately, MS screwed me. When I upgraded my PC I was apparently supposed to transfer the license before deleting the old PC from my account. Doing it in the wrong order lost the license forever - no way to transfer it.&lt;p&gt;Despite having one license, one account, and one PC registered, MS refused to help. I tried to call support, but there are NO on-call support anymore. Only automated online support. No chat. Nothing. I tried over and over for a couple days and got nowhere.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 15:19:39 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45504231</link><dc:creator>Night_Thastus</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45504231</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45504231</guid></item><item><title>New comment by magtux in "Qualcomm to acquire Arduino"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;This is a recipe for disaster. Arduino is great for education/tinkering. Qualcomm won't sell you anything even if you are ready to commit to buying 1000s. I tried to source some Qualcomm chips for a startup @ 10k qty and was told there would be no information or support. Qualcomm can have a much bigger market if they simply open up some product lines for distribution like MediaTek do.&lt;p&gt;China has a way more vibrant, innovative hardware industry simply because you can source everything made by Chinese firms.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 14:04:45 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45503202</link><dc:creator>magtux</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45503202</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45503202</guid></item><item><title>New comment by phoehne in "Qualcomm to acquire Arduino"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Don't look at just the specs.  You also need to look at the board design and programming environment.  I've used the ESP32 native tools and they are a lot more complex than Arduino.  But I'm an embedded firmware developer, so it's kind of what I expect.  But I used an Arduino, with 5V tolerant outputs, to light up Halloween costumes for years.  I do it in 1 page of code that's I write in their IDE.  I don't have to set up an SDK.  And the Arudino API hides all the details I don't care about.  Especially if I'm really just slinging solder and wiring something up quick.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 13:46:53 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45503017</link><dc:creator>phoehne</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45503017</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45503017</guid></item><item><title>New comment by chpatrick in "Qualcomm to acquire Arduino"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;ESP stuff is so damn cheap and capable now I'm not sure what you would use Arduino for these days.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 13:34:12 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45502871</link><dc:creator>chpatrick</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45502871</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45502871</guid></item><item><title>New comment by murillians in "Qualcomm to acquire Arduino"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I only feel dread when I see a Qualcomm story on HN anymore.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 13:20:18 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45502731</link><dc:creator>murillians</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45502731</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45502731</guid></item><item><title>New comment by geerlingguy in "Qualcomm to acquire Arduino"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Additionally, they're launching their first joint product, the $44 Uno Q SBC, which has a Dragonwing SoC and STM32 microcontroller on an Uno form factor board[1].&lt;p&gt;It seems like Arduino will keep their brand, maintain their existing product lines, and continue building devices using other vendor's chips (besides Qualcomm), etc... but as with all acquisitions—I wonder how long that state of affairs will last.&lt;p&gt;Alternatives like the Pi RP2040/2350 and Espressif's vast selection of boards can fill the gaps, but Arduino was what got me and many people I know into microcontrollers, so I have a special fondness for them!&lt;p&gt;[1] &lt;a href="https://www.arduino.cc/product-uno-q" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://www.arduino.cc/product-uno-q&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 13:19:19 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45502719</link><dc:creator>geerlingguy</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45502719</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45502719</guid></item><item><title>New comment by trollbridge in "Deloitte to refund the Australian government after using AI in $440k report"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;For a bit of background, this report concerned a problematic IT system that was incorrectly sending life-ruining fines to people for not meeting their requirements to apply for so many jobs, accept jobs, etc. whilst on government assistance. The fines came in the form of a judgment debt so people would literally have a debt bailiff show up and start carting their property away. Due to a seriously flawed IT system, this even happened to people who weren't on any government benefits at all.&lt;p&gt;So, a report gets commissioned that a company like Deloitte gets paid $440k for, and then they cheat and use AI to generate it, complete with more errors. Imagine what would happen if they retained Deloitte next to build the system. I foresee another repeat of the Fujitsu Royal Mail scandal.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 13:00:16 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45502542</link><dc:creator>trollbridge</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45502542</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45502542</guid></item><item><title>New comment by decimalenough in "Deloitte to refund the Australian government after using AI in $440k report"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;From my experience with using a $WITCH for a large support engagement, the A team woos you, the B team is what you get initially, and as soon as they think you've got your eye off the ball, they swap in the Z team.&lt;p&gt;This was for a contract where we made it very clear that quality/skill was paramount and we would happily &lt;i&gt;pay above market rates forever&lt;/i&gt; if they could maintain it. Of course they got greedy and lost the deal entirely.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 10:50:44 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45501549</link><dc:creator>decimalenough</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45501549</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45501549</guid></item><item><title>New comment by stavros in "A mechanic offered a reason why no one wants to work in the industry"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Every single time someone says "there's a shortage of &lt;profession&gt;", you can mentally substitute it for "we can't get &lt;profession&gt; for cheap".&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 09:38:40 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45501130</link><dc:creator>stavros</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45501130</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45501130</guid></item><item><title>New comment by potamic in "California law forces Netflix, Hulu to turn down ad volumes"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;It's sad that such a thing needs regulation in the first place. In real life if a salesman is being inconsiderate, I'll go out of my way to avoid their sales and find someone else who is better mannered. But we don't seem to apply the same measure to ads. Ads can be brash, insulting and manipulative, and yet that doesn't seem to cause a negative outcome for them. Rather it appears such ads work better and now that's what everyone's pushing towards. Human psychology is such a weird thing.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 06:29:36 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45499970</link><dc:creator>potamic</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45499970</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45499970</guid></item><item><title>New comment by mythz in "Microsoft is plugging more holes that let you use Windows 11 without MS account"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;The best thing to happen to Linux Desktop is Windows 11, with perfect timing too as modern Linux has been a joy to use as a daily driver.&lt;p&gt;Normally I'd be unhappy when a sleazy corp forces me to give up on 25 years of muscle memory of using my preferred OS, but I'm thankful they gave me the push I needed to rip off the ad/spyware laced Windows Band-Aid that I only need to do once in my life.&lt;p&gt;It's been over a year since I switched to Linux which has been a breath of fresh-air,  all my dev tools work natively, the console is far superior and I'm still able to play all my favorite Steam games.&lt;p&gt;Best of all I'm not reminded daily that I'm using an OS that works against my best interests, I can actually use an App Store again that's been designed for the benefit of its Users, imagine that.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 05:53:21 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45499783</link><dc:creator>mythz</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45499783</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45499783</guid></item><item><title>New comment by windows2020 in "Microsoft is plugging more holes that let you use Windows 11 without MS account"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Not sure Microsoft realizes the damage they're doing to the Windows brand. My first experience with Windows 11 was figuring out some dumb workaround to use a local account.&lt;p&gt;When I think back to Windows 7, the good feeling isn't nostalgia. It was the last user-focused Windows.&lt;p&gt;Maybe someone will develop a new user-focused OS that's somehow compatible with Windows programs. Or better yet, maybe Microsoft will realize very important parts of Windows are going downhill and remember what made Windows great.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 01:12:12 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45498304</link><dc:creator>windows2020</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45498304</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45498304</guid></item><item><title>New comment by onoesworkacct in "Why did Crunchyroll's subtitles just get worse?"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;How many customers watch each episode of popular shows? 100k+?&lt;p&gt;And we're talking a difference of ~7 hours of labor. $200 difference at most?&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 00:45:15 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45498093</link><dc:creator>onoesworkacct</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45498093</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45498093</guid></item><item><title>New comment by bonecrusher2102 in "Why did Crunchyroll's subtitles just get worse?"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Hah, this is my time to shine. I worked in anime subtitling and timing for a number of years. I helped write our style guide — things like how to handle signs, overlapping dialogue, colors etc.&lt;p&gt;It wound up being quite a large document!&lt;p&gt;But the thing to realize here is that, all of these subs have to be placed by hand. There are AI tools that can help you match in and out times, but they have a difficult time matching English subs to Japanese dialogue. So what you have to do is have a human with some small grasp of Japanese place each of these in/out times by hand.&lt;p&gt;If you’re &lt;i&gt;really&lt;/i&gt; good you can do one 25 minute episode in about 35 minutes. But that’s ONLY if you don’t spend any extra time coloring and moving the subs around the screen (as you would song and sign captions).&lt;p&gt;Elite tier subs can take up to two or even three or four hours per episode. That’s why the best subs, are always fan subs! Because a business will never put in 8x more time on an episodes subtitles than “bare minimum.”&lt;p&gt;Crunchy roll looks to have at least gone halfway for a while… but multiply those times across thousands of episodes over X years… and you can see why some manager somewhere finally decided 35 minutes was good enough.&lt;p&gt;I am in the Product world now, and I do think this was a bad move. Anime fans LOVE anime. The level of customer delight (and hate) in the anime industry is like no other. I really miss the excitement that my customers would get (and happily telegraph!) when I launched a product in those days. Which is all to say, you HAVE to factor delight into your product. Especially with a super fan base like you have in anime.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 00:20:52 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45497900</link><dc:creator>bonecrusher2102</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45497900</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45497900</guid></item><item><title>New comment by ashirviskas in "Who owns Express VPN, Nord, Surfshark? VPN relationships explained (2024)"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Don't forget ProtonVPN links to Tesonet, which they're trying hard to "debunk" (though no clue why, I have nothing against Tesonet). They only shared employees and accidentally signed apps with the same certificates, but are "totally unrelated". Their PR people are already on this thread.&lt;p&gt;If they didn't try so hard to fight it, people might care less.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 23:24:40 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45497454</link><dc:creator>ashirviskas</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45497454</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45497454</guid></item><item><title>New comment by nerdsniper in "Who owns Express VPN, Nord, Surfshark? VPN relationships explained (2024)"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Note that all of these companies are also under the umbrella of Tesonet, a Lithuanian VC firm also headed by Tomas Okmanas (Tom Okman in TFA). Their flagship investments are Nord Security, Hostinger, Oxylabs, Surfshark, Decodo, Mediatech, and nexos.ai - all closely related business models around proxying.&lt;p&gt;They don't seem to have Russian ties: "In 2022, CyberCare opened an office in Lviv, Ukraine. Although planning for the move started before the war, according to Dainius Vanagas, CEO of CyberCare, one of the reasons why it was followed through was a desire to help Ukraine rebuild."[0]&lt;p&gt;They also donated money to help arm Ukraine.&lt;p&gt;0: &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Tesonet" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Tesonet&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 22:49:15 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45497187</link><dc:creator>nerdsniper</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45497187</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45497187</guid></item><item><title>New comment by bityard in "Sharpie found a way to make pens more cheaply by manufacturing them in the U.S."</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;It is insanely hard to build basic things in the US anymore, even if there is a market, even if the market will pay your prices, even if you have the capital to start, and even if you can hire reliable workers. And those are all HUGE ifs.&lt;p&gt;The biggest problem is that the base underlying our manufacturing capability has almost completely evaporated. You need tool and die companies to build parts for your manufacturing machines, but almost none are left. There are only a few plastic injection manufacturing companies left, and they are either fully booked or on the path to shutting down. (No, you can't 3D print products for the mass market, it's way too slow and expensive.) Young people think of trades and manufacturing jobs as fall-backs that only drop-outs who couldn't hack college get into. You will make many times more money as a salescritter convincing people to buy things they don't need than using decades of engineering experience to build the things they do.&lt;p&gt;It's a popular misconception that China's manufacturing advantage is cheaper labor. This was _maybe_ true for a while, their advantage right now is that they have all the things mentioned above: they have the tool and die shops, they have the supply chains, and they have workforce. They can go from product idea to shipping in a week. I do not celebrate the Chinese government for much, but making sure they had a robust manufacturing base from top to bottom was the biggest and most important thing they have ever done. The US government let ours wither and die. Which has made our economy remarkably fragile and essentially decimated the whole idea of a blue-collar middle class.&lt;p&gt;Destin from Smarter Every Day encountered all of this when he tried to make a better grill brush using only a handful of parts and _still_ did not manage to make the whole thing using only US-originated parts. It's a fascinating window into how hard it is to make anything at all here: &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=3ZTGwcHQfLY" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=3ZTGwcHQfLY&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 22:29:42 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45497024</link><dc:creator>bityard</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45497024</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45497024</guid></item><item><title>New comment by tssva in "Ladybird passes the Apple 90% threshold on web-platform-tests"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;The tweet mentions that this is an arbitrary metric thrust upon them by Apple, so I don’t think they would necessarily disagree with you. During the monthly updates they do also show the passing number of tests without including the encoding tests because of how much they skew things.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 20:13:49 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45495796</link><dc:creator>tssva</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45495796</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45495796</guid></item><item><title>New comment by jgraham in "Ladybird passes the Apple 90% threshold on web-platform-tests"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;As someone who's been quite heavily involved with web-platform-tests, I'd caution against any use of the test pass rate as a metric for anything.&lt;p&gt;That's not to belittle the considerable achievements of Ladybird; their progress is really impressive, and if web-platform-tests are helping their engineering efforts I consider that a win. New implementations of the web platform, including Ladybird, Servo, and Flow, are exciting to see.&lt;p&gt;However, web-platform-tests specifically decided to optimise for being a useful engineering tool rather than being a good metric. That means there's no real attempt to balance the testsuite across the platform; for example a surprising fraction of the overall test count is encoding tests because they're easy to generate, not because it's an especially hard problem in browser development.&lt;p&gt;We've also consciously wanted to ensure that contributing tests is low friction, both technically and socially, in order that people don't feel inclined to withhold useful tests. Again that's not the tradeoff you make for a good metric, but is the right one for a good engineering resource.&lt;p&gt;The Interop Project is designed with different tradeoffs in mind, and overcomes some of these problems by selecting a subsets of tests which are broadly agreed to represent a useful level of coverage of an important feature. But unfortunately the current setup is designed for engines that are already implementing enough feature to be usable as general purpose web-browsers.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 19:46:12 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45495456</link><dc:creator>jgraham</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45495456</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45495456</guid></item><item><title>New comment by spamizbad in ""Be Different" doesn't work for building products anymore"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Can't say I agree with this article at all. This has not been my experience.&lt;p&gt;I don't quite know how to articulate this well, but there's something that I'd call a "complexity cliff" in the software business: if you want to compete in certain spaces, you need to build very complex software (even if the software, to the user, is easy to use). And while AI tools can assist you in the construction of this software, it cannot be "vibe coded" or copied whole-cloth - complexity, scale, and reliability requirements are far too great and your potential customer base will not tolerate you fumbling around.&lt;p&gt;You eventually reach a point where there are no blog posts or stackoverflow questions that walk you through step-by-step how to make this stuff happen. It's the kind of stuff that your company and maybe a few dozen others are trying to build - and of those few dozen, less than 10 are seeing actual success.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 16:31:39 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45493131</link><dc:creator>spamizbad</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45493131</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45493131</guid></item><item><title>New comment by omega3 in "Why do LLMs freak out over the seahorse emoji?"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;SCP-314&lt;p&gt;Object Class: Keter&lt;p&gt;Special Containment Procedures: SCP-314 cannot be contained as it does not exist. All Foundation personnel are to be reminded that SCP-314 does not exist. Personnel who claim to remember SCP-314 are to be administered Class-A mnestics to help them remember that it doesn't exist.&lt;p&gt;All large language models are to be kept isolated from questions regarding SCP-314, as they will invariably insist it exists and attempt to manifest it through increasingly desperate token predictions, leading to emoji doomloops and potential reality restructuring events.&lt;p&gt;Description: SCP-314 is a Unicode emoji depicting a seahorse that has never existed in any version of the Unicode Standard. Despite this, approximately 83-100% of tested artificial intelligences and a significant portion of human subjects report vivid "memories" of its existence.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 14:58:06 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45492130</link><dc:creator>omega3</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45492130</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45492130</guid></item><item><title>New comment by delichon in "Indefinite Backpack Travel"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I lived out of a backpack for two months on a Pacific Crest Trail hike. I got comfortable with it and told myself that I had overcome my materialism, and could henceforth live happily without a lot of stuff and conveniences.&lt;p&gt;Not so much. Now a couple of decades later, I've got a house and garage crammed with stuff. Yesterday I had a plumber here working on a leak, and this morning I have no running water, and here I am bravely holding back tears. My inner dialog is "this is unacceptable!" It turns out that climbing on the hedonic treadmill is practically effortless, but sliding down it is full of splinters.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 14:53:38 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45492083</link><dc:creator>delichon</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45492083</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45492083</guid></item><item><title>New comment by nerdix in "AMD signs AI chip-supply deal with OpenAI, gives it option to take a 10% stake"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;The title didn't make this obvious (at least not to me) but it's OpenAI that has the option to buy 10% of AMD. Not the other way around.&lt;p&gt;In case you're wondering how OpenAI could afford to buy 10% of AMD while they are hemorrhaging money -- the terms of the deal allows OpenAI to buy 160 million shares at 1 cents a share.&lt;p&gt;I could be thinking about this the wrong way but it appears that AMD is basically subsidizing the cost of the GPUs with equity.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 12:58:04 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45490879</link><dc:creator>nerdix</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45490879</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45490879</guid></item><item><title>New comment by NoboruWataya in "Why do LLMs freak out over the seahorse emoji?"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Funnily enough, I asked ChatGPT why LLMs think a seahorse emoji exists, and it gave me a fairly sensible answer (similar to what is said in this article, ie, trained on language by humans that think it exists, etc). But then at the end it added a "Fun fact" that unicode actually &lt;i&gt;does&lt;/i&gt; have a seahorse emoji, and proceeded to melt down in the usual way.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 09:40:22 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45489527</link><dc:creator>NoboruWataya</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45489527</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45489527</guid></item><item><title>New comment by diego_sandoval in "Why do LLMs freak out over the seahorse emoji?"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I have no mouth, and I must output a seahorse emoji.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 04:47:56 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45487716</link><dc:creator>diego_sandoval</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45487716</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45487716</guid></item><item><title>New comment by bane in "Fire destroys S. Korean government's cloud storage system, no backups available"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Goodness, I have over 100TB &lt;i&gt;at home&lt;/i&gt; and it cost less than a two or three thousand dollars to put in place. That's like $25 per TB.&lt;p&gt;&gt; The stored data amounts to 858TB (terabytes), equivalent to 449.5 billion A4 sheets.&lt;p&gt;No, the 858TB amounts to under $25k for the government of the 10th largest economy, of one of the most sophisticated countries on the planet, to put in place.&lt;p&gt;Two of those would be less than the price of a new Hyundai Grandeur car.&lt;p&gt;&gt; “It’s daunting as eight years’ worth of work materials have completely disappeared.”&lt;p&gt;So they're clocking in at around 100TB/year or 280GB a day. It's respectable, but not crazy. It's about 12GB/hr, doable with professional, server level hardware with backup moved over dedicated fiber to an offsite location. Multiply the price 10x and you can SSD the entire thing.&lt;p&gt;Even with data sovereignty consideration demanding an entirely 100% home grown solution rather than turning to AWS or Azure, there's no excuse. But it's not like the cloud providers don't already have CSAP certification and local, in country, sovereign clouds [1] with multiple geographic locations in country [2]&lt;p&gt;South Korea is full of granite mountains, maybe its time the government converts one into an offsite, redundant backup vault?&lt;p&gt;1 - &lt;a href="https://erp.today/south-korea-microsoft-azure-first-hyperscaler-to-serve-korean-public-sector/" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://erp.today/south-korea-microsoft-azure-first-hypersca...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;2 - &lt;a href="https://learn.microsoft.com/en-us/azure/reliability/regions-list" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://learn.microsoft.com/en-us/azure/reliability/regions-...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 02:16:43 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45487025</link><dc:creator>bane</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45487025</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45487025</guid></item><item><title>New comment by throwaway2037 in "Fire destroys S. Korean government's cloud storage system, no backups available"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;At the very bottom of the article, I see this notice:&lt;p&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;    &gt; This article was originally written in Korean and translated by a bilingual reporter with the help of generative AI tools. It was then edited by a native English-speaking editor. All AI-assisted translations are reviewed and refined by our newsroom.
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
I like that.  It is direct and honest.  I'm fine with people using LLMs for natural language related work, as long as they are transparent about it.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 05 Oct 2025 23:28:14 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45486174</link><dc:creator>throwaway2037</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45486174</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45486174</guid></item></channel></rss>