<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>Hacker News: Best Comments</title><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/bestcomments</link><description>Hacker News RSS</description><docs>https://hnrss.org/</docs><generator>hnrss v2.1.1</generator><lastBuildDate>Sun, 09 Nov 2025 00:19:42 +0000</lastBuildDate><ns0:link href="https://hnrss.org/bestcomments" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item><title>New comment by tedivm in "I Want You to Understand Chicago"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I live in Chicago, and this article doesn't even scratch the surface of how bad it is. My wife went to the beach yesterday for 10 minutes to try and rest from the chaos and a fucking black hawk helicopter buzzed by her. They literally fly over my house daily.&lt;p&gt;People, US citizens included, are literally being abducted. People have been shot and killed by masked agents. People have had their children abandoned on the side of the road after being kidnapped. Just today they raided Little Village with hundreds of masked troops. I'm in a dozen signal groups to get alerted about where things are.&lt;p&gt;What scares me the most is how few people seem to actually know what is happening here. I talk to people outside of Chicago, and watch the news, and I don't see or hear about anything that's going on here. I tell them what's happening and they are shocked.&lt;p&gt;It is impossible to convey what is happening here, how scared we all are for this country, and how much things seem to escalate every single day that this goes on.&lt;p&gt;Edit: This post has been flagged and hidden, just demonstrating how much this country wants to pretend this isn't happening. It's unflagged now, but the fact that anyone would want to hide what's happening here shows how bad things are for all of us.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 08 Nov 2025 20:47:43 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45859830</link><dc:creator>tedivm</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45859830</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45859830</guid></item><item><title>New comment by web3-is-a-scam in "Btop: A better modern alternative of htop"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I’m a btop user how is it gamified?  If by “gamified” thy mean “looks like something you would see in a video game (or movie)” then yeah tha tracks but that’s not what “gamified” typically means…&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 08 Nov 2025 16:56:53 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45858114</link><dc:creator>web3-is-a-scam</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45858114</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45858114</guid></item><item><title>New comment by risho in "Btop: A better modern alternative of htop with a gamified interface"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;i dont think they could have possibly chosen a word to make me want to use it less than gamified.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 08 Nov 2025 16:27:43 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45857864</link><dc:creator>risho</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45857864</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45857864</guid></item><item><title>New comment by SonnyTark in "Why is Zig so cool?"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;This is a very confusing blog post. I found myself looking for ChatGPT markers because it doesn't make sense to say: omg zig is so much cooler than C here's why, then start listing the absolute basics of the language that are identical in most modern languages without any actual reflection why writing the same thing in a different syntax somehow makes zig superior?&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 08 Nov 2025 13:41:18 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45856597</link><dc:creator>SonnyTark</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45856597</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45856597</guid></item><item><title>New comment by adastra22 in "Valdi – A cross-platform UI framework that delivers native performance"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I have never once experienced a WebView app that I would say had “a really good experience.”&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 08 Nov 2025 05:02:40 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45854285</link><dc:creator>adastra22</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45854285</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45854285</guid></item><item><title>New comment by unscaled in "Why is Zig so cool?"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I'm afraid this article kinda fails at at its job. It starts out with a very bold claim ("Zig is not only a new programming language, but it’s a totally new way to write programs"), but ends up listing a bunch of features that are not unique to Zig or even introduced by Zig: type inference (Invented in the late 60s, first practically implemented in the 80s), anonymous structs (C#, Go, Typescript, many ML-style languages), labeled breaks, functions that are not globally public by default...&lt;p&gt;It seems like this is written from the perspective of C/C++ and Java and perhaps a couple of traditional (dynamically typed) languages.&lt;p&gt;On the other hand, the concept that makes Zig really unique (comptime) is not touched upon at all. I would argue compile-time evaluation is not entirely new (you can look at Lisp macros back in the 60s), but the way Zig implements this  feature and how it is used instead of generics is interesting enough to make Zig unique. I still feel like the claim is a bit hyperbolic, but there is a story that you can sell about Zig being unique. I wanted to read this story, but I feel like this is not it.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 08 Nov 2025 04:23:00 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45854097</link><dc:creator>unscaled</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45854097</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45854097</guid></item><item><title>New comment by WarOnPrivacy in "YouTube Removes Windows 11 Bypass Tutorials, Claims 'Risk of Physical Harm'"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Mount a Windows 11 ISO.  Open an administrative command window. Navigate to the new drive letter. Enter this command:&lt;p&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;    .\setup.exe /product server /auto upgrade /EULA accept /migratedrivers all /ShowOOBE none /Compat IgnoreWarning /Telemetry Disable
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
I've used this to upgrade 10 to 11 on non approved hardware, going back to at least 2nd gen Intel CPUs. I've used it to upgrade existing Pro, EDU and IOT that didn't want to upgrade.&lt;p&gt;The install window will say server but it isn't.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 08 Nov 2025 00:43:45 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45853012</link><dc:creator>WarOnPrivacy</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45853012</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45853012</guid></item><item><title>New comment by Aurornis in "YouTube Removes Windows 11 Bypass Tutorials, Claims 'Risk of Physical Harm'"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&gt; This is now a Streisand effect - as people see that Google and Microsoft try to hide information from them&lt;p&gt;This comment section is wild.&lt;p&gt;The videos are up. Microsoft and Google weren't meeting in secret backrooms to censor this one channel. The most likely explanation is that a competing channel was trying to move their own videos up in the rankings by mass-reporting other videos on the topic.&lt;p&gt;It's a growing problem on social media platforms: Cutthroat channels or influencers will use alt accounts or even paid services to report their competition. They know that with enough reports in a short period of time they can get the content removed for a while, which creates a window for their own content to get more views.&lt;p&gt;The clue is the "risk of physical harm". People who abuse the report function know that the report options involving physical harm, violence, or suicide are the quickest way to get content taken down.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 22:31:59 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45851983</link><dc:creator>Aurornis</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45851983</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45851983</guid></item><item><title>New comment by shevy-java in "YouTube Removes Windows 11 Bypass Tutorials, Claims 'Risk of Physical Harm'"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Google censors the world, together with Microsoft.&lt;p&gt;Well - it is time that the rest of the world censors these two corporation. I don't want them to restrict information.&lt;p&gt;People will find workarounds by the way. This is now a Streisand effect - as people see that Google and Microsoft try to hide information from them, they will now look at this much more closely than before, with more attention.&lt;p&gt;(Having said that, my bypass strategy is to not use Windows 11 altogether. I don't depend on it, having used Linux since 21 years now, but my machine to the left is actually using Win10, for various reasons, such as that I can fix problems of elderly relatives still using Windows. But I won't use Win11 ever with its recall-spy software. I also don't care that it can be disabled - any corporation that tries to sniff-invade on me, is evil and must be banned.)&lt;p&gt;Edit: Ok so the video was restored. That was good, but still, we need an alternative here. Google holds WAY too much power via youtube.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 22:03:21 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45851681</link><dc:creator>shevy-java</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45851681</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45851681</guid></item><item><title>New comment by gwd in "Apple is crossing a Steve Jobs red line"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&gt; From that point on, Steve would go on to spend lavishly on things that improved the experience, and he would reject—often brutally—any idea that diluted or harmed the experience. ...I’ll go out on a limb and say that uninvited advertising is not normally equated with a better customer experience.&lt;p&gt;YES!!!  SOO much of the Apple user experience has degraded due to this.  I can't listen to my own music that I bought on the Music app, without being interrupted asking if I want Apple Music.  I open up the Books app to read Winnie the Pooh to my son, and the opening screen has loads of random trashy romances to try to sell me.  I go to comfort read Ender's Game, which I did buy though the store a decade ago, and it helpfully "groups" it with the other four (!?) books in that series which I haven't bought, as if to say, "Don't you want to buy these too?"  NO!   If I want to buy them, I know where to find them!&lt;p&gt;It is SUCH an unpleasant experience.  EVERY time I open the App Store to update some apps, I'm angry that I have to wander past advertising assaults to do it.  EVERY time I open the music app to play an old favorite, I'm angry that I have to go past the advertising assault.  EVERY time I open up the book app, I'm angry that I have to go past the advertising assault.&lt;p&gt;I very much doubt the execs understand how much they're damaging the brand for that little bit of extra revenue.  The see the extra revenue, but they don't see the lost brand, or the people that switch away.  Is it really worth it?&lt;p&gt;ETA: I don't think it's an exaggeration to say:&lt;p&gt;Modern iPhones don't come with a music player.  They come with a music store, that you happen to be able to put your own music into.  But it's not structured to help you play your music, it's structured to sell you what they want to sell you.&lt;p&gt;Modern iPhones don't come with an e-book app.  They come with a book store that you happen to be able to upload some of your own books into.  But it's not structured to help you organize and read your books -- even the ones you've bought; it's structured to sell you more books.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 21:35:53 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45851385</link><dc:creator>gwd</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45851385</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45851385</guid></item><item><title>New comment by rs186 in "YouTube Removes Windows 11 Bypass Tutorials, Claims 'Risk of Physical Harm'"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&gt; Rich appealed both immediately. The first appeal was denied in 45 minutes. The second in just five.&lt;p&gt;&gt; The platform claimed its "initial actions" (could be either the first takedown or appeal denial, or both) were not the result of automation.&lt;p&gt;Didn't know YouTube can improve their review time from 45 minutes to 5 minutes without automation. I bet it's pure magic.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 21:18:24 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45851216</link><dc:creator>rs186</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45851216</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45851216</guid></item><item><title>New comment by skrebbel in "Ruby already solved my problem"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Unrelated side note, but I haven't written any Ruby in maybe 15 years or so and dammn I forgot how elegant the language is at its core. The author's AppVersion class is so nicely done, it's nuts how succinct eg the compare implementation is.&lt;p&gt;Having done mostly TypeScript and Elixir lately, I had forgotten things could be so succinct yet so clear. The combo of modern (to me) Ruby's lambda syntax (in the .map call), parentheses-less function calls, the fact that arrays implement &lt;=&gt; by comparing each item in order, that there's an overloadable compare operator at all, having multiple value assignments in one go...  It all really adds up!&lt;p&gt;In any other language I can think of real quick (TS, Elixir, C#, Python, PHP, Go) a fair number of these parts would be substantially more wordy or syntaxy at little immediately obvious benefit. Like, this class is super concise but it doesn't trade away any readability at all.&lt;p&gt;Having learned Ruby before Rails became commonplace, with its love for things that automagically work (until they don't), I had kinda grown to dislike it. But had forgotten how core Ruby is just an &lt;i&gt;excellent&lt;/i&gt; programming language, regardless of what I think of the Rails ecosystem.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 20:01:59 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45850389</link><dc:creator>skrebbel</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45850389</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45850389</guid></item><item><title>New comment by worldfoodgood in "Rockstar employee shares account of the company's union-busting efforts"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Valve makes a &lt;i&gt;significant&lt;/i&gt; amount of their money from the gambling they've attached to their games, and profits immensely from the culture of farming loot boxes to gamble on for skins and such.&lt;p&gt;They also take an absurd cut of developer income and saddle devs with costs that they don't always want. (Selling on Steam? Valve takes 30% and forces you to moderate the forums on your listing page that you cannot opt out of.)&lt;p&gt;They also have an internal culture that's been fairly regularly criticized as being pretty uncomfortable for women and minorities.&lt;p&gt;Valve has done some cool stuff, but let's not lionize them too much. They are probably better than an average company, for sure, but it's important to remember that they are also sketchy in some very gross ways as well.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 19:41:22 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45850178</link><dc:creator>worldfoodgood</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45850178</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45850178</guid></item><item><title>New comment by glerk in "Gmail AI gets more intrusive"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Google must have some awful PMs and designers. The worst UX decision I have seen recently is AI auto-dubbing all youtube videos by default with no way to disable this behavior globally. How could you miss that people can be fluent in multiple languages and if I click on a video in a foreign language, I most likely want the original soundtrack? Clearly, the intention was to boost some metric “X users are using this feature” with no regard for the actual user.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 19:39:00 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45850156</link><dc:creator>glerk</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45850156</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45850156</guid></item><item><title>New comment by lwn in "Vodafone Germany is killing the open internet – one peering connection at a time"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I recently moved to a Dutch municipality that runs its own non-profit ISP. They installed a symmetric 1 Gbps fiber connection with a static IP at my house for 40 euros per month.&lt;p&gt;The service is solid, there’s no upselling or throttling, and hosting things from home just works. I bring this up because when we talk about “open”, “fair” and “monopolies” the model of a local, non-profit ISP backed by the municipality could offer a real alternative. It doesn’t directly solve the peering issues, but it shifts the balance of power (and cost) somewhat.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 18:57:51 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45849652</link><dc:creator>lwn</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45849652</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45849652</guid></item><item><title>New comment by trey-jones in "Denmark's government aims to ban access to social media for children under 15"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;As a parent who gave my oldest child a (very used) smartphone just before she turned 14, I would be in favor of making smartphones illegal under age 15 (or some other number, higher or lower I don't care).  I'm pretty sure they're worse than cigarettes for the future of humanity.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 18:38:28 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45849458</link><dc:creator>trey-jones</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45849458</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45849458</guid></item><item><title>New comment by phineyes in "Vodafone Germany is killing the open internet – one peering connection at a time"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;This isn't unique to Vodafone. Google has also been slowly withdrawing from IXes globally in favor of PNIs and "VPPs" (verified peering providers). This only makes it harder for smaller networks to establish presence on the internet and feels pretty anti-competitive.&lt;p&gt;On the flip side, IXes are becoming harder and less desirable to participate in: port fees are going up, useful networks are withdrawing, low quality network participants are joining and widening blast radius. I'm not sure what the answer to this is, but this has not been a great year for the "open" internet.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 18:25:35 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45849318</link><dc:creator>phineyes</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45849318</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45849318</guid></item><item><title>New comment by timhh in "Why I love OCaml (2023)"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&gt; why isn’t OCaml more popular&lt;p&gt;I've used OCaml a bit and found various issues with it:&lt;p&gt;* Terrible Windows support. With OCaml 5 it's upgraded to "pretty bad".&lt;p&gt;* The syntax is hard to parse for humans. Often it turns into a word soup, without any helpful punctuation to tell you what things are. It's like reading a book with no paragraphs, capitalisation or punctuation.&lt;p&gt;* The syntax isn't recoverable. Sometimes you can add a single character and the error message is essentially "syntax error in these 1000 lines".&lt;p&gt;* Ocamlfmt is pretty bad. It thinks it is writing prose. It will even put complex `match`es on one line if they fit. Really hurts readability.&lt;p&gt;* The documentation is super terse. Very few examples.&lt;p&gt;* OPAM. In theory... I feel like it should be great. But in practice I find it to be incomprehensible, full of surprising behaviours, and also surprisingly buggy. I still can't believe the bug where it can't find `curl` if you're in more than 32 Unix groups.&lt;p&gt;* Optional type annotation for function signatures throws away a significant benefit of static typing - documentation/understanding and nice error messages.&lt;p&gt;* Tiny ecosystem. Rust gets flak for its small standard library, but OCaml doesn't even have a built in function to copy files.&lt;p&gt;* Like all FP languages it has a weird obsession with singly linked lists, which are actually a pretty awful data structure.&lt;p&gt;It's not all bad though, and I'd definitely take it over C and Python. Definitely wouldn't pick it over Rust though, unless I was &lt;i&gt;really&lt;/i&gt; worried about compile times.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 18:19:50 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45849254</link><dc:creator>timhh</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45849254</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45849254</guid></item><item><title>New comment by randycupertino in "A.I. and Social Media Contribute to 'Brain Rot'"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I'm in a local facebook group for my town where people post hiking pics, bird pics, local business updates, contractor recommendations etc.  I am annoyed to see "brain rot" videos starting to take over the page.&lt;p&gt;There is one dude promoting his succulent repotting/resale business and he's posted like 5-8 ai generated surfer dude monkey surfing and partying with his potted succulents just in the last week.  I opened the comments expecting to see other people complaining, "hey buddy take your ai-spam elsewhere" but all the comments were "cute!" "adorable" and "love this!"  I just ended up blocking this dude but I am sad for humanity lol.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 16:14:44 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45847921</link><dc:creator>randycupertino</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45847921</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45847921</guid></item><item><title>New comment by cs702 in "Leaving Meta and PyTorch"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Many of the comments here are judging PyTorch &lt;i&gt;in hindsight&lt;/i&gt;, which is unfair.&lt;p&gt;When Soumith Chintala co-launched PyTorch, and for many years after, the alternatives for fast, interactive, convenient development were &lt;i&gt;much worse&lt;/i&gt;. There was no Jax.&lt;p&gt;Every single AI researcher I know, including me, who &lt;i&gt;tried&lt;/i&gt; PyTorch back then &lt;i&gt;immediately wanted to switch to it, because it was so much better&lt;/i&gt;. Andrej Karpathy described what PyTorch felt like back then when he tweeted, on May 2017, "I've been using PyTorch a few months now and I've never felt better. I have more energy. My skin is clearer. My eyesight has improved."[a]&lt;p&gt;THANK YOU SOUMITH for your hard work over all these years! Your hard work has made a difference for a huge number of people, including many of us here on HN.&lt;p&gt;We wish you success in your future endeavors, whatever they turn out to be!&lt;p&gt;Please ignore all the petty criticism.&lt;p&gt;---&lt;p&gt;[a] &lt;a href="https://x.com/karpathy/status/868178954032513024" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://x.com/karpathy/status/868178954032513024&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 15:41:42 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45847552</link><dc:creator>cs702</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45847552</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45847552</guid></item><item><title>New comment by herodotus in "A Fond Farewell"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;In the early 1990's, during my days as a Comp. Sci. prof, I was so excited about the emergence of the internet. When I saw the Mosaic browser (a precursor to Netscape and later Firefox) I knew the world had changed for the better. Now I have such mixed feelings. Magazines (like the Farmers Almanac) either go online completely or just disappear. They just cannot compete for advertising dollars with Google. And small family run local retail stores, offering not just goods, but a social hub for people are shutting their doors because how can they compete with the convenience of Amazon. Much has been gained from the internet, and much has been lost.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 15:35:48 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45847475</link><dc:creator>herodotus</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45847475</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45847475</guid></item><item><title>New comment by fouronnes3 in "Meta projected 10% of 2024 revenue came from scams"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I don't see how the yearly tech support I do with my parents at Christmas will not one day converge to an outright ban of the internet. I am now demoing the level of sofistication of AI powered scams, telling them that it is now entirely possible they will get a VIDEO CALL from me that's not actually me asking for God knows what in a very convincing way using my face and voice. I am scared and this close to setting up a secret passphrase in case they need to tell me appart from a clone.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 13:59:38 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45846435</link><dc:creator>fouronnes3</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45846435</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45846435</guid></item><item><title>New comment by macNchz in "Meta projected 10% of 2024 revenue came from scams"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Alongside a password manager and keeping things up to date, using an ad blocker is truly a foundational security practice these days. The big advertising players simply have all of the wrong incentives to control this problem. They &lt;i&gt;could&lt;/i&gt; massively reduce the volume of scams advertised on their networks, but it’d be worse for them on two fronts: they’d have to pay for more moderation, &lt;i&gt;and&lt;/i&gt; they’d lose billions in revenue in the process. Shoulder surfing while a non-savvy user browses Facebook or YouTube without an ad blocker and engages with obviously fraudulent ads is painful.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 13:47:04 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45846303</link><dc:creator>macNchz</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45846303</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45846303</guid></item><item><title>New comment by cjonas in "Meta projected 10% of 2024 revenue came from scams"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;At least 50% of the YouTube promoted videos I get are crypto currency scams where some paid actor walks you though deploying an eth contract that empties your wallet. I report every one and nothing changes :(&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 13:16:10 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45846011</link><dc:creator>cjonas</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45846011</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45846011</guid></item><item><title>New comment by oxfordmale in "Leaving Meta and PyTorch"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I think you might be reading a bit too much into this.&lt;p&gt;He’s been with Meta for 11 years and is likely in a very comfortable financial position, given the substantial stock options he’s received over that time.&lt;p&gt;He also mentioned the arrival of a new child, and it’s well known that Meta's work-life balance isn’t always ideal.&lt;p&gt;On top of that, Meta, like many major tech companies, has been shifting its focus toward LLM-based AI, moving away from more traditional PyTorch use cases.&lt;p&gt;Considering all of this, it seems like a natural time for him to move on and pursue new, more exciting opportunities.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 12:28:37 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45845716</link><dc:creator>oxfordmale</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45845716</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45845716</guid></item><item><title>New comment by markphip in "A Fond Farewell"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;There is still the Old Farmer’s Almanac &lt;a href="https://www.almanac.com/old-farmers-almanac-233-years-and-still-going-strong" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://www.almanac.com/old-farmers-almanac-233-years-and-st...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 10:27:20 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45845131</link><dc:creator>markphip</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45845131</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45845131</guid></item><item><title>New comment by yanhangyhy in "Kimi K2 Thinking, a SOTA open-source trillion-parameter reasoning model"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;As a Chinese user, I can say that many people use Kimi, even though I personally don’t use it much. China’s open-source strategy has many significant effects—not only because it aligns with the spirit of open source. For domestic Chinese companies, it also prevents startups from making reckless investments to develop mediocre models. Instead, everyone is pushed to start from a relatively high baseline. Of course, many small companies in the U.S., Japan, and Europe are also building on Qwen. Kimi is similar: before DeepSeek and others emerged, their model quality was pretty bad. Once the open-source strategy was set, these companies had no choice but to adjust their product lines and development approaches to improve their models.&lt;p&gt;Moreover, the ultimate competition between models will eventually become a competition over energy. China’s open-source models have major advantages in energy consumption, and China itself has a huge advantage in energy resources. They may not necessarily outperform the U.S., but they probably won’t fall too far behind either.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 02:45:51 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45843056</link><dc:creator>yanhangyhy</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45843056</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45843056</guid></item><item><title>New comment by pizlonator in "A Note on Fil-C"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;This is super kind and awesome, I'm seriously flattered!&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 02:23:11 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45842935</link><dc:creator>pizlonator</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45842935</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45842935</guid></item><item><title>New comment by stefankuehnel in "FBI tries to unmask owner of archive.is"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Just a note: the White House also uses archive.ph.&lt;p&gt;Search for “Americans are spending like never before: Retail sales are booming — up 5% over last year, far outpacing inflation — as Americans spend in record amounts.” [1]&lt;p&gt;The phrase “up 5%” links directly to archive.ph.&lt;p&gt;[1] &lt;a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/articles/2025/09/the-economy-is-back-on-track-under-president-trump/" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://www.whitehouse.gov/articles/2025/09/the-economy-is-b...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2025 23:39:53 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45841916</link><dc:creator>stefankuehnel</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45841916</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45841916</guid></item><item><title>New comment by dave1010uk in "You should write an agent"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Two years ago I wrote an agent in 25 lines of PHP [0]. It was surprisingly effective, even back then before tool calling was a thing and you had to coax the LLM into returning structured output. I think it even worked with GPT-3.5 for trivial things.&lt;p&gt;In my mind LLMs are just UNIX strong manipulation tools like `sed` or `awk`: you give them an input and command and they give you an output. This is especially true if you use something like `llm` [1].&lt;p&gt;It then seems logical that you can compose calls to LLMs, loop and branch and combine them with other functions.&lt;p&gt;[0] &lt;a href="https://github.com/dave1010/hubcap" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://github.com/dave1010/hubcap&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;[1] &lt;a href="https://github.com/simonw/llm" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://github.com/simonw/llm&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2025 23:35:20 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45841886</link><dc:creator>dave1010uk</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45841886</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45841886</guid></item></channel></rss>