<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>Hacker News: Best Comments</title><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/bestcomments</link><description>Hacker News RSS</description><docs>https://hnrss.org/</docs><generator>hnrss v2.1.1</generator><lastBuildDate>Mon, 13 Oct 2025 23:59:27 +0000</lastBuildDate><ns0:link href="https://hnrss.org/bestcomments" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item><title>New comment by kswzzl in "Software update bricks some Jeep 4xe hybrids over the weekend"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;My 4xe died in my driveway on Saturday after the update. Let me explain, from the perspective of a 4xe owner, how bad the response has been from Jeep/Stellantis:&lt;p&gt;- As of Monday 8am ET, zero legitimate communication from any Jeep-related accounts on any social media platform, or any other form of acknowledgement from the company (unless I've missed something?)&lt;p&gt;- I only found out about the issue after finally searching a few Jeep groups on Facebook (of all places) to see if anyone else was experiencing the weird failure mode I was after the update.&lt;p&gt;- The only remotely-official info was from a 'JeepCares' account (which is ran by Jeep) on some random off-roading forum? We were seriously all living off of screenshots from this forum, and the advice coming from the JeepCares accounts was contradictory: they claimed that the Uconnect update was separate from the telematics update, and that there was no way to stop the telematics update if the vehicle received it. Later they gave advice to defer the Uconnect update, making it sound like they were coupled.&lt;p&gt;- Due to the lack of info from Jeep, people were coming up with all kinds of "if you reboot Uconnect while the Jeep's in ACC mode, it clears the check engine light". This probably did clear the CEL but didn't fix the fault.&lt;p&gt;- There is no way to tell if you received the bad update.&lt;p&gt;- There is no way to tell if you received the 'fix' either.&lt;p&gt;- Dealerships have literally no idea what is going on.&lt;p&gt;- You're basically at risk of your Jeep going limp (power loss, unable to safely make it to the shoulder) and being stranded on the highway, even as I write this.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 13 Oct 2025 16:34:51 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45570343</link><dc:creator>kswzzl</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45570343</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45570343</guid></item><item><title>New comment by jim201 in "Android's sideloading limits are its most anti-consumer move"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Antitrust action is badly needed in this area. It is ridiculous that I need permission from my device manufacturer to install software on hardware I own. There is no viable alternative than to live in Apple and Google’s ecosystems. This duopoly cannot be allowed to keep this much control of the mobile platforms.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 13 Oct 2025 16:34:15 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45570331</link><dc:creator>jim201</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45570331</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45570331</guid></item><item><title>New comment by HiPhish in "Android's sideloading limits are its most anti-consumer move"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;We need to stop calling it "sideloading", we should call it freely installing software. The term "sideloading" makes it sound shady and hacky when in reality it is what we have been able to do on our computers since forever. These are not phones, they are computers shaped like phones, computer which we fully bought with our money, and I we shall install what we want on our own computers.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 13 Oct 2025 16:27:27 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45570232</link><dc:creator>HiPhish</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45570232</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45570232</guid></item><item><title>New comment by itg in "Android's sideloading limits are its most anti-consumer move"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Installing any app I want outside the Play Store was the primary reason I decided to go with Android, despite most of the people I know using iPhones. If I can't do this anymore, I may as well switch and be able to use iMessage and FaceTime with them.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 13 Oct 2025 16:13:33 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45570037</link><dc:creator>itg</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45570037</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45570037</guid></item><item><title>New comment by MountDoom in "Smartphones and being present"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I always felt that I'm spending too much time in front of a computer, but it was at least somewhat meaningful because I had opportunities to create: write code, blog, and so on.&lt;p&gt;When smartphones came out, I made a decision early on that I'm just not going to use them in a way that makes my internet footprint follow me everywhere I go. I set them up using a throwaway email account, turned off almost all notifications, and added just family and real-world friends. I think this served me well for nearly two decades. I really only use my phone for maps, photos, and maybe 2-5 messages a day. I honestly never found myself in a situation where I thought to myself, "gosh, I wish I could read my e-mail right now".&lt;p&gt;But in the past five years, there's been this mounting pressure from app vendors to make sure I can no longer enjoy that. Every other time a friend sends me a web link, I get a popup that detects I'm on mobile and demands I install an app. And they increasingly can't be dismissed, so if I want to view that URL, I need to mail it to myself and open it on a desktop.&lt;p&gt;If you work for a place that does that, I just hope you stub your toe every morning.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 13 Oct 2025 15:44:38 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45569646</link><dc:creator>MountDoom</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45569646</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45569646</guid></item><item><title>New comment by 0x37 in "Modern Linux tools"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;These may be objectively superior (I haven't tested), but I have come to realize (like so many others) that if you ever change your OS installation, set up VMs, or SSH anywhere, preferring these is just an uphill battle that never ends. I don't want to have to set these up in every new environment I operate in, or even use a mix of these on my personal computer and the traditional ones elsewhere.&lt;p&gt;Learn the classic tools, learn them well, and your life will be much easier.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 13 Oct 2025 11:35:54 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45567223</link><dc:creator>0x37</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45567223</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45567223</guid></item><item><title>New comment by wolvesechoes in "Free software hasn't won"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I am baffled that people in this thread write something along "well, depends what you call &lt;i&gt;win&lt;/i&gt;" - the goal of Free Software is quite clear. The goal is freedom, computing freedom, freedom of the software user. It is very easy to notice that in 2025 users have less freedom even if they run some Libre Linux distro on their Thinkpads than they had running Win98, because of everything that happens OUTSIDE PC software ecosystem (phones, SaaS etc), and even inside PC world things sometimes are not obvious.&lt;p&gt;Free Software is losing, simple as that. Even with Kubernetes, as the goal was never to provide free labor and free software infra to companies.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 13 Oct 2025 07:50:38 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45565847</link><dc:creator>wolvesechoes</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45565847</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45565847</guid></item><item><title>New comment by azianmike in "Ask HN: What are you working on? (October 2025)"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;A couple of months ago, I saw a tweet from @awilkinson: “I just found out how much we pay for DocuSign and my jaw dropped. What's the best alternative?”&lt;p&gt;Me being naive, I thought “how hard could would it actually be to build a free e-sign tool?”&lt;p&gt;Turns out not that hard.&lt;p&gt;In about a weekend, I built a UETA and ESIGN compliant tool. And it was free. And it cost me less than $50. Unlimited free e-sign. &lt;a href="https://useinkless.com/" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://useinkless.com/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Mon, 13 Oct 2025 03:51:57 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45564517</link><dc:creator>azianmike</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45564517</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45564517</guid></item><item><title>New comment by matheusmoreira in "Free software hasn't won"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&gt; "Winning" doesn't have to mean owning every transistor&lt;p&gt;It absolutely does.&lt;p&gt;Corporations are pushing remote attestation now. They can detect if we "tampered" with our devices now. They discriminate against us for it. Installed your own open source software? All services denied. Can't even log into your own bank account.&lt;p&gt;We're marginalized. Second class citizens. There is no choice, it's either corporate owned computers or nothing. What good is free software if we can't run it?&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 12 Oct 2025 23:10:33 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45562899</link><dc:creator>matheusmoreira</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45562899</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45562899</guid></item><item><title>New comment by xwowsersx in "Free software hasn't won"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I think this post overstates the "loss" of free software. Yes, closed firmware and locked hardware are real gaps...but that doesn't erase the fact that open software has completely reshaped the modern stack. From Linux and K8s to Postgres and Python, it is the infra of the internet. "Winning" doesn't have to mean owning every transistor; it means setting the norms and powering most of what's built.&lt;p&gt;I tend to see this kind of absolutist, binary tone a lot from people deeply involved in FOSS... and sometimes I think maybe that mindset is necessary to push the movement forward, but it also feels detached from how much open software has already changed reality.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 12 Oct 2025 22:19:40 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45562540</link><dc:creator>xwowsersx</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45562540</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45562540</guid></item><item><title>New comment by cjflog in "Ask HN: What are you working on? (October 2025)"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Currently a one-man side project:
&lt;a href="https://laboratory.love" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://laboratory.love&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;Last year, PlasticList found plastic chemicals in 86% of tested foods—including 100% of baby foods they tested. Around the same time, the EU lowered its “safe” BPA limit by 20,000×, while the FDA still allows levels roughly 100× higher than Europe’s new standard.&lt;p&gt;That seemed solvable.&lt;p&gt;Laboratory.love lets you crowdfund independent lab testing of the specific products you actually buy. Think Consumer Reports × Kickstarter, but focused on detecting endocrine disruptors in your yogurt, your kid’s snacks, or whatever you’re curious about.&lt;p&gt;Find a product (or suggest one), contribute to its testing fund, and get full lab results when testing completes. If a product doesn’t reach its goal within 365 days, you’re automatically refunded. All results are published publicly.&lt;p&gt;We use the same ISO 17025-accredited methodology as PlasticList.org, testing three separate production lots per product and detecting down to parts-per-billion. The entire protocol is open.&lt;p&gt;Since last month’s “What are you working on?” post:&lt;p&gt;- 4 more products have been fully funded (now 10 total!)&lt;p&gt;- That’s 30 individual samples (we do triplicate testing on different batches) and 60 total chemical panels (two separate tests for each sample, BPA/BPS/BPF and phthalates)&lt;p&gt;- 6 results published, 4 in progress&lt;p&gt;The goal is simple: make supply chains transparent enough that cleaner ones win. When consumers have real data, markets shift.&lt;p&gt;Browse funded tests, propose your own, or just follow along:
 &lt;a href="https://laboratory.love" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://laboratory.love&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 12 Oct 2025 21:33:53 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45562127</link><dc:creator>cjflog</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45562127</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45562127</guid></item><item><title>New comment by delichon in "Addictive-like behavioural traits in pet dogs with extreme motivation for toys"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;  Perhaps not surprising, working breeds – many of which are known to have been artificially selected for high toy or predatory motivation – were overrepresented in the sample.
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
This is the vibe I get from my golden retriever. Chasing the tennis ball is more than play, it's a justification for life, her contribution to the pack. Actually eating food has a higher priority than chasing the ball, but not much else does. When I got her I thought that the "retriever" part was optional but it turns out to be obligate. As in I'm obligated to throw the damn ball.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 12 Oct 2025 16:52:58 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45559667</link><dc:creator>delichon</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45559667</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45559667</guid></item><item><title>New comment by Podrod in "No I don't want to turn on Windows Backup with One Drive"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I used to use Windows Backup with One Drive years ago but it just really pissed me off, especially with how My Documents is handled.&lt;p&gt;There was that time I discovered several GB of screenshots had been automatically saved to My Pictures from some setting they snuck into the printscreen screen grab tool and then that of course those were automatically uploaded to the cloud. After disabling the option it would sometimes reenable itself.&lt;p&gt;And game devs throwing random shit into My Documents was also fun. Ubisoft were terrible for this, after playing a game I'd notice a bunch of cache files they dumped into My Docs being uploaded. I mean putting save games and config files inside my docs is annoying enough, random cache files is just taking the piss.&lt;p&gt;Also windows backup would mess up my desktop between systems on occasion which was also very fun!&lt;p&gt;I disabled most of the shit but it was still annoying on occasion. Then a year or two ago I solved the problem by just using Linux for 90% of things, Mint at first but now Fedora, and grudgingly booting back into Windows for the other 10% of my needs.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 12 Oct 2025 16:22:13 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45559376</link><dc:creator>Podrod</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45559376</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45559376</guid></item><item><title>New comment by EvanAnderson in "Jeep pushed software update that bricked all 2024 Wrangler 4xe models"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;This is chilling (from &lt;a href="https://www.jlwranglerforums.com/forum/threads/2024-4xe-loss-of-motive-power-after-10-10-25-ota-update.157939/" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://www.jlwranglerforums.com/forum/threads/2024-4xe-loss...&lt;/a&gt;):&lt;p&gt;&gt; On my drive home I abruptly had absolutely no acceleration, the gear indicator on the dash started flashing, the power mode indicator disappeared, an alert said shift into park and press the brake + start button, and the check engine light and red wrench lights came on. I was still able to steer and brake with power steering and brakes for maybe 30 seconds before those went out too. After putting it into park and pressing the brake and start button it started back up and I could drive it normally for a little bit, but it happened two more times on my 1.5 mi drive home.&lt;p&gt;If that happened on the highway I could easily see people being killed.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 12 Oct 2025 14:57:49 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45558660</link><dc:creator>EvanAnderson</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45558660</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45558660</guid></item><item><title>New comment by renehsz in "Ask HN: Abandoned/dead projects you think died before their time and why?"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;The Plan 9 operating system.&lt;p&gt;It's the closest thing to a Unix successor we ever got, taking the "everything is a file" philosophy to another level and allowing to easily share those files over the network to build distributed systems. Accessing &lt;i&gt;any&lt;/i&gt; remote resources is easy and robust on Plan9, meanwhile on other systems we need to install specialized software with bad interoperability for each individual use case.&lt;p&gt;Plan9 also had some innovative UI features, such as mouse chording to edit text, nested window managers, the Plumber to run user-configurable commands on known text patterns system-wide, etc.&lt;p&gt;Its distributed nature &lt;i&gt;should&lt;/i&gt; have meant it's perfect for today's world with mobile, desktop, cloud, and IoT devices all connected to each other. Instead, we're stuck with operating systems that were never designed for that.&lt;p&gt;There are still active forks of Plan9 such as 9front, but the original from Bell Labs is dead. The reasons it died are likely:&lt;p&gt;- Legal challenges (Plan9 license, pointless lawsuits, etc.) meant it wssn't adopted by major players in the industry.&lt;p&gt;- Plan9 was a distributed OS during a time when having a local computer became popular and affordable, while using a terminal to access a centrally managed computer fell out of fashion (though the latter sort of came back in a worse fashion with cloud computing).&lt;p&gt;- Bad marketing and posing itself as merely a research OS meant they couldn't capitalize on the .com boom.&lt;p&gt;- AT&amp;T lost its near endless source of telephone revenue. Bell Labs was sold multiple times over the coming years, a lot of the Unix/Plan9 guys went to other companies like Google.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 12 Oct 2025 11:44:23 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45557467</link><dc:creator>renehsz</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45557467</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45557467</guid></item><item><title>New comment by klustregrif in "Why it took 4 years to get a lock files specification"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Overall it feels like UV is the best thing to happen to python packaging in two decades, by circumventing the endless non productive discussions on peps and instead just building something that works and is fast. In Rust naturally.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 12 Oct 2025 11:41:56 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45557448</link><dc:creator>klustregrif</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45557448</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45557448</guid></item><item><title>New comment by jwr in "Anthropic's Prompt Engineering Tutorial (2024)"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I find the word "engineering" used in this context extremely annoying. There is no "engineering" here. Engineering is about applying knowledge, laws of physics, and rules learned over many years to predictably design and build things. This is throwing stuff at the wall to see if it sticks.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 12 Oct 2025 09:10:07 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45556685</link><dc:creator>jwr</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45556685</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45556685</guid></item><item><title>New comment by zaptheimpaler in "Ask HN: Abandoned/dead projects you think died before their time and why?"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Adobe Flash / Shockwave. After all these decades, I've yet to see a tool that makes it as easy to make games or multimedia as Flash did. One of many reminders recently (many others in politics) that humanity doesn't just inevitably or linearly move forward in any domain, or even 2 steps forward 1 step back. Some things are just lost to time - maybe rediscovered in a century, maybe never.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 12 Oct 2025 08:20:53 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45556394</link><dc:creator>zaptheimpaler</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45556394</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45556394</guid></item><item><title>New comment by Animats in "Ask HN: Abandoned/dead projects you think died before their time and why?"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;- Photon, the graphical interface for QNX. Oriented more towards real time (widgets included gauges) but good enough to support two different web browsers. No delays. This was a real time operating system.&lt;p&gt;- MacOS 8. Not the Linux thing, but Copeland. This was a modernized version of the original MacOS, continuing the tradition of no command line. Not having a command line forces everyone to get their act together about how to install and configure things. Probably would have eased the tradition to mobile. A version was actually shipped to developers, but it had to be covered up to justify the bailout of Next by Apple to get Steve Jobs.&lt;p&gt;- Transaction processing operating systems. The first one was IBM's Customer Information Control System. A transaction processor is a kind of OS where everything is like a CGI program - load program, do something, exit program. Unix and Linux are, underneath, terminal oriented time sharing systems.&lt;p&gt;- IBM MicroChannel. Early minicomputer and microcomputer designers thought "bus", where peripherals can talk to memory and peripherals look like memory to the CPU. Mainframes, though, had "channels", simple processors which connected peripherals to the CPU. Channels could run simple channel programs, and managed device access to memory. IBM tried to introduce that with the PS2, but they made it proprietary and that failed in the marketplace. Today, everything has something like channels, but they're not a unified interface concept that simplifies the OS.&lt;p&gt;- CPUs that really hypervise properly. That is, virtual execution environments look just like real ones. 
IBM did that in VM, and it worked well because channels are a good abstraction for both a real machine and a VM. Storing into device registers to make things happen is not. x86 has added several layers below the "real machine" layer, and they're all hacks.&lt;p&gt;- The Motorola 680x0 series. Should have been the foundation of the microcomputer era, but it took way too long to get the MMU out the door. The original 68000 came out in 1978, but then Motorola fell behind.&lt;p&gt;- Modula. Modula 2 and 3 were reasonably good languages. Oberon was a flop. DEC was into Modula, but Modula went down with DEC.&lt;p&gt;- XHTML. Have you ever read the parsing rules for HTML 5, where the semantics for bad HTML were formalized? Browsers should just punt at the first error, display an error message, and render the rest of the page in Times Roman.
Would it kill people to have to close their tags properly?&lt;p&gt;- Word Lens. Look at the world through your phone, and text is translated, standalone, on the device. No Internet connection required. Killed by Google in favor of hosted Google Translate.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 12 Oct 2025 07:24:22 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45556053</link><dc:creator>Animats</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45556053</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45556053</guid></item><item><title>New comment by kouteiheika in "Google blocks Android hack that let Pixel users enable VoLTE anywhere"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;The same way being allowed to install programs on your own computer is called "jailbreaking".&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 12 Oct 2025 04:09:51 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45555139</link><dc:creator>kouteiheika</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45555139</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45555139</guid></item><item><title>New comment by coreyhn in "Ask HN: Abandoned/dead projects you think died before their time and why?"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Yahoo pipes. It was so great at creating rss feeds and custom workflows. There are replacements now like Zapier and n8n but loved that. Also google reader which is mentioned multiple times already.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 12 Oct 2025 03:07:30 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45554825</link><dc:creator>coreyhn</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45554825</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45554825</guid></item><item><title>New comment by forgotoldacc in "Microsoft only lets you opt out of AI photo scanning 3x a year"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;This is Microsoft. They have a proven record of turning these toggles back on automatically without your consent.&lt;p&gt;So you can opt out of them taking all of your most private moments and putting them into a data set that will be leaked, but you can only opt out 3 times. What are the odds a "bug" (feature) turns it on 4 times? Anything less than 100% is an underestimate.&lt;p&gt;And what does a disclaimer mean, legally speaking? They won't face any consequences when they use it for training purposes. They'll simply deny that they do it. When it's revealed that they did it, they'll say sorry, that wasn't intentional. When it's revealed to be intentional, they'll say it's good for you so be quiet.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 12 Oct 2025 03:05:50 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45554816</link><dc:creator>forgotoldacc</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45554816</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45554816</guid></item><item><title>New comment by BirAdam in "Ask HN: Abandoned/dead projects you think died before their time and why?"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Google Wave.&lt;p&gt;Edit: you asked why. I first saw it at SELF where Chris DiBona showed it to me and a close friend. It was awesome. Real time translation, integration of various types of messaging, tons of cool capabilities, and it was fully open source. What made it out of Google was a stripped down version of what I was shown, the market rejected it, and it was a sad day. Now, I am left with JIRA, Slack, and email. It sucks.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 12 Oct 2025 02:43:19 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45554716</link><dc:creator>BirAdam</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45554716</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45554716</guid></item><item><title>New comment by userbinator in "Testing two 18 TB white label SATA hard drives from datablocks.dev"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Reading the part about using foam to make these drives quieter, and the link to the author's other article about putting drives on foam, makes me write this obligatory warning: hard drives do &lt;i&gt;not&lt;/i&gt; like non-rigid mounting. Yes, the servo can usually still position the heads on the right track (since it's a servo), but power dissipation will be higher, performance will be lower, and you may get more errors with a non-rigid mount. Around 20 years ago it was a short-lived fad in the silent-PC community to suspend drives on rubber bands, and many of those who did that experienced unusually short drive lifetimes and very high seek error rates. Elasticity is the worst, since it causes the actuator arm to oscillate. The ideal mount is as rigid as possible.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 12 Oct 2025 02:24:53 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45554612</link><dc:creator>userbinator</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45554612</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45554612</guid></item><item><title>New comment by ipsum2 in "Meta Superintelligence Labs' first paper is about RAG"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;This has nothing to do with superintelligence, it's just the people that were working on the paper prior to the re-org happened to publish after the name change.&lt;p&gt;Though it is notable that contrary to many (on HN and Twitter) that Meta would stop publishing papers and be like other AI labs (e.g. OpenAI). They're continued their rapid pace of releasing papers AND open source models.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 12 Oct 2025 01:00:25 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45554169</link><dc:creator>ipsum2</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45554169</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45554169</guid></item><item><title>New comment by godelski in "Meta Superintelligence Labs' first paper is about RAG"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;It's kinda funny, Meta has long had some of the best in the field, but left them untapped. I really think if they just took a step back and stop being so metric focused and let their people freely explore then they'd be winning the AI race. But with this new team, I feel like meta mostly hired the people who are really good at gaming the system. The people that care more about the money than the research.&lt;p&gt;A bit of this is true at every major lab. There's tons of untapped potential. But these organizations are very risk adverse. I mean why not continue with the strategy that got us to the point we're at in the first place. Labs used to hire researchers and give them a lot of free reign. But those times ended and AI progress also slowed down. Maybe if you want to get ahead you gotta stop thinking like everyone else&lt;p&gt;Well meta... you can "hold me hostage" for a lot cheaper than those guys. I'm sure this is true for hundreds of passionate ML researchers. I'd take a huge pay cut to have autonomy and resources. I know for a fact there's many working at Mets right now that would do the same. Do maybe if you're going to throw money at the problem, diversify a bit and look back at what made SV what it is today and what made AI take leaps forward&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 12 Oct 2025 00:55:34 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45554147</link><dc:creator>godelski</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45554147</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45554147</guid></item><item><title>New comment by brandonb927 in "Ask HN: Abandoned/dead projects you think died before their time and why?"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Google Reader: I will forever be salty about how Google killed something that likely required very little maintenance in the long run. It could have stayed exactly the same for a decade and I wouldn't have cared because I use an RSS reader exactly the same way I do that I did back in 2015.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 12 Oct 2025 00:50:47 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45554121</link><dc:creator>brandonb927</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45554121</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45554121</guid></item><item><title>New comment by Aurornis in "Microsoft only lets you opt out of AI photo scanning 3x a year"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;They could have avoided the negative press by changing the requirement to be that you can’t re-enable the feature after switching it off 3 times per year.&lt;p&gt;It’s not hard to guess the problem: Steady state operation will only incur scanning costs for newly uploaded photos, but toggling the feature off and then on would trigger a rescan of every photo in the library. That’s a potentially very expensive operation.&lt;p&gt;If you’ve ever studied user behavior you’ve discovered situations where users toggle things on and off in attempts to fix some issue. Normally this doesn’t matter much, but when a toggle could potentially cost large amounts of compute you have to be more careful.&lt;p&gt;For the privacy sensitive user who only wants to opt out this shouldn’t matter. Turn the switch off, leave it off, and it’s not a problem. This is meant to address the users who try to turn it off and then back on every time they think it will fix something. It only takes one bad SEO spam advice article about “How to fix _____ problem with your photos” that suggests toggling the option to fix some problem to trigger a wave of people doing it for no reason.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sun, 12 Oct 2025 00:47:58 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45554101</link><dc:creator>Aurornis</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45554101</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45554101</guid></item><item><title>New comment by bxparks in "Ask HN: Abandoned/dead projects you think died before their time and why?"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;A lot of things on &lt;a href="https://killedbygoogle.com/" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://killedbygoogle.com/&lt;/a&gt; . I used to use 30-40 Google products and services. I'm down to 3-4.&lt;p&gt;Google Picasa: Everything local, so fast, so good. I'm never going to give my photos to G Photos.&lt;p&gt;Google Hangouts: Can't keep track of all the Google chat apps. I use Signal now.&lt;p&gt;Google G Suite Legacy: It was supposed to be free forever. They killed it, tried to make me pay. I migrated out of Google.&lt;p&gt;Google Play Music: I had uploaded thousands of MP3 files there. They killed it. I won't waste my time uploading again.&lt;p&gt;Google Finance: Tracked my stocks and funds there. Then they killed it. Won't trust them with my data again.&lt;p&gt;Google NFC Wallet: They killed it. Then Apple launched the same thing, and took over.&lt;p&gt;Google Chromecast Audio: It did one thing, which is all I needed. Sold mine as soon as they announced they were killing it.&lt;p&gt;Google Chromecast: Wait, they killed Chromecast? I did not know that until I started writing this..&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 11 Oct 2025 23:45:27 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45553791</link><dc:creator>bxparks</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45553791</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45553791</guid></item><item><title>New comment by haunter in "Ask HN: Abandoned/dead projects you think died before their time and why?"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Vine. It was already pretty big back in 2013
but
Twitter had no idea what to do with it. TikTok actually launched just a few months before Vine was shut down and erased from the internet.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Sat, 11 Oct 2025 23:06:09 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45553492</link><dc:creator>haunter</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45553492</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45553492</guid></item></channel></rss>