<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>Hacker News: Best Comments</title><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/bestcomments</link><description>Hacker News RSS</description><docs>https://hnrss.org/</docs><generator>hnrss v2.1.1</generator><lastBuildDate>Fri, 26 Dec 2025 00:20:41 +0000</lastBuildDate><ns0:link href="https://hnrss.org/bestcomments" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item><title>New comment by JoeAltmaier in "Salesforce regrets firing 4000 experienced staff and replacing them with AI"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Somebody has to be the brave experimenter that tries the new thing. I'm just glad it was these folk. Since they make no tangible product and contribute nothing to society, they were perhaps the optimal choice to undergo these first catastrophic failed attempts at AI business.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 15:55:49 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46385114</link><dc:creator>JoeAltmaier</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46385114</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46385114</guid></item><item><title>New comment by A_D_E_P_T in "Alzheimer’s disease can be reversed in animal models? Study"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;The authors report that restoring NAD+ balance in the brain -- using a compound called P7C3-A20 -- completely reversed Alzheimer's pathology and recovered cognitive function in two different transgenic mouse models (one amyloid-based, one tau-based). The mice had advanced disease before treatment began.&lt;p&gt;Three comments:&lt;p&gt;- You can actually buy the drug here:  &lt;a href="https://focusbiomolecules.com/p7c3-a20-nampt-activator-proneurogenic-agent/" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://focusbiomolecules.com/p7c3-a20-nampt-activator-prone...&lt;/a&gt;
It's a simple small molecule.  If this stuff works, expect it to be everywhere within just a couple of years.&lt;p&gt;- There's room for skepticism.  As Derek Lowe once wrote: "Alzheimer's therapies have, for the most part, been a cliff over which people push bales of money. There are plenty of good reasons for this: we don't really know what the cause of Alzheimer's is, when you get down to it, and we're the only animal that we know of that gets it. Mouse models of the disease would be extremely useful – you wouldn't even have to know what the problem was to do some sort of phenotypic screen – but the transgenic mice used for these experiments clearly don't recapitulate the human disease. The hope for the last 25 years or so has been that they'd be close enough to get somewhere, but look where we are."&lt;p&gt;&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.science.org/content/blog-post/just-how-worthless-are-standard-alzheimer-s-models" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://www.science.org/content/blog-post/just-how-worthless...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;- If the drug's mechanism of action has been correctly assigned, it's very plausible that simply supplementing with NMN, NR, or NADH would work equally well.  The authors caution against this on, IMO, extremely shaky and unjustified grounds.  "Pieper emphasized that current over-the-counter NAD+-precursors have been shown in animal models to raise cellular NAD+ to dangerously high levels that promote cancer."&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 15:37:47 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46385008</link><dc:creator>A_D_E_P_T</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46385008</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46385008</guid></item><item><title>New comment by Zephilinox in "Mattermost restricted access to old messages after 10000 limit is reached"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;so not only did they enforce a ridiculously small message limit, they also did it for the self-hosted version, and they did it without announcing it AND without a suitable migration path&lt;p&gt;and still no one from that company has admitted to it being a mistake?&lt;p&gt;very nice&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 12:30:01 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46384018</link><dc:creator>Zephilinox</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46384018</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46384018</guid></item><item><title>New comment by cogman10 in "We invited a man into our home at Christmas and he stayed with us for 45 years"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Beautiful story but with a sad undertone.&lt;p&gt;A large percentage of the homeless have autism [1].  And that really sucks.  If these people don't have support, their lives can turn miserable fast.  And unfortunately it's just way too easy for these people to end up in abusive situations.&lt;p&gt;It's a lot of work to care for people with autism (moderate to severe).  There is no standard for what they need, their capabilities can be all over the board.  Some of them are capable like ronny in this story and they can hold down jobs.  But others need 24/7 caregiving in order to survive.  Unfortunately I don't think those with severe autism survive for long when they become homeless.&lt;p&gt;I hope this story at very least gets people to view the homeless a little differently.  They aren't all there because of vices or failure.  A large percentage are there because society does not care for those with mental disabilities.  It was good on this story to highlight that Ron had problems with gambling.  Autism does, in fact, make an individual more prone to various addictions.&lt;p&gt;My point in writing this, please have some humanity about the homeless.  I get that they can be inconvenient.  They are people and they aren't necessarily bad people due to their circumstances.&lt;p&gt;[1] &lt;a href="https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/29633853/" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/29633853/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 11:57:55 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46383864</link><dc:creator>cogman10</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46383864</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46383864</guid></item><item><title>New comment by wjnc in "We invited a man into our home at Christmas and he stayed with us for 45 years"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;My parents once took a struggling man in. I think he stayed with them for about three years, up until the moment I was conceived and my mom started planning for a future for our family and helped him get into a housing project. For all of my life before adulthood this man would show up once in a while on his racing bike  for coffee, talk and proceed to stay for dinner. He was kind, funny and a tidbit strange. His life's story had more drama than a soap opera, but you wouldn't know it. After my father died I proceeded to look for him, but never found him. I still search online for him once in a while, fully knowing he probably isn't alive anymore and probably wouldn't use online anyways. There is some story in my head that he probably showed up to my dads doorstep once on his racing bike to find other people living there, but was too shy to ask for details. A trace lost.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 11:38:39 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46383792</link><dc:creator>wjnc</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46383792</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46383792</guid></item><item><title>New comment by onion2k in "Tell HN: Merry Christmas"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Pretty sure it's a regex to match email address strings.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 08:29:52 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46383008</link><dc:creator>onion2k</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46383008</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46383008</guid></item><item><title>New comment by jbkkd in "Nvidia to buy assets from Groq for $20B cash"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I have a friend who worked in a company that got "not acquired" in a similar deal.&lt;p&gt;She didn't see a dime out of it, and was let off (together with a big chunk of people) within 6 months.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 05:29:55 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46382321</link><dc:creator>jbkkd</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46382321</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46382321</guid></item><item><title>New comment by NaOH in "Tell HN: Merry Christmas"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I'm taking a moment to recognize once more the work that user @atdrummond (Alex Thomas Drummond) did for a couple years to help others here. I did not know him, don’t think I ever interacted with him, and I did not benefit from his generosity, but I admired his kindness. Just beautiful.&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Ask HN: Who needs holiday help? (Follow up thread)&lt;/i&gt; - &lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=38706167"&gt;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=38706167&lt;/a&gt; - Dec 2023 (9 comments)&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Ask HN: Who needs help this holidays?&lt;/i&gt; - &lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=38492378"&gt;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=38492378&lt;/a&gt; - Dec 2023 (210 comments)&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Tell HN: Thank You&lt;/i&gt; - &lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=34140096"&gt;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=34140096&lt;/a&gt; - Dec 2022 (42 comments)&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Tell HN: Everyone should have a holiday dinner this year&lt;/i&gt; - &lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=34122118"&gt;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=34122118&lt;/a&gt; - Dec 2022 (58 comments)&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, Alex died a few months after his last round of holiday giving, about 1½ years ago now.&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Tell HN: In Memory of Alexander Thomas Drummond&lt;/i&gt; - &lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=40508725"&gt;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=40508725&lt;/a&gt; - May 2024 (5 comments)&lt;p&gt;If you read the comments in that last thread, know that @toomuchtodo followed through last year and kept the tradition alive. Amazing and magnificent.&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Ask HN: Who needs help this holidays?&lt;/i&gt; - &lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42291246"&gt;https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42291246&lt;/a&gt; - Dec 2024 (46 comments)&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 02:55:11 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46381665</link><dc:creator>NaOH</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46381665</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46381665</guid></item><item><title>New comment by andy_ppp in "Tell HN: Merry Christmas"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Happy Christmas everyone, I’m at 29000 feet on a flight to Hong Kong after a mini version of planes, trains and automobiles and including cancelled planes and taxis to different airports. I’m struck by honestly what a miracle it is that we can travel thousands of miles at hundreds of MPH and have okay internet access and communicate. I don’t think people quite realise how delicate all of the technology is now and how easily it could fail if we don’t all look after each other. I hope you all have a brilliant Christmas and new year!&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 00:32:21 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46380918</link><dc:creator>andy_ppp</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46380918</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46380918</guid></item><item><title>New comment by Grosvenor in "Tell HN: Merry Christmas"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;         *             ,
                      _/^\_
                     &lt;     &gt;
    *                 /.-.\         *
             *        `/&amp;\`                   *
                     ,@.*;@,
                    /_o.I %_\    *
       *           (`'--:o(_@;
                  /`;--.,__ `')             *
                 ;@`o % O,*`'`&amp;\
           *    (`'--)_@ ;o %'()\      *
                /`;--._`''--._O'@;
               /&amp;*,()~o`;-.,_ `""`)
    *          /`,@ ;+&amp; () o*`;-';\
              (`""--.,_0 +% @' &amp;()\
              /-.,_    ``''--....-'`)  *
         *    /@%;o`:;'--,.__   __.'\
             ;*,&amp;(); @ % &amp;^;~`"`o;@();         *
             /(); o^~; &amp; ().o@*&amp;`;&amp;%O\
       jgs   `"="==""==,,,.,="=="==="`
          __.----.(\-''#####---...___...-----._
        '`         \)_`"""""`
                .--' ')
              o(  )_-\
                `"""` `&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 23:57:01 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46380660</link><dc:creator>Grosvenor</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46380660</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46380660</guid></item><item><title>New comment by conqrr in "How I Left YouTube"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&gt; In the software engineering world, we exist on a ladder. We call this ”Leveling”.&lt;p&gt;Career is a made up game. There are no true levels or ladders in life that you have to chase. Nobody will care or remember what you did or what level you were given enough timespan. Take the bits that you want (money, skills etc) to live life, but don't get too caught up trying to win the game.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 23:45:48 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46380572</link><dc:creator>conqrr</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46380572</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46380572</guid></item><item><title>New comment by pdevr in "Tell HN: Merry Christmas"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Merry Christmas to everyone.&lt;p&gt;Being a non-Christian and it being Christmas time, I am sharing one verse from the New Testament that is, in my opinion, useful - or at the very least, insightful - to anyone, regardless of religion.&lt;p&gt;Luke 16:10: He who is faithful in a very little thing is faithful also in much; and he who is unrighteous in a very little thing is unrighteous also in much.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 23:40:49 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46380531</link><dc:creator>pdevr</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46380531</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46380531</guid></item><item><title>New comment by cluckindan in "Tell HN: Merry Christmas"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;      o
     / \
    o   o
       / \
      o   o
         / \
        o   o
       /   / \
      o   o   o
         /   / \
        o   o   o
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
I knew I should have invested in that fancy self-balancing one, oh well.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 23:40:31 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46380526</link><dc:creator>cluckindan</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46380526</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46380526</guid></item><item><title>New comment by DetectDefect in "Tell HN: Merry Christmas"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Shall we showcase our trees?&lt;p&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;        *
        |
       /.\
      /o..\
      /..O\
     /.o..o\
     /...o.\
    /..O..o.\
    ^^^[_]^^^&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 23:18:25 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46380357</link><dc:creator>DetectDefect</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46380357</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46380357</guid></item><item><title>New comment by sho_hn in "Phoenix: A modern X server written from scratch in Zig"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Pretty interesting approach to make an X server that is essentially "Wayland-like" (merging display server/compositor by default, isolated apps by default, no remoting of GLX, dropping legacy protocol features to the point of breaking compat with the core protocol, etc.). Not sure who this is for, but by itself it looks like a fairly reasonable set of choices.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 23:12:59 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46380322</link><dc:creator>sho_hn</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46380322</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46380322</guid></item><item><title>New comment by cosmic_cheese in "I'm returning my Framework 16"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;The crux of the matter is that even if one values upgradability and repairability, neither is a frequent need for practically anybody. Reliable machines rarely need repairs outside of owner mistreatment, and most people I know who are technically capable enough to care about upgrading generally do it maybe once every 4-6 years, by which point hardware has usually advanced far enough that buying a new laptop is easy to justify.&lt;p&gt;So while upgradability and repairability are great to have, their material impact on day to day user experience is minimal, except maybe for people who have a tendency to severely underspec their initial hardware purchases. On the other hand, things like chassis rigidity, cooling performance, fan noise, and battery life being subpar are constant reminders that you spent a pretty penny on a laptop that's not meeting your needs.&lt;p&gt;The reality may be that wanting a laptop that's well rounded and competent across the board AND repairable+upgradable is akin to having your cake and eating it too, but that doesn't stop people from wanting it anyway.&lt;p&gt;As an aside, I believe that Framework could probably get closer to that ideal if they unchained themselves from the port module idea. Yes it's cool, but it forces all sorts of design compromises that otherwise wouldn't be necessary, and I'd bet that something like 80-90% of Framework buyers would be just as happy if changing ports required opening up the chassis, swapping out side plates, and doing a little bit of internal wiring.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 22:16:18 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46379854</link><dc:creator>cosmic_cheese</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46379854</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46379854</guid></item><item><title>New comment by gchadwick in "Nvidia to buy assets from Groq for $20B cash"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Another example of the growing trend of buying out key parts of a company to avoid any actual acquisition?&lt;p&gt;I wonder if equity holding employees get anything from the deal or indeed if all the investors will be seeing a return from this?&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 22:15:13 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46379848</link><dc:creator>gchadwick</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46379848</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46379848</guid></item><item><title>New comment by justincormack in "Nvidia to buy assets from Groq for $20B cash"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;So it is not structured as an acquisition to avoid anti trust but effectively it probably is.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 21:56:05 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46379693</link><dc:creator>justincormack</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46379693</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46379693</guid></item><item><title>New comment by nickysielicki in "Nvidia to buy assets from Groq for $20B cash"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Groq press release: &lt;a href="https://groq.com/newsroom/groq-and-nvidia-enter-non-exclusive-inference-technology-licensing-agreement-to-accelerate-ai-inference-at-global-scale" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://groq.com/newsroom/groq-and-nvidia-enter-non-exclusiv...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;&gt; Today, Groq announced that it has entered into a non-exclusive licensing agreement with Nvidia for Groq’s inference technology. The agreement reflects a shared focus on expanding access to high-performance, low cost inference.&lt;p&gt;&gt; As part of this agreement, Jonathan Ross, Groq’s Founder, Sunny Madra, Groq’s President, and other members of the Groq team will join Nvidia to help advance and scale the licensed technology.&lt;p&gt;&gt; Groq will continue to operate as an independent company with Simon Edwards stepping into the role of Chief Executive Officer.&lt;p&gt;&gt; GroqCloud will continue to operate without interruption.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 21:48:08 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46379609</link><dc:creator>nickysielicki</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46379609</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46379609</guid></item><item><title>New comment by syntaxing in "Nvidia to buy assets from Groq for $20B cash"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I don’t see how this isn’t anti trust but knowing this political climate, this deal will go through.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 21:30:30 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46379445</link><dc:creator>syntaxing</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46379445</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46379445</guid></item><item><title>New comment by comte7092 in "I'm returning my Framework 16"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I appreciate the authors thoughtful review here, but I can’t help but be frustrated by the constant lack of understanding of the core value proposition of framework both in this post and in many comments here on hn.&lt;p&gt;Frequently the author brings up that for 2,000 euros they expect a premium experience, but no where is there an evaluation of the value granted by upgradability and repeatability of the machine, and only briefly is there mention of the configurability.&lt;p&gt;People (not necessarily the author, but likely many commentators that make similar complains about the frameworks price) will lament how manufacturers don’t have upgradable ram, etc and then turn around and are upset at the bulkiness of a repairable laptop, or the price.&lt;p&gt;I think ultimately what frustrates me is that people don’t consider the ability to repair or upgrade your machine part of a “premium” experience, but that’s is just something I have to accept. I think it is unfortunate that our consumerist culture places so little value on it though.&lt;p&gt;Rergardless, what I feel like we see here (along with a lack of scale from a small company) is the core tradeoffs that we’d have to make to get back repairability, etc. framework certainly isn’t above criticism, but if you don’t care about these things then why look at this machine? A large established brand is always going to offer a a better value on the things you care about.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 17:34:42 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46377476</link><dc:creator>comte7092</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46377476</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46377476</guid></item><item><title>New comment by pwg in "Some Epstein file redactions are being undone"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;The journalist writing the story has the same level of technical knowledge about how to "redact" properly in the digital realm as the individuals doing the redaction.  To the journalist, with zero knowledge of the technical aspects, viewing the "redacted" document, it appears to be "redacted", so when someone "unredacts" it, the action of revealing the otherwise hidden material appears to be "magical" to them (in the vein of the Arthur C Clarke quote of: "Any sufficiently advanced technology is indistinguishable from magic").&lt;p&gt;To the journalist, it looks like "hackers at work" because the result looks like magic.  Therefore their editor attaching "hacks" to the title for additional clickbait as well.&lt;p&gt;To us technical people, who understand the concept of layers in digital editing, it is no big deal at all (and is not surprising that some percentage of the PDF's have been processed this way).&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 13:18:15 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46375311</link><dc:creator>pwg</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46375311</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46375311</guid></item><item><title>New comment by barrkel in "Avoid Mini-Frameworks"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&gt; &lt;i&gt;real and only difference between a library and a framework, is whether it introduces new concepts&lt;/i&gt;&lt;p&gt;This isn't what is normally understood in software engineering by those terms.&lt;p&gt;A library is something you call.&lt;p&gt;A framework is some kind of application scaffolding that normally calls you.&lt;p&gt;You can use more than one library. You normally only have one framework in-process.&lt;p&gt;I found the blog post a little hard to parse. Is it an argument against wrapping frameworks, or wrapping libraries?&lt;p&gt;I agree that wrapping frameworks is fraught with danger. I can't quite agree for wrapping libraries. Wrapping libraries makes a lot of sense if you're only using a tiny fraction of the library functionality, the breadth of the wrapper's API is much smaller than the library's API, wrapping it enables you to substitute it (whether for a smaller / faster / whatever dependency in the future, or for testing, etc.), and so on.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 13:00:31 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46375199</link><dc:creator>barrkel</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46375199</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46375199</guid></item><item><title>New comment by Arch-TK in "Some Epstein file redactions are being undone"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;It sets a bad precedent to call things like this hacks.&lt;p&gt;Firstly, calling this redaction implies that the data is missing, and calling what was done "unredacting" is akin to saying someone "decrypted" a cryptographic hash function.&lt;p&gt;Nobody unredacted anything here, they merely discovered that it hadn't been redacted, and simply looked like it was redacted.&lt;p&gt;Calling this a hack places responsibility on the people who discovered the information, rather than on the people were put in charge of handling the redaction and screwed it up.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 12:48:31 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46375128</link><dc:creator>Arch-TK</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46375128</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46375128</guid></item><item><title>New comment by OneMorePerson in "Some Epstein file redactions are being undone"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;It's funny seeing this play out because in my personal life anytime I'm sharing a sensitive document where someone needs to see part of it but I don't want them to see the rest that's not relevant, I'll first block out/redact the text I don't want them to see (covering it, using a redacting highlighter thing, etc.), and then I'll screenshot the page and make that image a PDF.&lt;p&gt;I always felt paranoid (without any real evidence, just a guess) that there would always be a chance that anything done in software could be reversed somehow.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 06:36:46 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46373061</link><dc:creator>OneMorePerson</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46373061</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46373061</guid></item><item><title>New comment by RadiozRadioz in "Show HN: Turn raw HTML into production-ready images for free"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;They're bedazzled by a little bit of marketing flair.&lt;p&gt;Generally I find production-ready images have more synergy and tend to be web-scale. Often they're built from the ground up for AI &amp; are blazing fast, at scale, and empower your team  whilst unlocking new possibilities. As my sibling comment suggests, being cloud-native is a crucial factor too.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 06:32:58 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46373042</link><dc:creator>RadiozRadioz</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46373042</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46373042</guid></item><item><title>New comment by heavyset_go in "Some Epstein file redactions are being undone"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I want to believe this is malicious compliance.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 06:02:08 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46372914</link><dc:creator>heavyset_go</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46372914</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46372914</guid></item><item><title>New comment by vincengomes in "Some Epstein file redactions are being undone"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;"Never interrupt your enemy when he is making a mistake" -  Napoleon Bonaparte&lt;p&gt;Let all the files get released first.&lt;p&gt;Then show your hacks.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 04:20:05 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46372417</link><dc:creator>vincengomes</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46372417</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46372417</guid></item><item><title>New comment by wateralien in "Unifi Travel Router"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I never travel without my GL-AXT1800. Saved me so many times: &lt;a href="https://www.gl-inet.com/products/gl-axt1800/" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://www.gl-inet.com/products/gl-axt1800/&lt;/a&gt;
I’m actually on it right now.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 01:06:19 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46371338</link><dc:creator>wateralien</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46371338</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46371338</guid></item><item><title>New comment by robkop in "Texas app store age verification law blocked by federal judge"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;For those curious about the "consistent principle of law" here - SCOTUS wrestled with nearly exactly this question in Free Speech Coalition v. Paxton earlier this year, and effectively emboldened more of these laws.&lt;p&gt;Previously the Fifth Circuit had relied heavily on Ginsberg v. New York (1968) to justify rational basis review. But Ginsberg was a narrow scope - it held that minors don't have the same First Amendment rights as adults to access "obscene as to minors" material. It wasn't about burdens on adults at all. Later precedent (Ashcroft, Sable, Reno, Playboy) consistently applied strict scrutiny when laws burdened adults' access to protected speech, even when aimed at protecting minors.&lt;p&gt;In Paxton the majority split the difference and applied intermediate scrutiny - a lower bar than strict - claiming the burden on adults is merely "incidental." Kagan had a dissent worth reading, arguing this departs from precedent even if the majority won't frame it that way. You could call it "overturning" or "distinguishing" depending on how charitable you're feeling.&lt;p&gt;The oral arguments are worth watching if you want to understand how to grapple with these questions: &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ckoCJthJEqQ" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ckoCJthJEqQ&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;On 1A: The core concern isn't that age-gating exists - it's that mandatory identification to access legal speech creates chilling effects and surveillance risks that don't exist when you flash an ID at a liquor store.&lt;p&gt;Note: IANAL but do enjoy reading many SC transcripts&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2025 00:01:56 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46370957</link><dc:creator>robkop</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46370957</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46370957</guid></item></channel></rss>