<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>Hacker News: Best Comments</title><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/bestcomments</link><description>Hacker News RSS</description><docs>https://hnrss.org/</docs><generator>hnrss v2.1.1</generator><lastBuildDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2025 01:16:56 +0000</lastBuildDate><ns0:link href="https://hnrss.org/bestcomments" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item><title>New comment by usrnm in "The EU made Apple adopt new Wi-Fi standards, and now Android can support AirDrop"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Apple also helped develop USB C more than a decade ago, they still had to be forced to actually use it in their phones. There is no contradiction here&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 21:49:53 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46062756</link><dc:creator>usrnm</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46062756</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46062756</guid></item><item><title>New comment by 3rodents in "S&amp;box is now an open source game engine"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;For those unfamiliar, the studio behind S&amp;box is Facepunch, creators of Garry's Mod and Rust. Facepunch as a company doesn't get much attention but they're wildly successful. Started as just some guy in a bedroom, now ~$100m/year in revenue (all via Steam), $100m in the bank, ~100 employees and almost entirely a company of game developers (maybe 20% of employees are administrative staff). Still owned and ran by the founder, Garry. S&amp;box (and Garry's Mod and Rust) is pure game developers making things they want to make.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 20:44:55 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46062114</link><dc:creator>3rodents</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46062114</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46062114</guid></item><item><title>New comment by vessenes in "Cloudflare outage should not have happened"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;"If they had a perfectly normalized database, no NULLing and formally verified code, this bug would not have happened."&lt;p&gt;That may be. What's not specified there is the immense, immense cost of driving a dev org on those terms. It limits, radically, the percent of engineers you can hire (to those who understand this and are willing to work this way), and it slows deployment radically.&lt;p&gt;Cloudflare may well need to transition to this sort of engineering culture, but there is no doubt that they would not be in the position they are in if they &lt;i&gt;started&lt;/i&gt; with this culture -- they would have been too slow to capture the market.&lt;p&gt;I think critiques that have actionable plans for real dev teams are likely to be more useful than what, to me, reads as a sort of complaint from an ivory tower. Culture matters, shipping speed matters, quality matters, team DNA matters. That's what makes this stuff hard (and interesting!)&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 17:11:32 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46059729</link><dc:creator>vessenes</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46059729</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46059729</guid></item><item><title>New comment by locknitpicker in "Cloudflare outage should not have happened"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;This sort of Monday morning quarterbacking is pointless and only serves as a way for random bloggers to try to grab credit without actually doing or creating any value.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 17:10:17 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46059705</link><dc:creator>locknitpicker</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46059705</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46059705</guid></item><item><title>New comment by easterncalculus in "I don't care how well your "AI" works"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&gt; I find it particularly disillusioning to realize how deep the LLM brainworm is able to eat itself even into progressive hacker circles.&lt;p&gt;That's the thing, hacker circles didn't always have this 'progressive' luddite mentality. This is the culture that replaced hacker culture.&lt;p&gt;I don't like AI, generally. I am skeptical of corporate influence, I doubt AI 2027 and so-called 'AGI'. I'm certain we'll be "five years away" from superintelligence for the forseeable future. All that said, the actual workday is absolutely filled with busy work that no one really wants to do, and the refusal of a loud minority to engage with that fact is what's leading to this. It's why people can't post a meme, quote, article, whatever could be interpreted (very often, falsely) as AI-generated in a public channel, or ask a chatbot to explain a hand-drawn image without the off chance that they get an earful from one of these 'progressive' people. These people bring way more toxicity to daily life than who they wage their campaigns against.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 14:58:07 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46057976</link><dc:creator>easterncalculus</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46057976</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46057976</guid></item><item><title>New comment by embedding-shape in "I don't care how well your "AI" works"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&gt; And yeah, I get it. We programmers are currently living through the devaluation of our craft, in a way and rate we never anticipated possible.&lt;p&gt;I'm a programmer, been coding professionally for 10 something years, and coding for myself longer than that.&lt;p&gt;What are they talking about? What is this "devaluation"? I'm getting paid more than ever for a job I feel like I almost shouldn't get paid for (I'm just having fun), and programmers should be some of the most worry-free individuals on this planet, the job is easy, well-paid, not a lot of health drawbacks if you have a proper setup and relatively easy to find a new job when you need it (granted, the US seems to struggle with that specific point as of late, yet it remains true in the rest of the world).&lt;p&gt;And now, we're having a huge explosion of tools for developers, to build software that has to be maintained by developers, made by developers for developers.&lt;p&gt;If anything, it seems like Balmers plea of "Developers, developers, developers" has came true, and if there will be one profession left in 100 year when AI does everything for us (if the vibers are to be believed), then that'd probably be software developers and machine learning experts.&lt;p&gt;What exactly is being de-valuated for a profession that seems to be continuously growing and been doing so for at least 20 years?&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 11:37:21 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46056395</link><dc:creator>embedding-shape</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46056395</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46056395</guid></item><item><title>New comment by pxc in "Ilya Sutskever: We're moving from the age of scaling to the age of research"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;If "Era of Scaling" means "era of rapid and predictable performance improvements that easily attract investors", it sounds a lot like "AI summer". So... is "Era of Research" a euphemism for "AI winter"?&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 01:00:43 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46052864</link><dc:creator>pxc</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46052864</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46052864</guid></item><item><title>New comment by dav43 in "Someone at YouTube Needs Glasses: The Prophecy Has Been Fulfilled"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;It’s crazy you can pay for premium, which is not cheap, and you can’t disable shorts.&lt;p&gt;The number of times I clicked “show less” and it has zero effect on the number of shorts.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 00:19:09 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46052579</link><dc:creator>dav43</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46052579</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46052579</guid></item><item><title>New comment by MBCook in "Someone at YouTube Needs Glasses: The Prophecy Has Been Fulfilled"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I noticed this morning there was a new version of the YouTube app on my Apple TV. I can’t wait to find out how they screwed this one up.&lt;p&gt;My personal long-term complaint is the length of video titles.&lt;p&gt;Lots of people like to make really long video titles. So right now there is one on my screen titled “The Best Decisions Every Video Game Console Developer Made”.&lt;p&gt;Now if you didn’t know, that is not the whole title. But there’s absolutely no indication of that. The only way you actually know that is either by checking or if the stuff on the screen is clearly not the end of a sentence.&lt;p&gt;So what is the full title? Well if you click and hold on the video, you get a pop-up letting you choose a couple of things such as play or safe to watch later or indicate you’re not interested. And at the top of the pop-up you see more words in the title. In this case you also see “(Part”.&lt;p&gt;Yep. You get ONE extra word. Sometimes not even that.&lt;p&gt;The ONLY way to see the full title is to start watching the video.&lt;p&gt;Obnoxious.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 23:58:10 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46052377</link><dc:creator>MBCook</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46052377</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46052377</guid></item><item><title>New comment by JumpCrisscross in "Someone at YouTube Needs Glasses: The Prophecy Has Been Fulfilled"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I used to pay for YouTube premium. I stopped doing that, uninstalled the apps, and now use it through the browser with adblockers. (Yes, on my phone and iPad.)&lt;p&gt;It works so well I’ve gotten at least half a dozen neighbours to do the same. If you haven’t tried it, it’s a definitive step up in UX.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 23:51:01 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46052317</link><dc:creator>JumpCrisscross</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46052317</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46052317</guid></item><item><title>New comment by 7373737373 in "Someone at YouTube Needs Glasses: The Prophecy Has Been Fulfilled"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Whoever made automatic AI dubs a default and impossible to disable also needs to be fired&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 23:49:48 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46052301</link><dc:creator>7373737373</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46052301</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46052301</guid></item><item><title>New comment by aorist in "Python is not a great language for data science"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&gt; Examples include converting boxplots into violins or vice versa, turning a line plot into a heatmap, plotting a density estimate instead of a histogram, performing a computation on ranked data values instead of raw data values, and so on.&lt;p&gt;Most of this is not about Python, it’s about matplotlib. If you want the admittedly very thoughtful design of ggplot in Python, use plotnine&lt;p&gt;&gt; I would consider the R code to be slightly easier to read (notice how many quotes and brackets the Python code needs)&lt;p&gt;This isn’t about Python, it’s about the tidyverse. The reason you can use this simpler syntax in R is because it’s non-standard-evaluation allows packages to extend the syntax in a way Python does not expose: &lt;a href="http://adv-r.had.co.nz/Computing-on-the-language.html" rel="nofollow"&gt;http://adv-r.had.co.nz/Computing-on-the-language.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 22:08:10 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46051391</link><dc:creator>aorist</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46051391</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46051391</guid></item><item><title>New comment by shagie in "Trillions spent and big software projects are still failing"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&gt; If you need to make a national payroll, you have to use it for a small town with a payroll of 50 people first, get the bugs worked out, then try it with a larger town, then a small city, then a large city, then a province, and then and only then are you ready to try it at a national level.&lt;p&gt;At a large box retail chain (15 states, ~300 stores) I worked on a project to replace the POS system.&lt;p&gt;The original plan had us getting everything working (Ha!) and then deploying it out to stores and then ending up with the two oddball "stores".  The company cafeteria and surplus store were technically stores in that they had all the same setup and processes but were odd.&lt;p&gt;When the team that I was on was brought into this project, we flipped that around and &lt;i&gt;first&lt;/i&gt; deployed to those two several months ahead of the schedule to deploy to the regular stores.&lt;p&gt;In particular, the surplus store had a few dozen transactions a day.  If anything broke, you could do reconciliation by hand. The cafeteria had single register transaction volume that surpassed a surplus store on most any other day.  Furthermore, all of its transactions were payroll deductions (swipe your badge rather than credit card or cash).  This meant that if anything went wrong &lt;i&gt;there&lt;/i&gt; we weren't in trouble with PCI and could debit and credit accounts.&lt;p&gt;Ultimately, we made our deadline to get things out to stores.  We did have one &lt;i&gt;nasty&lt;/i&gt; bug that showed up in late October (or was it early November?) with repackaging counts (if a box of 6 was $24 and if purchased as a single item it was $4.50 ... but if you bought 6 single items it was "repackaged" to cost $24 rather than $27) which interacted with a BOGO sale.  That bug resulted in absurd receipts with sales and discounts (the receipt showed you spent $10,000 but were discounted $9,976 ... and then the GMs got alerts that the store was not able to make payroll because of a $9,976 discount ... one of the devs pulled an all nighter to fix that one and it got pushed to the stores ).&lt;p&gt;I shudder to think about what would have happened if we had tried to push the POS system out to customer facing stores where the performance issues in the cafeteria where worked out first or if we had to reconcile transactions to hunt down incorrect tax calculations.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 21:45:07 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46051170</link><dc:creator>shagie</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46051170</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46051170</guid></item><item><title>New comment by rossdavidh in "Trillions spent and big software projects are still failing"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;It's a great article, until the end where they say what the solution would be.  I'm afraid that the solution is: build something small, and use it in production before you add more features.  If you need to make a national payroll, you have to use it for a small town with a payroll of 50 people first, get the bugs worked out, then try it with a larger town, then a small city, then a large city, then a province, and then and only then are you ready to try it at a national level.  There is no software development process which reliably produces software that works at scale without doing it small, and medium sized, first, and fixing what goes wrong before you go big.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 19:30:45 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46049703</link><dc:creator>rossdavidh</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46049703</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46049703</guid></item><item><title>New comment by wingmanjd in "Google Antigravity exfiltrates data via indirect prompt injection attack"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I really liked Simon's Willison's [1] and Meta's [2] approach using the "Rule of Two".  You can have no more than 2 of the following:&lt;p&gt;- A) Process untrustworthy input
- B) Have access to private data
- C) Be able to change external state or communicate externally.&lt;p&gt;It's not bullet-proof, but it has helped communicate to my management that these tools have inherent risk when they hit all three categories above (and any combo of them, imho).&lt;p&gt;[EDIT] added "or communicate externally" to option C.&lt;p&gt;[1] &lt;a href="https://simonwillison.net/2025/Nov/2/new-prompt-injection-papers/" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://simonwillison.net/2025/Nov/2/new-prompt-injection-pa...&lt;/a&gt;
[2] &lt;a href="https://ai.meta.com/blog/practical-ai-agent-security/" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://ai.meta.com/blog/practical-ai-agent-security/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 19:23:06 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46049625</link><dc:creator>wingmanjd</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46049625</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46049625</guid></item><item><title>New comment by decimalenough in "Jakarta is now the biggest city in the world"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I used to spend a lot of time in Jakarta for work, and it's an underrated city. Yes, it's hot, congested, polluted and largely poor, but so is Bangkok.&lt;p&gt;Public transport remains not great, but it's improved a lot with the airport link, the metro, LRT, Transjakarta BRT. SE Asia's only legit high speed train now connects to Bandung in minutes. Grab/Gojek (Uber equivalents) make getting around cheap and bypass the language barrier. Hotels are incredible value, you can get top tier branded five stars for $100. Shopping for locally produced clothes etc is stupidly cheap. Indonesian food is amazing, there's so much more to it than nasi goreng, and you can find great Japanese, Italian, etc too; these are comparatively expensive but lunch at the Italian place in the Ritz-Carlton was under $10. The nightlife scene is &lt;i&gt;wild&lt;/i&gt;, although you need to make local friends to really get into it. And it's reasonably safe, violent crime is basically unknown and I never had problems with pickpockets (although they do exist) or scammers.&lt;p&gt;I think Jakarta's biggest problems are lack of marketing and top tier obvious attractions. Bangkok has royal palaces and temples galore plus a wild reputation for go-go bars etc, Jakarta does not, so nobody even considers it as a vacation destination.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 19:18:31 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46049578</link><dc:creator>decimalenough</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46049578</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46049578</guid></item><item><title>New comment by ArcHound in "Google Antigravity exfiltrates data via indirect prompt injection attack"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Who would have thought that having access to the whole system can be used to bypass some artificial check.&lt;p&gt;There are tools for that, sandboxing, chroots, etc... but that requires engineering and it slows GTM, so it's a no-go.&lt;p&gt;No, local models won't help you here, unless you block them from the internet or setup a firewall for outbound traffic. EDIT: they did, but left a site that enables arbitrary redirects in the default config.&lt;p&gt;Fundamentally, with LLMs you can't separate instructions from data, which is the root cause for 99% of vulnerabilities.&lt;p&gt;Security is hard man, excellent article, thoroughly enjoyed.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 19:02:04 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46049385</link><dc:creator>ArcHound</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46049385</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46049385</guid></item><item><title>New comment by baobabKoodaa in "Show HN: We built an open source, zero webhooks payment processor"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;For those who are wondering, like me, what is this? Is this a new alternative to Stripe? The answer is: no. This is an added layer of abstraction on top of Stripe.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 17:46:24 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46048412</link><dc:creator>baobabKoodaa</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46048412</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46048412</guid></item><item><title>New comment by malfist in "Trillions spent and big software projects are still failing"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I work at $FANG, every one of our org's big projects go off the rails at the end of the project and there's always a mad rush at the end to push developers to solve all the failures of project management in their off hours before the arbitrary deadline arrives.&lt;p&gt;After every single project, the org comes together to do a retrospective and ask "What can devs do differently next time to keep this from happening again". People leading the project take no action items, management doesn't hold themselves accountable at all, nor product for late changing requirements. And so, the cycle repeats next time.&lt;p&gt;I led and effort one time, after a big bug made it to production after one of those crunches that painted the picture of the root cause being a huge complicated project being handed off to offshore junior devs with no supervision, and then the junior devs managing it being completely switched twice in the 8 month project with no handover, nor introspection by leadership. My manager's manager killed the document and wouldn't allow publication until I removed any action items that would constrain management.&lt;p&gt;And thus, the cycle continues to repeat, balanced on the backs of developers.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 17:14:06 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46048044</link><dc:creator>malfist</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46048044</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46048044</guid></item><item><title>New comment by BirAdam in "Trillions spent and big software projects are still failing"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I study and write quite a bit of tech history. IMHO from what I've learned over the last few years of this hobby, the primary issue is quite simple. While hardware folks study and learn from the successes and failures of past hardware, software folks do not. People do not regularly pull apart old systems for learning. Typically, software folks build new and every generation of software developers must relearn the same problems.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 16:27:27 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46047424</link><dc:creator>BirAdam</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46047424</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46047424</guid></item><item><title>New comment by slfnflctd in "Brain has five 'eras' with adult mode not starting until early 30s"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;It took me until my mid-30s to feel like I had crossed a threshold in processing grief and trauma from my late teen years.  I was capable of adult behavior long before then, but my concept of the world and how I fit into it (or don't) was still childlike in many ways on a fundamental level.&lt;p&gt;Like most such things, I'd expect this to be a spectrum, and I may be somewhat of a late bloomer.  Regardless, I have a theory that there is somewhat of a protective effect operating here.  Believing in a simpler reality which involved future wish fulfillment for me - however unrealistic it was - may have helped me survive.  Coming to acceptance of what I see as a more accurate but far bleaker perspective required me to grow strong enough to sustain my will to live despite that perspective.&lt;p&gt;Biggest lesson learned:  I could not do it without at least one other person (or more) who I trust almost 100% with all of myself.  Realizing that going it alone is futile is definitely part of what I consider becoming an adult, and it can take a long time to fully accept that.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 15:03:38 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46046376</link><dc:creator>slfnflctd</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46046376</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46046376</guid></item><item><title>New comment by geerlingguy in "APT Rust requirement raises questions"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I remembered reading about this news back when that first message was posted on the mailing list, and didn't think much of it then (rust has been worming its way into a lot of places over the past few years, just one more thing I tack on for some automation)...&lt;p&gt;But seeing the maintainer works for Canonical, it seems like the tail (Ubuntu) keeps trying to wag the dog (Debian ecosystem) without much regard for the wider non-Ubuntu community.&lt;p&gt;I think the whole message would be more palatable if it weren't written as a decree including the dig on "retro computers", but instead positioned only on the merits of the change.&lt;p&gt;As an end user, it doesn't concern me too much, but someone choosing to add a new dependency chain to critical software plumbing does, at least slightly, if not done for very good reason.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 14:57:48 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46046320</link><dc:creator>geerlingguy</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46046320</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46046320</guid></item><item><title>New comment by benterix in "AI has a deep understanding of how this code works"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Did these Ocaml maintainers undergo some special course for dealing with difficult people? They show enormous amounts of maturity and patience. I'd just give the offender Torvalds' treatment and block them from the repo, case closed.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 13:14:01 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46045482</link><dc:creator>benterix</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46045482</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46045482</guid></item><item><title>New comment by leo_e in "Pebble Watch software is now open source"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;As someone dealing with open-source compliance in distributed systems, the purity tests in these comments are exhausting.&lt;p&gt;Hardware is messy. IP licensing for sensors and radios is a nightmare. Getting a functional OS out with "only" a few binary blobs is a massive engineering and legal victory.&lt;p&gt;I'd rather have a working, 95% open ecosystem that I can actually hack on, than a 100% pure theoretical one that never ships. Kudos to Eric for navigating the legal minefield to make this happen.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 12:56:09 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46045339</link><dc:creator>leo_e</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46045339</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46045339</guid></item><item><title>New comment by oliwarner in "AI has a deep understanding of how this code works"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;There are LLMs with more self-awareness than this guy.&lt;p&gt;Repeatedly using AI to answer questions about the legitimacy of commits from an AI, to people who are &lt;i&gt;clearly&lt;/i&gt; skeptical is breathtakingly dense. At least they're open about it.&lt;p&gt;I did love the ~"I'll help maintain this trash mountain, but I'll need paying". Classy.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 12:02:22 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46045021</link><dc:creator>oliwarner</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46045021</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46045021</guid></item><item><title>New comment by theknarf in "Claude Advanced Tool Use"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;We should just build more CLI tools, that way the agentic AI can just run `yourtool --help` to learn how to use it. Instead of needing an MCP-server to access ex. Jira it should just call a cli tool `jira`. Better CLI tools for everything would help both AI and humans alike.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 10:26:02 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46044438</link><dc:creator>theknarf</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46044438</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46044438</guid></item><item><title>New comment by liendolucas in "Google's new 'Aluminium OS' project brings Android to PC"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;No one tech-savvy wants this. We are already sick of Google's Android lockdowns on mobile phones, and now coming after laptops and desktops?&lt;p&gt;What's that going to be like? Will developers have to beg to have control over devices they own? Will we be locked down on the store and have to manually install "unverified" software? Will I be able to take screenshots at will on MY computer, or get a black screen because Google decides so?&lt;p&gt;The list can go on and on ad nauseam. Given what Google has done on the mobile space I have zero interest in having the same autocratic experience to be replicated on the last type of devices (PCs and laptops) where we can really have true open choices and alternatives. Screw them.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 09:03:32 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46043865</link><dc:creator>liendolucas</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46043865</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46043865</guid></item><item><title>New comment by Animats in "Human brains are preconfigured with instructions for understanding the world"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Some animals are ready to go as soon as they are born. These are called precocial animals. They are born knowing how to walk.&lt;p&gt;It's interesting seeing what comes built-in. You can see this if you watch a horse being born. Within the first hour, the foal will stand, and despite long legs, this usually works the first time. Lying down, however, is not preprogrammed. I've watched a foal circle trying to figure out how to get down from standing, and finally collapsing to the ground in a heap. Standing up quickly is essential to survival, but smoothly lying down is not.
Within a day, a newborn foal can run with the herd.&lt;p&gt;Of the mammals, most of the equines and some of the rodents (beavers) are precocial.
Pigs are, monkeys are not. It's not closely tied to evolutionary ancestry.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 07:02:32 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46043084</link><dc:creator>Animats</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46043084</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46043084</guid></item><item><title>New comment by autumnstwilight in "AI has a deep understanding of how this code works"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&gt;&gt;&gt; Here's my question: why did the files that you submitted name Mark Shinwell as the author?&lt;p&gt;&gt;&gt;&gt; Beats me. AI decided to do so and I didn't question it.&lt;p&gt;Really sums the whole thing up...&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 01:41:50 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46041467</link><dc:creator>autumnstwilight</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46041467</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46041467</guid></item><item><title>New comment by userbinator in "Unpowered SSDs slowly lose data"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;One key point about retention which is not often mentioned, and indeed neither does this article, is that retention is inversely proportional to program/erase cycles and decreases exponentially with increasing temperature. Hence why retention specs are usually X amount of time after Y cycles at Z temperature. Even a QLC SSD that has only been written to once, and kept in a freezer at -40, may hold data for several decades.&lt;p&gt;Manufacturers have been playing this game with DWPD/TBW numbers too --- by reducing the retention spec, they can advertise a drive as having a higher endurance with the exact same flash. But if you compare the numbers over the years, it's clear that NAND flash has gotten significantly worse; the only thing that has gone up, multiplicatively, is capacity, while endurance and rentention have both gone down by a few orders of magnitude.&lt;p&gt;For a long time, 10 years after 100K cycles was the gold standard of SLC flash.&lt;p&gt;Now we are down to several months after less than 1K cycles for QLC.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 01:37:46 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46041442</link><dc:creator>userbinator</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46041442</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46041442</guid></item></channel></rss>