<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:ns0="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>Hacker News: Best Comments</title><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/bestcomments</link><description>Hacker News RSS</description><docs>https://hnrss.org/</docs><generator>hnrss v2.1.1</generator><lastBuildDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 00:29:54 +0000</lastBuildDate><ns0:link href="https://hnrss.org/bestcomments" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item><title>New comment by jonny_eh in "Tell HN: HN was down"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Your sleep is more important than our work distraction.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 19:51:33 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46304618</link><dc:creator>jonny_eh</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46304618</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46304618</guid></item><item><title>New comment by rsanek in "AWS CEO says replacing junior devs with AI is 'one of the dumbest ideas'"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;"without losing face"? What culture are you referring to? The Western companies I have worked at do not discourage such questions -- in fact, it's often the sign of someone very senior when they ask a seemingly 'dumb' question that others have taken for granted.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 19:46:30 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46304549</link><dc:creator>rsanek</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46304549</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46304549</guid></item><item><title>New comment by alexgotoi in "AWS CEO says replacing junior devs with AI is 'one of the dumbest ideas'"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;The thing people miss in these “replace juniors with AI” takes is that juniors were never mainly about cheap hands on keyboards. They’re the only people in the org who are still allowed to ask “dumb” questions without losing face, and those questions are often the only signal you get that your abstractions are nonsense.&lt;p&gt;What AI does is remove a bunch of the humiliating, boring parts of being junior: hunting for the right API by cargo-culting Stack Overflow, grinding through boilerplate, getting stuck for hours on a missing import. If a half-decent model can collapse that search space for them, you get to spend more of their ramp time on “here’s how our system actually fits together” instead of “here’s how for-loops work in our house style”.&lt;p&gt;If you take that setup and then decide “cool, now we don’t need juniors at all”, you’re basically saying you want a company with no memory and no farm system – just an ever-shrinking ring of seniors arguing about strategy while no one actually grows into them.&lt;p&gt;Always love to include a good AI x work thread in my &lt;a href="https://hackernewsai.com/" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://hackernewsai.com/&lt;/a&gt; newsletter.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 19:16:40 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46304163</link><dc:creator>alexgotoi</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46304163</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46304163</guid></item><item><title>New comment by dang in "Tell HN: HN was down"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Yes, sorry! We're investigating, but my current theory is we got overloaded because I relaxed some of our anti-crawler protections a few days ago.&lt;p&gt;(The reason I did that is that the anti-crawler protections also unfortunately hit some legit users, and we don't want to block legit users. However, it seems that I turned the knobs down too far.)&lt;p&gt;In this case, though, we had a secondary failure: PagerDuty woke me up at 5:24am, I checked HN and it seemed fine, so I told PagerDuty the problem was resolved. But the problem wasn't resolved - at that point I was just sleeping through it.&lt;p&gt;I'll add more as we find out more, but it probably won't be till later this afternoon PST.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 18:09:25 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46303196</link><dc:creator>dang</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46303196</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46303196</guid></item><item><title>New comment by Elfener in "Tell HN: HN was down"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I got stuck in an infinite loop.&lt;p&gt;Try opening HN -&gt; it's down, better check HN to see everyone talking about a major website being down -&gt; Try opening HN -&gt; loop&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 17:09:28 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46302283</link><dc:creator>Elfener</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46302283</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46302283</guid></item><item><title>New comment by manbitesdog in "Tell HN: HN was down"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;TIL I have a "open Hacker News" hand reflex&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 16:51:43 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46301962</link><dc:creator>manbitesdog</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46301962</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46301962</guid></item><item><title>New comment by samyok in "Gemini 3 Flash: Frontier intelligence built for speed"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Don’t let the “flash” name fool you, this is an amazing model.&lt;p&gt;I have been playing with it for the past few weeks, it’s genuinely my new favorite; it’s so fast and it has such a vast world knowledge that it’s more performant than Claude Opus 4.5 or GPT 5.2 extra high, for a fraction (basically order of magnitude less!!) of the inference time and price&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 16:46:20 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46301897</link><dc:creator>samyok</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46301897</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46301897</guid></item><item><title>New comment by JoeJonathan in "Is Mozilla trying hard to kill itself?"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Like many others, the ability to run uBO is the main reason I use Firefox. Otherwise I'd use Chrome or Safari.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 11:37:05 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46300847</link><dc:creator>JoeJonathan</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46300847</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46300847</guid></item><item><title>New comment by nialv7 in "Is Mozilla trying hard to kill itself?"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;The interpretation is not the problem. Whether he will do it, is actually secondary to the fact that he thinks cutting adblock can bringing in money.&lt;p&gt;No, it will just kill the browser. The fact he thinks otherwise tells me how out of touch he is.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 10:41:53 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46300387</link><dc:creator>nialv7</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46300387</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46300387</guid></item><item><title>New comment by lxgr in "Is Mozilla trying hard to kill itself?"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&gt;&gt; He says he could begin to block ad blockers in Firefox and estimates that’d bring in another $150 million, but he doesn’t want to do that. It feels off-mission.&lt;p&gt;&gt; It may be just me, but I read this as “I don't want to   but I'll kill AdBlockers in Firefox for buckerinos ”.&lt;p&gt;Yes, that does seem like a pretty uncharitable interpretation of that quote. I read it as "we won't do it, even though it would bring in $150M USD".&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 10:30:18 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46300288</link><dc:creator>lxgr</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46300288</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46300288</guid></item><item><title>New comment by herobird in "Is Mozilla trying hard to kill itself?"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;It's kinda frustrating that Mozilla's CEO thinks that axing ad-blockers would be financially beneficial for them. Quite the opposite is true (I believe) since a ton of users would leave Firefox for alternatives.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 10:18:56 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46300189</link><dc:creator>herobird</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46300189</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46300189</guid></item><item><title>New comment by QuadrupleA in "AI will make formal verification go mainstream"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I don't think formal verification really addresses most day-to-day programming problems:&lt;p&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;    * A user interface is confusing, or the English around it is unclear
    * An API you rely on changes, is deprecated, etc.
    * Users use something in unexpected ways
    * Updates forced by vendors or open source projects cause things to break
    * The customer isn't clear what they want
    * Complex behavior between interconnected systems, out of the purview of the formal language (OS + database + network + developer + VM + browser + user + web server)
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
For some mathematically pure task, sure, it's great. Or a low-level library like a regular expression parser or a compression codec. But I don't think that represents a lot of what most of us are tasked with, and those low-level "mathematically pure" libraries are generally pretty well handled by now.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 03:46:12 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46298001</link><dc:creator>QuadrupleA</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46298001</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46298001</guid></item><item><title>New comment by inkysigma in "No AI* Here – A Response to Mozilla's Next Chapter"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&gt; Large language models are something else entirely*. They are black boxes. You cannot audit them. You cannot truly understand what they do with your data. You cannot verify their behaviour. And Mozilla wants to put them at the heart of the browser and that doesn't sit well.&lt;p&gt;Am I being overly critical here or is this kind of a silly position to have right after talking about how neural machine translation is okay? Many of Firefox's LLM features like summarization afaik are powered by local models (hell even Chrome has local model options). It's weird to say neural translation is not a black box but LLMs are somehow black boxes that we cannot hope to understand what they do with the data, especially when viewed a bit fuzzily LLMs are scaled up versions of an architecture that was originally used for neural translation. Neural translation also has unverifiable behavior in the same sense.&lt;p&gt;I could interpret some of the data talk as talking about non local models but this very much seems like a more general criticism of LLMs as a whole when talking about Firefox features. Moreover, some of the critiques like verifiability of outputs and unlimited scope still don't make sense in this context. Browser LLM features except for explicitly AI browsers like Comet have so far had some scoping to their behavior, either in very narrow scopes like translation or summarization. The broadest scope I can think of is the side panels that show up which allow you to ask about a web page with context. Even then, I do not see what is inherently problematic about such scoping since the output behavior is confined to the side panel.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 00:13:27 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46296574</link><dc:creator>inkysigma</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46296574</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46296574</guid></item><item><title>New comment by klysm in "Announcing the Beta release of ty"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I really hope astral can monetize without a highly destructive rugpull, because they are building great tools and solving real problems.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 22:40:27 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46295665</link><dc:creator>klysm</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46295665</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46295665</guid></item><item><title>New comment by throwaway150 in "Pricing Changes for GitHub Actions"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;It is us, developers, who convinced our management to purchase GitHub Enterprise to be our forge. We didn't pay any heed to the values of software freedom. A closed source, proprietary software had good features. We saw that and convinced our management to purchase it. Never mind what cost it would impose in the future when the good software gets bad owners. Never mind that there were alternatives that were inferior but were community-developed, community-maintained and libre.&lt;p&gt;The writing is in the wall. First it was UX annoyances. Then it was GitHub Actions woes. Now it is paying money for running their software on your own hardware. It's only going to go downhill. Is it a good time now to learn from our mistakes and convince our teams and management to use community-maintained, libre alternatives? They may be inferior. They may lack features. But they're not going to pull user hostile tricks like this on you and me. And hey, if they are lacking features, maybe we should convince our management to let us contribute time to the community to add those features? It's a much better investment than sinking money into a software that will only grow more and more user hostile, isn't it?&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 21:57:23 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46295141</link><dc:creator>throwaway150</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46295141</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46295141</guid></item><item><title>New comment by vunderba in "GPT Image 1.5"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Okay results are in for GenAI Showdown with the new gpt-image 1.5 model for the editing portions of the site!&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://genai-showdown.specr.net/image-editing" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://genai-showdown.specr.net/image-editing&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;Conclusions&lt;p&gt;- OpenAI has always had some of the strongest prompt understanding alongside the weakest image fidelity. This update goes some way towards addressing this weakness.&lt;p&gt;- It's leagues better at making localized edits without altering the entire image's aesthetic than gpt-image-1, doubling the previous score from 4/12 to 8/12 and the only model that &lt;i&gt;legitimately passed the Giraffe prompt&lt;/i&gt;.&lt;p&gt;- It's one of the most steerable models with a 90% compliance rate&lt;p&gt;Updates to GenAI Showdown&lt;p&gt;- Added outtakes sections to each model's detailed report in the Text-to-Image category, showcasing notable failures and unexpected behaviors.&lt;p&gt;- New models have been added including REVE and Flux.2 Dev (a new locally hostable model).&lt;p&gt;- Finally got around to implementing a weighted scoring mechanism which considers pass/fail, quality, and compliance for a more holistic model evaluation (click pass/fail icon to toggle between scoring methods).&lt;p&gt;If you just want to compare gpt-image-1, gpt-image-1.5, and NB Pro at the same time:&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://genai-showdown.specr.net/image-editing?models=o4,nbp,g15" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://genai-showdown.specr.net/image-editing?models=o4,nbp...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 21:40:55 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46294934</link><dc:creator>vunderba</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46294934</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46294934</guid></item><item><title>New comment by ianstormtaylor in "Thin desires are eating life"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I can't help but feel that this article was written in a format that is the textual equivalent of thin desires…&lt;p&gt;Every sentence is separated into its own paragraph, like each one is supposed to be revelatory (or maybe tweet-worthy). It's pretty common design knowledge that if you try to emphasize everything, you end up emphasizing nothing. The result is that reading the article feels choppy, and weirdly unsatisfying, since the larger arc of each point is constantly being interrupted.&lt;p&gt;Why choose such an antithetical form, to what is otherwise an important and deep message?&lt;p&gt;The only answer that comes to mind is that the author's livelihood, or at least their internal gauge of success, is tied to manipulating readers' thin desires.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 21:16:00 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46294586</link><dc:creator>ianstormtaylor</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46294586</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46294586</guid></item><item><title>New comment by opminion in "No Graphics API"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;The article is missing this motivation paragraph, taken from the blog index:&lt;p&gt;&gt; &lt;i&gt;Graphics APIs and shader languages have significantly increased in complexity over the past decade. It’s time to start discussing how to strip down the abstractions to simplify development, improve performance, and prepare for future GPU workloads.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 20:08:51 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46293716</link><dc:creator>opminion</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46293716</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46293716</guid></item><item><title>New comment by golovast in "Pricing Changes for GitHub Actions"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;I got contacted by our rep a couple weeks ago, who informed me of this news. I thought it was a disaster and it really pissed me off. The rep couldn't even explain the reasoning well. It basically summed up to "because we can" and "where are you going to go?". He was shocked to find out that I didn't like it.&lt;p&gt;We currently self-host on kubernets/aws. The thing that really got to me isn't the new charge per se. It's the fact that GHA has a ton of problems. I can hold my nose and deal with them when it's free. But now that you're squeezing me, at least you could have created something like GHA 2.0 and added a charge for that. Instead, there are vague roadmap promises which don't even include things that I care about. Specifically:&lt;p&gt;- Jenkins had better kubernetes integration years ago. It's crazy that GHA can't beat that.&lt;p&gt;- "Reintroducing multi-label functionality" - yeah, so they first broke it. They did supply "reasons", which looked like they never talked to a customer. [1]&lt;p&gt;- Still no SDK of any kind.&lt;p&gt;- "Actions Data Stream" - or you can just fix your logging.&lt;p&gt;There are dozens more complains, which are easy enough to find. This kind of an approach just makes me want to make sure that I don't use GHA again. Even if I end up paying another vendor, at least I'll be treated as a customer.&lt;p&gt;[1] - &lt;a href="https://github.com/orgs/community/discussions/160682#discussioncomment-8063837" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://github.com/orgs/community/discussions/160682#discuss...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 18:33:37 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46292376</link><dc:creator>golovast</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46292376</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46292376</guid></item><item><title>New comment by fainpul in "alpr.watch"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;For years I've thought about doing an "art project" to make people more aware of the fact they are being observed – but I never actually got up and did it.&lt;p&gt;The idea was to seek spots in the city where public web cams are pointed at, and paint QR codes on the ground at those spots (using a template), linking to the camera stream. So when curious passerbys scan the code, they see themselves in a camera stream and feel "watched".&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 18:19:46 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46292120</link><dc:creator>fainpul</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46292120</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46292120</guid></item><item><title>New comment by andsens in "Pricing Changes for GitHub Actions"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;That's not a move of a company that thinks it can still grow. That's a Netflix "we have 90% of the market, let's squeeze them" move.  
This is the beginning. We have all seen this pattern over the last 5+ years. You &lt;i&gt;know&lt;/i&gt; their next few moves.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 18:10:42 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46291992</link><dc:creator>andsens</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46291992</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46291992</guid></item><item><title>New comment by gkoberger in "Mozilla appoints new CEO Anthony Enzor-Demeo"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Having worked at Mozilla a while ago, the CEO role is one I wouldn't wish on my worst enemy. Success is oddly defined: it's a non-profit (well, a for-profit owned by a non-profit) that needs to make a big profit in a short amount of time. And anything done to make that profit will annoy the community.&lt;p&gt;I hope Anthony leans into what makes Mozilla special. The past few years, Mozilla's business model has been to just meekly "us-too!" trends... IoT, Firefox OS, and more recently AI.&lt;p&gt;What Mozilla is good at, though, is taking complex things the average user doesn't really understand, and making it palpable and safe. They did this with web standards... nobody cared about web standards, but Mozilla focused on usability.&lt;p&gt;(Slide aside, it's not a coincidence the best CEO Mozilla ever had was a designer.)&lt;p&gt;I'm not an AI hater, but I don't think Mozilla can compete here. There's just too much good stuff already, and it's not the type of thing Mozilla will shine with.&lt;p&gt;Instead, if I were CEO, I'd go the opposite way: I'd focus on privacy. Not AI privacy, but privacy in general. Buy a really great email provider, and start to own "identity on the internet". As there's more bots and less privacy, identity is going to be incredibly important over the years.. and right now, Google defacto owns identity. Make it free, but also give people a way to pay.&lt;p&gt;Would this work? I don't know. But like I said, it's not a job I envy.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 17:56:50 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46291798</link><dc:creator>gkoberger</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46291798</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46291798</guid></item><item><title>New comment by MathiasPius in "Pricing Changes for GitHub Actions"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;Introducing a separate charge specifically targeting those of your customers who choose to self-host your hilariously fragile infrastructure is certainly a choice.. And one I assume is in no way tied to adoption/usage-based KPIs.&lt;p&gt;Of course, if you can just fence in your competition and charge admission, it'd be silly to invest time in building a superior product.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 17:46:00 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46291634</link><dc:creator>MathiasPius</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46291634</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46291634</guid></item><item><title>New comment by Arcuru in "Pricing Changes for GitHub Actions"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;&gt; We are introducing a $0.002 per-minute Actions cloud platform charge for all Actions workflows across GitHub-hosted and self-hosted runners.&lt;p&gt;Charging for self-hosted runners is an interesting choice. That's the same cost as their smallest hosted runners [1]&lt;p&gt;[1] - &lt;a href="https://docs.github.com/en/billing/reference/actions-runner-pricing#standard-github-hosted-runners" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://docs.github.com/en/billing/reference/actions-runner-...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 17:27:57 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46291358</link><dc:creator>Arcuru</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46291358</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46291358</guid></item><item><title>New comment by perlgeek in "Mozilla appoints new CEO Anthony Enzor-Demeo"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;They also have the "extensions that can do &lt;i&gt;real&lt;/i&gt; ad blocking" angle.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 14:18:40 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46288761</link><dc:creator>perlgeek</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46288761</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46288761</guid></item><item><title>New comment by tchalla in "Children with cancer scammed out of millions fundraised for their treatment"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;The root cause of the problem is that parents and children need to raise funds for cancer treatment in the first place.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 08:42:45 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46286208</link><dc:creator>tchalla</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46286208</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46286208</guid></item><item><title>New comment by isoprophlex in "JetBlue flight averts mid-air collision with US Air Force jet"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;We have the best mid-air collisions. Noone does it better, or so people tell me. We don't do sleepy silent disappearances over the Bermuda Triangle, that's SAD!! We blow em up, BIGLY, in someone else's airspace. A great PRESIDENT knows how to WIN at mid-air collisions. Thank you for your attention to this matter.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 08:09:42 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46286005</link><dc:creator>isoprophlex</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46286005</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46286005</guid></item><item><title>New comment by Animats in "Children with cancer scammed out of millions fundraised for their treatment"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;"The campaigns with the biggest apparent international reach were under the name of an organisation called Chance Letikva (Chance for Hope, in English) - registered in Israel and the US."&lt;p&gt;Chance Letikva is registered with the US IRS as a charity. They've filed a Form 990. Location is Brooklyn, NY. [1] Address is listed. It's a small house. It's also incorporated as CHANCE LETIKVA, INC. in New York State. Address matches. Names of officers not given. There's one name in the IRS filing, listed as the president.&lt;p&gt;Web site "&lt;a href="https://chanceletikva.org" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://chanceletikva.org&lt;/a&gt;" has been "suspended". Domain is still registered, via Namecheap.&lt;p&gt;Some on the ground digging and subpoenas should reveal who's behind this.&lt;p&gt;[1] &lt;a href="https://projects.propublica.org/nonprofits/organizations/852049371" rel="nofollow"&gt;https://projects.propublica.org/nonprofits/organizations/852...&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 07:45:57 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46285838</link><dc:creator>Animats</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46285838</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46285838</guid></item><item><title>New comment by tekno45 in "Ford kills the All-Electric F-150"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;The F-150 is a great power bank that comes with a very useful set of 4 tires and a steering wheel for a truly portable charging experience.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 03:11:16 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46284308</link><dc:creator>tekno45</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46284308</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46284308</guid></item><item><title>New comment by malvim in "JetBlue flight averts mid-air collision with US Air Force jet"</title><description>
&lt;p&gt;They could also not invade a country that did nothing to attack them, but I guess that’s asking too much.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 02:32:21 +0000</pubDate><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46284037</link><dc:creator>malvim</dc:creator><comments>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46284037</comments><guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=46284037</guid></item></channel></rss>